<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">42184726</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-622X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>203</Volume><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Behaviour research and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Behav Res Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Targeting hyperarousal to improve sleep: A network intervention analysis of a digital intervention for insomnia.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>105075</StartPage><MedlinePgn>105075</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.brat.2026.105075</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0005-7967(26)00128-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Digital cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia (CBT-I) is an effective and scalable treatment for chronic insomnia. However, treatment outcomes are typically evaluated using aggregated symptom scores, which obscure differential effects on individual symptoms and limit insights into underlying mechanisms. This study applied network intervention analysis (NIA) to investigate how somnovia, a self-guided digital CBT-I intervention, is associated with changes in individual symptoms of insomnia, depression, and anxiety over time.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">This secondary analysis used data from a randomized controlled trial including 290 adults with chronic insomnia who were randomized to somnovia plus treatment as usual or treatment as usual alone. Using item-level data from the Insomnia Severity Index (ISI), Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9), and Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7) collected at baseline, 3 months, and 6 months, NIA was conducted to identify direct and indirect associations between treatment assignment and individual symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At 3 months, somnovia was primarily associated with reductions in sleep-related worry, dissatisfaction with sleep, and difficulties relaxing, indicating early effects on cognitive and physiological arousal processes. Improvements in other symptoms appeared to occur indirectly through these core arousal-related processes. By 6 months, treatment-related associations were more broadly distributed across the symptom network, consistent with generalized improvements extending beyond sleep-specific complaints.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Together, these findings suggest that somnovia exerts its clinical effects by reducing hyperarousal as a central transdiagnostic process, through which improvements in insomnia may contribute to sustained benefits in broader mental health outcomes, including symptoms of depression and anxiety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov (NCT05558865).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Betz</LastName><ForeName>Linda T</ForeName><Initials>LT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GAIA, Research Department, Hamburg, Germany. Electronic address: linda.betz@gaia-group.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>G&#xf6;der</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe4;tsklinikum Schleswig-Holstein, Campus Kiel, Klinik f&#xfc;r Psychiatrie und Psychotherapie, Christian-Albrechts Universit&#xe4;t, Kiel, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jacob</LastName><ForeName>Gitta A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GAIA, Research Department, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riemann</LastName><ForeName>Dieter</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Medical Centre, Faculty of Medicine, University of Freiburg, Breisgau, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05558865</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Behav Res Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372477</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0005-7967</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Internet-based intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Network analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep initiation and maintenance disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transdiagnostic processes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest GAIA, the developer of somnovia, funds the positions of LTB and GAJ. DR is now speaker of the board of the German Sleep Society (non profit organization) and receives monthly honoraria for this task. DR is a member of the Executive Board of FAVT (Freiburger Ausbildungsinstitut f&#xfc;r Verhaltentherapie/Freiburg Institute for Behavioral Therapy; non profit organisation). In this function he receives honoraria for running examinations, giving lectures, attending board meetings and participating in the selection of candidates. DR was Editor-in-Chief of the Journal of Sleep Research which is owned by the European Sleep Research Society (non profit organisation) &#x2013; he received monthly payments for this task till December 2025. DR receives royalties for authored books and book chapters from several publishing companies (Elsevier, Hogrefe, Kohlhammer. Wiley and Sons, etc.). The published materials mainly deal with insomnia and its treatment. DR frequently lectures at conferences, meetings, seminars, mostly invited by the organizing bodies &#x2013; sometimes honoraria are paid for his engagement and usually travel costs (if travelling is involved) are covered. Most of his talks deal with aspects of insomnia. In the last 36 months DR received lecturing honoraria also from Novartis, GAIA AG and Idorsia. DR receives honoraria from GAIA (Germany), Meinstresscoach (Switzerland),/Mind (Germany), 7Mind (Germany), HelloBetter (Germany), Sympatient (Germany) and X-Trodes (Israel) for advising on the development of internet-based approaches to insomnia treatment and development of new measurement devices. RG has no competing interests to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">42184726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2026.105075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0005-7967(26)00128-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>