<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29691208</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2369-2529</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR rehabilitation and assistive technologies</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Use of Digital and Remote Communication Technologies as a Tool for Multiple Sclerosis Management: Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e5</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e5</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e5</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/rehab.7805</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Despite recent advances in multiple sclerosis (MS) care, many patients only infrequently access health care services, or are unable to access them easily, for reasons such as mobility restrictions, travel costs, consultation and treatment time constraints, and a lack of locally available MS expert services. Advances in mobile communications have led to the introduction of electronic health (eHealth) technologies, which are helping to improve both access to and the quality of health care services. As the Internet is now readily accessible through smart mobile devices, most people can take advantage of eHealth apps. The development of digital applications and remote communication technologies for patients with MS has increased rapidly in recent years. These apps are intended to complement traditional in-clinic approaches and can bring significant benefits to both patients with MS and health care providers (HCPs). For patients, such eHealth apps have been shown to improve outcomes and increase access to care, disease information, and support. These apps also help patients to participate actively in self-management, for example, by tracking adherence to treatment, changes in bladder and bowel habits, and activity and mood. For HCPs, MS eHealth solutions can simplify the multidisciplinary approaches needed to tailor MS management strategies to individual patients; facilitate remote monitoring of patient symptoms, adverse events, and outcomes; enable the efficient use of limited resources and clinic time; and potentially allow more timely intervention than is possible with scheduled face-to-face visits. These benefits are important because MS is a long-term, multifaceted chronic condition that requires ongoing monitoring, assessment, and management. We identified in the literature 28 eHealth solutions for patients with MS that fall within the four categories of screening and assessment, disease monitoring and self-management, treatment and rehabilitation, and advice and education. We review each solution, focusing on any clinical evidence supporting their use from prospective trials (including ASSESS MS, Deprexis, MSdialog, and the Multiple Sclerosis Performance Test) and consider the opportunities, barriers to adoption, and potential pitfalls of eHealth technologies in routine health care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Martin Marziniak, Giampaolo Brichetto, Peter Feys, Uta Meyding-Lamad&#xe9;, Karen Vernon, Sven G. Meuth. Originally published in JMIR Rehabilitation and Assistive Technology (http://rehab.jmir.org), 24.04.2018.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marziniak</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2128-1246</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Isar-Amper-Klinikum Munich-East, Haar, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brichetto</LastName><ForeName>Giampaolo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2026-3572</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Scientific Research Area, Italian Multiple Sclerosis Foundation, Genova, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feys</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5680-5495</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation Research Center, Biomedical Research Center, Faculty of Medicine and Life Sciences, Hasselt University, Diepenbeek, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyding-Lamad&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Uta</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4692-8843</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Krankenhaus Nordwest, Frankfurt, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vernon</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5194-4840</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Salford Royal National Health Service Foundation Trust, Salford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meuth</LastName><ForeName>Sven G</ForeName><Initials>SG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2571-3501</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of M&#xfc;nster, M&#xfc;nster, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101703412</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2369-2529</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">communication</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multiple sclerosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">technology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telehealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telemedicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telerehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: MM has received lecture fees, travel grants, and fees for consulting from Bayer HealthCare AG, Beiersdorf AG, Biogen Idec GmbH, Merck KGaA, Novartis Pharma GmbH, Pfizer Pharma GmbH, Sanofi-Aventis (Genzyme), and Teva. GB has nothing to disclose. PF has received lecture fees from Excemed and Biogen Idec and consulting fees from Biogen Idec and Novartis. UM-L has received lecture fees and travel grants from Almirall, Bayer, Biogen Idec, Genzyme, Merck Serono, Novartis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Sanofi, and Teva. KV has received lecture fees, travel grants, and fees for consulting from Bayer Schering, Biogen Idec, Genzyme, Merck Serono, Novartis, and Teva. SGM has received honoraria for lecturing and travel expenses for attending meetings and has received financial research support from Bayer, Bayer Schering, Biogen Idec, Genzyme, Merck Serono, MSD, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Sanofi-Aventis, Teva, and UCB.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29691208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/rehab.7805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v5i1e5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Khan F, Amatya B, Kesselring J, Galea M. Telerehabilitation for persons with multiple sclerosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015 Apr 09;(4):CD010508. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD010508.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD010508.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7211044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25854331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feys P, Giovannoni G, Dijsselbloem N, Centonze D, Eelen P, Lykke Andersen S. The importance of a multi-disciplinary perspective and patient activation programmes in MS management. Mult Scler. 2016 Aug;22(2 Suppl):34&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1177/1352458516650741.22/2_suppl/34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458516650741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27465614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingwell E, van der Kop M, Zhao Y, Shirani A, Zhu F, Oger J, Tremlett H. Relative mortality and survival in multiple sclerosis: findings from British Columbia, Canada. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2012 Jan;83(1):61&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2011-300616.jnnp-2011-300616</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2011-300616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21865212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan F, Amatya B, Kesselring J, Galea MP. Telerehabilitation for persons with multiple sclerosis. A Cochrane review. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2015 Jun;51(3):311&#x2013;25. 
 
R33Y9999N00A150029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25943744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasova K, Martinkova P, Pavlikoma M, Cattaneo D, Jonsdottir J, Henze T, Baert I, Van Asch P, Santovo C, Smedal T, Beiske AG, Stachowiak M, Kovalewski M, Nedeljkovic U, Bakalidou D, Alves-Guerreiro J, Nilsag&#xe5;rd Y, Dimitrova EN, Habek M, Armutlu K, Donz&#xe9; C, Ross E, Ilie AM, Marti&#x107; A. Physical therapy provision in multiple sclerosis across Europe: a regional lottery? Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2015 Dec;51(6):850&#x2013;2. 
 
R33Y9999N00A150066</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26334364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berbece C, Gavenas &#x17d;, Kasilingam E. 2013.  [2018-02-23].  MS Barometer 2013
 http://www.ms-sep.be/userfiles/files/emsp/MS%20Barometer%202013.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MSTrust.  [2017-03-24].  Is MS care fair?
 https://www.mstrust.org.uk/file/ms-care-media-reportpdf/download?token=R8dXTbMB
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G. What is e-health? J Med Internet Res. 2001 Jun;3(2):E20. doi: 10.2196/jmir.3.2.e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3.2.e20</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1761894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11720962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlayson M, Holberg C. Evaluation of a teleconference-delivered energy conservation education program for people with multiple sclerosis. Can J Occup Ther. 2007 Oct 04;74(4):337&#x2013;47. doi: 10.2182/cjot.06.0018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2182/cjot.06.0018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17985756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balkhi AM, Reid AM, Westen SC, Olsen B, Janicke DM, Geffken GR. Telehealth interventions to reduce management complications in type 1 diabetes: a review. World J Diabetes. 2015 Apr 15;6(3):371&#x2013;9. doi: 10.4239/wjd.v6.i3.371. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4239/wjd.v6.i3.371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4398894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25897348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison D, Wyke S, Agur K, Cameron EJ, Docking RI, Mackenzie AM, McConnachie A, Raghuvir V, Thomson NC, Mair FS. Digital asthma self-management interventions: a systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2014;16(2):e51. doi: 10.2196/jmir.2814. 
 
v16i2e51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.2814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3958674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godinho C, Domingos J, Cunha G, Santos AT, Fernandes RM, Abreu D, Gon&#xe7;alves N, Matthews H, Isaacs T, Duffen J, Al-Jawad A, Larsen F, Serrano A, Weber P, Thoms A, Sollinger S, Graessner H, Maetzler W, Ferreira JJ. A systematic review of the characteristics and validity of monitoring technologies to assess Parkinson's disease. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2016 Mar 12;13:24. doi: 10.1186/s12984-016-0136-7. 
 
10.1186/s12984-016-0136-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-016-0136-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4788909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26969628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lublin FD, Reingold SC, Cohen JA, Cutter GR, S&#xf8;rensen PS, Thompson AJ, Wolinsky JS, Balcer LJ, Banwell B, Barkhof F, Bebo Jr B, Calabresi PA, Clanet M, Comi G, Fox RJ, Freedman MS, Goodman AD, Inglese M, Kappos L, Kieseier BC, Lincoln JA, Lubetzki C, Miller AE, Montalban X, O'Connor PW, Petkau J, Pozzilli C, Rudick RA, Sormani MP, St&#xfc;ve O, Waubant E, Polman CH. Defining the clinical course of multiple sclerosis: the 2013 revisions. Neurology. 2014 Jul 15;83(3):278&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000000560. 
 
WNL.0000000000000560</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4117366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24871874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WeAreSocial. 2017.  [2018-02-14].  Special Reports - Digital in 2017: Global Overview
 https://wearesocialcom/special-reports/digital-in-2017-global-overview
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marrie RA, Salter AR, Tyry T, Fox RJ, Cutter GR. Preferred sources of health information in persons with multiple sclerosis: degree of trust and information sought. J Med Internet Res. 2013;15(4):e67. doi: 10.2196/jmir.2466. 
 
v15i4e67</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.2466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23635393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosslet GT, Torke AM, Hickman SE, Terry CL, Helft PR. The patient-doctor relationship and online social networks: results of a national survey. J Gen Intern Med. 2011 Oct;26(10):1168&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1007/s11606-011-1761-2. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-011-1761-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21706268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown J, Ryan C, Harris A. How doctors view and use social media: a national survey. J Med Internet Res. 2014;16(12):e267. doi: 10.2196/jmir.3589. 
 
v16i12e267</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4275505</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25470407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatzakis Jr M, Haselkorn J, Williams R, Turner A, Nichol P. Telemedicine and the delivery of health services to veterans with multiple sclerosis. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2003;40(3):265&#x2013;82. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14582530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flodgren G, Rachas A, Farmer AJ, Inzitari M, Shepperd S. Interactive telemedicine: effects on professional practice and health care outcomes. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;(9):CD002098. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD002098.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD002098.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26343551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudick RA, Miller D, Bethoux F, Rao SM, Lee JC, Stough D, Reece C, Schindler D, Mamone B, Alberts J. The Multiple Sclerosis Performance Test (MSPT): an iPad-based disability assessment tool. J Vis Exp. 2014 Jun 30;(88):e51318. doi: 10.3791/51318. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3791/51318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4209820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25046650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambercy O, Fluet MC, Lamers I, Kerkhofs L, Feys P, Gassert R. Assessment of upper limb motor function in patients with multiple sclerosis using the Virtual Peg Insertion Test: a pilot study. IEEE Int Conf Rehabil Robot. 2013 Jun;2013:6650494. doi: 10.1109/ICORR.2013.6650494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ICORR.2013.6650494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24187309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison C, D'Souza M, Huckvale K, Dorn JF, Burggraaff J, Kamm CP, Steinheimer SM, Kontschieder P, Criminisi A, Uitdehaag B, Dahlke F, Kappos L, Sellen A. Usability and acceptability of ASSESS MS: assessment of motor dysfunction in multiple sclerosis using depth-sensing computer vision. JMIR Hum Factors. 2015;2(1):e11. doi: 10.2196/humanfactors.4129. 
 
v2i1e11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/humanfactors.4129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4797664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27025782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Younes M, Hill J, Quinless J, Kilduff M, Peng B, Cook SD, Cadavid D. Internet-based cognitive testing in multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler. 2007 Sep;13(8):1011&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1177/1352458507077626.1352458507077626</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458507077626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17623730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlanger DM, Kaushik T, Broshek D, Freeman J, Feldman D, Festa J. Development and validation of a web-based screening tool for monitoring cognitive status. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2002 Oct;17(5):458&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12802255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beadnall HN, Kuppanda KE, O'Connell A, Hardy TA, Reddel SW, Barnett MH. Tablet-based screening improves continence management in multiple sclerosis. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2015 Jun;2(6):679&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1002/acn3.205. doi: 10.1002/acn3.205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4479527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26125042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurtzke JF. Rating neurologic impairment in multiple sclerosis: an expanded disability status scale (EDSS) Neurology. 1983 Nov;33(11):1444&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6685237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leddy S, Hadavi S, McCarren A, Giovannoni G, Dobson R. Validating a novel web-based method to capture disease progression outcomes in multiple sclerosis. J Neurol. 2013 Oct;260(10):2505&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1007/s00415-013-7004-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-013-7004-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23807152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lechner-Scott J, Kappos L, Hofman M, Polman CH, Ronner H, Montalban X, Tintore M, Frontoni M, Buttinelli C, Amato MP, Bartolozzi ML, Versavel M, Dahlke F, Kapp JF, Gibberd R. Can the Expanded Disability Status Scale be assessed by telephone? Mult Scler. 2003 Mar;9(2):154&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1191/1352458503ms884oa.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1191/1352458503ms884oa</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12708811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nortvedt MW, Riise T, Frug&#xe5;rd J, Mohn J, Bakke A, Sk&#xe5;r AB, Nyland H, Glad SB, Myhr KM. Prevalence of bladder, bowel and sexual problems among multiple sclerosis patients two to five years after diagnosis. Mult Scler. 2007 Jan;13(1):106&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1177/1352458506071210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458506071210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17294618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahajan ST, Patel PB, Marrie RA. Under treatment of overactive bladder symptoms in patients with multiple sclerosis: an ancillary analysis of the NARCOMS Patient Registry. J Urol. 2010 Apr;183(4):1432&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.juro.2009.12.029.S0022-5347(09)03193-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.juro.2009.12.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20171697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritvo P, Fischer J, Miller D. 1997.  [2018-03-11].  Multiple sclerosis quality of life inventory: a user's manual
 http://walkcoc.nationalmssociety.org/docs/HOM/MSQLI_Manual_and_Forms.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>University of California San Francisco.  [2017-03-22].  The MS Bioscreen
 http://neurology.ucsf.edu/research/ms-bioscreen
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gourraud PA, Henry RG, Cree BA, Crane JC, Lizee A, Olson MP, Santaniello AV, Datta E, Zhu AH, Bevan CJ, Gelfand JM, Graves JS, Goodin DS, Green AJ, von B&#xfc;dingen H, Waubant E, Zamvil SS, Crabtree-Hartman E, Nelson S, Baranzini SE, Hauser SL. Precision medicine in chronic disease management: the multiple sclerosis BioScreen. Ann Neurol. 2014 Nov;76(5):633&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1002/ana.24282. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4214886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25263997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauser S, Gourraud PA. 2013.  MS Bioscreen Project Summary
 http://campuslifeservices.ucsf.edu/upload/neurology/files/Bioscreen_Research_Summary.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kern R, Haase R, Eisele JC, Thomas K, Ziemssen T. Designing an electronic patient management system for multiple sclerosis: building a next generation multiple sclerosis documentation system. Interact J Med Res. 2016 Jan 08;5(1):e2. doi: 10.2196/ijmr.4549. 
 
v5i1e2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/ijmr.4549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4723723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisele J, Kern R, Alexander S, Gro&#xdf;mann L, Schultheiss T, Ziemssen T. Multiple Sclerosis Documentation System MSDS3D - innovative management of patients with multiple sclerosis (I8-1.003) Neurology. 2014 Apr;82(10 supplement) 
 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jongen PJ, Sinnige LG, van Geel BM, Verheul F, Verhagen WI, van der Kruijk RA, Haverkamp R, Schrijver HM, Baart JC, Visser LH, Arnoldus EP, Gilhuis HJ, Pop P, Booy M, Heerings M, Kool A, van Noort NE. The interactive web-based program MSmonitor for self-management and multidisciplinary care in multiple sclerosis: utilization and valuation by patients. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2016;10:243&#x2013;50. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S93786. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S93786.ppa-10-243</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PPA.S93786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4780403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27042018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shammas L, Zentek T, von Haaren B, Schlesinger S, Hey S, Rashid A. Home-based system for physical activity monitoring in patients with multiple sclerosis (Pilot study) Biomed Eng Online. 2014 Feb 06;13:10. doi: 10.1186/1475-925X-13-10. 
 
1475-925X-13-10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-925X-13-10</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3927216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24502230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks P, Vaughan TE, Massagli MP. The multiple sclerosis rating scale, revised (MSRS-R): development, refinement, and psychometric validation using an online community. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2012 Jun 18;10:70. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-10-70. 
 
1477-7525-10-70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-10-70</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3502161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22709981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Novartis.  [2018-02-14].  SymTrac
 https://www.novartis.co.uk/symtrac.shtml
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Multiple Sclerosis Association of America  Mymsaa.  [2018-02-14].  My MS Manager&#x2122;
 https://mymsaa.org/msaa-community/mobile/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greiner P, Sawka A, Imison E. Patient and physician perspectives on MSdialog, an electronic PRO diary in multiple sclerosis. Patient. 2015 Dec;8(6):541&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1007/s40271-015-0140-1. 
 
10.1007/s40271-015-0140-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40271-015-0140-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4662959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26350792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tensai Solutions LLC.  MS Journal
 https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ms-journal/id523663325
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betaseron.  [2018-02-14].  myBETAapp&#x2122;
 https://www.betaseron.com/betaconnect-system/mybetaapp/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Settle JR, Maloni HW, Bedra M, Finkelstein J, Zhan M, Wallin MT. Monitoring medication adherence in multiple sclerosis using a novel web-based tool: A pilot study. J Telemed Telecare. 2016 Jun;22(4):225&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1177/1357633X15597115.1357633X15597115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1357633X15597115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26253748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roche J, McCarry Y, Mellors K. Enhanced patient support services improve patient persistence with multiple sclerosis treatment. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2014;8:805&#x2013;11. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S59496. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S59496.ppa-8-805</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PPA.S59496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4062553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24966668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jongen PJ, Sinnige LG, van Geel BM, Verheul F, Verhagen WI, van der Kruijk RA, Haverkamp R, Schrijver HM, Baart JC, Visser LH, Arnoldus EP, Gilhuis HJ, Pop P, Booy M, Lemmens W, Donders R, Kool A, van Noort E. The interactive web-based program MSmonitor for self-management and multidisciplinary care in multiple sclerosis: concept, content, and pilot results. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2015;9:1741&#x2013;50. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S93783. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S93783.ppa-9-1741</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PPA.S93783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4685885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26715841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gijbels D, Alders G, Van Hoof E, Charlier C, Roelants M, Broekmans T, Eijnde BO', Feys P. Predicting habitual walking performance in multiple sclerosis: relevance of capacity and self-report measures. Mult Scler. 2010 May;16(5):618&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1177/1352458510361357.1352458510361357</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458510361357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20207785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viqueira Villarejo M, Maeso Garcia J, Garc&#xed;a Zapirain B, M&#xe9;ndez Zorrilla A. Technological solution for determining gait parameters using pressure sensors: a case study of multiple sclerosis patients. Biomed Mater Eng. 2014;24(6):3511&#x2013;22. doi: 10.3233/BME-141177.X60834615J18408V</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BME-141177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25227064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sola-Valls N, Blanco Y, Sep&#xfa;lveda M, Llufriu S, Mart&#xed;nez-Lapiscina EH, La PD, Graus F, Villoslada P, Saiz A. Walking function in clinical monitoring of multiple sclerosis by telemedicine. J Neurol. 2015 Jul;262(7):1706&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1007/s00415-015-7764-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-015-7764-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25957639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks P, Massagli M, Frost J, Brownstein C, Okun S, Vaughan T, Bradley R, Heywood J. Sharing health data for better outcomes on PatientsLikeMe. J Med Internet Res. 2010;12(2):e19. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1549. 
 
v12i2e19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2956230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20542858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts M, Lush T, Pohorely J. Improving reporting of multiple sclerosis relapse. Nurs Times. 2015;111(48):12&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26775329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebismart.  [2018-02-14].  What is MSdialog?
 http://www.rebismart.com/en/msdialog/what_is_msdialog/what_is_msdialog.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebismart.  [2018-02-14].  What is RebiSmart&#xae;?
 http://www.rebismart.com/en/rebismart/what_is_rebismart/what_is_rebismart.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heesen C, Bruce J, Feys P, Sastre-Garriga J, Solari A, Eliasson L, Matthews V, Hausmann B, Ross AP, Asano M, Imonen-Charalambous K, K&#xf6;pke S, Clyne W, Bissell P. Adherence in multiple sclerosis (ADAMS): classification, relevance, and research needs. A meeting report. Mult Scler. 2014 Nov;20(13):1795&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1177/1352458514531348.1352458514531348</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458514531348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24756569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelstein J, Wood J. Design and implementation of Home Automated Telemanagement system for patients with multiple sclerosis. Conf Proc IEEE Eng Med Biol Soc. 2009;2009:6091&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1109/IEMBS.2009.5334948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/IEMBS.2009.5334948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19965257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuifbergen AK, Becker H, Perez F, Morison J, Kullberg V, Todd A. A randomized controlled trial of a cognitive rehabilitation intervention for persons with multiple sclerosis. Clin Rehabil. 2012 Oct;26(10):882&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1177/0269215511434997.0269215511434997</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215511434997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22301679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amato MP, Goretti B, Viterbo RG, Portaccio E, Niccolai C, Hakiki B, Iaffaldano P, Trojano M. Computer-assisted rehabilitation of attention in patients with multiple sclerosis: results of a randomized, double-blind trial. Mult Scler. 2014 Jan;20(1):91&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1177/1352458513501571.1352458513501571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458513501571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23959713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frevel D, M&#xe4;urer M. Internet-based home training is capable to improve balance in multiple sclerosis: a randomized controlled trial. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med. 2015 Feb;51(1):23&#x2013;30. 
 
R33Y9999N00A140316</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24755773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tacchino A, Pedull&#xe0; L, Bonzano L, Vassallo C, Battaglia MA, Mancardi G, Bove M, Brichetto G. A new app for at-home cognitive training: description and pilot testing on patients with multiple sclerosis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2015 Aug 31;3(3):e85. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.4269. 
 
v3i3e85</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.4269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4704979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26323749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul L, Coulter EH, Miller L, McFadyen A, Dorfman J, Mattison PG. Web-based physiotherapy for people moderately affected with multiple sclerosis; quantitative and qualitative data from a randomized, controlled pilot study. Clin Rehabil. 2014 Sep;28(9):924&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1177/0269215514527995.0269215514527995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215514527995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24691218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss-Morris R, McCrone P, Yardley L, van Kessel K, Wills G, Dennison L. A pilot randomised controlled trial of an Internet-based cognitive behavioural therapy self-management programme (MS Invigor8) for multiple sclerosis fatigue. Behav Res Ther. 2012 Jun;50(6):415&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2012.03.001.S0005-7967(12)00051-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2012.03.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22516321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamson BC, Learmonth YC, Kinnett-Hopkins D, Bohri M, Motl RW. Feasibility study design and methods for Project GEMS: Guidelines for Exercise in Multiple Sclerosis. Contemp Clin Trials. 2016 Mar;47:32&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.cct.2015.12.002.S1551-7144(15)30133-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2015.12.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26655434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Schr&#xf6;der J, Vettorazzi E, Wolf OT, P&#xf6;ttgen J, Lau S, Heesen C, Moritz S, Gold SM. An online programme to reduce depression in patients with multiple sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Psychiatry. 2015 Mar;2(3):217&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00049-2.S2215-0366(14)00049-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00049-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasschau M, Reisner J, Sherman K, Bikson M, Datta A, Charvet LE. Transcranial direct current stimulation is feasible for remotely supervised home delivery in multiple sclerosis. Neuromodulation. 2016 Dec;19(8):824&#x2013;831. doi: 10.1111/ner.12430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ner.12430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27089545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasschau M, Sherman K, Haider L, Frontario A, Shaw M, Datta A, Bikson M, Charvet L. A protocol for the use of remotely-supervised transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) in multiple sclerosis (MS) J Vis Exp. 2015 Dec 26;(106):e53542. doi: 10.3791/53542. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3791/53542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4780857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuifbergen A, Becker H, Morgan S, Morrison J, Perez F. Home-based computer-assisted cognitive training: feasibility and perceptions of people with multiple sclerosis. Int J MS Care. 2011 Jan 01;13(4):189&#x2013;198. doi: 10.7224/1537-2073-13.4.189. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7224/1537-2073-13.4.189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3381728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22740777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedull&#xe0; L, Brichetto G, Tacchino A, Vassallo C, Zaratin P, Battaglia MA, Bonzano L, Bove M. Adaptive vs. non-adaptive cognitive training by means of a personalized app: a randomized trial in people with multiple sclerosis. J Neuroeng Rehabil. 2016 Oct 04;13(1):88. doi: 10.1186/s12984-016-0193-y. 
 
10.1186/s12984-016-0193-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12984-016-0193-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5050994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27716336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul L.  [2018-02-14].  Web based physiotherapy
 https://www.webbasedphysio.com/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelstein J, Lapshin O, Castro H, Cha E, Provance PG. Home-based physical telerehabilitation in patients with multiple sclerosis: a pilot study. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2008;45(9):1361&#x2013;73. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19319760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motl RW, Dlugonski D. Increasing physical activity in multiple sclerosis using a behavioral intervention. Behav Med. 2011 Oct;37(4):125&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1080/08964289.2011.636769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08964289.2011.636769</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22168329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dlugonski D, Motl RW, Mohr DC, Sandroff BM. Internet-delivered behavioral intervention to increase physical activity in persons with multiple sclerosis: sustainability and secondary outcomes. Psychol Health Med. 2012;17(6):636&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1080/13548506.2011.652640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13548506.2011.652640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22313192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forsberg A, Nilsag&#xe5;rd Y, Bostr&#xf6;m K. Perceptions of using videogames in rehabilitation: a dual perspective of people with multiple sclerosis and physiotherapists. Disabil Rehabil. 2015;37(4):338&#x2013;44. doi: 10.3109/09638288.2014.918196. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/09638288.2014.918196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4364246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24833535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pau M, Coghe G, Corona F, Leban B, Marrosu MG, Cocco E. Effectiveness and limitations of unsupervised home-based balance rehabilitation with Nintendo Wii in people with multiple sclerosis. Biomed Res Int. 2015;2015:916478. doi: 10.1155/2015/916478. doi: 10.1155/2015/916478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/916478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4637091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26583146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor MJ, Griffin M. The use of gaming technology for rehabilitation in people with multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler. 2015 Apr;21(4):355&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1177/1352458514563593.1352458514563593</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458514563593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25533296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brichetto G, Spallarossa P, de Carvalho ML, Battaglia MA. The effect of Nintendo&#xae; Wii&#xae; on balance in people with multiple sclerosis: a pilot randomized control study. Mult Scler. 2013 Aug;19(9):1219&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1177/1352458512472747.1352458512472747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458512472747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23322502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsag&#xe5;rd YE, Forsberg AS, von Koch L. Balance exercise for persons with multiple sclerosis using Wii games: a randomised, controlled multi-centre study. Mult Scler. 2013 Feb;19(2):209&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1177/1352458512450088.1352458512450088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458512450088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22674972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson J, Dixon J, Macsween A, van Schaik P, Martin D. The effects of exergaming on balance, gait, technology acceptance and flow experience in people with multiple sclerosis: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Sports Sci Med Rehabil. 2015;7:8. doi: 10.1186/s13102-015-0001-1. 
 
1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13102-015-0001-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4427959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25969739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prosperini L, Fanelli F, Petsas N, Sbardella E, Tona F, Raz E, Fortuna D, De Angelis F, Pozzilli C, Pantano P. Multiple sclerosis: changes in microarchitecture of white matter tracts after training with a video game balance board. Radiology. 2014 Nov;273(2):529&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1148/radiol.14140168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.14140168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25158046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eguiluz-Perez G, Garcia-Zapirain B. Comprehensive verticality analysis and web-based rehabilitation system for people with multiple sclerosis with supervised medical monitoring. Biomed Mater Eng. 2014;24(6):3493&#x2013;502. doi: 10.3233/BME-141175.WV8H309160621554</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/BME-141175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25227062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehde DM, Elzea JL, Verrall AM, Gibbons LE, Smith AE, Amtmann D. Efficacy of a telephone-delivered self-management intervention for persons with multiple sclerosis: a randomized controlled trial with a one-year follow-up. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2015 Nov;96(11):1945&#x2013;58.e2. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2015.07.015.S0003-9993(15)00647-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.apmr.2015.07.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26254948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baron KG, Corden M, Jin L, Mohr DC. Impact of psychotherapy on insomnia symptoms in patients with depression and multiple sclerosis. J Behav Med. 2011 Apr;34(2):92&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1007/s10865-010-9288-2. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10865-010-9288-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3520065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20809354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner AP, Hartoonian N, Sloan AP, Benich M, Kivlahan DR, Hughes C, Hughes AJ, Haselkorn JK. Improving fatigue and depression in individuals with multiple sclerosis using telephone-administered physical activity counseling. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2016 Apr;84(4):297&#x2013;309. doi: 10.1037/ccp0000086.2016-10040-001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/ccp0000086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26913621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr DC, Likosky W, Bertagnolli A, Goodkin DE, Van Der Wende J, Dwyer P, Dick LP. Telephone-administered cognitive-behavioral therapy for the treatment of depressive symptoms in multiple sclerosis. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2000 Apr;68(2):356&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10780138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosio D, Jin L, Siddique J, Mohr DC. The effect of telephone-administered cognitive-behavioral therapy on quality of life among patients with multiple sclerosis. Ann Behav Med. 2011 Apr;41(2):227&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1007/s12160-010-9236-y. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12160-010-9236-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3108488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21069585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilutti LA, Dlugonski D, Sandroff BM, Klaren R, Motl RW. Randomized controlled trial of a behavioral intervention targeting symptoms and physical activity in multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler. 2014 Apr;20(5):594&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1177/1352458513503391.1352458513503391</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458513503391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24009162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boeschoten RE, Dekker J, Uitdehaag BM, Polman CH, Collette EH, Cuijpers P, Beekman AT, van Oppen P. Internet-based self-help treatment for depression in multiple sclerosis: study protocol of a randomized controlled trial. BMC Psychiatry. 2012 Sep 11;12:137. doi: 10.1186/1471-244X-12-137. 
 
1471-244X-12-137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-12-137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3493307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22967202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavalera C, Pagnini F, Rovaris M, Mendozzi L, Pugnetti L, Garegnani M, Molinari E. A telemedicine meditation intervention for people with multiple sclerosis and their caregivers: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2016 Jan 04;17:4. doi: 10.1186/s13063-015-1136-9. 
 
10.1186/s13063-015-1136-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-015-1136-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4700623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26729330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egner A, Phillips VL, Vora R, Wiggers E. Depression, fatigue, and health-related quality of life among people with advanced multiple sclerosis: results from an exploratory telerehabilitation study. NeuroRehabilitation. 2003;18(2):125&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12867675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kessel K, Wouldes T, Moss-Morris R. A New Zealand pilot randomized controlled trial of a web-based interactive self-management programme (MSInvigor8) with and without email support for the treatment of multiple sclerosis fatigue. Clin Rehabil. 2016 May;30(5):454&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1177/0269215515584800.0269215515584800</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269215515584800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25952587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deprexis.  [2017-03-22].  Deprexis: the effective online program for treating depression
 http://deprexis.com/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallner A, Streber R, Hentschke C, Morgott M, Geidl W, M&#xe4;urer M, Pfeifer K. Internet-supported physical exercise training for persons with multiple sclerosis-a randomised, controlled study. Int J Mol Sci. 2016 Sep 30;17(10) doi: 10.3390/ijms17101667. 
 
ijms17101667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms17101667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5085700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27706046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tallner A, Pfeifer K, M&#xe4;urer M. Web-based interventions in multiple sclerosis: the potential of tele-rehabilitation. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2016 Jul;9(4):327&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1177/1756285616640684. 
 
10.1177_1756285616640684</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1756285616640684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4916521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27366240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healthline Networks Inc.  MS Buddy (version 2.0.1)
 https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ms-buddy/id1040195462
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acorda Therapeutics Inc.  [2018-02-14].  MS self&#x2122;, the Multiple Sclerosis Mobile App
 http://www.moveoverms.org/multiple-sclerosis-app-ms-self/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atreja A, Mehta N, Miller D, Moore S, Nichols K, Miller H, Harris CM. One size does not fit all: using qualitative methods to inform the development of an Internet portal for multiple sclerosis patients. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2005 Jan 1;:16&#x2013;20. 
 
58909</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1560589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16778993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DM, Moore SM, Fox RJ, Atreja A, Fu AZ, Lee J, Saupe W, Stadtler M, Chakraborty S, Harris CM, Rudick RA. Web-based self-management for patients with multiple sclerosis: a practical, randomized trial. Telemed J E Health. 2011;17(1):5&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1089/tmj.2010.0133. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/tmj.2010.0133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21214498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen AS, Halamka JD, Kinkel RP. Internet portal use in an academic multiple sclerosis center. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2012 Feb;19(1):128&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1136/amiajnl-2011-000177. 
 
amiajnl-2011-000177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/amiajnl-2011-000177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3240754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21571744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haase R, Schultheiss T, Kempcke R, Thomas K, Ziemssen T. Use and acceptance of electronic communication by patients with multiple sclerosis: a multicenter questionnaire study. J Med Internet Res. 2012;14(5):e135. doi: 10.2196/jmir.2133. 
 
v14i5e135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.2133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3510727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23069209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lejbkowicz I, Paperna T, Stein N, Dishon S, Miller A. Internet usage by patients with multiple sclerosis: implications to participatory medicine and personalized healthcare. Mult Scler Int. 2010;2010:640749. doi: 10.1155/2010/640749. doi: 10.1155/2010/640749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2010/640749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22096625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner AP, Wallin MT, Sloan A, Maloni H, Kane R, Martz L, Haselkorn JK. Clinical management of multiple sclerosis through home telehealth monitoring: results of a pilot project. Int J MS Care. 2013;15(1):8&#x2013;14. doi: 10.7224/1537-2073.2012-012. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7224/1537-2073.2012-012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3883035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24453757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cha E, Castro HK, Provance P, Finkelstein J. Acceptance of home telemanagement is high in patients with multiple sclerosis. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2007 Oct 11;:893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18693994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Plow M, Finlayson M. A qualitative study exploring the usability of Nintendo Wii Fit among persons with multiple sclerosis. Occup Ther Int. 2014 Mar;21(1):21&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1002/oti.1345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oti.1345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23613154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tahir R, Tahir H, McDonald-Maier K. Securing health sensing using integrated circuit metric. Sensors (Basel) 2015 Oct 20;15(10):26621&#x2013;42. doi: 10.3390/s151026621. 
 
s151026621</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s151026621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4634399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26492250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jongen PJ, Heerings M, Lemmens WA, Donders R, van der Zande A, van Noort E, Kool A. A prospective web-based patient-centred interactive study of long-term disabilities, disabilities perception and health-related quality of life in patients with multiple sclerosis in The Netherlands: the Dutch Multiple Sclerosis Study protocol. BMC Neurol. 2015 Aug 04;15:128. doi: 10.1186/s12883-015-0379-0. 
 
10.1186/s12883-015-0379-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-015-0379-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4524214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26238866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemssen T, Kempcke R, Eulitz M, Gro&#xdf;mann L, Suhrbier A, Thomas K, Schultheiss T. Multiple sclerosis documentation system (MSDS): moving from documentation to management of MS patients. J Neural Transm. 2013 Sep;120 Suppl 1:S61&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1007/s00702-013-1041-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-013-1041-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23728704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotopf M, Narayan V. Radar-cns. 2016.  [2018-02-14].  Remote Assessment of Disease and Relapse in Central Nervous System Disorders (RADAR-CNS)
 https://www.radar-cns.org/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brichetto G, De Vita I, Tacchino A, Bulgheroni M, d'Amico E. Assessment of an m-health intervention to deliver self-management strategies in patients with multiple sclerosis. Lancet Neurology conference; October, 19-21; London, UK. 2016.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>