<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">31999743</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of a tailored, integrative Internet intervention (deprexis) for depression: Updated meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0228100</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0228100</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0228100</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0228100</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Digitally delivered interventions for depression vary in many aspects, including their therapeutic orientation, depth of content, interactivity, individual tailoring, inclusion of multimedia, cost, and effectiveness. However, their effectiveness is rarely examined in intervention-specific meta-analyses. An earlier meta-analysis of eight randomized controlled trials (RCT) demonstrated the effectiveness of a tailored, integrative digital intervention (deprexis), which is delivered via the Internet. This updated meta-analysis of twelve deprexis-specific RCT with a total of N = 2901 participants confirmed the effectiveness of deprexis for depression reduction at post-intervention (g = 0.51, 95% CI: 0.40-0.62, I2 = 26%). Results were analogous when study quality, screening and randomization procedure were taken into account. Clinician guidance, developer-involvement, setting (community vs. clinical), and initial symptom severity did not have statistically significant effects on the effect size, and there was no evidence of publication bias. Thus, these findings demonstrate that deprexis can facilitate clinically relevant reduction of depressive symptoms over 8-12 weeks across a broad range of initial symptom severity, and that the intervention can be combined with other forms of depression treatment. There is now a need to study the intervention's implementation in routine care settings as well as its long-term effectiveness and cost-effectiveness in diverse cultural and linguistic settings.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Twomey</LastName><ForeName>Conal</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, University College Dublin, Belfield, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Reilly</LastName><ForeName>Gary</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, University College Dublin, Belfield, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B&#xfc;ltmann</LastName><ForeName>Oliver</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department, Gaia, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyer</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1100-0260</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Department, Gaia, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, City, University of London, London, England, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="Y">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020407" MajorTopicYN="Y">Internet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Competing Interests Statement: Two of the authors (B.M. and O.B.) are employed by Gaia AG, Hamburg, the company that developed, owns and operates the Internet intervention examined in this article. This does not alter our adherence to PLOS ONE policies on sharing data and materials.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31999743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0228100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-19-25463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chisholm D, Sweeny K, Sheehan P, Rasmussen B, Smit F, Cuijpers P, et al. Scaling-up treatment of depression and anxiety: a global return on investment analysis. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2016;3(5):415&#x2013;24. 10.1016/S2215-0366(16)30024-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(16)30024-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27083119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E, Riper H, Twisk J, Hoogendoorn A, Kleiboer A, Mira A, et al. Efficacy of self-guided internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy in the treatment of depressive symptoms: a meta-analysis of individual participant data. JAMA psychiatry. 2017;74(4):351&#x2013;9. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28241179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Carlbring P, Titov N, Lindefors N. Internet Interventions for Adults with Anxiety and Mood Disorders: A Narrative Umbrella Review of Recent Meta-Analyses. The Canadian Journal of Psychiatry. 2019:0706743719839381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6610559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31096757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renton T, Tang H, Ennis N, Cusimano MD, Bhalerao S, Schweizer TA, et al. Web-based intervention programs for depression: a scoping review and evaluation. Journal of medical Internet research. 2014;16(9):e209 10.2196/jmir.3147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4211022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbody S, Littlewood E, Hewitt C, Brierley G, Tharmanathan P, Araya R, et al. Computerised cognitive behaviour therapy (cCBT) as treatment for depression in primary care (REEACT trial): large scale pragmatic randomised controlled trial. Bmj. 2015;351:h5627 10.1136/bmj.h5627</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.h5627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26559241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Turner EH, Koole SL, Dijke A, Smit F. What is the threshold for a clinically relevant effect? The case of major depressive disorders. Depression and anxiety. 2014;31(5):374&#x2013;8. 10.1002/da.22249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24677535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O&#x2019;Reilly G. Effectiveness of a freely available computerised cognitive behavioural therapy programme (MoodGYM) for depression: Meta-analysis. Australian &amp; New Zealand Journal of Psychiatry. 2017;51(3):260&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27384752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Berger T, Caspar F, Beevers C, Andersson G, Weiss M. Effectiveness of a novel integrative online treatment for depression (Deprexis): randomized controlled trial. Journal of medical Internet research. 2009;11(2):e15 10.2196/jmir.1151</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19632969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Bierbrodt J, Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Beevers CG, Weiss M, et al. Effects of an internet intervention (Deprexis) on severe depression symptoms: randomized controlled trial. Internet Interventions. 2015;2(1):48&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beevers CG, Pearson R, Hoffman JS, Foulser A, Shumake J, Meyer B. Effectiveness of an internet intervention for depression in a US adult sample: A parallel-group pragmatic randomized controlled trial. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28230390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O&#x2019;Reilly G, Meyer B. Effectiveness of an individually-tailored computerised cognitive behavioural therapy programme (Deprexis) for depression: a meta-analysis. Psychiatry Research. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold SM, Enck P, Hasselmann H, Friede T, Hegerl U, Mohr DC, et al. Control conditions for randomised trials of behavioural interventions in psychiatry: a decision framework. The lancet Psychiatry. 2017;4(9):725&#x2013;32. 10.1016/S2215-0366(17)30153-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(17)30153-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28396067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furukawa T, Noma H, Caldwell D, Honyashiki M, Shinohara K, Imai H, et al. Waiting list may be a nocebo condition in psychotherapy trials: A contribution from network meta&#x2010;analysis. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica. 2014;130(3):181&#x2013;92. 10.1111/acps.12275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acps.12275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24697518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Green S. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S. A Reply to "Effectiveness of an individually-tailored computerised CBT programme (Deprexis) for depression: A meta-analysis" by Twomey and colleagues [Psychiatry Res. 256 (2017) 371&#x2013;377]. Psychiatry research. 2018;263 10.1016/j.psychres.2017.08.033</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2017.08.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29046227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O'Reilly G, Meyer B. Reply to Dr Moritz. Psychiatry research. 2018;263:283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29050750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval S, Tweedie R. Trim and fill: a simple funnel&#x2010;plot&#x2013;based method of testing and adjusting for publication bias in meta&#x2010;analysis. Biometrics. 2000;56(2):455&#x2013;63. 10.1111/j.0006-341x.2000.00455.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0006-341x.2000.00455.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Hammerli K, Gubser N, Andersson G, Caspar F. Internet-based treatment of depression: a randomized controlled trial comparing guided with unguided self-help. Cogn Behav Ther. 2011;40(4):251&#x2013;66. Epub 2011/11/09. 10.1080/16506073.2011.616531 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2011.616531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22060248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Krieger T, Sude K, Meyer B, Maercker A. Evaluating an e-mental health program ("deprexis") as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: Results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. Journal of Affective Disorders. 10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;cker L, Bierbrodt J, Hand I, Wittekind C, Moritz S. Effects of a depression-focused internet intervention in slot machine gamblers: A randomized controlled trial. PloS one. 2018;13(6):e0198859 10.1371/journal.pone.0198859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0198859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5993308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29883479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Schr&#xf6;der J, Vettorazzi E, Wolf OT, P&#xf6;ttgen J, Lau S, et al. An online programme to reduce depression in patients with multiple sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2015;2(3):217&#x2013;23. 10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00049-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00049-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuhr K, Fahse B, Hautzinger M, Gulewitsch MD. Erste Erfahrungen zur Implementierbarkeit einer internet-basierten Selbsthilfe zur &#xdc;berbr&#xfc;ckung der Wartezeit auf eine ambulante Psychotherapie. Psychother Psych Med. 2018;(EFirst). Epub 19.01.2018. 10.1055/s-0043-122241</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-122241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Berger T, Schr&#xf6;der J, Sp&#xe4;th C, Meyer B, Caspar F, et al. Effects of a Psychological Internet Intervention in the Treatment of Mild to Moderate Depressive Symptoms: Results of the EVIDENT Study, a Randomized Controlled Trial. Psychotherapy and psychosomatics. 2016;85(4):218&#x2013;28. 10.1159/000445355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000445355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Schilling L, Hauschildt M, Schr&#xf6;der J, Treszl A. A randomized controlled trial of internet-based therapy in depression. Behaviour research and therapy. 2012;50(7):513&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J, Br&#xfc;ckner K, Fischer A, Lindenau M, K&#xf6;ther U, Vettorazzi E, et al. Efficacy of a psychological online intervention for depression in people with epilepsy: a randomized controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55(12):2069&#x2013;76. 10.1111/epi.12833</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25410633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwerenz R, Becker J, Knickenberg RJ, Siepmann M, Hagen K, Beutel ME. Online Self-Help as an Add-On to Inpatient Psychotherapy: Efficacy of a New Blended Treatment Approach. Psychotherapy and Psychosomatics. 2017;86(6):341&#x2013;50. 10.1159/000481177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000481177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A-G, Buchner A. G* Power 3: A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behavior research methods. 2007;39(2):175&#x2013;91. 10.3758/bf03193146</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/bf03193146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P. Meta-analyses in mental health research A practical guide. Amsterdam, the Netherlands: Pim Cuijpers Uitgeverij; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwerenz R, Baumgarten C, Becker J, Tibubos A, Siepmann M, Knickenberg RJ, et al. Improving the Course of Depressive Symptoms After Inpatient Psychotherapy Using Adjunct Web-Based Self-Help: Follow-Up Results of a Randomized Controlled Trial. Journal of medical Internet research. 2019;21(10):e13655 10.2196/13655</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/13655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31651403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower P, Kontopantelis E, Sutton A, Kendrick T, Richards DA, Gilbody S, et al. Influence of initial severity of depression on effectiveness of low intensity interventions: meta-analysis of individual patient data. Bmj. 2013;346:f540 10.1136/bmj.f540</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.f540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3582703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23444423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leucht S, Corves C, Arbter D, Engel RR, Li C, Davis JM. Second-generation versus first-generation antipsychotic drugs for schizophrenia: a meta-analysis. The Lancet. 2009;373(9657):31&#x2013;41. 10.1016/S0140-6736(08)61764-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(08)61764-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19058842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lj&#xf3;tsson B, Hedman E, Mattsson S, Andersson E. The effects of cognitive&#x2013;behavioral therapy for depression are not falling: A re-analysis of Johnsen and Friborg (2015). 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28230412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnsen TJ, Friborg O. The effects of cognitive behavioral therapy as an anti-depressive treatment is falling: A meta-analysis. Psychological Bulletin. 2015;141(4):747 10.1037/bul0000015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/bul0000015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25961373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Reichler L, Munzinger M, Lin J. The impact of guidance on Internet-based mental health interventions&#x2014;A systematic review. Internet Interventions. 2014;1(4):205&#x2013;15. 10.1016/j.invent.2014.08.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2014.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordy H, Wolf M, Aulich K, B&#xfc;rgy M, Hegerl U, H&#xfc;sing J, et al. Internet-delivered disease management for recurrent depression: a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Psychotherapy and psychosomatics. 2016;85(2):91&#x2013;8. 10.1159/000441951</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000441951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26808817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titov N, Dear B, Staples L, Terides M, Karin E, Sheehan J, et al. Disorder-specific versus transdiagnostic and clinician-guided versus self-guided treatment for major depressive disorder and comorbid anxiety disorders: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Anxiety Disorders. 2015;35:88&#x2013;102. 10.1016/j.janxdis.2015.08.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.janxdis.2015.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26422822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Karyotaki E, Reijnders M, Ebert DD. Was Eysenck right after all? A reassessment of the effects of psychotherapy for adult depression. Epidemiology and Psychiatric Sciences. 2018:1&#x2013;10. Epub 02/28. 10.1017/S2045796018000057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S2045796018000057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6999031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29486804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Smit F, Bohlmeijer E, Hollon SD, Andersson G. Efficacy of cognitive&#x2013;behavioural therapy and other psychological treatments for adult depression: meta-analytic study of publication bias. The British Journal of Psychiatry. 2010;196(3):173&#x2013;8. 10.1192/bjp.bp.109.066001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.109.066001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20194536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, van Straten A, Bohlmeijer E, Hollon S, Andersson G. The effects of psychotherapy for adult depression are overestimated: a meta-analysis of study quality and effect size. Psychological medicine. 2010;40(2):211&#x2013;23. 10.1017/S0033291709006114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291709006114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19490745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner EH, Matthews AM, Linardatos E, Tell RA, Rosenthal R. Selective publication of antidepressant trials and its influence on apparent efficacy. New England Journal of Medicine. 2008;358(3):252&#x2013;60. 10.1056/NEJMsa065779</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMsa065779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18199864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arnberg FK, Linton SJ, Hultcrantz M, Heintz E, Jonsson U. Internet-delivered psychological treatments for mood and anxiety disorders: a systematic review of their efficacy, safety, and cost-effectiveness. PLoS One. 2014;9(5):e98118 10.1371/journal.pone.0098118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0098118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4028301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24844847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barth J, Munder T, Gerger H, N&#xfc;esch E, Trelle S, Znoj H, et al. Comparative efficacy of seven psychotherapeutic interventions for patients with depression: a network meta-analysis. Focus. 2016;14(2):229&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6519647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31997951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedetti F, Carlino E, Piedimonte A. Increasing uncertainty in CNS clinical trials: the role of placebo, nocebo, and Hawthorne effects. The Lancet Neurology. 2016;15(7):736&#x2013;47. 10.1016/S1474-4422(16)00066-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(16)00066-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27106073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirsch I, Wampold B, Kelley JM. Controlling for the placebo effect in psychotherapy: Noble quest or tilting at windmills? Psychology of Consciousness: Theory, Research, and Practice. 2016;3(2):121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaab J, Locher C, Blease C. Placebo and psychotherapy: differences, similarities, and implications International review of neurobiology. 138: Elsevier; 2018. p. 241&#x2013;55. 10.1016/bs.irn.2018.01.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.irn.2018.01.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29681328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E, Kleiboer A, Smit F, Turner DT, Pastor AM, Andersson G, et al. Predictors of treatment dropout in self-guided web-based interventions for depression: an &#x2018;individual patient data&#x2019;meta-analysis. Psychological medicine. 2015;45(13):2717&#x2013;26. 10.1017/S0033291715000665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291715000665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25881626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuhr K, Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Moritz S, Meyer B, Lutz W, et al. The association between adherence and outcome in an Internet intervention for depression. Journal of Affective Disorders. 2018;229:443&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.jad.2017.12.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2017.12.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29331706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;fe V, Berger T, Hautzinger M, Hohagen F, Lutz W, Meyer B, et al. Health economic evaluation of a web-based intervention for depression: the EVIDENT-trial, a randomized controlled study. Health economics review. 2019;9(1):16 10.1186/s13561-019-0233-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13561-019-0233-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6734272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31175475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;fe V, Greiner W. Internet Based Treatment of Depressive Symptoms&#x2013;A Health Economic Evaluation of Costs and Benefits. Value in Health. 2017;20(9):A714.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuhr K, Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Moritz S, Meyer B, Lutz W, et al. The association between adherence and outcome in an Internet intervention for depression. Journal of affective disorders. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29331706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Gamon C, Sp&#xe4;th C, Berger T, Meyer B, Hohagen F, et al. Does recruitment source moderate treatment effectiveness? A subgroup analysis from the EVIDENT study, a randomised controlled trial of an internet intervention for depressive symptoms. BMJ open. 2017;7(7):e015391 10.1136/bmjopen-2016-015391</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2016-015391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5734368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28710212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Sp&#xe4;th C, Schr&#xf6;der J, Meyer B, Greiner W, Hautzinger M, et al. Time to remission from mild to moderate depressive symptoms: One year results from the EVIDENT-study, an RCT of an internet intervention for depression. Behaviour research and therapy. 2017;97:154&#x2013;62. 10.1016/j.brat.2017.07.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2017.07.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28797829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz W, Arndt A, Rubel J, Berger T, Schr&#xf6;der J, Sp&#xe4;th C, et al. Defining and Predicting Patterns of Early Response in a Web-Based Intervention for Depression. Journal of medical Internet research. 2017;19(6).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5482926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28600278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Meyer B, Lutz W, Sp&#xe4;th C, Michel P, et al. Impact and change of attitudes toward Internet interventions within a randomized controlled trial on individuals with depression symptoms. Depression and Anxiety. 2018;0(0). 10.1002/da.22727</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29489038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>