<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32548724</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2191-1991</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>16</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health economics review</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Econ Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>19</StartPage><MedlinePgn>19</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">19</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Depressive disorders often remain undiagnosed or are treated inadequately. Online-based programs may reduce the present treatment gap for depressive disorders and reduce disease-related costs. This study aimed to examine the potential of the internet intervention "deprexis" to reduce the total costs of statutory health insurance. Changes in depression severity, health-related quality of life and impairment in functioning were also examined.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 3805 participants with, at minimum, mild depressive symptoms were randomized to either a 12-week online intervention (deprexis) or a control condition. The primary outcome measure was statutory health insurance costs, estimated using health insurers' administrative data. Secondary outcomes were: depression severity, health-related quality of life, and impairment in functioning; assessed on patient's self-report at baseline, post-treatment, and three-months' and nine-months' follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In both groups, total costs of statutory health insurance decreased during the study period, but changes from baseline differed significantly. In the intervention group total costs decreased by 32% from 3139&#x20ac; per year at baseline to 2119&#x20ac; in the study year (vs. a mean reduction in total costs of 13% in the control group). In comparison to the control group, the intervention group also showed a significantly greater reduction in depression severity, and impairment in functioning and a significantly greater increase in health-related quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study underlines the potential of innovative internet intervention programs in treating depressive disorders. The results suggest that the use of deprexis over a period of 12&#x2009;weeks leads to a significant improvement in symptoms with a simultaneous reduction in the costs of statutory health insurance.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gr&#xe4;fe</LastName><ForeName>Viola</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0314-2042</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Economics and Health Care Management, School of Public Health, Bielefeld University, Universit&#xe4;tsstra&#xdf;e 25, 33615, Bielefeld, Germany. viola.graefe@uni-bielefeld.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moritz</LastName><ForeName>Steffen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Martinistra&#xdf;e 52, 20246, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greiner</LastName><ForeName>Wolfgang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Economics and Health Care Management, School of Public Health, Bielefeld University, Universit&#xe4;tsstra&#xdf;e 25, 33615, Bielefeld, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Health Econ Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101583209</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2191-1991</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Health Econ Rev. 2020 Jul 30;10(1):24. doi: 10.1186/s13561-020-00280-1.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">32734480</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deprexis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">E-mental-health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Economic issues</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health economic evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Outcome studies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized controlled trial</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no financial or other relationship relevant to this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32548724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7298860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>GBE-Bund: Krankheitskosten. [http://www.gbe-bund.de/oowa921-install/servlet/oowa/aw92/dboowasys921.xwdevkit/xwd_init?gbe.isgbetol/xs_start_neu/&amp;p_aid=i&amp;p_aid=62622391&amp;nummer=63&amp;p_sprache=D&amp;p_indsp=-&amp;p_aid=46786904]. [Last accessed 16 Feb 2020].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch MA, Maske UE, Ryl L, Schlack R, Hapke U. Pr&#xe4;valenz von depressiver Symptomatik und diagnostizierter Depression bei Erwachsenen in Deutschland. Ergebnisse der Studie zur Gesundheit Erwachsener in Deutschland (DEGS1) Bundesgesundheitsblatt, Gesundheitsforschung, Gesundheitsschutz. 2013;56(5&#x2013;6):733&#x2013;739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23703492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klesse C, Bermejo I, H&#xe4;rter M. Neue Versorgungsmodelle in der Depressionsbehandlung. Nervenarzt. 2007;78(Suppl 3):585&#x2013;594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17934708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietsch B, H&#xe4;rter M, Nolting A, Nocon M, Kulig M, Gruber S, R&#xfc;ther A, Siering U, Perleth M. Verbesserte Versorgungsorientierung am Beispiel Depression - Ergebnisse aus dem Pilotprojekt des Gemeinsamen Bundesausschusses (G-BA). In: Gerste B, Robra B-P, G&#xfc;nster C, Klauber J, Schmacke N, editors. Versorgungs-Report 2013/2014. Schwerpunkt: Depression - Mit Online-Zugang zum Internet-Portal, vol. 2014. Stuttgart: Schattauer GmbH. p. 55&#x2013;75. www.versorgungs-report-online.de.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ters S, Hoebel J, Lange C. Diagnose Depression: Unterschiede bei Frauen und M&#xe4;nnern. GBE kompakt. 2013;4(2):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittchen H-U. Depressive Erkrankungen. Berlin: Robert-Koch-Inst; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner CJ, Dintsios CM, Metzger FG, L'Hoest H, Marschall U, Stollenwerk B, Stock S. Longterm persistence and nonrecurrence of depression treatment in Germany. A four-year retrospective follow-up using linked claims data. Int J Methods Psychiatr Res. 2018;27(2):e1607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6877203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29446186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi F, Klose M, Wittchen H-U. Psychische St&#xf6;rungen in der deutschen Allgemeinbev&#xf6;lkerung. Inanspruchnahme von Gesundheitsleistungen und Ausfalltage. Bundesgesundheitsblatt, Gesundheitsforschung, Gesundheitsschutz. 2004;47(8):736&#x2013;744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15340716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knieps F, Pfaff H, editors. Gesundheit und Arbeit. Zahlen, Daten, Fakten ; mit Gastbeitr&#xe4;gen aus Wissenschaft, Politik und Praxis. Berlin: MWV Medizinisch Wissenschaftliche Verlagsgesellschaft; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friemel S, Bernert S, Angermeyer MC, K&#xf6;nig H-H. Die direkten Kosten von depressiven Erkrankungen in Deutschland -- Ergebnisse aus dem European Study of the Epidemiology of Mental Disorders (ESEMeD) Projekt. Psychiatr Prax. 2005;32(3):113&#x2013;121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15818527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salize HJ, Stamm K, Schubert M, Bergmann F, H&#xe4;rter M, Berger M, Gaebel W, Schneider F. Behandlungskosten von Patienten mit Depressionsdiagnose in haus- und fach&#xe4;rztlicher Versorgung in Deutschland. Psychiatr Prax. 2004;31(3):147&#x2013;156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15042478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dintsios C-M, Wagner CJ. Letter to the editor of the journal of affective disorders. Supporting the guideline's quest for real direct costs of depression care. J Affect Disord. 2017;208:101&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27769004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner CJ, Metzger FG, Sievers C, Marschall U, L'Hoest H, Stollenwerk B, Stock S. Depression-related treatment and costs in Germany. Do they change with comorbidity? A claims data analysis. J Affective Disord. 2016;193:257&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26773923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistisches Bundesamt: Krankheitskosten. Deutschland, Jahre, Krankheitsdiagnosen (ICD-10). [https://www-genesis.destatis.de/genesis/online;jsessionid=6107D1CD35C7658B3D2AFF7932F33DAE.tomcat_GO_1_3?operation=previous&amp;levelindex=2&amp;levelid=1506025077390&amp;step=2]. [Last Accessed 03 May 2017].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieper L, Schulz H, Klotsche J, Eichler T, Wittchen H-U. Depression als komorbide St&#xf6;rung in der prim&#xe4;r&#xe4;rztlichen Versorgung. Bundesgesundheitsblatt, Gesundheitsforschung, Gesundheitsschutz. 2008;51(4):411&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18385962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohn R, Saxena S, Levav I, Saraceno B. The treatment gap in mental health care. Bull World Health Organ. 2004;82(11):858&#x2013;866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2623050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15640922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Donker T, Johansson R, Mohr DC, van Straten A, Andersson G. Self-guided psychological treatment for depressive symptoms. A meta-analysis. PloS one. 2011;6(6):e21274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21712998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Erbe D, Berking M. Rief: Internetbasierte psychologische Interventionen (PSYNDEXshort) In: Berking M, Rief W, editors. Klinische Psychologie und Psychotherapie f&#xfc;r Bachelor. Band II: Therapieverfahren Lesen, H&#xf6;ren, Lernen im Web. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2012. pp. 131&#x2013;140.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laux G. Online&#x2212;/Internet-Programme zur Psychotherapie bei Depression eine Zwischenbilanz. J Neurol Neurochir Psychiatr. 2017;18(1):16&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E, Riper H, Twisk J, Hoogendoorn A, Kleiboer A, Mira A, Mackinnon A, Meyer B, Botella C, Littlewood E, Andersson G, Christensen H, Klein JP, Schr&#xf6;der J, Bret&#xf3;n-L&#xf3;pez J, Scheider J, Griffiths K, Farrer L, Huibers MJH, Phillips R, Gilbody S, Moritz S, Berger T, Pop V, Spek V, Cuijpers P. Efficacy of self-guided internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy in the treatment of depressive symptoms. A meta-analysis of individual participant data. JAMA Psychiat. 2017;74(4):351&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28241179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paganini S, Teigelk&#xf6;tter W, Buntrock C, Baumeister H. Economic evaluations of internet- and mobile-based interventions for the treatment and prevention of depression. A systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2018;225:733&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28922737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolier L, Majo C, Smit F, Westerhof GJ, Haverman M, Walburg JA, Riper H, Bohlmeijer E. Cost-effectiveness of online positive psychology. Randomized controlled trial. J Posit Psychol. 2014;9(5):460&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerhards SAH, Graaf LE d, Jacobs LE, Severens JL, Huibers MJH, Arntz A, Riper H. Widdershoven G, Metsemakers JFM, Evers SMAA: economic evaluation of online computerised cognitive-behavioural therapy without support for depression in primary care. Randomised trial. The British journal of psychiatry : the journal of mental science. 2010;196(4):310&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20357309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips R, Schneider J, Molosankwe I, Leese M, Foroushani PS, Grime P, McCrone P, Morriss R, Thornicroft G. Randomized controlled trial of computerized cognitive behavioural therapy for depressive symptoms. Effectiveness and costs of a workplace intervention. Psychol Med. 2014;44(4):741&#x2013;752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3898729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23795621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Berger T, Caspar F, Beevers CG, Andersson G, Weiss M. Effectiveness of a novel integrative online treatment for depression (Deprexis). Randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2009;11(2):e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19632969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O'Reilly G, Meyer B. Effectiveness of an individually-tailored computerised CBT programme (Deprexis) for depression. A meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2017;256:371&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von der Schulenburg J-M G, Greiner W, Jost F, Klusen N, Kubin M, Leidl R, Mittendorf T, Rebscher H, Sch&#xf6;ffski O, Vauth C, Volmer T, Wahler S, Wasem J, Weber C. Deutsche Empfehlungen zur gesundheits&#xf6;konomischen Evaluation - dritte und aktualisierte Fassung des Hannoveraner Konsens. Gesundh &#xf6;kon Qual manag. 2007;12(5):285&#x2013;290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SERVIER Deutschland GmbH: deprexis 24 - Ihr Online-Therapieprogramm bei Depressionen. [https://deprexis24-shop.servier.de/]. [Last Accessed 25 Jun 2018].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;we B, Un&#xfc;tzer J, Callahan CM, Perkins AJ, Kroenke K. Monitoring depression treatment outcomes with the patient health Questionnaire-9. Med Care. 2004;42(12):1194&#x2013;1201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15550799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JBW, L&#xf6;we B. The patient health questionnaire somatic, anxiety, and depressive symptom scales. A systematic review. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2010;32(4):345&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20633738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JBW. The PHQ-9. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16(9):606&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greiner W, Weijnen T, Nieuwenhuizen M, Oppe S, Badia X, Busschbach J, Buxton M, Dolan P, Kind P, Krabbe P, Ohinmaa A, Parkin D, Roset M, Sintonen H, Tsuchiya A, Charro F d. A single European currency for EQ-5D health states. Results from a six-country study. Eur J Health Econ. 2003;4(3):222&#x2013;231.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15609189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melville MR. Quality of life assessment using the short form 12 questionnaire is as reliable and sensitive as the short form 36 in distinguishing symptom severity in myocardial infarction survivors. Heart. 2003;89(12):1445&#x2013;1446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1767983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14617561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salyers MP, Bosworth HB, Swanson JW, Lamb-Pagone J, Osher FC. Reliability and validity of the SF-12 health survey among people with severe mental illness. Med Care. 2000;38(11):1141&#x2013;1150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11078054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware J, Kosinski M, Keller SD. A 12-item short-form health survey. Construction of scales and preliminary tests of reliability and validity. Med Care. 1996;34(3):220&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8628042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Layte R, Jenkinson D, Lawrence K, Petersen S, Paice C, Stradling J. A shorter form health survey. Can the SF-12 replicate results from the SF-36 in longitudinal studies? J Public Health Med. 1997;19(2):179&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9243433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mundt JC, Marks IM, Shear MK, Greist JH. The Work and Social Adjustment Scale. A simple measure of impairment in functioning. British J Psychiat. 2002;180:461&#x2013;464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11983645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen G, Kvarstein EH, Wilberg T. The work and social adjustment scale. Psychometric properties and validity among males and females, and outpatients with and without personality disorders. Personal Ment Health. 2017;11(4):215&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28681505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan GM, Feinn R. Using effect size-or why the P value is not enough. J Graduate Med Educ. 2012;4(3):279&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3444174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23997866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leppink J, O'Sullivan P, Winston K. Effect size - large, medium, and small. Perspectives Med Educ. 2016;5(6):347&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5122517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27752936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ML, Fiero M, Horton NJ, Hsu C-H. Handling missing data in RCTs; a review of the top medical journals. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4247714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25407057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;fe V, Berger T, Hautzinger M, Hohagen F, Lutz W, Meyer B, Moritz S, Rose M, Schr&#xf6;der J, Sp&#xe4;th C, Klein JP, Greiner W. Health economic evaluation of a web-based intervention for depression. The EVIDENT-trial, a randomized controlled study. Health Econ Rev. 2019;9(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6734272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31175475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Berger T, Schr&#xf6;der J, Sp&#xe4;th C, Meyer B, Caspar F, Lutz W, Arndt A, Greiner W, Gr&#xe4;fe V, Hautzinger M, Fuhr K, Rose M, Nolte S, L&#xf6;we B, Anderssoni G, Vettorazzi E, Moritz S, Hohagen F. Effects of a psychological internet intervention in the treatment of mild to moderate depressive symptoms. Results of the EVIDENT study, a randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2016;85(4):218&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, H&#xe4;mmerli K, Gubser N, Andersson G, Caspar F. Internet-based treatment of depression. A randomized controlled trial comparing guided with unguided self-help. Cogn Behav Ther. 2011;40(4):251&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22060248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Schilling L, Hauschildt M, Schr&#xf6;der J, Treszl A. A randomized controlled trial of internet-based therapy in depression. Behav Res Ther. 2012;50(7&#x2013;8):513&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Bierbrodt J, Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Beevers CG, Weiss M, Jacob G, Sp&#xe4;th C, Andersson G, Lutz W, Hautzinger M, L&#xf6;we B, Rose M, Hohagen F, Caspar F, Greiner W, Moritz S, Klein JP. Effects of an internet intervention (Deprexis) on severe depression symptoms. Randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. 2015;2(1):48&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sp&#xe4;th C, Hapke U, Maske U, Schr&#xf6;der J, Moritz S, Berger T, Meyer B, Rose M, Nolte S, Klein JP. Characteristics of participants in a randomized trial of an internet intervention for depression (EVIDENT) in comparison to a national sample (DEGS1) Internet Interv. 2017;9:46&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brouwer W, Oenema A, Raat H, Crutzen R, de Nooijer J, de Vries NK, Brug J. Characteristics of visitors and revisitors to an internet-delivered computer-tailored lifestyle intervention implemented for use by the general public. Health Educ Res. 2010;25(4):585&#x2013;595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19897515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leggett LE, Khadaroo RG, Holroyd-Leduc J, Lorenzetti DL, Hanson H, Wagg A, Padwal R, Clement F. Measuring resource utilization. A systematic review of validated self-reported questionnaires. Medicine. 2016;95(10):e2759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4998854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26962773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palin JL, Goldner EM, Koehoorn M, Hertzman C. Primary mental health care visits in self-reported data versus provincial administrative records. Health Rep. 2011;22(2):41&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21848132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goossens ME, M&#xf6;lken MP-v, Vlaeyen JW, van der Linden SM. The cost diary. J Clin Epidemiol. 2000;53(7):688&#x2013;695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10941945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>