<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37590052</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2561-326X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR formative research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Form Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of an Internet-Based Self-Guided Program to Treat Depression in a Sample of Brazilian Users: Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e46326</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e46326</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e46326</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/46326</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Depression is undertreated in Brazil. Deprexis is a self-guided internet-based program used to treat depressive symptoms based on empirically supported integrative and cognitive behavioral therapy. Evidence from a meta-analysis supports Deprexis' efficacy in German-speaking countries and the United States, but no study has been conducted using this program in countries with low literacy rates and large social disparities. Furthermore, few studies have investigated whether internet-based interventions ameliorate the psychological processes that might underlie depressive symptomatology, such as low perceived self-efficacy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The main objective of this study was to replicate in Brazil previously reported effects of Deprexis on depressive symptom reduction. Therefore, the main research question was whether Deprexis is effective in reducing depressive symptoms and the general psychological state in Brazilian users with moderate and severe depression in comparison with a control group that does not receive access to Deprexis. A secondary research question was whether the use of Deprexis affects perceptions of self-efficacy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We interviewed 312 participants recruited over the internet and randomized 189 participants with moderate to severe depression (according to the Patient Health Questionnaire-9 and a semistructured interview) to an intervention condition (treatment as usual plus immediate access to Deprexis for 90 days, n=94) or to a control condition (treatment as usual and delayed access to Deprexis, after 8 weeks, n=95).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Participants from the immediate access group logged in at Deprexis an average of 14.81 (SD 12.16) times. The intention-to-treat analysis using a linear mixed model showed that participants who received Deprexis improved significantly more than participants assigned to the delayed access control group on the primary depression self-assessment measure (Patient Health Questionnaire-9; Cohen d=0.80; P&lt;.001) and secondary outcomes, such as general psychological state measure (Clinical Outcome in Routine Evaluation-Outcome Measurement; Cohen d=0.82; P&lt;.001) and the perceived self-efficacy measure (Cohen d=0.63; P&lt;.001). The intention-to-treat analyses showed that 21% (20/94) of the participants achieved remission compared with 7% (7/95) in the control group (P&lt;.001). The deterioration rates were lower in the immediate access control group. The dropout rate was high, but no differences in demographic and clinical variables were found. Participants reported a medium to high level of satisfaction with Deprexis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These results replicate previous findings by showing that Deprexis can facilitate symptomatic improvement over 3 months in depressed samples of Brazilian users. From a public health perspective, this is important information to expand the reach of internet-based interventions for those who really need them, especially in countries with less access to mental health care. This extends previous research by showing significant effects on perceived self-efficacy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Registro Brasileiro de Ensaios Cl&#xed;ncos (ReBec) RBR-6kk3bx UTN U1111-1212-8998; https://ensaiosclinicos.gov.br/rg/RBR-6kk3bx/.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERNATIONAL REGISTERED REPORT IDENTIFIER (IRRID)" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">RR2-10.1590/1516-4446-2019-0582.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Rodrigo T Lopes, Gustavo Chapetta da Rocha, Maria Adriana Svacina, Bj&#xf6;rn Meyer, Dajana &#x160;ipka, Thomas Berger. Originally published in JMIR Formative Research (https://formative.jmir.org), 17.08.2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6579-3043</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>da Rocha</LastName><ForeName>Gustavo Chapetta</ForeName><Initials>GC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5574-4013</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of Petropolis, Petr&#xf3;polis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Svacina</LastName><ForeName>Maria Adriana</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3151-7534</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Catholic University of Petropolis, Petr&#xf3;polis, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyer</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1100-0260</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gaia Group, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x160;ipka</LastName><ForeName>Dajana</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8197-1698</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berger</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2432-7791</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Form Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101726394</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2561-326X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">internet-based interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-guided interventions</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: BM is employed full time as the research director at Gaia AG, the company that developed and owns the Deprexis program. BM was not involved in funding, data collection, data organization, or analysis. All other authors declare no other conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37590052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10472176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/46326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v7i1e46326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andrews PW, Thomson jr A. The bright side of being blue: depression as an adaptation for analyzing complex problems. Psychol Rev. 2009 Jul;116(3):620&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1037/a0016242. 
 
2009-10379-009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0016242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2734449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19618990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roness A, Mykletun A, Dahl AA. Help-seeking behaviour in patients with anxiety disorder and depression. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2005 Jan;111(1):51&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0447.2004.00433.x.ACP433</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0447.2004.00433.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15636594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Schilling L, Hauschildt M, Schr&#xf6;der J, Treszl A. A randomized controlled trial of internet-based therapy in depression. Behav Res Ther. 2012 Aug;50(7-8):513&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2012.04.006.S0005-7967(12)00075-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2012.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr DC, Ho J, Duffecy J, Baron KG, Lehman KA, Jin L, Reifler D. Perceived barriers to psychological treatments and their relationship to depression. J Clin Psychol. 2010 Apr;66(4):394&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1002/jclp.20659. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.20659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2907887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20127795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf6;ller-Leimk&#xfc;hler AM. Barriers to help-seeking by men: a review of sociocultural and clinical literature with particular reference to depression. J Affect Disord. 2002 Sep;71(1-3):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/s0165-0327(01)00379-2.S0165032701003792</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0165-0327(01)00379-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12167495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang PS, Berglund P, Olfson M, Pincus HA, Wells KB, Kessler RC. Failure and delay in initial treatment contact after first onset of mental disorders in the National Comorbidity Survey Replication. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005 Jun;62(6):603&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.62.6.603.62/6/603</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.62.6.603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15939838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnyder N, Panczak R, Groth N, Schultze-Lutter F. Association between mental health-related stigma and active help-seeking: systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Psychiatry. 2017 Apr;210(4):261&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.116.189464.S0007125000281105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.116.189464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chisholm D, Sweeny K, Sheehan P, Rasmussen B, Smit F, Cuijpers P, Saxena S. Scaling-up treatment of depression and anxiety: a global return on investment analysis. Lancet Psychiatry. 2016 May;3(5):415&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(16)30024-4. 
 
S2215-0366(16)30024-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(16)30024-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27083119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Berger T. Internet approaches to psychotherapy: empirical findings and future directions. In: Barkham M, Lutz W, Castonguay LG, editors. Bergin and Garfield's Handbook of Psychotherapy and Behavior Change. 50th anniversary edition. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2021. pp. 731&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;fe V, Moritz S, Greiner W. Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (Deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. Health Econ Rev. 2020 Jun 16;10(1):19. doi: 10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0. 
 
10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7298860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32548724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barak A, Grohol JM. Current and future trends in internet-supported mental health interventions. J Technol Hum Serv. 2011 Jul;29(3):155&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1080/15228835.2011.616939. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15228835.2011.616939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin ME, Krafft J, Levin C. Does self-help increase rates of help seeking for student mental health problems by minimizing stigma as a barrier? J Am Coll Health. 2018 May;66(4):302&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/07448481.2018.1440580.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2018.1440580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29447600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spanhel K, Balci S, Feldhahn F, Bengel J, Baumeister H, Sander LB. Cultural adaptation of internet- and mobile-based interventions for mental disorders: a systematic review. NPJ Digit Med. 2021 Aug 25;4(1):128. doi: 10.1038/s41746-021-00498-1. doi: 10.1038/s41746-021-00498-1.10.1038/s41746-021-00498-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-021-00498-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8387403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34433875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieta MA, Gomes WB. Psicoterapia pela Internet: vi&#xe1;vel ou invi&#xe1;vel? Psicol Cienc Prof. 2014 Mar;34(1):18. doi: 10.1590/s1414-98932014000100003. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/s1414-98932014000100003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Berger T, Caspar F, Beevers CG, Andersson G, Weiss M. Effectiveness of a novel integrative online treatment for depression (Deprexis): randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2009 May 11;11(2):e15. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1151. 
 
v11i2e15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19632969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O'Reilly G, B&#xfc;ltmann O, Meyer B. Effectiveness of a tailored, integrative Internet intervention (deprexis) for depression: Updated meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2020 Jan 30;15(1):e0228100. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0228100. 
 
PONE-D-19-25463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0228100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31999743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Barthel B, Berger T, Moritz S. Feasibility, effectiveness and safety of the self-management intervention deprexis in routine medical care: results of an uncontrolled observational study. Internet Interv. 2020 Dec;22:100341. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2020.100341. 
 
S2214-7829(20)30107-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2020.100341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7450999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Krieger T, Sude K, Meyer B, Maercker A. Evaluating an e-mental health program ("deprexis") as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J Affect Disord. 2018 Feb;227:455&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021.S0165-0327(17)31255-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, H&#xe4;mmerli K, Gubser N, Andersson G, Caspar F. Internet-based treatment of depression: a randomized controlled trial comparing guided with unguided self-help. Cogn Behav Ther. 2011;40(4):251&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1080/16506073.2011.616531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2011.616531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22060248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;cker L, Bierbrodt J, Hand I, Wittekind C, Moritz S. Effects of a depression-focused internet intervention in slot machine gamblers: a randomized controlled trial. PLoS One. 2018 Jun 08;13(6):e0198859. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0198859. 
 
PONE-D-18-03215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0198859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5993308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29883479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Schr&#xf6;der J, Vettorazzi E, Wolf OT, P&#xf6;ttgen J, Lau S, Heesen C, Moritz S, Gold SM. An online programme to reduce depression in patients with multiple sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Psychiatry. 2015 Mar;2(3):217&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00049-2.S2215-0366(14)00049-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00049-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuhr K, Fahse B, Hautzinger M, Gulewitsch MD. Erste Erfahrungen zur Implementierbarkeit einer internet-basierten Selbsthilfe zur &#xdc;berbr&#xfc;ckung der Wartezeit auf eine ambulante Psychotherapie. Psychother Psychosom Med Psychol. 2018 Jun;68(6):234&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1055/s-0043-122241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-122241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Berger T, Schr&#xf6;der J, Sp&#xe4;th C, Meyer B, Caspar F, Lutz W, Arndt A, Greiner W, Gr&#xe4;fe V, Hautzinger M, Fuhr K, Rose M, Nolte S, L&#xf6;we B, Anderssoni G, Vettorazzi E, Moritz S, Hohagen F. Effects of a psychological internet intervention in the treatment of mild to moderate depressive symptoms: results of the EVIDENT study, a randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2016;85(4):218&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1159/000445355. 
 
000445355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000445355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Bierbrodt J, Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Beevers CG, Weiss M, Jacob G, Sp&#xe4;th C, Andersson G, Lutz W, Hautzinger M, L&#xf6;we B, Rose M, Hohagen F, Caspar F, Greiner W, Moritz S, Klein JP. Effects of an internet intervention (Deprexis) on severe depression symptoms: randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. 2015 Mar;2(1):48&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2014.12.003. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2014.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J, Br&#xfc;ckner K, Fischer A, Lindenau M, K&#xf6;ther U, Vettorazzi E, Moritz S. Efficacy of a psychological online intervention for depression in people with epilepsy: a randomized controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014 Dec;55(12):2069&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1111/epi.12833. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25410633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwerenz R, Becker J, Knickenberg RJ, Siepmann M, Hagen K, Beutel ME. Online self-help as an add-on to inpatient psychotherapy: efficacy of a new blended treatment approach. Psychother Psychosom. 2017;86(6):341&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1159/000481177.000481177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000481177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beevers CG, Pearson R, Hoffman JS, Foulser AA, Shumake J, Meyer B. Effectiveness of an internet intervention (Deprexis) for depression in a united states adult sample: a parallel-group pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2017 Apr;85(4):367&#x2013;80. doi: 10.1037/ccp0000171.2017-08289-001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/ccp0000171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28230390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamadeh N, Van Rompaey C, Metreau E, Eapen SG. New World Bank country classifications by income level: 2022-2023. World Bank Blogs. 2022. Jul 1,  [2023-07-20].  
 https://blogs.worldbank.org/opendata/new-world-bank-country-classifications-income-level-2022-2023
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self Efficacy: The Exercise of Control. New York, NY: Worth Publishers; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luszczynska A, Scholz U, Schwarzer R. The general self-efficacy scale: multicultural validation studies. J Psychol. 2005 Sep;139(5):439&#x2013;57. doi: 10.3200/JRLP.139.5.439-457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3200/JRLP.139.5.439-457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16285214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddux JE, Meier LJ. Self-efficacy and depression. In: Maddux JE, editor. Self-Efficacy, Adaptation, and Adjustment. Boston, MA: Springer; 1995. pp. 143&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf3;mez Penedo JM, Babl AM, Grosse Holtforth M, Hohagen F, Krieger T, Lutz W, Meyer B, Moritz S, Klein JP, Berger T. The association of therapeutic alliance with long-term outcome in a guided internet intervention for depression: secondary analysis from a randomized control trial. J Med Internet Res. 2020 Mar 24;22(3):e15824. doi: 10.2196/15824. 
 
v22i3e15824</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/15824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7139432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32207689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backenstrass M, Schwarz T, Fiedler P, Joest K, Reck C, Mundt C, Kronmueller K. Negative mood regulation expectancies, self-efficacy beliefs, and locus of control orientation: moderators or mediators of change in the treatment of depression? Psychotherapy Research. 2006 Mar;16(2):250&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1080/10503300500485474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10503300500485474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilhelmsen M, Lillevoll K, Ris&#xf8;r MB, H&#xf8;if&#xf8;dt R, Johansen ML, Waterloo K, Eisemann M, Kolstrup N. Motivation to persist with internet-based cognitive behavioural treatment using blended care: a qualitative study. BMC Psychiatry. 2013 Nov 07;13:296. doi: 10.1186/1471-244X-13-296. 
 
1471-244X-13-296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-13-296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4226213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24199672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes RT, Meyer B, Berger T, Svacina MA. Effectiveness of an internet-based self-guided program to treat depression in a sample of Brazilian users: a study protocol. Braz J Psychiatry. 2020;42(3):322&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1590/1516-4446-2019-0582. 
 
S1516-44462020005005201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1516-4446-2019-0582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32159711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos IS, Tavares BF, Munhoz TN, Almeida LS, Silva NT, Tams BD, Patella AM, Matijasevich A. Sensibilidade e especificidade do Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) entre adultos da popula&#xe7;&#xe3;o geral. Cad Saude Publica. 2013 Aug;29(8):1533&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1590/0102-311x00144612. 
 
S0102-311X2013000800006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0102-311x00144612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24005919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB. Validation and utility of a self-report version of PRIME-MD: the PHQ primary care study. Primary care evaluation of mental disorders. Patient health questionnaire. JAMA. 1999 Nov 10;282(18):1737&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1001/jama.282.18.1737.joc90770</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.282.18.1737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association . Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders: DSM-5. New York, NY: American Psychiatric Association; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo&#x15b;cicki EK, Clarke DE, Kuramoto SJ, Kraemer HC, Narrow WE, Kupfer DJ, Regier DA. Testing DSM-5 in routine clinical practice settings: feasibility and clinical utility. Psychiatr Serv. 2013 Oct;64(10):952&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.201300098.1712781</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.201300098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23852272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narrow WE, Clarke DE, Kuramoto SJ, Kraemer HC, Kupfer DJ, Greiner L, Regier DA. DSM-5 field trials in the United States and Canada, Part III: development and reliability testing of a cross-cutting symptom assessment for DSM-5. Am J Psychiatry. 2013 Jan;170(1):71&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2012.12071000.1387907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2012.12071000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23111499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraguas Jr R, Henriques Jr SG, De Lucia MS, Iosifescu DV, Schwartz FH, Menezes PR, Gattaz WF, Martins MA. The detection of depression in medical setting: a study with PRIME-MD. J Affect Disord. 2006 Mar;91(1):11&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2005.12.003.S0165-0327(05)00359-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2005.12.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16427132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lima Os&#xf3;rio F, Vilela Mendes A, Crippa JA, Loureiro SR. Study of the discriminative validity of the PHQ-9 and PHQ-2 in a sample of Brazilian women in the context of primary health care. Perspect Psychiatr Care. 2009 Jul;45(3):216&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1111/j.1744-6163.2009.00224.x.PPC224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1744-6163.2009.00224.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19566694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morilha A, Karagulian S, Lotufo PA, Santos IS, Bense&#xf1;or IM, Goulart AC. Abuso de &#xc1;lcool ap&#xf3;s S&#xed;ndrome Coronariana Aguda: Avalia&#xe7;&#xe3;o Prospectiva no Estudo ERICO. Arq Bras Cardiol Arq Bras Cardiol Arq Bras Cardiol Arq Bras Cardiol Arq Bras Cardiol. 2015;104(6):457&#x2013;67. doi: 10.11606/d.5.2014.tde-05082014-150022. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11606/d.5.2014.tde-05082014-150022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4484678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26131701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Moraes e Silva M, Mercer PB, Witt MC, Pessoa RG, Viveiros CP, Gazola BB, de Oliveira DH, Ianisky R. Testes de rastreio para altera&#xe7;&#xf5;es psiqui&#xe1;tricas em esclerose m&#xfa;ltipla &#x2013; Revis&#xe3;o sistem&#xe1;tica com metan&#xe1;lise. J Bras Psiquiatr. 2018 Dec;67(4):255&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1590/0047-2085000000213. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0047-2085000000213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB, L&#xf6;we B. The patient health questionnaire somatic, anxiety, and depressive symptom scales: a systematic review. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2010 Jul;32(4):345&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2010.03.006.S0163-8343(10)00056-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2010.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20633738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans C, Connell J, Barkham M, Margison F, McGrath G, Mellor-Clark J, Audin K. Towards a standardised brief outcome measure: psychometric properties and utility of the CORE-OM. Br J Psychiatry. 2002 Jan;180:51&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1192/bjp.180.1.51.S0007125000160453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.180.1.51</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11772852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana MR, da Silva MM, de Moraes DS, Fukuda CC, Freitas LH, Ramos ME, Fleury HJ, Evans C. Brazilian Portuguese version of the CORE-OM: cross-cultural adaptation of an instrument to assess the efficacy and effectiveness of psychotherapy. Trends Psychiatry Psychother. 2015 Oct;37(4):227&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1590/2237-6089-2015-0002. doi: 10.1590/2237-6089-2015-0002.S2237-60892015003400227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/2237-6089-2015-0002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R, Jerusalem M. Measures in Health Psychology: A User's Portfolio. Windsor, UK: NFER-Nelson Publishing; 1995. Generalized Self-Efficacy Scale; pp. 35&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luszczynska A, Guti&#xe9;rrez&#x2010;Do&#xf1;a B, Schwarzer R. General self&#x2010;efficacy in various domains of human functioning: evidence from five countries. Int J Psychol. 2005 Apr;40(2):80&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/00207590444000041. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00207590444000041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R, Born A. Optimistic self-beliefs: assessment of general perceived self-efficacy in thirteen cultures. World Psychol. 1997;3(1):177&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attkisson CC, Zwick R. The client satisfaction questionnaire. Psychometric properties and correlations with service utilization and psychotherapy outcome. Eval Program Plann. 1982;5(3):233&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/0149-7189(82)90074-x.0149-7189(82)90074-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0149-7189(82)90074-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10259963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attkisson CC, Greenfield TK. The UCSF client satisfaction scales: I. the client satisfaction questionnaire-8. In: Maruish ME, editor. The Use of Psychological Testing for Treatment Planning and Outcomes Assessment: Instruments for Adults. 3rd edition. Mahwah, NJ: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates Publishers; 2004. pp. 799&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Randomization plans: never the same thing twice! Randomization. 2020. Dec 23,  [2023-07-20].  
 http://www.jerrydallal.com/random/randomize.htm
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan YH. Biostatistics 301A. Repeated measurement analysis (mixed models) Singapore Med J. 2004 Oct;45(10):456&#x2013;61. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15455165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gueorguieva R, Krystal JH. Move over ANOVA: progress in analyzing repeated-measures data and its reflection in papers published in the Archives of General Psychiatry. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2004 Mar;61(3):310&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.61.3.310.61/3/310</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.61.3.310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14993119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson NS, Truax P. Clinical significance: a statistical approach to defining meaningful change in psychotherapy research. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1991 Feb;59(1):12&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1037//0022-006x.59.1.12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0022-006x.59.1.12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2002127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao J, Zhong B. Last observation carry-forward and last observation analysis. Stat Med. 2003 Aug 15;22(15):2429&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1002/sim.1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.1519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12872300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G, CONSORT-EHEALTH Group  CONSORT-EHEALTH: improving and standardizing evaluation reports of web-based and mobile health interventions. J Med Internet Res. 2011 Dec 31;13(4):e126. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1923. 
 
v13i4e126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22209829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Schulz KF, Altman DG, CONSORT  The CONSORT statement: revised recommendations for improving the quality of reports of parallel group randomized trials. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2001;1:2. doi: 10.1186/1471-2288-1-2. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-1-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC32201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11336663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#xf3;digo de &#xc9;tica Profissional do Psic&#xf3;logo. Conselho Federal de Psicologia. 2005.  [2014-09-30].  
 http://site.cfp.org.br/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/codigo_etica1.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resolu&#xe7;&#xe3;o CFP N&#xb0; 011/2018: Regulamenta a presta&#xe7;&#xe3;o de servi&#xe7;os psicol&#xf3;gicos realizados por meios de tecnologias da informa&#xe7;&#xe3;o e da comunica&#xe7;&#xe3;o e revoga a Resolu&#xe7;&#xe3;o CFP N.o 11/2012. Conselho Federal de Psicologia. Conselho Federal de Psicologia. 2018.  [2018-11-13].  
 https://site.cfp.org.br/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/RESOLU%C3%87%C3%83O-N%C2%BA-11-DE-11-DE-MAIO-DE-2018.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lamela D, Soreira C, Matos P, Morais A. Systematic review of the factor structure and measurement invariance of the patient health questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) and validation of the Portuguese version in community settings. J Affect Disord. 2020 Nov 01;276:220&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2020.06.066.S0165-0327(20)32463-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2020.06.066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melville KM, Casey LM, Kavanagh DJ. Dropout from internet-based treatment for psychological disorders. Br J Clin Psychol. 2010 Nov;49(Pt 4):455&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1348/014466509X472138.bjcp840</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1348/014466509X472138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19799804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mekonen T, Ford S, Chan GC, Hides L, Connor JP, Leung J. What is the short-term remission rate for people with untreated depression? a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2022 Jan 01;296:17&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2021.09.046.S0165-0327(21)01005-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2021.09.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34583099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>