<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37897326</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-0970</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>29</Volume><Issue>14</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Multiple sclerosis (Houndmills, Basingstoke, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mult Scler</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mobile health interventions in multiple sclerosis: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1709</StartPage><EndPage>1720</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1709-1720</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/13524585231201089</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Persons with multiple sclerosis (pwMS) might be particularly well suited to benefit from digital health applications because they are, on average, younger and less severely disabled than patients with many other chronic diseases. Many digital health applications for pwMS have been developed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">Analysis of the evidence of digital health applications to improve health outcomes from a patient perspective.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A systematic review was performed on all randomized controlled trials (RCTs) that have studied mobile health interventions for pwMS, that is, which can be applied with a smartphone, tablet, or laptop to improve patient-reported outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of the 1127 articles identified in the literature search, 13 RCTs fit the inclusion criteria. Two trials studied messaging systems, two depression interventions, one addressed MS fatigue, five cognition, and three mobility issues, of which two focused on spasticity management. One trial aimed to enhance physical activity. Most were pilot studies that cannot yield definitive conclusions regarding efficacy. One depression intervention and one fatigue intervention showed significant results across several outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Several mobile self-guided digital health applications for pwMS have been tested in RCTs, and two interventions targeting depression and fatigue have demonstrated significant effects. Challenges remain regarding implementation into routine care.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heesen</LastName><ForeName>Christoph</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8131-9467</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Rehabilitative MS Research, Institute of Neuroimmunology and Multiple Sclerosis, University Medical Center, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berger</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riemann-Lorenz</LastName><ForeName>Karin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Rehabilitative MS Research, Institute of Neuroimmunology and Multiple Sclerosis, University Medical Center, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krause</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Rehabilitative MS Research, Institute of Neuroimmunology and Multiple Sclerosis, University Medical Center, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friede</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5347-7441</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Statistics, University Medical Center G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>P&#xf6;ttgen</LastName><ForeName>Jana</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical and Rehabilitative MS Research, Institute of Neuroimmunology and Multiple Sclerosis, University Medical Center, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyer</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>GAIA AG, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xfc;hmann</LastName><ForeName>Dagmar</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Practice and Primary Care, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Mult Scler</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9509185</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1352-4585</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068997" MajorTopicYN="N">Smartphone</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mobile health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digitalization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient-reported outcomes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trials</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting InterestsThe author(s) declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: B.M. is employed as the Research Director by GAIA, the company that has developed, owns, and operates deprexis, amiria, and elevida. C.H. and J.P. also contributed to the trials of these applications. K.R.-L. and N.K. are involved in another digital health intervention development with GAIA. T.B. and D.L. declare no conflicts of interest. T.F. has no conflicts of interest. C.H. received research support from Bristol Myers Squibb, Novartis, and Merck. He received honoraria from Roche for digital health presentations.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37897326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10687804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13524585231201089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Haase R, Schultheiss T, Kempcke R, et al. Modern communication technology skills of patients with multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler 2013; 19(9): 1240&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23388164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marziniak M, Brichetto G, Feys P, et al. The use of digital and remote communication technologies as a tool for multiple sclerosis management: Narrative review. JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol 2018; 5(1): e5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29691208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeroushalmi S, Maloni H, Costello K, et al. Telemedicine and multiple sclerosis: A comprehensive literature review. J Telemed Telecare 2020; 26(7&#x2013;8): 400&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31042118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marrie RA, Salter AR, Tyry T, et al. Preferred sources of health information in persons with multiple sclerosis: Degree of trust and information sought. J Med Internet Res 2013; 15(4): e67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3650929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23635393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolinario-Hagen J, Menzel M, Hennemann S, et al. Acceptance of mobile health apps for disease management among people with multiple sclerosis: Web-based survey study. JMIR Form Res 2018; 2(2): e11977.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6334710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30684408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seboka BT, Yilma TM, Birhanu AY. Factors influencing healthcare providers&#x2019; attitude and willingness to use information technology in diabetes management. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak 2021; 21(1): 24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7818744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33478502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundesministerium f&#xfc;r Gesundheit. Gesetz f&#xfc;r eine bessere Versorgung durch Digitalisierung und Innovation (Digitale-Versorgung-Gesetz&#x2014;DVG). Bundesgesetzblatt Teil I 2019; 49: 18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavorgna L, Brigo F, Moccia M, et al. E-Health and multiple sclerosis: An update. Mult Scler 2018; 24(13): 1657&#x2013;1664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30231004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
DiGA-Leitfaden, https://www.bfarm.de/SharedDocs/Downloads/DE/Medizinprodukte/diga_leitfaden.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Higgins JPT, Savovic J, Page MJ, et al. Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in a randomised trial. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, et al. (eds) Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions: Version 6.3, 2022, www.training.cochrane.org/handbook</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kieser M, Hauschke M. Assessment of clinical relevance by considering point estimates and associated confidence intervals. Pharm 2005; 4: 101&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Heesen C, Riemann-Lorenz K, L&#xfc;hmann D, et al. Multiple Sklerose: F&#xfc;hrt die Nutzung von mhealth-L&#xf6;sungen (z. B. Apps) im Selbstmanagement der Betroffenen zu besseren Ergebnissen?
https://www.iqwig.de/download/ht19-03_apps-zum-selbstmanagement-bei-multipler-sklerose_hta-bericht_v1-0.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller DM, Moore SM, Fox RJ, et al. Web-based self-management for patients with multiple sclerosis: A practical, randomized trial. Telemed J eHealth 2011; 17(1): 5&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21214498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin RA, Lincoln NB, das Nair R, et al. Evaluation of NeuroPage as a memory aid for people with multiple sclerosis: A randomised controlled trial. Neuropsychol Rehabil 2020; 30(1): 15&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29557731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Schroder J, Vettorazzi E, et al. An online programme to reduce depression in patients with multiple sclerosis: A randomised controlled trial. Lancet Psychiatry 2015; 2(3): 217&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper CL, Hind D, Parry GD, et al. Computerised cognitive behavioural therapy for the treatment of depression in people with multiple sclerosis: External pilot trial. Trials 2011; 12: 259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3272061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22168507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xf6;ttgen J, Moss-Morris R, Wendebourg JM, et al. Randomised controlled trial of a self-guided online fatigue intervention in multiple sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2018; 89(9): 970&#x2013;976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29549193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Giglio L, De Luca F, Prosperini L, et al. A low-cost cognitive rehabilitation with a commercial video game improves sustained attention and executive functions in multiple sclerosis: A pilot study. Neurorehabil Neur Repair 2015; 29(5): 453&#x2013;461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25398725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charvet LE, Shaw MT, Haider L, et al. Remotely-delivered cognitive remediation in multiple sclerosis (MS): Protocol and results from a pilot study. Mult Scler J Exp Transl Clin 2015; 1: 5609629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5433334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28607707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charvet LE, Yang J, Shaw MT, et al. Cognitive function in multiple sclerosis improves with telerehabilitation: Results from a randomized controlled trial. PLoS ONE 2017; 12(5): e0177177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5426671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28493924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell J, Langdon D, Cercignani M, et al. A randomised controlled trial of efficacy of cognitive rehabilitation in multiple sclerosis: A cognitive, behavioural, and MRI study. Neur Plast 2016; 2016: 4292585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5223046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28116167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bove R, Rowles W, Zhao C, et al. A novel in-home digital treatment to improve processing speed in people with multiple sclerosis: A pilot study. Mult Scler 2021; 27(5): 778&#x2013;789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32584155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehling R, Edlinger M, Hermann K, et al. Successful long-term management of spasticity in patients with multiple sclerosis using a software application (APP): A pilot study. Mult Scler Relat Disord 2017; 17: 15&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29055449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehling R, Seebacher B, Hars&#xe1;nyi A, et al. Successful long-term management of spasticity in people with multiple sclerosis using a software application: Results from a randomized, controlled, multicenter study. Eur J Neurol 2022; 29(6): 1697&#x2013;1707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35122365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasseri NN, Ghezelbash E, Zhai Y, et al. Feasibility of a smartphone app to enhance physical activity in progressive MS: A pilot randomized controlled pilot trial over three months. PeerJ 2020; 8: e9303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7319035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32612882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penner IK, Raselli C, St&#xf6;cklin M, et al. The fatigue scale for motor and cognitive functions (FSMC): Validation of a new instrument to assess multiple sclerosis-related fatigue. Mult Scler 2009; 15(12): 1509&#x2013;1517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19995840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella M, Chalder T. Measuring fatigue in clinical and community settings. J Psychosom Res 2010; 69: 17&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20630259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fricke U, Apolinario&#x2014;Hagen J. E&#x2014;Health&#x2014;Dienste und M&#x2014;Health Apps zur Verbesserung des Selbstmanagements bei Multipler Sklerose&#x2014;Ein Review zur aktuellen Forschungsliteratur zur Online-Selbsthilfe f&#xfc;r MS-Betroffene. eBeratungsNet 2016; 12(2): 59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold SM, Friede T, Meyer B, et al. Online intervention to reduce depressive symptoms in multiple sclerosis: An international multicenter randomised controlled phase III trial. Lancet Dig Health 2023. (in press).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O&#x2019;Reilly G, Meyer B. Effectiveness of an individually-tailored computerised CBT programme (Deprexis) for depression: A meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res 2017; 256: 371&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrar JT, Troxel AB, Stott C, et al. Validity, reliability, and clinical importance of change in a 0-10 numeric rating scale measure of spasticity: A post hoc analysis of a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Clin Ther 2008; 30: 974&#x2013;985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18555944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dillenseger A, Weidemann ML, Trentzsch K, et al. Digital biomarkers in multiple sclerosis. Brain Sci 2021; 11(11): 1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8615428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34827518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haase R, Vogt I, Scholz M, et al. Profiles of eHealth adoption in persons with multiple sclerosis and their caregivers. Brain Sci 2021; 11(8): 1087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8392753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34439706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G. CONSORT-EHEALTH. Improving and standardizing evaluation reports of web-based and mobile health interventions. J Med Internet Res 2011; 13(4): e126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22209829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spath C, Hapke U, Maske U, et al. Characteristics of participants in a randomized trial of an Internet intervention for depression (EVIDENT) in comparison to a national sample (DEGS1). Internet Interv 2017; 9: 46&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedland KE, King AC, Ambrosius WT, et al. The selection of comparators for randomized controlled trials of health-related behavioral interventions: Recommendations of an NIH expert panel. J Clin Epidemiol 2019; 110: 74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6543841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30826377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>