<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38568139</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2561-326X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR formative research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Form Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prospective Acceptability of Digital Therapy for Major Depressive Disorder in France: Multicentric Real-Life Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e53204</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e53204</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e53204</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/53204</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Major depressive disorder is one of the leading causes of disability worldwide. Although most international guidelines recommend psychological and psychosocial interventions as first-line treatment for mild to moderate depression, access remains limited in France due to the limited availability of trained clinicians, high costs for patients in the context of nonreimbursement, and the fear of stigmatization. Therefore, online blended psychological treatment such as Deprexis could improve access to care for people with depression. It has several advantages, such as easy accessibility and scalability, and it is supported by evidence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aims to evaluate the real-life acceptability of Deprexis for people with depression in France outside of a reimbursement pathway.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Deprexis Acceptability Study Measure in Real Life (DARE) was designed as a multicenter cross-sectional study in which Deprexis was offered to any patient meeting the inclusion criteria during the fixed inclusion period (June 2022-March 2023). Inclusion criteria were (1) depression, (2) age between 18 and 65 years, (3) sufficient French language skills, and (4) access to the internet with a device to connect to the Deprexis platform. Exclusion criteria were previous or current diagnoses of bipolar disorder, psychotic symptoms, and suicidal thoughts during the current episode. The primary objective was to measure the prospective acceptability of Deprexis, a new digital therapy. Secondary objectives were to examine differences in acceptability according to patient and clinician characteristics and to identify reasons for refusal. All investigators received video-based training on Deprexis before enrollment to ensure that they all had the same level of information and understanding of the program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 245 patients were eligible (n=159, 64.9% were women and n=138, 56.3% were single). The mean age was 40.7 (SD 14.1) years. A total of 78% (n=191) of the patients had moderate to severe depression (according to the Patient Health Questionnaire-9 [PHQ-9]). More than half of the population had another psychiatric comorbidity (excluding bipolar disorder, psychotic disorders, and suicidal ideation). A total of 33.9% (n=83) of patients accepted the idea of using Deprexis; the main reason for refusal was financial at 83.3% (n=135). Multivariate logistic regression identified factors that might favor the acceptability of Deprexis. Among these, being a couple, being treated with an antidepressant, or having a low severity level favored the acceptance of Deprexis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">DARE is the first French study aiming at evaluating the prospective acceptability of digital therapy in the treatment of depression. The main reason for the refusal of Deprexis was financial. DARE will allow better identification of factors influencing acceptability in a natural setting. This study highlights the importance of investigating factors that may be associated with the acceptability of digital interventions, such as marital status, medication use, and severity of depression.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Odile Amiot, Anne Sauvaget, Isabelle Alamome, Samuel Bulteau, Thomas Charpeaud, Anne-H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne Clair, Philippe Courtet, Dominique Drapier, Emmanuel Haffen, Eric Fakra, Christian Gaudeau-Bosma, Adeline Gaillard, St&#xe9;phane Mouchabac, Fanny Pineau, V&#xe9;ronique Narboni, Anne Duburcq, Laurent Lecardeur. Originally published in JMIR Formative Research (https://formative.jmir.org), 20.05.2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Amiot</LastName><ForeName>Odile</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-6938-4872</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Groupe Hospitalier Paul Guiraud, Boulogne Billancourt, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sauvaget</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1822-8535</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Movement - Interactions - Performance, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire Nantes, Nantes Universit&#xe9;, Nantes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alamome</LastName><ForeName>Isabelle</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6104-8727</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Hospitalier ESQUIROL, Limoges, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bulteau</LastName><ForeName>Samuel</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4855-2173</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institut national de la sant&#xe9; et de la recherche m&#xe9;dicale 1246, MethodS in Patient-Centered Outcomes and HEalth ResEarch, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nantes, Department of Addictology, Psychiatry and Old Age Psychiatry, University of Nantes, Nantes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Addictology, Psychiatry and Old Age Psychiatry, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Nantes, Nantes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charpeaud</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9053-5735</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinique du Grand Pr&#xe9;, Durtol, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clair</LastName><ForeName>Anne-H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne</ForeName><Initials>AH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4489-781X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Courtet</LastName><ForeName>Philippe</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6519-8586</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuropsychiatrie: Recherche Epidemiologique et Clinique, Institut national de la sante et de la recherche medicale, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Montpellier, University of Montpellier, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Psychiatry and Acute Care, Lapeyronie Hospital, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Montpellier, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Drapier</LastName><ForeName>Dominique</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0083-8677</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Hospitalier Guillaume R&#xe9;gnier, P&#xf4;le hospitalo universitaire de psychiatrie adulte, Rennes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre d'Investigation Clinique Institut national de la sante et de la recherche medicale 1414 &#xe9;quipe neuropsychiatrie du d&#xe9;veloppement et du comportement, Universit&#xe9; de Rennes, Rennes, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haffen</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4091-518X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service de Psychiatrie de l'Adulte, Centre d'Investigation Clinique 1431-Institut national de la sante et de la recherche medicale, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Besan&#xe7;on, Universit&#xe9; de Franche-Comt&#xe9;, Besan&#xe7;on, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fakra</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3522-4584</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>P&#xf4;le Universitaire de Psychiatrie, Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Saint-Etienne, Universit&#xe9; Jean Monnet, Equipe Troubles psychiatriques, Recherche en Neurosciences et Recherche Clinique- InInstitut national de la sante et de la recherche medicaleserm, Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique 5292, Universit&#xe9; Lyon 1, Universit&#xe9; Jean Monnet, Saint-Etienne, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaudeau-Bosma</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-1756-1020</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Espace Territoriale d'Accompagnement Psychosociale, Groupe Hospitaliser Territorial Val de Marne-Est, Saint-Maurice, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaillard</LastName><ForeName>Adeline</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0002-7983-1407</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>17 rue des marronniers, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mouchabac</LastName><ForeName>St&#xe9;phane</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4226-7956</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, H&#xf4;pital Saint-Antoine, Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pineau</LastName><ForeName>Fanny</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-2025-5125</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cabinet de psychologie, Bureaux du Polygone, Montpellier, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narboni</LastName><ForeName>V&#xe9;ronique</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-7390-2329</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>EDT- 194 Bureau de la Colline, Saint-Cloud, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duburcq</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-4344-9393</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CEMKA - 43, boulevard du Mar&#xe9;chal Joffre, Bourg-La-Reine, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lecardeur</LastName><ForeName>Laurent</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2016-9925</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>DueL, Nice, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Form Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101726394</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2561-326X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deprexis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">e-mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prospective acceptability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychotherapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: All authors received financial support from Ethypharm Digital Therapy (EDT) for patient recruitment in this study. OA, AS, AHC, PC, DD, EH, EF, and LL received financial compensation from EDT for their participation in the advisory board. EH has served in an advisory capacity; has conducted clinical trials related to the development of a drug; has received personal research, study, or travel funding; has made presentations at meetings; and has received remuneration for his contributions from the following pharmaceutical organizations: Janssen, Lundbeck, Otsuka, EISAI, CEMKA, Ethypharm, Neuraxpharm, and Sanofi. EH held a senior position in the FondaMental Foundation (Cr&#xe9;teil) and the French Association of Biological Psychiatry and Neuropsychopharmacology (Paris). IA received personal travel expenses and gave presentations at meetings for Janssen, Otsuka, and Lundbeck. AHC has received honoraria from Ethypharm Digital Therapy outside the submitted work, and along with PC and EH received financial support for being speakers at symposia. AD is a consultant for CEMKA. LL is a consultant to DueL. VN was employed by EDT. EF is a consultant for Ethypharm, Janssen, and Lundbeck. AGG received financial support for travel expenses for a conference. SM received fees related to the subject matter of the article from the following companies: Ethypharm, Dallia, Did2are.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38568139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11148517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/53204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v8i1e53204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Arias-de la Torre J, Vilagut G, Ronaldson A, Serrano-Blanco A, Mart&#xed;n V, Peters M, Valderas JM, Dregan A, Alonso J. Prevalence and variability of current depressive disorder in 27 European countries: a population-based study. Lancet Public Health. 2021;6(10):e729&#x2013;e738. doi: 10.1016/S2468-2667(21)00047-5. 
 
S2468-2667(21)00047-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-2667(21)00047-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8460452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33961802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of COVID-19 on mental health cannot be made light of. World Health Organization.  [2024-04-16].  
 https://www.who.int/news-room/feature-stories/detail/the-impact-of-covid-19-on-mental-health-cannot-be-made-light-of
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Schoevers RA. Increased mortality in depressive disorders: a review. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2004;6(6):430&#x2013;437. doi: 10.1007/s11920-004-0007-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11920-004-0007-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15538991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rapport sur la qualification d&#x2019;une approche population centr&#xe9;e et partenariale en sant&#xe9; mentale. France Strat&#xe9;gie, R&#xe9;publique Fran&#xe7;aise.  [2024-04-16].  
 https://www.strategie.gouv.fr/publications/rapport-qualification-dune-approche-population-centree-partenariale-sante-mentale
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Titov N, Dear BF, Rozental A, Carlbring P. Internet-delivered psychological treatments: from innovation to implementation. World Psychiatry. 2019;18(1):20&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1002/wps.20610. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6313242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30600624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digital Trade Alliance.  [2024-04-16].  
 https://dtalliance.org
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sepah SC, Jiang L, Peters AL. Long-term outcomes of a web-based diabetes prevention program: 2-year results of a single-arm longitudinal study. J Med Internet Res. 2015;17(4):e92. doi: 10.2196/jmir.4052. 
 
v17i4e92</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.4052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4409647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25863515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E, Efthimiou O, Miguel C, Bermpohl FMG, Furukawa TA, Cuijpers P, Individual Patient Data Meta-Analyses for Depression (IPDMA-DE) Collaboration. Riper H, Patel V, Mira A, Gemmil AW, Yeung AS, Lange A, Williams AD, Mackinnon A, Geraedts A, van Straten A, Meyer B, Bj&#xf6;rkelund C, Knaevelsrud C, Beevers CG, Botella C, Strunk DR, Mohr DC, Ebert DD, Kessler D, Richards D, Littlewood E, Forsell E, Feng F, Wang F, Andersson G, Hadjistavropoulos H, Christensen H, Ezawa ID, Choi I, Rosso IM, Klein JP, Shumake J, Garcia-Campayo J, Milgrom J, Smith J, Montero-Marin J, Newby JM, Bret&#xf3;n-L&#xf3;pez J, Schneider J, Vernmark K, B&#xfc;cker L, Sheeber LB, Warmerdam L, Farrer L, Heinrich M, Huibers MJH, Kivi M, Kraepelien M, Forand NR, Pugh N, Lindefors N, Lintvedt O, Zagorscak P, Carlbring P, Phillips R, Johansson R, Kessler RC, Brabyn S, Perini S, Rauch SL, Gilbody S, Moritz S, Berger T, Pop V, Kaldo V, Spek V, Forsell Y. Internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy for depression: a systematic review and individual patient data network meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78(4):361&#x2013;371. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.4364. 
 
2774861</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.4364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33471111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depression in adults: treatment and management. National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) 2022.  [2024-04-16].  
 https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng222
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35977056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digitally enabled therapies for adults with depression: early value assessment. National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) 2023.  [2024-04-16].  
 https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/hte8
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O'Reilly G, B&#xfc;ltmann O, Meyer B. Effectiveness of a tailored, integrative internet intervention (deprexis) for depression: updated meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15(1):e0228100. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0228100. 
 
PONE-D-19-25463</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0228100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31999743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JBW. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16(9):606&#x2013;613. doi: 10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x. 
 
jgi01114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Courtet P, Amiot O, Baca-Garcia E, Bellardita L, Cerveri G, Clair AH, De Leo D, Drapier D, Fakra E, Gheysen F, Giner L, Gonzalez-Pinto A, Gussoni G, Haffen E, Lecardeur L, Mayoral-Cleries F, Mennini FS, S&#xe1;iz PA, Vieta E, Hidalgo DA, Volpe U. Understanding the potential of digital therapies in implementing the standard of care for depression in Europe. Eur Psychiatry. 2023;66(1):e82. doi: 10.1192/j.eurpsy.2023.2453. 
 
S0924933823024537</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/j.eurpsy.2023.2453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10755564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37872705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Kessel R, Roman-Urrestarazu A, Anderson M, Kyriopoulos I, Field S, Monti G, Reed SD, Pavlova M, Wharton G, Mossialos E. Mapping factors that affect the uptake of digital therapeutics within health systems: scoping review. J Med Internet Res. 2023;25:e48000. doi: 10.2196/48000. 
 
v25i1e48000</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/48000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10410406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37490322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perski Olga, Short CE. Acceptability of digital health interventions: embracing the complexity. Transl Behav Med. 2021;11(7):1473&#x2013;1480. doi: 10.1093/tbm/ibab048. 
 
6272497</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tbm/ibab048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8320880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33963864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadal C, Sas C, Doherty G. Technology acceptance in mobile health: scoping review of definitions, models, and measurement. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22(7):e17256. doi: 10.2196/17256. 
 
v22i7e17256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/17256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes RT, da Rocha GC, Svacina MA, Meyer B, &#x160;ipka D, Berger T. Effectiveness of an internet-based self-guided program to treat depression in a sample of Brazilian users: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Form Res. 2023;7:e46326. doi: 10.2196/46326. 
 
v7i1e46326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/46326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10472176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37590052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter LE, Machleit-Ebner A, Scherbaum N, Bonnet U. How effective is a web-based mental health intervention (deprexis) in the treatment of moderate and major depressive disorders when started during routine psychiatric inpatient treatment as an adjunct therapy? A pragmatic parallel-group randomized controlled trial. Fortschr Neurol Psychiatr. 2023;91(7-08):297&#x2013;310. doi: 10.1055/a-1826-2888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1826-2888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35882364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;fe V, Moritz S, Greiner W. Health economic evaluation of an internet intervention for depression (deprexis), a randomized controlled trial. Health Econ Rev. 2020;10(1):19. doi: 10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0. 
 
10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13561-020-00273-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7298860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32548724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hafner J, Sch&#xf6;nfeld S, Tokg&#xf6;z P, Choroschun K, Schlubach A, Dockweiler C. Digital health interventions in depression care-a survey on acceptance from the perspective of patients, their relatives and health professionals. Healthcare (Basel) 2022;10(10):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.3390/healthcare10102019. 
 
healthcare10102019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare10102019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9602748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36292466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salk RH, Hyde JS, Abramson LY. Gender differences in depression in representative national samples: meta-analyses of diagnoses and symptoms. Psychol Bull. 2017;143(8):783&#x2013;822. doi: 10.1037/bul0000102. 
 
2017-18894-001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/bul0000102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5532074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28447828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghouts J, Eikey E, Mark G, De Leon C, Schueller SM, Schneider M, Stadnick N, Zheng K, Mukamel D, Sorkin DH. Barriers to and facilitators of user engagement with digital mental health interventions: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2021;23(3):e24387. doi: 10.2196/24387. 
 
v23i3e24387</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/24387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8074985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33759801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Schr&#xf6;der J, Meyer B, Hauschildt M. The more it is needed, the less it is wanted: attitudes toward face-to-face intervention among depressed patients undergoing online treatment. Depress Anxiety. 2013;30(2):157&#x2013;167. doi: 10.1002/da.21988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.21988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Bierbrodt J, Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Beevers CG, Weiss M, Jacob G, Sp&#xe4;th C, Andersson G, Lutz W, Hautzinger M, L&#xf6;we B, Rose M, Hohagen F, Caspar F, Greiner W, Moritz S, Klein JP. Effects of an internet intervention (deprexis) on severe depression symptoms: randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. 2015;2(1):48&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2014.12.003. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2014.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurchie W, Macleod F, Power K, Laidlaw K, Prentice N. Computerised cognitive behavioural therapy for depression and anxiety with older people: a pilot study to examine patient acceptability and treatment outcome. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2013;28(11):1147&#x2013;1156. doi: 10.1002/gps.3935. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gps.3935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23495124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourla A, Ferreri F, Ogorzelec L, Peretti CS, Guinchard C, Mouchabac S. Psychiatrists' attitudes toward disruptive new technologies: mixed-methods study. JMIR Ment Health. 2018;5(4):e10240. doi: 10.2196/10240. 
 
v5i4e10240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30552086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Gemert-Pijnen JEWC, Nijland N, van Limburg M, Ossebaard HC, Kelders SM, Eysenbach G, Seydel ER. A holistic framework to improve the uptake and impact of eHealth technologies. J Med Internet Res. 2011;13(4):e111. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1672. 
 
v13i4e111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22155738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>