<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39990627</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2667-1743</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Biological psychiatry global open science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Biol Psychiatry Glob Open Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Augmenting Internet-Based Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Major Depressive Disorder With Transcranial Infrared Laser Stimulation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100449</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100449</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100449</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bpsgos.2025.100449</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Transcranial infrared laser stimulation (TILS) is a noninvasive form of photobiomodulation that facilitates prefrontal energy metabolism and oxygenation, resulting in cognitive-enhancing effects. Cognitive behavioral therapy is a mainstream treatment for major depressive disorder. This is the first study to investigate whether TILS would augment the antidepressant effects of internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sixty participants with major depressive disorder were given access to Deprexis, a form of internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy, for 12 weeks. After the first 2 weeks, the 40 participants who had improved at least 10% in depressive symptoms from baseline as measured by the Quick Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology-Self-Report were randomly assigned to Deprexis in combination with TILS or sham/placebo. There were no significant group differences in demographics or initial depression data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There was a 43% reduction in Quick Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology-Self-Report scores in the sham group from the initial score to the week 12 score, while adding TILS as an adjunct therapy resulted in a reduction of 56%. Therefore, TILS resulted in an additional 30% reduction in Quick Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology-Self-Report scores ([56-43]/43&#xa0;= 30%). Participants who received TILS to the right forehead once a week for 4 weeks showed a significantly greater reduction of depressive symptoms than participants who received sham/placebo. Participants reported no adverse effects.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">While Deprexis alone significantly reduced depression scores in the placebo control group, this beneficial effect was augmented with the addition of TILS as an adjunct therapy. Additional research that pairs neuroenhancement methods such as TILS with cognitive interventions may reveal the potential to improve treatment outcomes in depression and other psychiatric disorders.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barrett</LastName><ForeName>Douglas W</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Psychology, Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, and Institute for Neuroscience, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beevers</LastName><ForeName>Christopher G</ForeName><Initials>CG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Psychology, Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, and Institute for Neuroscience, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonzalez-Lima</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Psychology, Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, and Institute for Neuroscience, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Biol Psychiatry Glob Open Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918227369306676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2667-1743</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Transcranial infrared laser stimulation (TILS) is a safe and noninvasive form of photobiomodulation that can be used to increase brain activity in the frontal lobes, resulting in enhanced cognition and emotional regulation. Deprexis is a form of internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy for treating depression. TILS administration to the forehead had a synergistic effect on improving depression symptoms when combined with Deprexis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive enhancement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Deprexis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Major depressive disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prefrontal cortex stimulation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Transcranial infrared laser stimulation</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39990627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11847300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpsgos.2025.100449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2667-1743(25)00003-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Butler A.C., Chapman J.E., Forman E.M., Beck A.T. The empirical status of cognitive-behavioral therapy: A review of meta-analyses. Clin Psychol Rev. 2006;26:17&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16199119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B., Berger T., Caspar F., Beevers C.G., Andersson G., Weiss M. Effectiveness of a novel integrative online treatment for depression (Deprexis): Randomized controlled trial. J&#xa0;Med Internet Res. 2009;11:e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19632969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beevers C.G., Pearson R., Hoffman J.S., Foulser A.A., Shumake J., Meyer B. Effectiveness of an internet intervention (Deprexis) for depression in a United States adult sample: A parallel-group pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J&#xa0;Consult Clin Psychol. 2017;85:367&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28230390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C., O&#x2019;Reilly G., Meyer B. Effectiveness of an individually-tailored computerised CBT programme (Deprexis) for depression: A meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2017;256:371&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C., O&#x2019;Reilly G., B&#xfc;ltmann O., Meyer B. Effectiveness of a tailored, integrative internet intervention (Deprexis) for depression: Updated meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31999743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullarkey M.C., Stein A.T., Pearson R., Beevers C.G. Network analyses reveal which symptoms improve (or not) following an Internet intervention (Deprexis) for depression. Depress Anxiety. 2020;37:115&#x2013;124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31710772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajeshkumar L., Mishkind M., Coleman J.J., Pahwa M., LaPreze D., Solenske S., Wright J.H. Computer-assisted cognitive behavior therapy and mobile apps for depression and anxiety: Evidence-based digital tools for clinical practice. J&#xa0;Psychiatr Pract. 2024;30:389&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39655965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Lima F. In: Modern Approaches to Augmentation of Brain Function. Opris I., Lebedev M.A., Casanova M.F., editors. Springer International Publishing; Cham: 2021. Neuroprotection and neurocognitive augmentation by photobiomodulation; pp. 165&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Tian F., Reddy D.D., Nalawade S.S., Barrett D.W., Gonzalez-Lima F., Liu H. Up-regulation of cerebral cytochrome-c-oxidase and hemodynamics by transcranial infrared laser stimulation: A broadband near-infrared spectroscopy study. J&#xa0;Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2017;37:3789&#x2013;3802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5718323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28178891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes E., Barrett D.W., Saucedo C.L., O&#x2019;Connor P., Liu H., Gonzalez-Lima F. Cognitive enhancement by transcranial photobiomodulation is associated with cerebrovascular oxygenation of the prefrontal cortex. Front Neurosci. 2019;13:1129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6813459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31680847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett D.W., Gonzalez-Lima F. Transcranial infrared laser stimulation produces beneficial cognitive and emotional effects in humans. Neuroscience. 2013;230:13&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23200785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco N.J., Maddox W.T., Gonzalez-Lima F. Improving executive function using transcranial infrared laser stimulation. J&#xa0;Neuropsychol. 2017;11:14&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4662930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26017772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco N.J., Saucedo C.L., Gonzalez-Lima F. Transcranial infrared laser stimulation improves rule-based, but not information-integration, category learning in humans. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2017;139:69&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28039085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disner S.G., Beevers C.G., Gonzalez-Lima F. Transcranial laser stimulation as neuroenhancement for attention bias modification in adults with elevated depression symptoms. Brain Stimul. 2016;9:780&#x2013;787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5007141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldieraro M.A., Cassano P. Transcranial and systemic photobiomodulation for major depressive disorder: A systematic review of efficacy, tolerability and biological mechanisms. J&#xa0;Affect Disord. 2019;243:262&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30248638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira W.F., Iosifescu D.V., McEachern K.M., Gersten M., Cassano P. Photobiomodulation: An emerging treatment modality for depression. Psychiatr Clin North Am. 2023;46:331&#x2013;348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37149348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radloff L.S. The CES-D scale: A self-report depression scale for research in the general population. Appl Psychol Meas. 1977;1:385&#x2013;401.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush A.J., Trivedi M.H., Ibrahim H.M., Carmody T.J., Arnow B., Klein D.N., et al. The 16-Item Quick Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology (QIDS), Clinician Rating (QIDS-C), and Self-Report (QIDS-SR): A psychometric evaluation in patients with chronic major depression. Biol Psychiatry. 2003;54:573&#x2013;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12946886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaizar E.D., Papini S., Gonzalez-Lima F., Telch M.J. Singular and combined effects of transcranial infrared laser stimulation and exposure therapy on pathological fear: A randomized clinical trial. Psychol Med. 2023;53:908&#x2013;917.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9976021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34284836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang L.-D., Kao T.-C., Sung K.-B., Abraham J.A. Simulation study on the optimization of photon energy delivered to the prefrontal cortex in low-level-light therapy using red to near-infrared light. IEEE J Select Top Quantum Electron. 2021;27:1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaizar E.D., Gonzalez-Lima F., Telch M.J. Singular and combined effects of transcranial infrared laser stimulation and exposure therapy: A randomized clinical trial. Contemp Clin Trials. 2018;72:95&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30092284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffer F., Johnston A.L., Ravichandran C., Polcari A., Teicher M.H., Webb R.H., Hamblin M.R. Psychological benefits 2 and 4 weeks after a single treatment with near infrared light to the forehead: A pilot study of 10 patients with major depression and anxiety. Behav Brain Funct. 2009;5:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2796659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19995444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhle J.T., Silvers J.A., Wager T.D., Lopez R., Onyemekwu C., Kober H., et al. Cognitive reappraisal of emotion: A meta-analysis of human neuroimaging studies. Cereb Cortex. 2014;24:2981&#x2013;2990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4193464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23765157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R., Zhang S., Yin S., Ren W., He R., Li J. The fronto-insular cortex causally mediates the default-mode and central-executive networks to contribute to individual cognitive performance in healthy elderly. Hum Brain Mapp. 2018;39:4302&#x2013;4311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6866622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29974584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shumake J., Poremba A., Edwards E., Gonzalez-Lima F. Congenital helpless rats as a genetic model for cortex metabolism in depression. Neuroreport. 2000;11:3793&#x2013;3798.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11117493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biver F., Goldman S., Delvenne V., Luxen A., De Maertelaer V., Hubain P., et al. Frontal and parietal metabolic disturbances in unipolar depression. Biol Psychiatry. 1994;36:381&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7803599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayberg H.S., Liotti M., Brannan S.K., McGinnis S., Mahurin R.K., Jerabek P.A., et al. Reciprocal limbic-cortical function and negative mood: Converging PET findings in depression and normal sadness. Am J Psychiatry. 1999;156:675&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10327898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Disner S.G., Beevers C.G., Haigh E.A.P., Beck A.T. Neural mechanisms of the cognitive model of depression. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2011;12:467&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21731066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldin P.R., Ziv M., Jazaieri H., Weeks J., Heimberg R.G., Gross J.J. Impact of cognitive-behavioral therapy for social anxiety disorder on the neural bases of emotional reactivity to and regulation of social evaluation. Behav Res Ther. 2014;62:97&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4253719</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25193002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vieira W.F., Gersten M., Caldieraro M.A.K., Cassano P. Photobiomodulation for major depressive disorder: Linking transcranial infrared light, biophotons and oxidative stress. Harv Rev Psychiatry. 2023;31:124&#x2013;141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37171473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Gonzalez-Lima F., Liu H. In: The Oxford Handbook of Transcranial Stimulation. 2nd ed. Wassermann E.M., Peterchev A.V., Ziemann U., Lisanby S.H., Siebner H.R., Walsh V., editors. Oxford University Press; 2024. Transcranial infrared laser stimulation; pp. 276&#x2013;298.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso F.D.S., Gonzalez-Lima F., Gomes Da Silva S. Photobiomodulation for the aging brain. Ageing Res Rev. 2021;70</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34325071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cardoso F.D.S., Salehpour F., Coimbra N.C., Gonzalez-Lima F., Gomes Da Silva S. Photobiomodulation for the treatment of neuroinflammation: A systematic review of controlled laboratory animal studies. Front Neurosci. 2022;16</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9531128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36203812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayberg H. Neuromodulation of emotion networks in patients with depression: Lessons learned. Brain Stimul. 2023;16:118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell C.M., Barrett D.W., O&#x2019;Connor P., Gonzalez-Lima F. Prefrontal photobiomodulation produces beneficial mitochondrial and oxygenation effects in older adults with bipolar disorder. Front Neurosci. 2023;17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10644301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38027522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>