<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36967402</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2047-9158</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Translational neurodegeneration</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Transl Neurodegener</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Modulating arousal to overcome gait impairments in Parkinson's disease: how the noradrenergic system may act as a double-edged sword.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15</StartPage><MedlinePgn>15</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">15</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40035-023-00347-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In stressful or anxiety-provoking situations, most people with Parkinson's disease (PD) experience a general worsening of motor symptoms, including their gait impairments. However, a proportion of patients actually report benefits from experiencing-or even purposely inducing-stressful or high-arousal situations. Using data from a large-scale international survey study among 4324 people with PD and gait impairments within the online Fox Insight (USA) and ParkinsonNEXT (NL) cohorts, we demonstrate that individuals with PD deploy an array of mental state alteration strategies to cope with their gait impairment. Crucially, these strategies differ along an axis of arousal-some act to heighten, whereas others diminish, overall sympathetic tone. Together, our observations suggest that arousal may act as a double-edged sword for gait control in PD. We propose a theoretical, neurobiological framework to explain why heightened arousal can have detrimental effects on the occurrence and severity of gait impairments in some individuals, while alleviating them in others. Specifically, we postulate that this seemingly contradictory phenomenon is explained by the inherent features of the ascending arousal system: namely, that arousal is related to task performance by an inverted u-shaped curve (the so-called Yerkes and Dodson relationship). We propose that the noradrenergic locus coeruleus plays an important role in modulating PD symptom severity and expression, by regulating arousal and by mediating network-level functional integration across the brain. The ability of the locus coeruleus to facilitate dynamic 'cross-talk' between distinct, otherwise largely segregated brain regions may facilitate the necessary cerebral compensation for gait impairments in PD. In the presence of suboptimal arousal, compensatory networks may be too segregated to allow for adequate compensation. Conversely, with supraoptimal arousal, increased cross-talk between competing inputs of these complementary networks may emerge and become dysfunctional. Because the locus coeruleus degenerates with disease progression, finetuning of this delicate balance becomes increasingly difficult, heightening the need for mental strategies to self-modulate arousal and facilitate shifting from a sub- or supraoptimal state of arousal to improve gait performance. Recognition of this underlying mechanism emphasises the importance of PD-specific rehabilitation strategies to alleviate gait disability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tosserams</LastName><ForeName>Anouk</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center of Expertise for Parkinson and Movement Disorders, Radboud University Medical Centre, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Center of Expertise for Parkinson and Movement Disorders, Radboud University Medical Centre, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour, PO Box 9101, 6500 HB, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bloem</LastName><ForeName>Bastiaan R</ForeName><Initials>BR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center of Expertise for Parkinson and Movement Disorders, Radboud University Medical Centre, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ehgoetz Martens</LastName><ForeName>Kaylena A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology and Health Sciences, University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Helmich</LastName><ForeName>Rick C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Center of Expertise for Parkinson and Movement Disorders, Radboud University Medical Centre, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kessels</LastName><ForeName>Roy P C</ForeName><Initials>RPC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neuropsychology and Rehabilitation Psychology, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour, Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Psychology and Radboudumc Alzheimer Center, Radboud University Medical Centre, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour, Nijmegen, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vincent Van Gogh Institute for Psychiatry, Venray, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Klimmendaal Rehabilitation Center, Arnhem, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shine</LastName><ForeName>James M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, Parkinson's Disease Research Clinic, School of Medical Sciences, University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Complex Systems, The University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Natasha L</ForeName><Initials>NL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, Parkinson's Disease Research Clinic, School of Medical Sciences, University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wainstein</LastName><ForeName>Gabriel</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, Parkinson's Disease Research Clinic, School of Medical Sciences, University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lewis</LastName><ForeName>Simon J G</ForeName><Initials>SJG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Brain and Mind Centre, Parkinson's Disease Research Clinic, School of Medical Sciences, University of Sydney, Camperdown, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nonnekes</LastName><ForeName>Jorik</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2434-1427</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Center of Expertise for Parkinson and Movement Disorders, Radboud University Medical Centre, Donders Institute for Brain, Cognition and Behaviour, PO Box 9101, 6500 HB, Nijmegen, The Netherlands. jorik.nonnekes@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation, Sint Maartenskliniek, Nijmegen, The Netherlands. jorik.nonnekes@radboudumc.nl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Transl Neurodegener</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101591861</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2047-9158</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005684" MajorTopicYN="N">Gait</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001143" MajorTopicYN="N">Arousal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Arousal</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Freezing of gait</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gait</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Locus coeruleus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors report no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36967402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10040128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40035-023-00347-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40035-023-00347-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Berlot R, Rothwell JC, Bhatia KP, Kojovic M. Variability of movement disorders: the influence of sensation, action, cognition, and emotions. Mov Disord. 2021;36(3):581&#x2013;593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33332680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HJ, Lee WW, Kim SK, Park H, Jeon HS, Kim HB, et al. Tremor frequency characteristics in Parkinson's disease under resting-state and stress-state conditions. J Neurol Sci. 2016;362:272&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26944162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blakemore RL, MacAskill MR, Shoorangiz R, Anderson TJ. Stress-evoking emotional stimuli exaggerate deficits in motor function in Parkinson's disease. Neuropsychologia. 2018;112:66&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29522760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dirkx MF, Zach H, van Nuland AJ, Bloem BR, Toni I, Helmich RC. Cognitive load amplifies Parkinson&#x2019;s tremor through excitatory network influences onto the thalamus. Brain. 2020;143(5):1498&#x2013;1511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zach H, Dirkx MF, Pasman JW, Bloem BR, Helmich RC. Cognitive stress reduces the effect of levodopa on Parkinson's resting tremor. CNS Neurosci Ther. 2017;23(3):209&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5324662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28071873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heide A, Speckens AEM, Meinders MJ, Rosenthal LS, Bloem BR, Helmich RC. Stress and mindfulness in Parkinson's disease&#x2014;a survey in 5000 patients. NPJ Parkinson's Dis. 2021;7(1):7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7813889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33462213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehgoetz Martens KA, Peterson DS, Almeida QJ, Lewis SJG, Hausdorff JM, Nieuwboer A. Behavioural manifestations and associated non-motor features of freezing of gait: a narrative review and theoretical framework. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2020;116:350&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32603716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehgoetz Martens KA, Ellard CG, Almeida QJ. Anxiety-provoked gait changes are selectively dopa-responsive in Parkinson's disease. Eur J Neurosci. 2015;42(4):2028&#x2013;2035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25899750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mirelman A, Bonato P, Camicioli R, Ellis TD, Giladi N, Hamilton JL, et al. Gait impairments in Parkinson's disease. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(7):697&#x2013;708.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30975519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehgoetz Martens KA, Ellard CG, Almeida QJ. Does anxiety cause freezing of gait in Parkinson's disease? PLoS ONE. 2014;9(9):e106561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4175083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25250691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehgoetz Martens KA, Hall JM, Gilat M, Georgiades MJ, Walton CC, Lewis SJG. Anxiety and freezing of gait: a new perspective for early intervention. Mov Disord. 2016;31(Supplement 2):S100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27513741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehgoetz Martens KA, Lukasik EL, Georgiades MJ, Gilat M, Hall JM, Walton CC, et al. Predicting the onset of freezing of gait: a longitudinal study. Mov Disord. 2018;33(1):128&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29150872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Economou K, Quek D, MacDougall H, Lewis SJG, Ehgoetz Martens KA. Heart rate changes prior to freezing of gait episodes are related to anxiety. J Parkinsons Dis. 2021;11(1):271&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33074191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagravinese G, Pelosin E, Bonassi G, Carbone F, Abbruzzese G, Avanzino L. Gait initiation is influenced by emotion processing in Parkinson's disease patients with freezing. Mov Disord. 2018;33(4):609&#x2013;617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29392774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieberman A. Are freezing of gait (FOG) and panic related? J Neurol Sci. 2006;248(1&#x2013;2):219&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16797596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macht M, Kaussner Y, Moller JC, Stiasny-Kolster K, Eggert KM, Kruger HP, et al. Predictors of freezing in Parkinson's disease: a survey of 6,620 patients. Mov Disord. 2007;22(7):953&#x2013;956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17377927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok JYY, Kwan JCY, Auyeung M, Mok VCT, Lau CKY, Choi KC, et al. Effects of mindfulness yoga vs stretching and resistance training exercises on anxiety and depression for people with Parkinson disease: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76(7):755&#x2013;763.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30958514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dissanayaka NN, Idu Jion F, Pachana NA, O'Sullivan JD, Marsh R, Byrne GJ, et al. Mindfulness for motor and nonmotor dysfunctions in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsons Dis. 2016;2016:7109052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4842053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27144052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Advocat J, Enticott J, Vandenberg B, Hassed C, Hester J, Russell G. The effects of a mindfulness-based lifestyle program for adults with Parkinson's disease: a mixed methods, wait list controlled randomised control study. BMC Neurol. 2016;16:166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5016929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27608621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Heide A, Meinders MJ, Speckens AEM, Peerbolte TF, Bloem BR, Helmich RC. Stress and mindfulness in Parkinson's disease: clinical effects and potential underlying mechanisms. Mov Disord. 2021;36(1):64&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7894549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33094858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlesinger I, Erikh I, Yarnitsky D. Paradoxical kinesia at war. Mov Disord. 2007;22(16):2394&#x2013;2397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17914720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duysens J, Nonnekes J. Parkinson's kinesia paradoxa is not a paradox. Mov Disord. 2021;36(5):1115&#x2013;1118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33656203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonanni L, Thomas A, Anzellotti F, Monaco D, Ciccocioppo F, Varanese S, et al. Paradoxical kinesia in parkinsonian patients surviving earthquake. Mov Disord. 2010;2:S361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20310034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonnekes J, Ruzicka E, Nieuwboer A, Hallett M, Fasano A, Bloem BR. Compensation strategies for gait impairments in Parkinson disease: a review. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76(6):718&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30907948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yerkes RM, Dodson JD. The relation of strength of stimulus to rapidity of habit-formation. J Comp Neurol Psychol. 1908;18(5):459&#x2013;482.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwboer A, Kwakkel G, Rochester L, Jones D, van Wegen E, Willems AM, et al. Cueing training in the home improves gait-related mobility in Parkinson's disease: the RESCUE trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78(2):134&#x2013;140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2077658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17229744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosserams A, Nijkrake MJ, Sturkenboom I, Bloem BR, Nonnekes J. Perceptions of compensation strategies for gait impairments in Parkinson's disease: a survey among 320 healthcare professionals. J Parkinsons Dis. 2020;10(4):1775&#x2013;1778.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7683052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32925103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosserams A, Wit L, Sturkenboom I, Nijkrake MJ, Bloem BR, Nonnekes J. Perception and use of compensation strategies for gait impairment by persons with Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2021;97(14):e1404&#x2013;e1412.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8520387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34497067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwboer A, Rochester L, Herman T, Vandenberghe W, Emil GE, Thomaes T, et al. Reliability of the new freezing of gait questionnaire: agreement between patients with Parkinson's disease and their carers. Gait Posture. 2009;30(4):459&#x2013;463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19660949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller J. The flow experience revisited: the influence of skills-demands-compatibility on experiential and physiological indicators. In: Harmat L, &#xd8;rsted Andersen F, Ull&#xe9;n F, Wright J, Sadlo G, editors. Flow experience: empirical research and applications. Cham: Springer; 2016. pp. 351&#x2013;374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breton-Provencher V, Sur M. Active control of arousal by a locus coeruleus GABAergic circuit. Nat Neurosci. 2019;22(2):218&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6385895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30643295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Totah NK, Neves RM, Panzeri S, Logothetis NK, Eschenko O. The locus coeruleus is a complex and differentiated neuromodulatory system. Neuron. 2018;99(5):1055&#x2013;1068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30122373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Guo T, Bai X, Wu J, Gao T, Guan X, et al. Locus coeruleus degeneration is associated with disorganized functional topology in Parkinson's disease. NeuroImage Clin. 2021;32:102873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8578042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34749290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuels ER, Szabadi E. Functional neuroanatomy of the noradrenergic locus coeruleus: its roles in the regulation of arousal and autonomic function part II: physiological and pharmacological manipulations and pathological alterations of locus coeruleus activity in humans. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2008;6(3):254&#x2013;285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2687931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19506724</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aston-Jones G, Cohen JD. Adaptive gain and the role of the locus coeruleus-norepinephrine system in optimal performance. J Comp Neurol. 2005;493(1):99&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16254995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aston-Jones G, Cohen JD. An integrative theory of locus coeruleus-norepinephrine function: adaptive gain and optimal performance. Annu Rev Neurosci. 2005;28:403&#x2013;450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16022602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wainstein G, Muller EJ, Taylor N, Munn B, Shine JM. The role of the locus coeruleus in shaping adaptive cortical melodies. Trends Cogn Sci. 2022;26(6):527&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35469726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermans EJ, van Marle HJ, Ossewaarde L, Henckens MJ, Qin S, van Kesteren MT, et al. Stress-related noradrenergic activity prompts large-scale neural network reconfiguration. Science. 2011;334(6059):1151&#x2013;1153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22116887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shine JM. Neuromodulatory influences on integration and segregation in the brain. Trends Cogn Sci. 2019;23(7):572&#x2013;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31076192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shine JM, Muller EJ, Munn B, Cabral J, Moran RJ, Breakspear M. Computational models link cellular mechanisms of neuromodulation to large-scale neural dynamics. Nat Neurosci. 2021;24(6):765&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33958801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shine JM, Aburn MJ, Breakspear M, Poldrack RA. The modulation of neural gain facilitates a transition between functional segregation and integration in the brain. Elife. 2018;7:e31130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5818252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29376825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shine JM, van den Brink RL, Hernaus D, Nieuwenhuis S, Poldrack RA. Catecholaminergic manipulation alters dynamic network topology across cognitive states. Netw Neurosci. 2018;2(3):381&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6145851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30294705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takakusaki K. Functional neuroanatomy for posture and gait control. J Mov Disord. 2017;10(1):1&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5288669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jahn K, Deutschlander A, Stephan T, Kalla R, Hufner K, Wagner J, et al. Supraspinal locomotor control in quadrupeds and humans. Prog Brain Res. 2008;171:353&#x2013;362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18718326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takakusaki K. Neurophysiology of gait: from the spinal cord to the frontal lobe. Mov Disord. 2013;28(11):1483&#x2013;1491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24132836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilat M, Dijkstra BW, D'Cruz N, Nieuwboer A, Lewis SJG. Functional MRI to study gait impairment in Parkinson's disease: a systematic review and exploratory ALE meta-analysis. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2019;19(8):49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31214901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nonnekes J, Bereau M, Bloem BR. Freezing of gait and its levodopa paradox. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(3):287&#x2013;288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31841600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilat M, Ginis P, Zoetewei D, De Vleeschhauwer J, Hulzinga F, D'Cruz N, et al. A systematic review on exercise and training-based interventions for freezing of gait in Parkinson's disease. NPJ Parkinson's Dis. 2021;7(1):81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8433229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34508083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avanzino L, Lagravinese G, Abbruzzese G, Pelosin E. Relationships between gait and emotion in Parkinson's disease: a narrative review. Gait Posture. 2018;65:57&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosserams A, Weerdesteyn V, Bal T, Bloem BR, Solis-Escalante T, Nonnekes J. Cortical correlates of gait compensation strategies in Parkinson disease. Ann Neurol. 2022;91(3):329&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9306676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35067999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwhof F, Helmich RC. Entangled cerebral networks in Parkinson's disease. Brain. 2017;140(11):2767&#x2013;2769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29088350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor NL, Wainstein G, Quek D, Lewis SJG, Shine JM, Ehgoetz Martens KA. The contribution of noradrenergic activity to anxiety-induced freezing of gait. Mov Disord. 2022;37(7):1432&#x2013;1443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9540856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shine JM, Matar E, Ward PB, Frank MJ, Moustafa AA, Pearson M, et al. Freezing of gait in Parkinson's disease is associated with functional decoupling between the cognitive control network and the basal ganglia. Brain. 2013;136(Pt 12):3671&#x2013;3681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24142148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis SJ, Barker RA. A pathophysiological model of freezing of gait in Parkinson's disease. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2009;15(5):333&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18930430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giguere N, Burke Nanni S, Trudeau LE. On cell loss and selective vulnerability of neuronal populations in Parkinson's disease. Front Neurol. 2018;9:455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6018545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29971039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oertel WH, Henrich MT, Janzen A, Geibl FF. The locus coeruleus: another vulnerability target in Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2019;34(10):1423&#x2013;1429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31291485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinshenker D. Long road to ruin: noradrenergic dysfunction in neurodegenerative disease. Trends Neurosci. 2018;41(4):211&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5878728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29475564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarow C, Lyness SA, Mortimer JA, Chui HC. Neuronal loss is greater in the locus coeruleus than nucleus basalis and substantia nigra in Alzheimer and Parkinson diseases. Arch Neurol. 2003;60(3):337&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12633144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braak H, Del Tredici K. Neuropathological staging of brain pathology in sporadic Parkinson's disease: separating the wheat from the chaff. J Parkinsons Dis. 2017;7(s1):S71&#x2013;S85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5345633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28282810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halliday G. An evidence base for noradrenergic deficits in Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2012;27(13):1589&#x2013;1591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23033160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shine JM, O'Callaghan C, Walpola IC, Wainstein G, Taylor N, Aru J, et al. Understanding the effects of serotonin in the brain through its role in the gastrointestinal tract. Brain. 2022;145(9):2967&#x2013;2981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35869620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calabresi P, Picconi B, Parnetti L, Di Filippo M. A convergent model for cognitive dysfunctions in Parkinson's disease: the critical dopamine&#x2013;acetylcholine synaptic balance. Lancet Neurol. 2006;5(11):974&#x2013;983.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17052664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alameda C, Sanabria D, Ciria LF. The brain in flow: a systematic review on the neural basis of the flow state. Cortex. 2022;154:348&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35926367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Linden D, Tops M, Bakker AB. The neuroscience of the flow state: involvement of the locus coeruleus norepinephrine system. Front Psychol. 2021;12:645498.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8079660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33935902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole LW. The relation of strength of stimulus to rate of learning in the chick. J Animal Behav. 1911;1(2):111&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodson JD. The relation of strength of stimulus to rapidity of habit-formation in the kitten. J Anim Behav. 1915;5:330&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delval A, Moreau C, Bleuse S, Guehl D, Bestaven E, Guillaud E, et al. Gait and attentional performance in freezers under methylphenidate. Gait Posture. 2015;41(2):384&#x2013;388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25468682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devos D. Methylphenidate for freezing of gait and attention deficit in parkinsonian patients under subthalamic stimulation (PARKGAIT-II): a randomised placebo-controlled trial. Mov Disord. 2012;1:S113&#x2013;S114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukada K, Endo T, Yokoe M, Hamasaki T, Hazama T, Sakoda S. L-threo-3,4-dihydroxyphenylserine (L-DOPS) co-administered with entacapone improves freezing of gait in Parkinson's disease. Med Hypotheses. 2013;80(2):209&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23265352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kutz C, Adams L, Moncheski E. Effects of droxidopa when measuring gait speed, kyphosis, and functional reach in Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2018;33(Supplement 2):S1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doppler CEJ, Kinnerup MB, Brune C, Farrher E, Betts M, Fedorova TD, et al. Regional locus coeruleus degeneration is uncoupled from noradrenergic terminal loss in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Brain. 2021;144(9):2732&#x2013;2744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34196700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasuhn J, Prasuhn M, Fellbrich A, Strautz R, Lemmer F, Dreischmeier S, et al. Association of locus coeruleus and substantia nigra pathology with cognitive and motor functions in patients with Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2021;97(10):e1007&#x2013;e1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34187859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betts MJ, Kirilina E, Otaduy MCG, Ivanov D, Acosta-Cabronero J, Callaghan MF, et al. Locus coeruleus imaging as a biomarker for noradrenergic dysfunction in neurodegenerative diseases. Brain. 2019;142(9):2558&#x2013;2571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6736046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31327002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tosserams A, Keijsers N, Kapelle W, Kessels RPC, Weerdesteyn V, Bloem BR, et al. Evaluation of compensation strategies for gait impairment in patients with Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2022;99(20):e2253&#x2013;e2263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9694838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36008154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerri S, Mus L, Blandini F. Parkinson's disease in women and men: what's the difference? J Parkinsons Dis. 2019;9(3):501&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6700650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31282427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>