<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41057657</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1740-634X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neuropsychopharmacology : official publication of the American College of Neuropsychopharmacology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neuropsychopharmacology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Transdiagnostic prevention in youth mental health, Part II: interventions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>310</StartPage><EndPage>322</EndPage><MedlinePgn>310-322</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41386-025-02234-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The emerging consensus regarding transdiagnostic and dimensional models of psychopathology has important implications for the development of effective approaches for early intervention and prevention of psychiatric conditions. Consistent with biological, epidemiological and clinical evidence, transdiagnostic prevention focuses on reducing risk factors and/or preventing outcomes that are shared across populations who may be at risk for a range of psychiatric disorders. This narrative review describes some of the efforts made to date to develop and test interventions aiming to support universal, selective, and indicated prevention of psychiatric conditions in a transdiagnostic manner, during childhood, adolescence, and early adulthood. An evidence-based transdiagnostic approach to the prevention of mental illness in youth, that accounts for the existing body of knowledge about transdiagnostic risk factors as well as constraints impacting "real world" feasibility of these approaches, has the broad potential to ultimately reduce the incidence and severity of psychiatric illnesses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DeTore</LastName><ForeName>Nicole R</ForeName><Initials>NR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balogun</LastName><ForeName>Oyenike</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Natural and Applied Sciences, Bentley University, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Choi</LastName><ForeName>Karmel W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holt</LastName><ForeName>Daphne J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA. dholt@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA. dholt@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K08 MH127413</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 MH131793</GrantID><Acronym>MH</Acronym><Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K08MH127413</GrantID><Agency>U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services | NIH | National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23MH131793</GrantID><Agency>U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services | NIH | National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>ROIMH122371</GrantID><Agency>U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services | NIH | National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Neuropsychopharmacology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904907</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0893-133X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: KWC is a paid consultant and member of the Mind Advisory Committee of Sword Health. The remaining authors have no disclosures.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41057657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12618500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-025-02234-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41386-025-02234-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gunnell D, Kidger J, Elvidge H Adolescent mental health in crisis. BMJ. 2018:k2608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29921659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuehn BM. Clinician Shortage Exacerbates Pandemic-Fueled &#x201c;Mental Health Crisis&#x201d;. Jama. 2022;327:2179&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35612873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satiani A, Niedermier J, Satiani B, Svendsen DP. Projected Workforce of Psychiatrists in the United States: A Population Analysis. Psychiatr Serv. 2018;69:710&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29540118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoare E, Collins S, Marx W, Callaly E, Moxham-Smith R, Cuijpers P, et al. Universal depression prevention: An umbrella review of meta-analyses. J Psychiatr Res. 2021;144:483&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34768070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz C, Barican JL, Yung D, Zheng Y, Waddell C. Six decades of preventing and treating childhood anxiety disorders: a systematic review and meta-analysis to inform policy and practice. Evid Based Ment Health. 2019;22:103&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6663062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31315926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stice E, Onipede ZA, Marti CN. A meta-analytic review of trials that tested whether eating disorder prevention programs prevent eating disorder onset. Clin Psychol Rev. 2021;87:102046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34048952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sangsawang B, Wacharasin C, Sangsawang N. Interventions for the prevention of postpartum depression in adolescent mothers: a systematic review. Arch Women&#x2019;s Ment Health. 2019;22:215&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30116896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen C, Wang X, Xu H, Li Y. Effectiveness of digital psychological interventions in reducing perinatal depression: a systematic review of meta-analyses. Arch Women&#x2019;s Ment Health. 2023;26:423&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10212734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37231116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremblay M, Baydala L, Khan M, Currie C, Morley K, Burkholder C, et al. Primary Substance Use Prevention Programs for Children and Youth: A Systematic Review. Pediatrics. 2020;146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32769198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusar-Poli P, Salazar de Pablo G, Correll CU, Meyer-Lindenberg A, Millan MJ, Borgwardt S, et al. Prevention of Psychosis: Advances in Detection, Prognosis, and Intervention. JAMA psychiatry. 2020;77:755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32159746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGorry PD, Hartmann JA, Spooner R, Nelson B. Beyond the &#x201c;at risk mental state&#x201d; concept: transitioning to transdiagnostic psychiatry. World psychiatry : Off J World Psychiatr Assoc (WPA). 2018;17:133&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5980504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29856558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knapp M, McDaid D, Parsonage M Mental health promotion and mental illness prevention: the economic case. London, UK: Department of Health; 2011 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDaid D, Park AL, Wahlbeck K. The Economic Case for the Prevention of Mental Illness. Annual Rev Public Health. 2019;40:373&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30601725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCrone P. Debate: Where to next for universal school-based mental health interventions? Universal versus targeted school-based mental health interventions: a health economic perspective. Child Adolesc Ment Health. 2025;30:99&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11754700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39654425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlow DH, Ellard KK, Fairholme CP Unified protocol for transdiagnostic treatment of emotional disorders. Press OU, editor2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7986982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33762811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P. Examining the effects of prevention programs on the incidence of new cases of mental disorders: the lack of statistical power. Am J Psychiatry. 2003;160:1385&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann JA, McGorry PD, Destree L, Amminger GP, Chanen AM, Davey CG, et al. Pluripotential Risk and Clinical Staging: Theoretical Considerations and Preliminary Data From a Transdiagnostic Risk Identification Approach. Front Psychiatry. 2020;11:553578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7819892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33488413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt DJ, Choi KW, DeTore NR, Balogun O Transdiagnostic prevention in youth mental health, Part I: rationale, shared risk factors. Neuropsychopharmacology Reviews. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12618674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41039099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy KP, Alexander JL, Garakani A, Gross LS, Mintz DL, Parikh T, et al. Vitamin B(12) Supplementation in Psychiatric Practice. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2024;26:265&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38696105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guu TW, Mischoulon D, Sarris J, Hibbeln J, McNamara RK, Hamazaki K, et al. International Society for Nutritional Psychiatry Research Practice Guidelines for Omega-3 Fatty Acids in the Treatment of Major Depressive Disorder. Psychother Psychosom. 2019;88:263&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31480057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shenk CE, Keeshin B, Bensman HE, Olson AE, Allen B. Behavioral and pharmacological interventions for the prevention and treatment of psychiatric disorders with children exposed to maltreatment. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 2021;211:173298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8643336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34774585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon RS Jr. An operational classification of disease prevention. Public Health Rep. 1983;98:107&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1424415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6856733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott J, Iorfino F, Capon W, Crouse J, Nelson B, Chanen AM, et al. Staging 2.0: refining transdiagnostic clinical staging frameworks to enhance reliability and utility for youth mental health. Lancet Psychiatry. 2024;11:461&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38643773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Berglund P, Demler O, Jin R, Merikangas KR, Walters EE. Lifetime prevalence and age-of-onset distributions of DSM-IV disorders in the National Comorbidity Survey Replication. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005;62:593&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15939837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacka FN, Reavley NJ, Jorm AF, Toumbourou JW, Lewis AJ, Berk M. Prevention of common mental disorders: What can we learn from those who have gone before and where do we go next?. Australian NZ J Psychiatry. 2013;47:920&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose GA, Khaw KT, Marmot M Rose&#x2019;s strategy of preventive medicine: the complete original text. USA: Oxford University Press; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Avenevoli S, Costello EJ, Georgiades K, Green JG, Gruber MJ, et al. Prevalence, persistence, and sociodemographic correlates of DSM-IV disorders in the National Comorbidity Survey Replication Adolescent Supplement. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2012;69:372&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22147808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caspi A, Houts RM, Ambler A, Danese A, Elliott ML, Hariri A, et al. Longitudinal Assessment of Mental Health Disorders and Comorbidities Across 4 Decades Among Participants in the Dunedin Birth Cohort Study. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e203221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7175086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32315069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stallard P, Skryabina E, Taylor G, Phillips R, Daniels H, Anderson R, et al. Classroom-based cognitive behaviour therapy (FRIENDS): a cluster randomised controlled trial to Prevent Anxiety in Children through Education in Schools (PACES). Lancet Psychiatry. 2014;1:185&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26360730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasserman D, Hoven CW, Wasserman C, Wall M, Eisenberg R, Hadlaczky G, et al. School-based suicide prevention programmes: the SEYLE cluster-randomised, controlled trial. Lancet. 2015;385:1536&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25579833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraag G, Van Breukelen GJ, Kok G, Hosman C. Learn Young, Learn Fair&#x2019;, a stress management program for fifth and sixth graders: longitudinal results from an experimental study. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2009;50:1185&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19490308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraguas D, D&#xed;az-Caneja CM, Ayora M, Dur&#xe1;n-Cutilla M, Abreg&#xfa;-Crespo R, Ezquiaga-Bravo I, et al. Assessment of School Anti-Bullying Interventions: A Meta-analysis of Randomized Clinical Trials. JAMA Pediatr. 2021;175:44&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7607493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33136156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P. Indirect Prevention and Treatment of Depression: An Emerging Paradigm?. Clin Psychol Eur. 2021;3:e6847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9667226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36398290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenwick-Smith A, Dahlberg EE, Thompson SC. Systematic review of resilience-enhancing, universal, primary school-based mental health promotion programs. BMC Psychol. 2018;6:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6034212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29976252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Embry DD. The Good Behavior Game: a best practice candidate as a universal behavioral vaccine. Clin Child Fam Psychol Rev. 2002;5:273&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12495270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joslyn PR, Donaldson JM, Austin JL, Vollmer TR. The Good Behavior Game: A brief review. J Appl Behav Anal. 2019;52:811&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31044435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrish HH, Saunders M, Wolf MM. Good behavior game: effects of individual contingencies for group consequences on disruptive behavior in a classroom. J Appl Behav Anal. 1969;2:119&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1311049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16795208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellam SG, Rebok GW, Ialongo N, Mayer LS. The course and malleability of aggressive behavior from early first grade into middle school: results of a developmental epidemiologically-based preventive trial. J Child Psychol Psychiatry. 1994;35:259&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8188798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellam SG, Brown CH, Poduska JM, Ialongo NS, Wang W, Toyinbo P, et al. Effects of a universal classroom behavior management program in first and second grades on young adult behavioral, psychiatric, and social outcomes. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2008;95:S5&#x2013;s28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2512256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18343607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maynard B, Solis M, Miller V, Brendel K. Mindfulness-based interventions for improving cognition, academic achievement, behavior, and socioemotional functioning of primary and secondary school students. Campbell Syst Rev. 2017;13:1&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuyken W, Ball S, Crane C, Ganguli P, Jones B, Montero-Marin J, et al. Effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of universal school-based mindfulness training compared with normal school provision in reducing risk of mental health problems and promoting well-being in adolescence: the MYRIAD cluster randomised controlled trial. Evid Based Ment Health. 2022;25:99&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35820992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montero-Marin J, Allwood M, Ball S, Crane C, De Wilde K, Hinze V, et al. School-based mindfulness training in early adolescence: what works, for whom and how in the MYRIAD trial?. Evid Based Ment Health. 2022;25:117&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9340034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35820993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guzman-Holst C, Streckfuss Davis R, Andrews JL, Foulkes L Scoping review: potential harm from school-based group mental health interventions. Child Adolesc Ment Health. 2025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12351197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40101758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teesson M, Newton NC, Slade T, Chapman C, Birrell L, Mewton L, et al. Combined prevention for substance use, depression, and anxiety in adolescence: a cluster-randomised controlled trial of a digital online intervention. Lancet Digit Health. 2020;2:e74&#x2013;e84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teesson M, Birrell L, Slade T, Mewton LR, Olsen N, Hides L, et al. Effectiveness of a universal, school-based, online programme for the prevention of anxiety, depression, and substance misuse among adolescents in Australia: 72-month outcomes from a cluster-randomised controlled trial. Lancet Digit Health. 2024;6:e334&#x2013;e44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38670742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JL, Birrell L, Chapman C, Teesson M, Newton N, Allsop S, et al. Evaluating the effectiveness of a universal eHealth school-based prevention programme for depression and anxiety, and the moderating role of friendship network characteristics. Psychol Med. 2023;53:5042&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35838377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duong MT, Bruns EJ, Lee K, Cox S, Coifman J, Mayworm A, et al. Rates of Mental Health Service Utilization by Children and Adolescents in Schools and Other Common Service Settings: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Adm Policy Ment Health. 2021;48:420&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32940884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates SM, Anderson-Butcher D, Wolfe T, Ondrus C, Delaney S, Marschhausen J, et al. Grow Your Own School Mental Health Specialists: A Policy Pilot to Address Behavioral Health Workforce Shortages in Schools. Behav Sci (Basel). 2024;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11428268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39336028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner-Seidler A, Spanos S, Calear AL, Perry Y, Torok M, O&#x2019;Dea B, et al. School-based depression and anxiety prevention programs: An updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Psychol Rev. 2021;89:102079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34571372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shinde S, Weiss HA, Varghese B, Khandeparkar P, Pereira B, Sharma A, et al. Promoting school climate and health outcomes with the SEHER multi-component secondary school intervention in Bihar, India: a cluster-randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2018;392:2465&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30473365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P. Universal prevention of depression at schools: dead end or challenging crossroad?. Evid Based Ment Health. 2022;25:96&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10231555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35820988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birrell L, Grummitt L, Smout S, Maulik P, Teesson M, Newton N. Debate: Where to next for universal school-based mental health interventions?. Child Adolesc Ment Health. 2025;30:92&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11754696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39789719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews JL, Foulkes L. Debate: Where to next for universal school-based mental health interventions? Time to move towards more effective alternatives. Child Adolesc Ment Health. 2025;30:102&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11754712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39644171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coetzee B, Loades M. Debate: Where to next for universal school-based mental health interventions? Addressing the mental health crisis among young people in low- and middle-income countries. Child Adolesc Ment Health. 2025;30:105&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11754709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39644172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogaert L, Van der Gucht K, Kuppens P, Kock M, Schreuder MJ, Kuyken W, et al. The effect of universal school-based mindfulness on anhedonia and emotional distress and its underlying mechanisms: A cluster randomised controlled trial via experience sampling in secondary schools. Behav Res Ther. 2023;169:104405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10938062</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37797436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P, Wang Z, Qiu S. Universal, school-based transdiagnostic interventions to promote mental health and emotional wellbeing: a systematic review. Child Adolesc Psychiatry Ment Health. 2024;18:47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11007989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38600562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradshaw M, Gericke H, Coetzee BJ, Stallard P, Human S, Loades M. Universal school-based mental health programmes in low- and middle-income countries: A systematic review and narrative synthesis. Prev Med. 2021;143:106317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33159922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodeur S, Oliver D, Ahmed MS, Radua J, Venables J, Gao Y, et al. Why we need to pursue both universal and targeted prevention to reduce the incidence of affective and psychotic disorders: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2024;161:105669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11480204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38599355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie K, Williams C. Universal, school-based interventions to promote mental and emotional well-being: what is being done in the UK and does it work? A systematic review. BMJ Open. 2018;8:e022560.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6129100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30196267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P. Preventing the Onset of Depressive Disorders: State of the Art and Future Directions. Current Directions Psychological Sci. 2024;34:51&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnstone KM, Kemps E, Chen J. A Meta-Analysis of Universal School-Based Prevention Programs for Anxiety and Depression in Children. Clin Child Fam Psychol Rev. 2018;21:466&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30105480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salazar de Pablo G, De Micheli A, Solmi M, Oliver D, Catalan A, Verdino V, et al. Universal and Selective Interventions to Prevent Poor Mental Health Outcomes in Young People: Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Harv Rev Psychiatry. 2021;29:196&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33979106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown J, James K, Lisk S, Shearer J, Byford S, Stallard P, et al. Clinical effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of a brief accessible cognitive behavioural therapy programme for stress in school-aged adolescents (BESST): a cluster randomised controlled trial in the UK. Lancet Psychiatry. 2024;11:504&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38759665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran TD, Nguyen H, Shochet I, Nguyen N, La N, Wurfl A, et al. School-based universal mental health promotion intervention for adolescents in Vietnam: Two-arm, parallel, controlled trial. Glob Ment Health (Camb. 2023;10:e69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10643236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38024797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fusar-Poli P, Correll CU, Arango C, Berk M, Patel V, Ioannidis JPA. Preventive psychiatry: a blueprint for improving the mental health of young people. World psychiatry : Off J World Psychiatr Assoc (WPA). 2021;20:200&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8129854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34002494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasic D, Hajek T, Alda M, Uher R. Risk of mental illness in offspring of parents with schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, and major depressive disorder: a meta-analysis of family high-risk studies. Schizophr Bull. 2014;40:28&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3885302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23960245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Sprang ED, Maciejewski DF, Milaneschi Y, Elzinga BM, Beekman ATF, Hartman CA, et al. Familial risk for depressive and anxiety disorders: associations with genetic, clinical, and psychosocial vulnerabilities. Psychol Med. 2022;52:696&#x2013;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32624018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence PJ, Murayama K, Creswell C. Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis: Anxiety and Depressive Disorders in Offspring of Parents With Anxiety Disorders. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2019;58:46&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30577938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay MT, Cannon M, Chambers D, Conroy RM, Coughlan H, Dodd P, et al. Childhood trauma and adult mental disorder: A systematic review and meta-analysis of longitudinal cohort studies. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2021;143:189&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33315268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xf6;ning S, Kumpfer K, Kruse K, Sack PM, Schaunig-Busch I, Ruths S, et al. Selective prevention programs for children from substance-affected families: a comprehensive systematic review. Subst Abus Treat Prev Policy. 2012;7:23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3490747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22691221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dozier M, Peloso E, Lindhiem O, Gordon MK, Manni M, Sepulveda S. Developing evidence-based interventions for foster children: An example of a randomized clinical trial with infants and toddlers. Journal Soc Issues. 2006;62:765&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grube WA, Liming KW. ATTACHMENT AND BIOBEHAVIORAL CATCH-UP: A SYSTEMATIC REVIEW. Infant Ment Health J. 2018;39:656&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30365173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Funderburk B, Eyberg S Parent-Child Interaction Therapy. In: Norcross J, VandenBos G, Freedheim D, editors. History of Psychotherapy: Continuity and Change. Washington, DC American Psychological Association; 2011. p. 415&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lieneman CC, Brabson LA, Highlander A, Wallace NM, McNeil CB. Parent-Child Interaction Therapy: current perspectives. Psychol Res Behav Manag. 2017;10:239&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5530857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28790873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos LE, Kaminski L, Stienwandt S, Hunter S, Giuliano R, Mota N, et al. The Building Regulation in Dual-Generations Program (BRIDGE): A Mixed-Methods Feasibility Pilot of a Parenting Program for Depressed Mothers of Preschoolers, Matched with Dialectical Behavior Therapy Skills. Child Psychiatry Hum Dev. 2023;54:34&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8335713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34347227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke GN, Hornbrook M, Lynch F, Polen M, Gale J, Beardslee W, et al. A randomized trial of a group cognitive intervention for preventing depression in adolescent offspring of depressed parents. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2001;58:1127&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11735841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber J, Clarke GN, Weersing VR, Beardslee WR, Brent DA, Gladstone TRG, et al. Prevention of Depression in At-Risk Adolescents: A Randomized Controlled Trial. JAMA. 2009;301:2215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2737625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19491183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beardslee WR, Brent DA, Weersing VR, Clarke GN, Porta G, Hollon SD, et al. Prevention of depression in at-risk adolescents: longer-term effects. JAMA psychiatry. 2013;70:1161&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3978119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24005242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolko DJ, Iselin AM, Gully KJ. Evaluation of the sustainability and clinical outcome of Alternatives for Families: A Cognitive-Behavioral Therapy (AF-CBT) in a child protection center. Child Abus Negl. 2011;35:105&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3069689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21354619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolko DJ, Herschell AD, Baumann BL, Hart JA, Wisniewski SR. AF-CBT for Families Experiencing Physical Aggression or Abuse Served by the Mental Health or Child Welfare System: An Effectiveness Trial. Child Maltreat. 2018;23:319&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30009632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson KS, Watts S, Carswell K, Shehadeh MH, Jordans MJD, Bryant RA, et al. Improving access to evidence-based interventions for young adolescents: Early Adolescent Skills for Emotions (EASE). World psychiatry : Off J World Psychiatr Assoc (WPA). 2019;18:105&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6313693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30600639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reed RV, Fazel M, Jones L, Panter-Brick C, Stein A. Mental health of displaced and refugee children resettled in low-income and middle-income countries: risk and protective factors. Lancet. 2012;379:250&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21835460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fine SL, Malik A, Guimond MF, Nemiro A, Temu G, Likindikoki S, et al. Improving mental health in low-resource settings: A feasibility randomized controlled trial of a transdiagnostic psychological intervention among Burundian refugee adolescents and their caregivers. Behav Res Ther. 2021;145:103944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34392115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody GH, Murry VM, Gerrard M, Gibbons FX, Molgaard V, McNair L, et al. The Strong African American Families Program: translating research into prevention programming. Child Dev. 2004;75:900&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15144493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody GH, Murry VM, Gerrard M, Gibbons FX, McNair L, Brown AC, et al. The strong African American families program: prevention of youths&#x2019; high-risk behavior and a test of a model of change. J Fam Psychol. 2006;20:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16569084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody GH, Kogan SM, Chen YF, McBride Murry V. Long-term effects of the strong African American families program on youths&#x2019; conduct problems. J Adolesc Health. 2008;43:474&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2592558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18848676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brody GH, Murry VM, Kogan SM, Gerrard M, Gibbons FX, Molgaard V, et al. The Strong African American Families Program: a cluster-randomized prevention trial of long-term effects and a mediational model. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2006;74:356&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16649880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller GE, Brody GH, Yu T, Chen E. A family-oriented psychosocial intervention reduces inflammation in low-SES African American youth. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2014;111:11287&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4128159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25049403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaton WW, Badawi M, Melton B. Prodromes and precursors: epidemiologic data for primary prevention of disorders with slow onset. Am J Psychiatry. 1995;152:967&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7793466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlucci L, Saggino A, Balsamo M. On the efficacy of the unified protocol for transdiagnostic treatment of emotional disorders: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Psychol Rev. 2021;87:101999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34098412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barlow DH, Farchione TJ, Bullis JR, Gallagher MW, Murray-Latin H, Sauer-Zavala S, et al. The Unified Protocol for Transdiagnostic Treatment of Emotional Disorders Compared With Diagnosis-Specific Protocols for Anxiety Disorders: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA psychiatry. 2017;74:875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28768327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Escalera J, Valiente RM, Sand&#xed;n B, Ehrenreich-May J, Prieto A, Chorot P. The Unified Protocol for Transdiagnostic Treatment of Emotional Disorders in Adolescents (UP-A) Adapted as a School-Based Anxiety and Depression Prevention Program: An Initial Cluster Randomized Wait-List-Controlled Trial. Behav Ther. 2020;51:461&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32402261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pel&#xe1;ez T, L&#xf3;pez-Carrilero R, Espinosa V, Balsells S, Ochoa S, Osma J. Efficacy of the unified protocol for transdiagnostic treatment of comorbid emotional disorders in patients with ultra high risk for psychosis: Results of a randomized controlled trial. J Affect Disord. 2024;367:934&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39260577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinsen KD, Rasmussen LMP, Wentzel-Larsen T, Holen S, Sund AM, L&#xf8;vaas MES, et al. Prevention of anxiety and depression in school children: Effectiveness of the transdiagnostic EMOTION program. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2019;87:212&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30550301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman R, Meltzer H, Bailey V. The Strengths and Difficulties Questionnaire: a pilot study on the validity of the self-report version. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2003;15:173&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12745329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeppesen P, Wolf RT, Nielsen SM, Christensen R, Plessen KJ, Bilenberg N, et al. Effectiveness of Transdiagnostic Cognitive-Behavioral Psychotherapy Compared With Management as Usual for Youth With Common Mental Health Problems: A Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA psychiatry. 2021;78:250&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7758821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33355633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Bouhaddani S, Veling W, Schaefer B, Doreleijers T, van Domburgh L. Transdiagnostic school-based intervention for adolescents with early persistent psychiatric symptoms: An initial single-group effect study. Early Inter Psychiatry. 2019;13:1199&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30479043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorentzen V, Fagermo K, Handeg&#xe5;rd BH, Neumer SP, Skre I. Long-term effectiveness and trajectories of change after treatment with SMART, a transdiagnostic CBT for adolescents with emotional problems. BMC Psychol. 2022;10:167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9258229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35791020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard BE, Stevens AK, Sher KJ, Littlefield AK. Reexamining the Psychometric Properties of the Substance Use Risk Profile Scale. Assessment. 2020;27:454&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30600689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch SJ, Chapman C, Sunderland M, Slade T, Teesson M, Conrod PJ, et al. The 3-year effects of a personality-targeted prevention program on general and specific dimensions of psychopathology. Prev Med. 2023;173:107595.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37385412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musiat P, Conrod P, Treasure J, Tylee A, Williams C, Schmidt U. Targeted prevention of common mental health disorders in university students: randomised controlled trial of a transdiagnostic trait-focused web-based intervention. PLoS One. 2014;9:e93621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3988039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24736388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansar N, Nissen Lie HA, Zahl-Olsen R, Bertelsen TB, Elliott R, Stiegler JR. Efficacy of Emotion-Focused Parenting Programs for Children&#x2019;s Internalizing and Externalizing Symptoms: A Randomized Clinical Study. J Clin Child Adolesc Psychol. 2022;51:923&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35648636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burkett JP, Young LJ The behavioral, anatomical and pharmacological parallels between social attachment, love and addiction. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3469771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22885871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeTore NR, Luther L, Deng WY, Zimmerman JE, Leathem L, Burke A, et al. Efficacy of a transdiagnostic, prevention-focused program for at-risk young adults: A waitlist-controlled trial. Psychological Medicine. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9433469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35227342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeTore NR, Burke A, Nyer M, Holt DJ. A Brief Resilience-Enhancing Intervention and Loneliness in At-Risk Young Adults: A Secondary Analysis of a Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2024;7:e2354728.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10844993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38315488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mei C, van der Gaag M, Nelson B, Smit F, Yuen HP, Berger M, et al. Preventive interventions for individuals at ultra high risk for psychosis: An updated and extended meta-analysis. Clinical Psychol Rev. 2021;86:102005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33810885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varghese D, Scott J, Welham J, Bor W, Najman J, O&#x2019;Callaghan M, et al. Psychotic-Like Experiences in Major Depression and Anxiety Disorders: A Population-Based Survey in Young Adults. Schizophrenia Bull. 2011;37:389&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3044630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19687152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh H, Koyanagi A, Kelleher I, DeVylder J. Psychotic experiences and disability: Findings from the Collaborative Psychiatric Epidemiology Surveys. Schizophrenia Res. 2018;193:343&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5912340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28797526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yates K, L&#xe5;ng U, Cederl&#xf6;f M, Boland F, Taylor P, Cannon M, et al. Association of Psychotic Experiences With Subsequent Risk of Suicidal Ideation, Suicide Attempts, and Suicide Deaths: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Longitudinal Population Studies. JAMA psychiatry. 2019;76:180&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6439738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30484818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Destr&#xe9;e L, McGorry P, Chanen A, Ratheesh A, Davey C, Polari A, et al. Transdiagnostic risk identification: A validation study of the Clinical High At Risk Mental State (CHARMS) criteria. Psychiatry Res. 2024;333:115745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38271886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGorry PD, Mei C, Amminger GP, Yuen HP, Kerr M, Spark J, et al. A Sequential Adaptive Intervention Strategy Targeting Remission and Functional Recovery in Young People at Ultrahigh Risk of Psychosis: The Staged Treatment in Early Psychosis (STEP) Sequential Multiple Assignment Randomized Trial. JAMA psychiatry. 2023;80:875&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10308298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37378974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solmi M, Soardo L, Kaur S, Azis M, Cabras A, Censori M, et al. Meta-analytic prevalence of comorbid mental disorders in individuals at clinical high risk of psychosis: the case for transdiagnostic assessment. Mol Psychiatry. 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10611568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37296309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartmann JA, Nelson B, Spooner R, Paul Amminger G, Chanen A, Davey CG, et al. Broad clinical high-risk mental state (CHARMS): Methodology of a cohort study validating criteria for pluripotent risk. Early Inter Psychiatry. 2019;13:379&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28984077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iorfino F, Scott EM, Carpenter JS, Cross SP, Hermens DF, Killedar M, et al. Clinical Stage Transitions in Persons Aged 12 to 25 Years Presenting to Early Intervention Mental Health Services With Anxiety, Mood, and Psychotic Disorders. JAMA psychiatry. 2019;76:1167&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6714017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31461129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linehan MM Cognitive-behavioral treatment of borderline personality disorder: Guilford Press; 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glenn CR, Esposito EC, Porter AC, Robinson DJ. Evidence Base Update of Psychosocial Treatments for Self-Injurious Thoughts and Behaviors in Youth. J Clin Child Adolesc Psychol. 2019;48:357&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6534465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31046461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehlum L, T&#xf8;rmoen AJ, Ramberg M, Haga E, Diep LM, Laberg S, et al. Dialectical behavior therapy for adolescents with repeated suicidal and self-harming behavior: a randomized trial. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2014;53:1082&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25245352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehlum L, Ramberg M, T&#xf8;rmoen AJ, Haga E, Diep LM, Stanley BH, et al. Dialectical Behavior Therapy Compared With Enhanced Usual Care for Adolescents With Repeated Suicidal and Self-Harming Behavior: Outcomes Over a One-Year Follow-Up. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2016;55:295&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27015720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauss JA, Bhiku K, Burke A, Pimentel-Diaz Y, DeTore NR, Zapetis S, et al. Development of a transdiagnostic, resilience-focused intervention for at-risk adolescents. Journal Ment health (Abingdon, Engl). 2023;32:592&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10175511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36369940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt DJ, DeTore NR, Aideyan B, Utter L, Vinke L, Johnson DS, et al. Enhancing social functioning using multi-user, immersive virtual reality. Sci Rep. 2025;15:2790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11754853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39843493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alvarez-Jimenez M, Rice S, D&#x2019;Alfonso S, Leicester S, Bendall S, Pryor I, et al. A Novel Multimodal Digital Service (Moderated Online Social Therapy+) for Help-Seeking Young People Experiencing Mental Ill-Health: Pilot Evaluation Within a National Youth E-Mental Health Service. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22:e17155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32788151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zagni B, Van Ryzin MJ. Technology-supported cooperative learning as a universal mental health intervention in middle and high school. Br J Educ Psychol. 2024;94:792&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11305977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38479858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergin AD, Vallejos EP, Davies EB, Daley D, Ford T, Harold G, et al. Preventive digital mental health interventions for children and young people: a review of the design and reporting of research. NPJ Digit Med. 2020;3:133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7562906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33083568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Cuijpers P, Mu&#xf1;oz RF, Baumeister H. Prevention of Mental Health Disorders Using Internet- and Mobile-Based Interventions: A Narrative Review and Recommendations for Future Research. Front Psychiatry. 2017;8:116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5554359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisel KK, Zarski AC, Berger T, Krieger T, Schaub MP, Moser CT, et al. Efficacy and cost-effectiveness of guided and unguided internet- and mobile-based indicated transdiagnostic prevention of depression and anxiety (ICare Prevent): A three-armed randomized controlled trial in four European countries. Internet Inter. 2019;16:52&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6364519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30775265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarski AC, Weisel KK, Berger T, Krieger T, Schaub MP, Berking M, et al. Efficacy of an Internet- and Mobile-Based Intervention for Subclinical Anxiety and Depression (ICare Prevent) with Two Guidance Formats: Results from a Three-Armed Randomized Controlled Trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2024;93:155&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11151970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38688243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reininghaus U, Paetzold I, Rauschenberg C, Hirjak D, Banaschewski T, Meyer-Lindenberg A, et al. Effects of a Novel, Transdiagnostic Ecological Momentary Intervention for Prevention, and Early Intervention of Severe Mental Disorder in Youth (EMIcompass): Findings From an Exploratory Randomized Controlled Trial. Schizophr Bull. 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10154707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36738168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasil AR, Gillespie S, Shingleton R, Wilks CR, Weisz JR. Examining the Reach of Smartphone Apps for Depression and Anxiety. Am J Psychiatry. 2020;177:464&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32354266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Daffer A, Colt SF, Wasil AR, Lau N. Efficacy and Conflicts of Interest in Randomized Controlled Trials Evaluating Headspace and Calm Apps: Systematic Review. JMIR Ment Health. 2022;9:e40924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9533203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36125880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster AA, Zabel M, Schober M. Youth Crisis: The Current State and Future Directions. Psychiatr Clin North Am. 2024;47:595&#x2013;611.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39122348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGorry P, Gunasiri H, Mei C, Rice S, Gao CX. The youth mental health crisis: analysis and solutions. Front Psychiatry. 2024;15:1517533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11790661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39906686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weersing VR, Shamseddeen W, Garber J, Hollon SD, Clarke GN, Beardslee WR, et al. Prevention of Depression in At-Risk Adolescents: Predictors and Moderators of Acute Effects. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2016;55:219&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4783159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26903255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young KS, van der Velden AM, Craske MG, Pallesen KJ, Fjorback L, Roepstorff A, et al. The impact of mindfulness-based interventions on brain activity: A systematic review of functional magnetic resonance imaging studies. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2018;84:424&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28797556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marwood L, Wise T, Perkins AM, Cleare AJ. Meta-analyses of the neural mechanisms and predictors of response to psychotherapy in depression and anxiety. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2018;95:61&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6267850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30278195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schrammen E, Roesmann K, Rosenbaum D, Redlich R, Harenbrock J, Dannlowski U, et al. Functional neural changes associated with psychotherapy in anxiety disorders - A meta-analysis of longitudinal fMRI studies. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2022;142:104895.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36179918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li H, Wei D, Browning M, Du X, Zhang Q, Qiu J. Attentional bias modification (ABM) training induces spontaneous brain activity changes in young women with subthreshold depression: a randomized controlled trial. Psychol Med. 2016;46:909&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26554304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pic&#xf3;-P&#xe9;rez M, Fullana MA, Albajes-Eizagirre A, Vega D, Marco-Pallar&#xe9;s J, Vilar A, et al. Neural predictors of cognitive-behavior therapy outcome in anxiety-related disorders: a meta-analysis of task-based fMRI studies. Psychol Med. 2023;53:3387&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35916600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodkind M, Eickhoff SB, Oathes DJ, Jiang Y, Chang A, Jones-Hagata LB, et al. Identification of a common neurobiological substrate for mental illness. JAMA psychiatry. 2015;72:305&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4791058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25651064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McTeague LM, Huemer J, Carreon DM, Jiang Y, Eickhoff SB, Etkin A. Identification of Common Neural Circuit Disruptions in Cognitive Control Across Psychiatric Disorders. Am J Psychiatry. 2017;174:676&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5543416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28320224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Wolf DH, Ciric R, Kable JW, Moore TM, Vandekar SN, et al. Common Dimensional Reward Deficits Across Mood and Psychotic Disorders: A Connectome-Wide Association Study. Am J Psychiatry. 2017;174:657&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5495611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28135847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insel TR, Gogtay N. National Institute of Mental Health clinical trials: new opportunities, new expectations. JAMA psychiatry. 2014;71:745&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24806613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahrig H, Vago DR, Passarelli MA, Auten A, Lynn NA, Brown KW. Meta-analytic evidence that mindfulness training alters resting state default mode network connectivity. Sci Rep. 2022;12:12260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9293892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35851275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezer I, Pizzagalli DA, Sacchet MD. Resting-state fMRI functional connectivity and mindfulness in clinical and non-clinical contexts: A review and synthesis. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2022;135:104583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9083081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35202647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochsner KN, Gross JJ. The cognitive control of emotion. Trends Cogn Sci. 2005;9:242&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15866151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Godsil BP, Kiss JP, Spedding M, Jay TM. The hippocampal-prefrontal pathway: the weak link in psychiatric disorders?. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2013;23:1165&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23332457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baltruschat S, C&#xe1;ndido A, Maldonado A, Verdejo-Lucas C, Catena-Verdejo E, Catena A. There Is More to Mindfulness Than Emotion Regulation: A Study on Brain Structural Networks. Front Psychol. 2021;12:659403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8046916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33868133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morawetz C, Basten U. Neural underpinnings of individual differences in emotion regulation: A systematic review. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2024;162:105727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38759742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt DJ, Sussman R, Johnson D, Vinke L, Berman T, Zimmerman J, et al. Candidate targets for resilience training to reduce transdiagnostic risk for mental illness. Schizophr Bull. In press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40570139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, van Straten A, Smit F, Mihalopoulos C, Beekman A. Preventing the onset of depressive disorders: a meta-analytic review of psychological interventions. Am J Psychiatry. 2008;165:1272&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18765483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zoonen K, Buntrock C, Ebert DD, Smit F, Reynolds CF, Beekman ATF, et al. Preventing the onset of major depressive disorder: A meta-analytic review of psychological interventions. International J Epidemiol. 2014;43:318&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4023317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24760873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buntrock C, Ebert DD, Lehr D, Smit F, Riper H, Berking M, et al. Effect of a Web-Based Guided Self-help Intervention for Prevention of Major Depression in Adults With Subthreshold Depression: A Randomized Clinical Trial. Jama. 2016;315:1854&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27139058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuch FB, Vancampfort D, Firth J, Rosenbaum S, Ward PB, Silva ES, et al. Physical Activity and Incident Depression: A Meta-Analysis of Prospective Cohort Studies. Am J Psychiatry. 2018;175:631&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29690792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu MX, Turner D, Generaal E, Bos D, Ikram MK, Ikram MA, et al. Exercise interventions for the prevention of depression: a systematic review of meta-analyses. BMC Public Health. 2020;20:1255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32811468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guloksuz S, Pries LK, Ten Have M, de Graaf R, van Dorsselaer S, Klingenberg B, et al. Association of preceding psychosis risk states and non-psychotic mental disorders with incidence of clinical psychosis in the general population: a prospective study in the NEMESIS-2 cohort. World psychiatry : Off J World Psychiatr Assoc (WPA). 2020;19:199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7215054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32394548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng W, Addington J, Bearden CE, Cadenhead KS, Cornblatt BA, Mathalon DH, et al. Depression Predicts Global Functional Outcomes in Individuals at Clinical High Risk for Psychosis. Psychiatr Res Clin Pr. 2021;3:163&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9175802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36101655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koutsouleris N, Dwyer DB, Degenhardt F, Maj C, Urquijo-Castro MF, Sanfelici R, et al. Multimodal Machine Learning Workflows for Prediction of Psychosis in Patients With Clinical High-Risk Syndromes and Recent-Onset Depression. JAMA psychiatry. 2021;78:195&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7711566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33263726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nestsiarovich A, Reps JM, Matheny ME, DuVall SL, Lynch KE, Beaton M, et al. Predictors of diagnostic transition from major depressive disorder to bipolar disorder: a retrospective observational network study. Translational psychiatry. 2021;11:642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8688463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34930903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Addington J, Farris MS, Liu L, Cadenhead KS, Cannon TD, Cornblatt BA, et al. Depression: An actionable outcome for those at clinical high-risk. Schizophr Res. 2021;227:38&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7854482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33129638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doering S, Lichtenstein P, Gillberg C, Middeldorp CM, Bartels M, Kuja-Halkola R, et al. Anxiety at age 15 predicts psychiatric diagnoses and suicidal ideation in late adolescence and young adulthood: results from two longitudinal studies. BMC Psychiatry. 2019;19:363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6857289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31727035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley V, Young AH, Smith P. Child and adolescent anxiety as a risk factor for bipolar disorder: A systematic review of longitudinal studies. Bipolar Disord. 2023;25:278&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36949612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGorry PD, Goldstone SD, Parker AG, Rickwood DJ, Hickie IB, Mei C, et al. Cultures for mental health care of young people: an Australian blueprint for reform. Lancet Psychiatry. 2014;1:559&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah JL, Jones N, van Os J, McGorry PD, G&#xfc;l&#xf6;ks&#xfc;z S. Early intervention service systems for youth mental health: integrating pluripotentiality, clinical staging, and transdiagnostic lessons from early psychosis. Lancet Psychiatry. 2022;9:413&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35430004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jed. Jed Campus Impact Report. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catanzano M, Bennett SD, Tibber MS, Coughtrey AE, Liang H, Heyman I, et al. A Mental Health Drop-In Centre Offering Brief Transdiagnostic Psychological Assessment and Treatment in a Paediatric Hospital Setting: A One-Year Descriptive Study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8157880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34069973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rickwood D, Paraskakis M, Quin D, Hobbs N, Ryall V, Trethowan J, et al. Australia&#x2019;s innovation in youth mental health care: The headspace centre model. Early Inter Psychiatry. 2019;13:159&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6585724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30311423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sim WH, Jorm AF, Yap MBH The Role of Parent Engagement in a Web-Based Preventive Parenting Intervention for Child Mental Health in Predicting Parenting, Parent and Child Outcomes. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8871768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35206394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eugene D, Du X, Kim Y School climate and peer victimization among adolescents: A moderated mediation model of school connectedness and parental involvement. Children and Youth Services Review. 2021;121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox RB, Washburn IJ, Croff JM, Ringwalt CL. Parental School-Involvement and Substance Use? A Novel Family-Based Prevention Strategy for Latino Youth. Family Relat. 2021;70:1178&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoopes AJ, Brandzel SD, Luce C, Ferguson DM, Shulman L, Chavez B, et al. What Do Adolescents and Their Parents Need From Mental Health Integration in Primary Care? A Qualitative Exploration of Design Insights. J Pediatr Health Care. 2022;36:570&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10544844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35953380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolton B, Rooney RM, Hughes A, Hopkins A, Mancini VO. Systematic review and meta-analysis of the prevention of internalizing disorders in early childhood. Front Psychol. 2023;14:1061825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10752964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38155699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>