<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29664482</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2561-1011</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>1</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2017</Year><Season>Jul-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR cardio</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Cardio</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>My Hypertension Education and Reaching Target (MyHEART): Development and Dissemination of a Patient-Centered Website for Young Adults with Hypertension.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e5</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/cardio.8025</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Young adults (18 to 39 years old) with hypertension have the lowest rates of blood pressure control (defined as blood pressure less than 140/90 mmHg) compared to other adult age groups. Approximately 1 in 15 young adults have high blood pressure, increasing their risk of future heart attack, stroke, congestive heart failure, and/or chronic kidney disease. Many young adults reported having few resources to address their needs for health education on managing cardiovascular risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The goal of our study was to develop and disseminate a website with evidence-based, clinical information and health behavior resources tailored to young adults with hypertension.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In collaboration with young adults, health systems, and community stakeholders, the My Hypertension Education and Reaching Target (MyHEART) website was created. A toolkit was also developed for clinicians and healthcare systems to disseminate the website within their organizations. The dissemination plan was guided by the Dissemination Planning Tool of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Google Analytics data were acquired for January 1, 2017 to June 29, 2017. The MyHEART website received 1090 visits with 2130 page views; 18.99% (207/1090) were returning visitors. The majority (55.96%, 610/1090) approached the website through organic searches, 34.95% (381/1090) accessed the MyHEART website directly, and 5.96% (65/1090) approached through referrals from other sites. There was a spike in site visits around times of increased efforts to disseminate the website.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The successfully implemented MyHEART website and toolkit reflect collaborative input from community and healthcare stakeholders to provide evidence-based, portable hypertension education to a hard-to-reach population. The MyHEART website and toolkit can support healthcare providers' education and counseling with young adults and organizations' hypertension population health goals.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Heather M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>LaMantia</LastName><ForeName>Jamie N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Colleen M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population Health Sciences, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warner</LastName><ForeName>Ryan C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Counselor Education and Counseling Psychology, Marquette University, Milwaukee, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeller</LastName><ForeName>Laura M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Preventive Cardiology, University of Wisconsin Hospitals and Clinics, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haggart</LastName><ForeName>Ryan C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stonewall</LastName><ForeName>Keven</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lauver</LastName><ForeName>Diane R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL112907</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 RR025011</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR000427</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Cardio</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101718325</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2561-1011</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">World Wide Web</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient engagement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality improvement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">young adults</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29664482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS929308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5898439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/cardio.8025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">e5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nwankwo T, Yoon SS, Burt V, Gu Q. Hypertension among adults in the United States: National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, 2011-2012. NCHS Data Brief. 2013 Oct;(133):1&#x2013;8. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24171916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go AS, Bauman MA, Coleman King SM, Fonarow GC, Lawrence W, Williams KA, Sanchez E. An effective approach to high blood pressure control: a science advisory from the American Heart Association, the American College of Cardiology, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2014 Apr 01;63(12):1230&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2013.11.007. 
 
S0735-1097(13)06077-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2013.11.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24246165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services  . Healthy People 2020: Heart Disease and Stroke. Washington, DC: 2014.  [2017-04-30].  Increase the proportion of adults with hypertension whose blood pressure is under control
 https://www.healthypeople.gov/node/4555/data_details
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Writing Group Members. Mozaffarian D, Benjamin EJ, Go AS, Arnett DK, Blaha MJ, Cushman M, Das SR, de FS, Despr&#xe9;s JP, Fullerton HJ, Howard VJ, Huffman MD, Isasi CR, Jim&#xe9;nez MC, Judd SE, Kissela BM, Lichtman JH, Lisabeth LD, Liu S, Mackey RH, Magid DJ, McGuire DK, Mohler ER, Moy CS, Muntner P, Mussolino ME, Nasir K, Neumar RW, Nichol G, Palaniappan L, Pandey DK, Reeves MJ, Rodriguez CJ, Rosamond W, Sorlie PD, Stein J, Towfighi A, Turan TN, Virani SS, Woo D, Yeh RW, Turner MB, American Heart Association Statistics Committee. Stroke Statistics Subcommittee  Heart disease and stroke statistics-2016 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2016 Jan 26;133(4):e38&#x2013;360. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000350. 
 
CIR.0000000000000350</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26673558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egan BM, Zhao Y, Axon RN. US trends in prevalence, awareness, treatment, and control of hypertension, 1988-2008. JAMA. 2010 May 26;303(20):2043&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1001/jama.2010.650.303/20/2043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2010.650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20501926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen QC, Tabor JW, Entzel PP, Lau Y, Suchindran C, Hussey JM, Halpern CT, Harris KM, Whitsel EA. Discordance in national estimates of hypertension among young adults. Epidemiology. 2011 Jul;22(4):532&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1097/EDE.0b013e31821c79d2. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/EDE.0b013e31821c79d2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3109249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21610501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention  . High Blood Pressure Facts. Atlanta, GA: 2016.  [2017-09-10].  
 http://www.cdc.gov/bloodpressure/facts.htm
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker DW, Williams MV, Parker RM, Gazmararian JA, Nurss J. Development of a brief test to measure functional health literacy. Patient Educ Couns. 1999 Sep;38(1):33&#x2013;42.S0738-3991(98)00116-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14528569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grubbs V, Lin F, Vittinghoff E, Shlipak MG, Peralta CA, Bansal N, Jacobs DR, Siscovick DS, Lewis CE, Bibbins-Domingo K. Body mass index and early kidney function decline in young adults: a longitudinal analysis of the CARDIA (Coronary Artery Risk Development in Young Adults) study. Am J Kidney Dis. 2014 Apr;63(4):590&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2013.10.055. 
 
S0272-6386(13)01442-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2013.10.055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3969447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24295611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schold JD, Goldfarb DA, Buccini LD, Rodrigue JR, Mandelbrot DA, Heaphy ELG, Fatica RA, Poggio ED. Comorbidity burden and perioperative complications for living kidney donors in the United States. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol. 2013 Oct;8(10):1773&#x2013;82. doi: 10.2215/CJN.12311212. 
 
CJN.12311212</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.12311212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3789355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24071651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell AB, Cole JW, McArdle PF, Cheng Y, Ryan KA, Sparks MJ, Mitchell BD, Kittner SJ. Obesity increases risk of ischemic stroke in young adults. Stroke. 2015 Jun;46(6):1690&#x2013;2. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.008940. 
 
STROKEAHA.115.008940</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.008940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4458137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25944320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones DW, Peterson ED. Improving hypertension control rates: technology, people, or systems? JAMA. 2008 Jun 25;299(24):2896&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1001/jama.299.24.2896.299/24/2896</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.299.24.2896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kearney PM, Whelton M, Reynolds K, Muntner P, Whelton PK, He J. Global burden of hypertension: analysis of worldwide data. Lancet. 2005;365(9455):217&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(05)17741-1.S0140-6736(05)17741-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(05)17741-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15652604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautista LE. High blood pressure. In: Remington PL, Brownson RC, Wegner MV, editors. Chronic disease epidemiology and control. Washington, DC: American Public Health Association; 2010. pp. 335&#x2013;362.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Jones DM, Leip EP, Larson MG, D'Agostino RB, Beiser A, Wilson PW, Wolf PA, Levy D. Prediction of lifetime risk for cardiovascular disease by risk factor burden at 50 years of age. Circulation. 2006 Feb 14;113(6):791&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.105.548206. 
 
CIRCULATIONAHA.105.548206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.105.548206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brosius FC, Hostetter TH, Kelepouris E, Mitsnefes MM, Moe SM, Moore MA, Pennathur S, Smith GL, Wilson PWF, American Heart Association KidneyCardiovascular Disease Council. Councils on High Blood Pressure Research&#x201a; Cardiovascular Disease in the Young&#x201a;EpidemiologyPrevention. Quality of CareOutcomes Research Interdisciplinary Working Group. National Kidney Foundation  Detection of chronic kidney disease in patients with or at increased risk of cardiovascular disease: a science advisory from the American Heart Association Kidney and Cardiovascular Disease Council; the Councils on High Blood Pressure Research, Cardiovascular Disease in the Young, and Epidemiology and Prevention; and the Quality of Care and Outcomes Research Interdisciplinary Working Group: Developed in Collaboration With the National Kidney Foundation. Hypertension. 2006 Oct;48(4):751&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.177321. 
 
48/4/751</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.106.177321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16990648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kernan WN, Dearborn JL. Obesity increases stroke risk in young adults: opportunity for prevention. Stroke. 2015 Jun;46(6):1435&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.009347. 
 
STROKEAHA.115.009347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.009347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25944321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Jones DM, Hong Y, Labarthe D, Mozaffarian D, Appel LJ, Van HL, Greenlund K, Daniels S, Nichol G, Tomaselli GF, Arnett DK, Fonarow GC, Ho PM, Lauer MS, Masoudi FA, Robertson RM, Roger V, Schwamm LH, Sorlie P, Yancy CW, Rosamond WD, American Heart Association Strategic Planning Task ForceStatistics Committee  Defining and setting national goals for cardiovascular health promotion and disease reduction: the American Heart Association's strategic Impact Goal through 2020 and beyond. Circulation. 2010 Feb 02;121(4):586&#x2013;613. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.192703. 
 
CIRCULATIONAHA.109.192703</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.109.192703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paramore LC, Halpern MT, Lapuerta P, Hurley JS, Frost FJ, Fairchild DG, Bates D. Impact of poorly controlled hypertension on healthcare resource utilization and cost. Am J Manag Care. 2001 Apr;7(4):389&#x2013;98. 
 
612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11310193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chobanian AV, Bakris GL, Black HR, Cushman WC, Green LA, Izzo JL, Jones DW, Materson BJ, Oparil S, Wright JT, Roccella EJ, National Heart&#x201a; Lung&#x201a;Blood Institute Joint National Committee on Prevention&#x201a; Detection&#x201a; Evaluation&#x201a;Treatment of High Blood Pressure. National High Blood Pressure Education Program Coordinating Committee The Seventh Report of the Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure: the JNC 7 report. JAMA. 2003 May 21;289(19):2560&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1001/jama.289.19.2560.289.19.2560</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.289.19.2560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12748199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ES, Ajani UA, Croft JB, Critchley JA, Labarthe DR, Kottke TE, Giles WH, Capewell S. Explaining the decrease in U.S. deaths from coronary disease, 1980-2000. N Engl J Med. 2007 Jun 07;356(23):2388&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1056/NEJMsa053935.356/23/2388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMsa053935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17554120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yano Y, Stamler J, Garside DB, Daviglus ML, Franklin SS, Carnethon MR, Liu K, Greenland P, Lloyd-Jones DM. Isolated systolic hypertension in young and middle-aged adults and 31-year risk for cardiovascular mortality: the Chicago Heart Association Detection Project in Industry study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2015 Feb 03;65(4):327&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2014.10.060. 
 
S0735-1097(14)07093-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2014.10.060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4948287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25634830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James PA, Oparil S, Carter BL, Cushman WC, Dennison-Himmelfarb C, Handler J, Lackland DT, LeFevre ML, MacKenzie TD, Ogedegbe O, Smith SC, Svetkey LP, Taler SJ, Townsend RR, Wright JT, Narva AS, Ortiz E. 2014 evidence-based guideline for the management of high blood pressure in adults: report from the panel members appointed to the Eighth Joint National Committee (JNC 8) JAMA. 2014 Feb 05;311(5):507&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.284427.1791497</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.284427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24352797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber MA, Schiffrin EL, White WB, Mann S, Lindholm LH, Kenerson JG, Flack JM, Carter BL, Materson BJ, Ram CVS, Cohen DL, Cadet J, Jean-Charles RR, Taler S, Kountz D, Townsend RR, Chalmers J, Ramirez AJ, Bakris GL, Wang J, Schutte AE, Bisognano JD, Touyz RM, Sica D, Harrap SB. Clinical practice guidelines for the management of hypertension in the community: a statement by the American Society of Hypertension and the International Society of Hypertension. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2014 Jan;16(1):14&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1111/jch.12237. doi: 10.1111/jch.12237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jch.12237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24341872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland N, Segraves D, Nnadi VO, Belletti DA, Wogen J, Arcona S. Identifying barriers to hypertension care: implications for quality improvement initiatives. Dis Manag. 2008 Apr;11(2):71&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1089/dis.2008.1120007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/dis.2008.1120007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18426375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Urizar GG, Alehegn T, Stafford RS. Diet and physical activity counseling during ambulatory care visits in the United States. Prev Med. 2004 Oct;39(4):815&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2004.03.006.S0091743504001641</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2004.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15351551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin EJ, Blaha MJ, Chiuve SE, Cushman M, Das SR, Deo R, de Ferranti SD, Floyd J, Fornage M, Gillespie C, Isasi CR, Jim&#xe9;nez MC, Jordan LC, Judd SE, Lackland D, Lichtman JH, Lisabeth L, Liu S, Longenecker CT, Mackey RH, Matsushita K, Mozaffarian D, Mussolino ME, Nasir K, Neumar RW, Palaniappan L, Pandey DK, Thiagarajan RR, Reeves MJ, Ritchey M, Rodriguez CJ, Roth GA, Rosamond WD, Sasson C, Towfighi A, Tsao CW, Turner MB, Virani SS, Voeks JH, Willey JZ, Wilkins JT, Wu JH, Alger HM, Wong SS, Muntner P, American Heart Association Statistics CommitteeStroke Statistics Subcommittee  Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics-2017 Update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2017 Mar 07;135(10):e146&#x2013;e603. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000485. 
 
CIR.0000000000000485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5408160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Olson AG, LaMantia JN, Kind AJH, Pandhi N, Mendon&#xe7;a EA, Craven M, Smith MA. Documented lifestyle education among young adults with incident hypertension. J Gen Intern Med. 2015 May;30(5):556&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1007/s11606-014-3059-7. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-014-3059-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4395591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25373831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Thorpe CT, Bartels CM, Schumacher JR, Palta M, Pandhi N, Sheehy AM, Smith MA. Undiagnosed hypertension among young adults with regular primary care use. J Hypertens. 2014 Jan;32(1):65&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1097/HJH.0000000000000008. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000000008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3868024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Thorpe CT, Bartels CM, Schumacher JR, Palta M, Pandhi N, Sheehy AM, Smith MA. Antihypertensive medication initiation among young adults with regular primary care use. J Gen Intern Med. 2014 May;29(5):723&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1007/s11606-014-2790-4. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-014-2790-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4000352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24493322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Warner RC, Bartels CM, LaMantia JN. &#x201c;They're younger&#x2026; it's harder.&#x201d; Primary providers' perspectives on hypertension management in young adults: a multicenter qualitative study. BMC Res Notes. 2017 Jan 03;10(1):9. doi: 10.1186/s13104-016-2332-8. 
 
10.1186/s13104-016-2332-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13104-016-2332-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5217565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Warner RC, LaMantia JN, Bowers BJ. &#x201c;I have to live like I'm old.&#x201d; Young adults' perspectives on managing hypertension: a multi-center qualitative study. BMC Fam Pract. 2016 Mar 11;17:31. doi: 10.1186/s12875-016-0428-9. 
 
10.1186/s12875-016-0428-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12875-016-0428-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4788815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26969619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saksena A. Computer-based education for patients with hypertension: a systematic review. Health Educ J. 2010 May 04;69(3):236&#x2013;245. doi: 10.1177/0017896910364889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0017896910364889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver DR, Ward SE, Heidrich SM, Keller ML, Bowers BJ, Brennan PF, Kirchhoff KT, Wells TJ. Patient-centered interventions. Res Nurs Health. 2002 Aug;25(4):246&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1002/nur.10044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nur.10044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12124719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wantland DJ, Portillo CJ, Holzemer WL, Slaughter R, McGhee EM. The effectiveness of Web-based vs. non-Web-based interventions: a meta-analysis of behavioral change outcomes. J Med Internet Res. 2004 Nov 10;6(4):e40. doi: 10.2196/jmir.6.4.e40. 
 
v6e40</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6.4.e40</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1550624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15631964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MyHEART. Madison, WI: University of Wisconsin Health Innovation Program; 2017.  
 http://myheartmychoice.org/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, LaMantia JN, Warner RC, Pandhi N, Bartels CM, Smith MA, Lauver DR. MyHEART: a non randomized feasibility study of a young adult hypertension intervention. J Hypertens Manag. 2016;2(2) 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5300088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28191544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephan G, Hoyt MJ, Storm DS, Shirima S, Matiko C, Matechi E. Development and promotion of a national website to improve dissemination of information related to the prevention of mother-to-child HIV transmission (PMTCT) in Tanzania. BMC Public Health. 2015 Oct 22;15:1077. doi: 10.1186/s12889-015-2422-x. 
 
10.1186/s12889-015-2422-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-015-2422-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4619088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26494170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong S, Kim J. Architectural criteria for website evaluation &#x2013; conceptual framework and empirical validation. Behav Inf Technol. 2004 Sep;23(5):337&#x2013;357. doi: 10.1080/01449290410001712753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01449290410001712753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiou W, Lin C, Perng C. A strategic framework for website evaluation based on a review of the literature from 1995&#x2013;2006. Inform Manage. 2010 Aug;47(5-6):282&#x2013;290. doi: 10.1016/j.im.2010.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.im.2010.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kincaid JP, Fishburne RP, Rogers RL, Chissom BS.  Naval Technical Training Command Research Branch Report 8-75. Millington, TN: Naval Air Station Memphis; 1975. Feb,  [2017-09-13].  Derivation of new readability formulas (Automated Readability Index, Fog Count and Flesch Reading Ease Formula) for Navy enlisted personnel
 http://www.dtic.mil/dtic/tr/fulltext/u2/a006655.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter D, Nieva V, Albaghal T, Sorra J.  Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality. Rockville, MD: 2005.  [2017-09-13].  Advances in patient safety: from research to implementation volumes 1-4
 http://www.ahrq.gov/professionals/quality-patient-safety/patient-safety-resources/resources/advances-in-patient-safety/index.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson H, LaMantia J.  HIPxChange. Madison, WI: University of Wisconsin Health Innovation Program; 2016.  MyHEART: information &amp; resources for young adults with hypertension
 https://www.hipxchange.org/MyHEART
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HIPxChange. Madison, WI: University of Wisconsin Health Innovation Program; 2016.  
 https://www.hipxchange.org/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berwick DM. Improving patient care. My right knee. Ann Intern Med. 2005 Jan 18;142(2):121&#x2013;5.142/2/121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15657160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert Wood Johnson Foundation  . Quality Field Notes: Public Reporting. Robert Wood Johnson Foundation; 2015. May,  [2017-09-13].  What we're learning: how to report on the quality of physician practices
 http://www.rwjf.org/content/dam/farm/reports/issue_briefs/2015/rwjf419545
.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>