<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">16727614</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2012</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0093-691X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>1994</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Theriogenology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Theriogenology</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Superovulatory response of ovarian follicles of Wave 1 versus Wave 2 in heifers.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1103</StartPage><EndPage>1113</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1103-13</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Experiments were designed to test the hypotheses that ovarian follicular response to superstimulatory treatment initiated during Wave 1 is equivalent to that of Wave 2, and recovery rate and quality of ova embryos derived from follicles of Wave 1 are equivalent to those derived from follicles of Wave 2. In a preliminary experiment (Experiment 1), heifers were given Folltropin-V (20 mg NIH-FSH-P1, im, bid for 5 d) beginning the day after emergence of the first (n=10) or second (n=10) follicular wave of the estrous cycle, equivalent to approximately Day 1 and Day 10, respectively (Day 0=ovulation). Luteolysis was induced with cloprostenol (500 mug im, bid) on the fourth day of treatment. Fewer (P&lt;0.05) ovulations per heifer were induced in the Wave 1 group than in the Wave 2 group (4.6+/-1.0 vs 9.1+/-1.3). However, the interval from wave emergence to initiation of treatment was found, in retrospect, to have been longer (P&lt;0.05) in the Wave 1 group, i.e., treatment was initiated relatively later with respect to wave emergence. Experiment 2 was designed to correct this disparity and to initiate the same treatment protocol on the day of wave emergence rather than the day after (n=21 per Wave group). There was no difference between Wave 1 and Wave 2 groups in the interval from wave emergence to initiation of treatment (0.4+/-0.1 d), the number of ovulations detected by ultrasonography (6.6+/-1.0 vs 8.2+/-1.7), the number of CL detected at slaughter (6.5+/-0.9 vs 8.1+/-1.8), the total number of ova embryos recovered (5.2+/-0.7 vs 5.1+/-0.8), or the number of fertilized embryos collected (2.8+/-0.6 vs 3.0+/-0.6). In addition, there was no difference between groups in the proportion of heifers that ovulated in either experiment; collectively, luteolysis and ovulation was induced in 58 of 60 heifers. The results supported the general hypothesis that follicles and oocytes of the first and second follicular waves are equivalent in the response to superstimulatory treatment. Regardless of which follicular wave, initiation of treatment near the time of wave emergence appears critical for maximal superovulatory response. Because of the consistency in the time of emergence of Wave 1 (day of ovulation) and equivalence in superovulatory response, use of Wave 1 rather than subsequent follicular waves may be more convenient and time-sparing in superovulation programs; the day of estrus (day before ovulation) may be used as a consistent point of reference for the start of treatment.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adams</LastName><ForeName>G P</ForeName><Initials>GP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Anatomy Saskatoon, Saskatchewan, Canada S7N 0W0.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nasser</LastName><ForeName>L F</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bo</LastName><ForeName>G A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garcia</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Campo</LastName><ForeName>M R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mapletoft</LastName><ForeName>R J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Theriogenology</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0421510</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0093-691X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>1994</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>1994</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>1994</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>1994</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>1994</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>1994</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>1994</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16727614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0093-691x(94)90858-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">0093-691X(94)90858-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>