<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32390591</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1929-0748</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR research protocols</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Res Protoc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Smartphone App-Based Mindfulness Intervention for Cancer Survivors: Protocol for a Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e15178</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e15178</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e15178</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/15178</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cancer patients transitioning to survivorship after completing cancer treatments need psychosocial interventions to manage stressors such as anxiety, depression, and fear of cancer recurrence. Mindfulness-based interventions (MBIs) are effective for treating these symptoms; however, cancer survivors are often unable to participate in face-to-face interventions because of difficulties such as work and family commitments, treatment-related side-effects, scheduling conflicts, and geography. Smartphone app-based MBIs are an innovative way to deliver psychosocial cancer care and can overcome several such difficulties, since patients can participate at their own convenience.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The SEAMLESS (Smartphone App-Based Mindfulness Intervention for Cancer Survivors) study aims to evaluate the efficacy of a tailored app-based mindfulness intervention for cancer survivors (the Am Mindfulness-Based Cancer Survivorship-MBCS-Journey) for treating (1) symptoms of stress (primary outcome), as well as (2) fear of cancer recurrence, anxiety, depression, fatigue, and overall physical functioning (secondary outcomes). This is the first Canadian efficacy trial of a tailored mindfulness app intervention in cancer survivors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a randomized waitlist-controlled trial, which will evaluate the effectiveness of Am MBCS for impacting the primary and secondary outcomes in cancer survivors who have completed all their cancer treatments. Outcomes will be assessed using web-based surveys with validated psychometric instruments at (1) baseline, (2) mid-intervention (2 weeks later), (3) immediately postintervention (4 weeks), (4) 3 months postbaseline, (5) 6 months postbaseline, and (6) 12 months postbaseline. The waitlist group will complete all assessments and will cross over to the intervention condition after the 3-month assessment. In addition, data will be obtained by the smartphone app itself, which includes users' engagement with the app-based intervention, their emotional state (eg, angry and elated) from a user-inputted digital emotion-mapping board, and psychobiometric data using photoplethysmography technology.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The study received ethics approval in September 2018 and recruitment commenced in January 2019. Participants are being recruited through a provincial cancer registry, and the majority of participants currently enrolled are breast (44/83, 53%) or colorectal (17/83, 20%) cancer survivors, although some survivors of other cancer are also present. Data collection for analysis of the primary outcome time-point will be complete by September 2019, and the follow-up data will be collected and analyzed by September 2020. Data will be analyzed to determine group differences using linear mixed modelling statistical techniques.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Cancer care providers are uncertain about the efficacy of app-based mindfulness interventions for patients, which are available in great supply in today's digital world. This study will provide rigorously evaluated efficacy data for an app-based mindfulness intervention for cancer survivors, which if helpful, could be made available for psychosocial care at cancer centers worldwide.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov NCT03484000; https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03484000.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERNATIONAL REGISTERED REPORT IDENTIFIER (IRRID)" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">DERR1-10.2196/15178.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Utkarsh B Subnis, Norman AS Farb, Katherine-Ann Laura Piedalue, Michael Speca, Sasha Lupichuk, Patricia A Tang, Peter Faris, Mark Thoburn, Bechara J Saab, Linda E Carlson. Originally published in JMIR Research Protocols (http://www.researchprotocols.org), 11.05.2020.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Subnis</LastName><ForeName>Utkarsh B</ForeName><Initials>UB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2313-9334</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Farb</LastName><ForeName>Norman As</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8407-2938</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Toronto Mississauga, Mississauga, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Piedalue</LastName><ForeName>Katherine-Ann Laura</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2106-5431</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Speca</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8929-6351</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lupichuk</LastName><ForeName>Sasha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9545-0802</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tang</LastName><ForeName>Patricia A</ForeName><Initials>PA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1497-8539</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Faris</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5208-817X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Thoburn</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3809-2724</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mobio Interactive, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Saab</LastName><ForeName>Bechara J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1673-129X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mobio Interactive, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Carlson</LastName><ForeName>Linda E</ForeName><Initials>LE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4411-2085</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT03484000</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Res Protoc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101599504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1929-0748</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mind-body therapies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mindfulness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psycho-oncology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: Two coinvestigators on this project, MT and BJS, are the cofounders of MI and are majority shareholders of the company at approximately 40% each. One coinvestigator, NASF, is an advisor for MI and holds &lt;1% of the company&#x2019;s stock. The remaining authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32390591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7248798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/15178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v9i5e15178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Easley J, Miedema B, Carroll JC, O'Brien MA, Manca DP, Grunfeld E. Patients' experiences with continuity of cancer care in Canada: Results from the CanIMPACT study. Can Fam Physician. 2016 Oct;62(10):821&#x2013;7.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5063773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27737982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Research Council. Institute of Medicine. Ganz PA, Hewitt M. From Cancer Patient to Cancer Survivor: Lost in Transition. Washington, DC: National Academies Press; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leach CR, Weaver KE, Aziz NM, Alfano CM, Bellizzi KM, Kent EE, Forsythe LP, Rowland JH. The complex health profile of long-term cancer survivors: prevalence and predictors of comorbid conditions. J Cancer Surviv. 2015 Jun;9(2):239&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1007/s11764-014-0403-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-014-0403-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25319681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward E, Sherman R, Henley S, Jemal A, Siegel D, Feuer E, Firth A, Kohler B, Scott S, Ma J, Anderson R, Benard V, Cronin K. Annual Report to the Nation on the Status of Cancer, featuring cancer in men and women age 20-49 years. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2019 Dec 1;111(12):1279&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1093/jnci/djz106.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/djz106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6910179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31145458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuthbert CA, Samawi HH, Hemmelgarn BR, Cheung WY. Effectiveness and components of self-management interventions in adult cancer survivors: a protocol for a systematic review and planned meta-analysis. Syst Rev. 2018 Dec 20;7(1):238. doi: 10.1186/s13643-018-0902-7.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13643-018-0902-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6300917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30572935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellison LF. Progress in net cancer survival in Canada over 20 years. Health Rep. 2018 Sep 19;29(9):10&#x2013;8.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30230521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall DL, Luberto CM, Philpotts LL, Song R, Park ER, Yeh GY. Mind-body interventions for fear of cancer recurrence: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychooncology. 2018 Nov;27(11):2546&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1002/pon.4757.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6488231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29744965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson LE. Mindfulness-based interventions for coping with cancer. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2016 Jun;1373(1):5&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1111/nyas.13029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nyas.13029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26963792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson L, Tamagawa R, Stephen J, Doll R, Faris P, Dirkse D, Speca M. Tailoring mind-body therapies to individual needs: patients' program preference and psychological traits as moderators of the effects of mindfulness-based cancer recovery and supportive-expressive therapy in distressed breast cancer survivors. J Natl Cancer Inst Monogr. 2014 Nov;2014(50):308&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1093/jncimonographs/lgu034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jncimonographs/lgu034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25749597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson LE, Doll R, Stephen J, Faris P, Tamagawa R, Drysdale E, Speca M. Randomized controlled trial of Mindfulness-based cancer recovery versus supportive expressive group therapy for distressed survivors of breast cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2013 Sep 1;31(25):3119&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2012.47.5210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2012.47.5210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23918953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lengacher CA, Reich RR, Ramesar S, Alinat CB, Moscoso M, Cousin L, Marino VR, Elias MN, Paterson CL, Pleasant ML, Rodriguez CS, Wang H, Kip KE, Meng H, Park JY. Feasibility of the mobile mindfulness-based stress reduction for breast cancer (mMBSR(BC)) program for symptom improvement among breast cancer survivors. Psychooncology. 2018 Feb;27(2):524&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1002/pon.4491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7771353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28665541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crandall A, Cheung A, Young A, Hooper AP. Theory-based predictors of mindfulness meditation mobile app usage: a survey and cohort study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019 Mar 22;7(3):e10794. doi: 10.2196/10794.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30900992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthew-Maich N, Harris L, Ploeg J, Markle-Reid M, Valaitis R, Ibrahim S, Gafni A, Isaacs S. Designing, implementing, and evaluating mobile health technologies for managing chronic conditions in older adults: a scoping review. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2016 Jun 9;4(2):e29. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.5127.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.5127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4919548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27282195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics Canada.  [2019-07-01].  The Internet and Digital Technology https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/pub/11-627-m/11-627-m2017032-eng.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leykin Y, Thekdi SM, Shumay DM, Mu&#xf1;oz RF, Riba M, Dunn LB. Internet interventions for improving psychological well-being in psycho-oncology: review and recommendations. Psychooncology. 2012 Sep;21(9):1016&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1002/pon.1993.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.1993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21608075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jongerius C, Russo S, Mazzocco K, Pravettoni G. Research-tested mobile apps for breast cancer care: systematic review. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019 Feb 11;7(2):e10930. doi: 10.2196/10930.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6388100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30741644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborn J, Ajakaiye A, Cooksley T, Subbe CP. Do mHealth applications improve clinical outcomes of patients with cancer? A critical appraisal of the peer-reviewed literature. Support Care Cancer. 2020 Mar;28(3):1469&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1007/s00520-019-04945-4.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-019-04945-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6989578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31273501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zernicke KA, Campbell TS, Speca M, McCabe-Ruff K, Flowers S, Carlson LE. A randomized wait-list controlled trial of feasibility and efficacy of an online mindfulness-based cancer recovery program: the eTherapy for cancer applying mindfulness trial. Psychosom Med. 2014 May;76(4):257&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1097/PSY.0000000000000053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PSY.0000000000000053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24804884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikolasek M, Witt CM, Barth J. Adherence to a mindfulness and relaxation self-care app for cancer patients: mixed-methods feasibility study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2018 Dec 6;6(12):e11271. doi: 10.2196/11271.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6302233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30522990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen K, Potter J. Participant engagement in a commercially available app-based mindfulness training intervention delivered to women diagnosed with breast cancer. iproc. 2018 Sep;4(2):e11907. doi: 10.2196/11907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen KD, Paniagua SM, Kazanis W, Jones S, Potter JS. Quality of life among women diagnosed with breast Cancer: A randomized waitlist controlled trial of commercially available mobile app-delivered mindfulness training. Psychooncology. 2018 Aug;27(8):2023&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1002/pon.4764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29766596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huberty J, Eckert R, Larkey L, Joeman L, Mesa R. Experiences of using a consumer-based mobile meditation app to improve fatigue in myeloproliferative patients: qualitative study. JMIR Cancer. 2019 Jul 22;5(2):e14292. doi: 10.2196/14292.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31333197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grewal N, Arya R, Malik R, Hasan Y, Golden D, McCall A. Implementing a tablet-guided mindfulness meditation intervention to reduce anxiety in women receiving radiotherapy for breast cancer. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2019 Sep;105(1):E588. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrobp.2019.06.1181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijrobp.2019.06.1181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noone C, Hogan MJ. A randomised active-controlled trial to examine the effects of an online mindfulness intervention on executive control, critical thinking and key thinking dispositions in a university student sample. BMC Psychol. 2018 Apr 5;6(1):13. doi: 10.1186/s40359-018-0226-3.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-018-0226-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5887193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29622047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puddicombe A. The Headspace Guide to Meditation and Mindfulness: How Mindfulness Can Change Your Life in Ten Minutes a Day. New York, NY: St. Martin's Griffin; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce NG, Bruce NG, Shapiro SL, Constantino MJ, Manber R. Psychotherapist mindfulness and the psychotherapy process. Psychotherapy (Chic) 2010 Mar;47(1):83&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1037/a0018842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0018842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22402003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan E, Martin SR, Seidman LC, Zeltzer LK, Cousineau TM, Payne LA, Trant M, Weiman M, Knoll M, Federman NC. A mobile-based mindfulness and social support program for adolescents and young adults with sarcoma: development and pilot testing. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019 Mar 18;7(3):e10921. doi: 10.2196/10921.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6441858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30882352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun Y, Zhang Y, Gwizdka J, Trace CB. A mobile-based mindfulness and social support program for adolescents and young adults with sarcoma: development and pilot testing. J Med Internet Res. 2019 May 2;21(5):e12522. doi: 10.2196/12522.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/12522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6521213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31045507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borah P, Xiao X. The importance of 'likes': the interplay of message framing, source, and social endorsement on credibility perceptions of health information on Facebook. J Health Commun. 2018;23(4):399&#x2013;411. doi: 10.1080/10810730.2018.1455770.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10810730.2018.1455770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29601271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan E, Zeltzer L, Federman N, Cousineau T, Payne L, Martin S, Seidman L, Weiman M, Knoll M, Burton J. A patient-centered approach to tailoring a mobile-based mindfulness and social support intervention for adolescents and young adults with cancer. iproc. 2017 Sep 22;3(1):e25. doi: 10.2196/iproc.8408.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/iproc.8408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobio Interactive.  [2019-11-21].  Team https://www.midigitaltherapeutics.com/team.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobio Interactive.  [2019-11-21].  R&amp;D https://www.midigitaltherapeutics.com/rd.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh KM, Saab BJ, Farb NA. Effects of a mindfulness meditation app on subjective well-being: active randomized controlled trial and experience sampling study. JMIR Ment Health. 2019 Jan 8;6(1):e10844. doi: 10.2196/10844.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6329416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30622094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costa MA, de Oliveira GS, Tatton-Ramos T, Manfro GG, Salum GA. Anxiety and stress-related disorders and mindfulness-based interventions: a systematic review and multilevel meta-analysis and meta-regression of multiple outcomes. Mindfulness. 2019;10(6):996&#x2013;1005. doi: 10.1007/s12671-018-1058-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12671-018-1058-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007 May;39(2):175&#x2013;91. doi: 10.3758/bf03193146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/bf03193146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kubo A, Kurtovich E, McGinnis M, Aghaee S, Altschuler A, Quesenberry C, Kolevska T, Avins AL. A randomized controlled trial of mHealth mindfulness intervention for cancer patients and informal cancer caregivers: a feasibility study within an integrated health care delivery system. Integr Cancer Ther. 2019;18:1534735419850634. doi: 10.1177/1534735419850634.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1534735419850634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31092044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)--a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009 Apr;42(2):377&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/j.jbi.2008.08.010.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbi.2008.08.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobio Interactive Inc.  [2019-07-01].   https://www.midigitaltherapeutics.com/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twilio - Communication APIs for SMS, Voice, Video and Authentication.  [2019-11-21].   https://www.twilio.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jason D, Audrey C, Brendan C, Robert A, Farnoud K, Xiao Yu W, David C, Alexander W. Photoplethysmographic Imaging via Spectrally Demultiplexed Erythema Fluctuation Analysis for Remote Heart Rate Monitoring. Proceedings of Multimodal Biomedical Imaging XI, Volume 9701; SPIE'16; February 13-14, 2016; San Francisco. 2016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1117/12.2213532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Jebrni A, Chwyl B, Wang X, Wong A, Saab B J. AI-enabled remote and objective quantification of stress at scale. Biomed Signal Process Control. 2020 doi: 10.1016/j.bspc.2020.101929. (forthcoming)(forthcoming)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bspc.2020.101929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson LE. Clinical Trials. 2019.  [2018-09-29].  The SEAMLESS Study: Smartphone App-based Mindfulness for Cancer Survivors https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03557762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G, CONSORT-EHEALTH Group  CONSORT-EHEALTH: improving and standardizing evaluation reports of Web-based and mobile health interventions. J Med Internet Res. 2011 Dec 31;13(4):e126. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1923.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22209829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutron I, Altman DG, Moher D, Schulz KF, Ravaud P, CONSORT NPT Group CONSORT statement for randomized trials of nonpharmacologic treatments: a 2017 update and a CONSORT extension for nonpharmacologic trial abstracts. Ann Intern Med. 2017 Jul 4;167(1):40&#x2013;7. doi: 10.7326/M17-0046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M17-0046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28630973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broderick J, DeWitt EM, Rothrock N, Crane P, Forrest CB. Advances in patient-reported outcomes: The NIH PROMIS(&#xae;) Measures. EGEMS (Wash DC) 2013;1(1):1015. doi: 10.13063/2327-9214.1015.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13063/2327-9214.1015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4371419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25848562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callahan CM, Unverzagt FW, Hui SL, Perkins AJ, Hendrie HC. Six-item screener to identify cognitive impairment among potential subjects for clinical research. Med Care. 2002 Sep;40(9):771&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1097/00005650-200209000-00007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005650-200209000-00007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12218768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson LE, Thomas BC. Development of the Calgary Symptoms of Stress Inventory (C-SOSI) Int J Behav Med. 2007;14(4):249&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1007/bf03003000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf03003000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18001241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simard S, Savard J. Fear of Cancer Recurrence Inventory: development and initial validation of a multidimensional measure of fear of cancer recurrence. Support Care Cancer. 2009 Mar;17(3):241&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1007/s00520-008-0444-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-008-0444-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18414902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson LE, Brown KW. Validation of the Mindful Attention Awareness Scale in a cancer population. J Psychosom Res. 2005 Jan;58(1):29&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2004.04.366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2004.04.366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15771867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trapnell PD, Campbell JD. Private self-consciousness and the five-factor model of personality: distinguishing rumination from reflection. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1999 Feb;76(2):284&#x2013;304. doi: 10.1037//0022-3514.76.2.284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0022-3514.76.2.284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10074710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes SC, Wilson KG, Gifford EV, Follette VM, Strosahl K. Experimental avoidance and behavioral disorders: a functional dimensional approach to diagnosis and treatment. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1996 Dec;64(6):1152&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1037//0022-006x.64.6.1152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0022-006x.64.6.1152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8991302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Riley W, Stone A, Rothrock N, Reeve B, Yount S, Amtmann D, Bode R, Buysse D, Choi S, Cook K, Devellis R, DeWalt D, Fries JF, Gershon R, Hahn EA, Lai J, Pilkonis P, Revicki D, Rose M, Weinfurt K, Hays R, PROMIS Cooperative Group  The Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) developed and tested its first wave of adult self-reported health outcome item banks: 2005-2008. J Clin Epidemiol. 2010 Nov;63(11):1179&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.011.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2010.04.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2965562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20685078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalet BD, Pilkonis PA, Yu L, Dodds N, Johnston KL, Yount S, Riley W, Cella D. Clinical validity of PROMIS Depression, Anxiety, and Anger across diverse clinical samples. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016 May;73:119&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2015.08.036.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2015.08.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4928679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26931289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Lai J, Jensen SE, Christodoulou C, Junghaenel DU, Reeve BB, Stone AA. PROMIS fatigue item bank had clinical validity across diverse chronic conditions. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016 May;73:128&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2015.08.037.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2015.08.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4902759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26939927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen RE, Potosky AL, Reeve BB, Hahn E, Cella D, Fries J, Smith AW, Keegan TH, Wu X, Paddock L, Moinpour CM. Validation of the PROMIS physical function measures in a diverse US population-based cohort of cancer patients. Qual Life Res. 2015 Oct;24(10):2333&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1007/s11136-015-0992-9.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-015-0992-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5079641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25935353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lengacher CA, Shelton MM, Reich RR, Barta MK, Johnson-Mallard V, Moscoso MS, Paterson C, Ramesar S, Budhrani P, Carranza I, Lucas J, Jacobsen PB, Goodman MJ, Kip KE. Mindfulness based stress reduction (MBSR(BC)) in breast cancer: evaluating fear of recurrence (FOR) as a mediator of psychological and physical symptoms in a randomized control trial (RCT) J Behav Med. 2014 Apr;37(2):185&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1007/s10865-012-9473-6.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10865-012-9473-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3627743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23184061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>