<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38458658</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2059-7029</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>ESMO open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>ESMO Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Pan-Asian adapted ESMO Clinical Practice Guidelines for the diagnosis, treatment and follow-up of patients with gastric cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>102226</StartPage><MedlinePgn>102226</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">102226</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.esmoop.2023.102226</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2059-7029(23)01467-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The European Society for Medical Oncology (ESMO) Clinical Practice Guidelines for the diagnosis, treatment and follow-up of patients with gastric cancer (GC), published in late 2022 and the updated ESMO Gastric Cancer Living Guideline published in July 2023, were adapted in August 2023, according to previously established standard methodology, to produce the Pan-Asian adapted (PAGA) ESMO consensus guidelines for the management of Asian patients with GC. The adapted guidelines presented in this manuscript represent the consensus opinions reached by a panel of Asian experts in the treatment of patients with GC representing the oncological societies of China (CSCO), Indonesia (ISHMO), India (ISMPO), Japan (JSMO), Korea (KSMO), Malaysia (MOS), the Philippines (PSMO), Singapore (SSO), Taiwan (TOS) and Thailand (TSCO), coordinated by ESMO and the Japanese Society of Medical Oncology (JSMO). The voting was based on scientific evidence and was independent of the current treatment practices, drug access restrictions and reimbursement decisions in the different Asian regions represented by the 10 oncological societies. The latter are discussed separately in the manuscript. The aim is to provide guidance for the optimisation and harmonisation of the management of patients with GC across the different regions of Asia, drawing on the evidence provided by both Western and Asian trials, whilst respecting the differences in screening practices, molecular profiling and age and stage at presentation. Attention is drawn to the disparity in the drug approvals and reimbursement strategies, between the different regions of Asia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shitara</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Gastrointestinal Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital East, Kashiwa, Japan. Electronic address: kshitara@east.ncc.go.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fleitas</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Hospital Cl&#xed;nico Universitario de Valencia, INCLIVA Biomedical Research Institute, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawakami</LastName><ForeName>H</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Curigliano</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istituto Europeo di Oncologia, IRCCS, Milan; Department of Oncology and Haemato-Oncology, University of Milano, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narita</LastName><ForeName>Y</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Aichi Cancer Center Hospital, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>F</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Sun Yat-sen University Cancer Center, Guangzhou, Mainland China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wardhani</LastName><ForeName>S O</ForeName><Initials>SO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine Division of Medical Hematology-Oncology, Brawijaya University, Dr. Saiful Anwar General Hospital Malang, East Java, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Basade</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Jaslok Hospital and Breach Candy Hospital, Mumbai, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rha</LastName><ForeName>S Y</ForeName><Initials>SY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Yonsei Cancer Center, Yonsei University Health System, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wan Zamaniah</LastName><ForeName>W I</ForeName><Initials>WI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Oncology Unit, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sacdalan</LastName><ForeName>D L</ForeName><Initials>DL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Department of Medicine, University of the Philippines, Manila, The Philippines.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ng</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of GI Oncology, National Cancer Centre Singapore, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeh</LastName><ForeName>K H</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, National Taiwan University Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan; Graduate Institute of Oncology, National Taiwan University College of Medicine, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sunpaweravong</LastName><ForeName>P</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Prince of Songkla University, Songkhla.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sirachainan</LastName><ForeName>E</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Department of Medicine, Faculty of Medicine Ramathibodi Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>M-H</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Taipei Veterans General Hospital, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yong</LastName><ForeName>W P</ForeName><Initials>WP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Haematology-Oncology, National University Cancer Institute, Singapore, Singapore.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peneyra</LastName><ForeName>J L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St. Peregrine Oncology Unit, San Juan de Dios Hospital, Pasay City, The Philippines.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ibtisam</LastName><ForeName>M N</ForeName><Initials>MN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Radiotherapy and Oncology, General Hospital Kuala Lumpur, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>K-W</ForeName><Initials>KW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Seoul National University College of Medicine, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krishna</LastName><ForeName>V</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, AIG Hospital, Hyderabad, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pribadi</LastName><ForeName>R R</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Pancreatobiliary Oncology and Digestive Endoscopy, Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia, Dr. Cipto Mangunkusumo National General Hospital, Jakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>J</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, University of Tongji, Shanghai East Hospital, Shanghai, Mainland China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lui</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Medical Oncology, Department of Internal Medicine, Southern Philippines Medical Center ESM, Davao City, The Philippines.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshino</LastName><ForeName>T</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Gastrointestinal Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital East, Kashiwa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baba</LastName><ForeName>E</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology and Social Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakayama</LastName><ForeName>I</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Chemotherapy, Cancer Institute Hospital of the Japanese Foundation for Cancer Research, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pentheroudakis</LastName><ForeName>G</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ESMO, Lugano, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoji</LastName><ForeName>H</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastrointestinal Medical Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cervantes</LastName><ForeName>A</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, INCLIVA Biomedical Research Institute, University of Valencia, Valencia; CIBERONC, Instituto de Salud Carlos III, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishioka</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Tohoku University Hospital, Sendai, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smyth</LastName><ForeName>E</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Oxford University Hospital NHS Foundation Trust, Oxford, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017065">Practice Guideline</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>ESMO Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101690685</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2059-7029</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013274" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stomach Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001208" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Asia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008495" MajorTopicYN="N">Medical Oncology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012955" MajorTopicYN="N">Societies, Medical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ESMO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pan-Asian</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastric cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">guidelines</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Disclosure KS declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Janssen Pharmaceutical; advisory role from AbbVie, Amgen, Astellas Pharma, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Meyers Squibb (BMS), Daiichi Sankyo, GlaxoSmithKline, Guardant Health Japan Corp, Lilly, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme (MSD), Novartis, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical and Takeda; institutional research grant from Amgen, Astellas, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Eisai, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical and Taiho Pharmaceutical. TF declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Amgen, Bayer, Bristol, Lilly, MSD, Roche and Servier; non-remunerated PI role from Adapt Immune, Beigene and Daiichi Sankyo. HK declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Bayer Yakuhin, Bristol-Meyers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly Japan, GlaxoSmithKline, Merck Biopharma, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Tiaho Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Teijin Pharma and Yakult Pharmaceutical Industry; advisory role from Daiichi Sankyo; institutional research grant from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Brisot-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Covance Japan Inc, Daiichi Sankyo, Eisai, Eli Lilly, Japan, EP-CRSU Co, EPS Corporation, EPS International, GlaxoSmithKline, IQVIA Services Japan, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Japan Clinical Research Operations, Kissei Pharmaceutical, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical, Mebix Inc, Medical Research Support, Mochida Pharmaceutical, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Nippon Kayaku, Novartis Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, PAREXEL International Corp, PPD-SNBL, PRA Health Sciences, Sanofi, SRL, SymBio Pharmaceuticals, SYNEOS Health Clinical, Sysmex Corporation, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical. GC declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from AstraZeneca, Daiichi Sankyo, Novartis, Pfizer and Roche; writer&#x2019;s engagement from Pfizer; advisory role from AstraZeneca, BMS, Celcuity, Daiichi Sankyo, Exact Sciences, Gilead, Lilly, Menarini, Merck, Pfizer, Roche and Veracyte; funding as coordinating PI from Relay Therapeutics; institutional funding from Astellas, AstraZeneca, Blueprint Medicine, BMS, Daiichi Sankyo, Kymab, Merck, Novartis, Philogen, Relay Therapeutics, Roche and Sanofi; non-remunerated advisory role for Italian National Health Council, Europa Donna patient advocacy association, EUSOMA and Fondazione Beretta Cancer Research Foundation; non-remunerated activity as chair of ESMO clinical practice guidelines and member of board of directors for Lega Italiana Lotta ai Tumori. YN declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from BMS, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Ono Pharma, Taiho and Yakult; advisory role from Daiichi Sankyo; funding as local PI from AstraZeneca, BMS, Daiichi Sankyo and Ono Pharma. SOW declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from AstraZeneca, Merck, MSD, Novartis, Pfizer and Sanofi Aventis; funding as local PI from Sanofi Aventis; non-remunerated advisory role to non-profit cancer survivor Sahabat Peduli Kanker. SYR declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Daiichi Sankyo, Lilly and MSD; steering committee/advisory role from Amgen, Astellas, Indivumed and LG Biochemical; institutional funding/research grant from BMS, Daiichi Sankyo, Lilly and MSD; funding as coordinating/local PI from Astra Zeneca, Beigine, Incyte, Indivumed, Merck, MSD and Zymeworks. WIWZ declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from AstraZeneca Malaysia, DKSH Malaysia, Eisai and MSD; advisory role from Astellas Pharma Inc., AstraZeneca Malaysia, MSD Malaysia and Roche Malaysia; funding as local PI from Amgen Inc., AstraZeneca, Beigene, Merck and Roche; non-remunerated role as an Asia Pacific Regional Council Member, International Cancer Corp Group member for ASCO and ATLAS board member for ATLAS group. DLS declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Abbott Nutrition, Pfizer and Zuellig Pharma; expert testimony role from AstraZeneca and MSD; writing engagement from Pfizer; employment from Unilab Inc; sponsorship of cancer centre activities from Kalbe Farma. MN declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from BMS, DKSH, MSD and Taiho; advisory role from AstraZeneca, BMS, MSD and Novartis; travel support from Eisai; stocks/shares in Amgen, AstraZeneca and Carsgen Therapeutics. KHY declares an advisory role from AstraZeneca, Daiichi Sankyo, Merck, Novartis, Ono and PhytoHealth; non-remunerated membership of American Association for Cancer Research (since 1995) and American Society of Clinical Oncology (since 1996). PS declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, BMS, DKSH, Janssen, Juniper biologics, MSD, Mundipharma, Novartis, Pfizer, Roche, Taiho and ZP Therapeutics; advisory role from Amgen, AstraZeneca, BMS, Eisai, Ipsen, Janssen, MSD, Pfizer, Novartis, and Roche; funding as local PI from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Exscientia, Janssen, MSD, Mirati Therapeutics, Novartis and Roche. ESi declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Amgen, Roche and Taiho; advisory role from Amgen, AstraZeneca, GSK, Janssen, Merck, Roche, Servier and Taiho; a non-remunerated PI role from AstraZeneca and Mirai; non-remunerated receipt of product samples from Roche. WPY declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, DKSH Singapore, MSD Pharma and Novartis; advisory role from Amgen and Ipsen Pharma; funding as local PI from Amgen and Novartis. MNI declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Novartis and Pfizer; advisory role from Maiwp Healthcare and Pusrawi Hospital; funding as coordinating/local PI from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Intraimmune, Mirati, MSD and Novartis; non-remunerated activity as PI from MSD and Novartis. KWL declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Boryung; advisory role from Astellas, Bayer, BMS, Daiichi Sankyo, MSD, Metafines and Vifor Pharma; funding as local PI from ABLBIO, ALX Oncology, Amgen, Arcus Biosciences, Astellas Pharma, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Bolt Therapeutics, Daiichi Sankyo, Exelixis, Genexine, Green Cross Corp, InventisBio, Leap Therapeutics, LSK Biopharma, Macrogenics, MedPacto, Merck KGaA, MSD, Oncologie, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Pharmacyclics, Seagen, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Trishula Therapeutics, Y-BIOLOGICS and Zymeworks; non-remunerated activity in leadership role from ALX Oncology and SMC chair of ASPEN-06 study. RRP declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Diastika, Eisai, Ferron, Takeda and Tanabe; employment from Cipto Mangunkusumo National General Hospital and EMC Hospital Pulomas; a role as a moderator for Johnson and Johnson; non-remunerated activities as officer for Indonesian College of Internal Medicine, Indonesian Society for Digestive Endoscopy, Indonesian Society of Gastroenterology and Indonesian Society of Internal Medicine. JL declares non-remunerated membership roles with ASCO and CSCO. AL declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Hi Esai, Johnson and Johnson, Merck, MSD, Nestle, Novartis and Pfizer; consultancy/advisory role from AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Merck, MSD, Novartis and Pfizer; funding as local PI from Arcus Biosciences, AstraZeneca, MSD and Roche; institutional funding from Pfizer; non-remunerated activity as member of the Philippine Society of Medical Oncology. TY declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Bayer Yakuhin, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Merck Biopharma, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical and Takeda Pharmaceutical; consultancy role from Sumitomo Corp; institutional research grant from Amgen, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Eisai, FALCO Biosystems, Genomedia Inc, Molecular Health GmbH, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer Japan, Roche Diagnostics, Sanofi, Sysmex Corp and Taiho Pharmaceutical. EB declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Bayer, BMS, Chugai, Eli Lilly, Janssen, Merck, MSD, Novartis, Ono, Taiho, Takeda and Tsumura; advisory role from Astellas, AstraZeneca and Daiichi Sankyo; institutional research grant from Chugai, Eli Lilly and Taiho. GP declares employment by ESMO; non-remunerated membership of ASCO, Hellenic Cooperative Oncology Group (HeCOG) and Hellenic Society of Medical Oncology. HS declares an advisory role from Ono Pharmaceutical and Zymeworks; funding as local PI from Amgen, Astellas, Daiichi Sankyo, MSD and Ono Pharmaceutical; institutional grant funding from Ono Pharmaceutical and Takeda Pharmaceuticals. AC declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Amgen, Foundation Medicine, Merck Serono and Roche; advisory role from Amgen, AnHeart Therapeutics, Merck Serono, Roche and Transgene; funding as local PI from Actuate Therapeutic, Adaptimmune, Amcure, Amgen, Astellas, AstraZeneca, Bayer, BeiGene, BMS, FibroGen, Genentech, Lilly, MedImmune, Merck Serono, MSD, Natera, Novartis, Servier, Sierra Oncology, Takeda and Replimmune; editorial role from Annals of Oncology, ESMO Open and Cancer Treatment Reviews; non-remunerated role as General and Scientific Director of INCLIVA Biomedical Research Institute. CI declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from AstraZeneca, Bayer, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Incyte, Kyowa-Kirin, Lilly Japan, M3, Merck, MSD, Nihon Kayaku, Novartis, Ono, Taiho and Takeda; expert testimony role from Merck; royalties from Hitachi and Riken Genesis; institutional funding/research grant from Asahi-Kasei, Chugai, Daiichi-Sankyo, Hitachi, Kyowa-Kirin, Nihon Kayuka and Taiho. ESm declares speaker&#x2019;s engagement from Amgen, Bristol-Meyers Squibb, Cor2Ed, Daiichi Sankyo, Elsevier, Imedex, Merck, Novartis, Peervoice, Prova Education, Servier and TouchIME; steering committee/advisory role from Amgen, Astellas, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Meyers Squibb, My Personal Therapeutics, Roche, Servier, Viracta and Zymeworks; expert testimony role from Bristol-Meyers Squibb; institutional research grant from Bristol-Meyers Squibb; funding as coordinating/local PI from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Basilea, Daiichi Sankyo, Merus, Mirati, MSD and Roche; independent data monitoring committee role from Beigene, Everest Clinical Research and Zymeworks; EORTC GI clinical trials group role; non-remunerated leadership role from UK &amp; Ireland Oesophagogastric Group (UKIOG). All other authors have declared no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38458658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10937212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esmoop.2023.102226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2059-7029(23)01467-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sung H., Ferlay J., Siegel R.L., et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71(3):209&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferlay J., Ervik M., Lam F., et al.   International Agency for Research on Cancer; 2020. Global Cancer Observatory: Cancer Today.https://gco.iarc.fr/ Available at.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun A., Arnold M., Ferlay J., et al. Global patterns of cardia and non-cardia gastric cancer incidence in 2012. Gut. 2015;64(12):1881&#x2013;1888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25748648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuno K., Ishihara R., Ohmori M., et al. Time trends in the incidence of esophageal adenocarcinoma, gastric adenocarcinoma, and superficial esophagogastric junction adenocarcinoma. J&#xa0;Gastroenterol. 2019;54(9):784&#x2013;791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30927083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lordick F., Carneiro F., Cascinu S., et al. Gastric cancer: ESMO Clinical Practice Guideline for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann Oncol. 2022;33(10):1005&#x2013;1020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rustgi S.D., Ching C.K., Kastrinos F. Inherited predisposition to gastric cancer. Gastrointest Endosc Clin N Am. 2021;31(3):467&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34053634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usui Y., Taniyama Y., Endo M., et al. Helicobacter pylori, homologous-recombination genes, and gastric cancer. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2023;388(13):1181&#x2013;1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36988593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang T.L., Fock K.M. Clinical epidemiology of gastric cancer. Singapore Med J. 2014;55(12):621&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4291998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25630323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang L., Kartsonaki C., Yao P., et al. The relative and attributable risks of cardia and non-cardia gastric cancer associated with Helicobacter pylori infection in China: a case-cohort study. Lancet Public Health. 2021;6(12):e888&#x2013;e896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8646857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34838195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Y., Xiao F., Wang Y., et al. Prevalence of helicobacter pylori in non-cardia gastric cancer in China: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Oncol. 2022;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9111517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35592678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim K.G., Palayan K. A&#xa0;review of gastric cancer research in Malaysia. Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2019;20(1):5&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6485554</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30677863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurjeet K., Subathra S., Bhupinder S. Differences in the pattern of gastric carcinoma between north-eastern and north-western peninsular Malaysia: a reflection of Helicobacter pylori prevalence. Med J Malaysia. 2004;59(4):560&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15779598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Z., Liu J., Zhang W., et al. Cardia and non-cardia gastric cancer risk associated with Helicobacter pylori in East Asia and the West: a systematic review, meta-analysis, and estimation of population attributable fraction. Helicobacter. 2023;28(2)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36645649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiang T.H., Chang W.J., Chen S.L., et al. Mass eradication of Helicobacter pylori to reduce gastric cancer incidence and mortality: a long-term cohort study on Matsu Islands. Gut. 2021;70(2):243&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7815911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32792335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford A.C., Forman D., Hunt R.H., et al. Helicobacter pylori eradication therapy to prevent gastric cancer in healthy asymptomatic infected individuals: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2014;348:g3174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4027797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24846275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liou J.M., Malfertheiner P., Lee Y.C., et al. Screening and eradication of Helicobacter pylori for gastric cancer prevention: the Taipei global consensus. Gut. 2020;69(12):2093&#x2013;2112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33004546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lordick F., Candia Montero L., Castelo-Branco L., et al.  Ann Oncol 2022;33(10):1005-1020. ESMO Gastric Cancer Living Guideline.v1.1 ed 2023. https://www.esmo.org/living-guidelines/esmo-gastric-cancer-living-guideline Available at.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi I.J., Kim C.G., Lee J.Y., et al. Family history of gastric cancer and helicobacter pylori treatment. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2020;382(5):427&#x2013;436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31995688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford A.C., Yuan Y., Forman D., et al. Helicobacter pylori eradication for the prevention of gastric neoplasia. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;7(7):CD005583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7389270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford A.C., Yuan Y., Moayyedi P. Helicobacter pylori eradication therapy to prevent gastric cancer: systematic review and meta-analysis. Gut. 2020;69(12):2113&#x2013;2121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32205420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Agency for Research on Cancer WHO Helicobacter pylori eradication as a strategy for preventing gastric cancer. IARC Working Group Report. 2014;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi K.S., Jun J.K., Suh M., et al. Effect of endoscopy screening on stage at gastric cancer diagnosis: results of the National Cancer Screening Programme in Korea. Br J Cancer. 2015;112(3):608&#x2013;612.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4453643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25490528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan X., Qin X., Zhang Y., et al. Screening for gastric cancer in China: advances, challenges and visions. Chin J Cancer Res. 2021;33(2):168&#x2013;180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8181866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34158737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mabe K., Inoue K., Kamada T., et al. Endoscopic screening for gastric cancer in Japan: current status and future perspectives. Dig Endosc. 2022;34(3):412&#x2013;419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34143908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japanese Gastric Cancer Association Japanese Gastric Cancer Treatment Guidelines 2021 (6th edition) Gastric Cancer. 2023;26(1):1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9813208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36342574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carneiro F, Fukayama M, Grabsch HI. Gastric adenocarcinoma. In: WHO Classification of Tumours Editorial Board, ed. <i>Digestive Stystem Tumours</i>. Vol 1. Lyon, France: IARC; 2019:85-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shitara K., Lordick F., Bang Y.J., et al. Zolbetuximab plus mFOLFOX6 in patients with CLDN18.2-positive, HER2-negative, untreated, locally&#xa0;advanced unresectable or metastatic gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma (SPOTLIGHT): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2023;401(10389):1655&#x2013;1668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah M.A., Shitara K., Ajani J.A., et al. Zolbetuximab plus CAPOX in CLDN18.2-positive gastric or gastroesophageal junction adenocarcinoma: the randomized, phase 3 GLOW trial. Nat Med. 2023;29(8):2133&#x2013;2141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10427418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37524953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y.K., Yook J.H., Park Y.K., et al. PRODIGY: a phase III study of neoadjuvant docetaxel, oxaliplatin, and S-1 plus surgery and adjuvant S-1 versus surgery and adjuvant S-1 for resectable advanced gastric cancer. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2021;39(26):2903&#x2013;2913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8425847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34133211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida K., Yasufuku I., Terashima M., et al. International retrospective cohort study of conversion therapy for stage IV gastric cancer 1 (CONVO-GC-1) Ann Gastroenterol Surg. 2022;6(2):227&#x2013;240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8889854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35261948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosogi H., Shinohara H., Tsunoda S., et al. Staging laparoscopy for advanced gastric cancer: significance of preoperative clinicopathological factors. Langenbecks Arch Surg. 2017;402(1):33&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27900486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irino T., Sano T., Hiki N., et al. Diagnostic staging laparoscopy in gastric cancer: a prospective cohort at a cancer institute in Japan. Surg Endosc. 2018;32(1):268&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28664424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miki Y., Tokunaga M., Tanizawa Y., et al. Staging laparoscopy for patients with cM0, type 4, and large type 3 gastric cancer. World J Surg. 2015;39(11):2742&#x2013;2747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26148519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamagata Y., Amikura K., Kawashima Y., et al. Staging laparoscopy in advanced gastric cancer: usefulness and issues requiring improvement. Hepatogastroenterology. 2013;60(124):751&#x2013;755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23159392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham D., Allum W.H., Stenning S.P., et al. Perioperative chemotherapy versus surgery alone for resectable gastroesophageal cancer. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2006;355(1):11&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16822992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ychou M., Boige V., Pignon J.P., et al. Perioperative chemotherapy compared with surgery alone for resectable gastroesophageal adenocarcinoma: an FNCLCC and FFCD multicenter phase III trial. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2011;29(13):1715&#x2013;1721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21444866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Liang H., Li Z., et al. Perioperative or postoperative adjuvant oxaliplatin with S-1 versus adjuvant oxaliplatin with capecitabine in patients with locally advanced gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma undergoing D2 gastrectomy (RESOLVE): an open-label, superiority and non-inferiority, phase 3 randomised controlled trial. Lancet Oncol. 2021;22(8):1081&#x2013;1092.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34252374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X., Li Z., Liang H., et al. Overall survival of perioperative or postoperative adjuvant oxaliplatin with S-1 versus adjuvant oxaliplatin with capecitabine in locally advanced gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma undergoing D2 gastrectomy: an updated analysis of RESOLVE trial. Ann Oncol. 2023;34(10) LBA 78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34252374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y.-K., Kim H.-D., Yook J.H., et al. Neoadjuvant docetaxel, oxaliplatin, and s-1 plus surgery and adjuvant s-1 for resectable advanced gastric cancer: final survival outcomes of the randomized phase 3 PRODIGY trial. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2023;41:4067.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwasaki Y., Terashima M., Mizusawa J., et al. Gastrectomy with or without neoadjuvant S-1 plus cisplatin for type 4 or large type 3 gastric cancer (JCOG0501): an open-label, phase 3, randomized controlled trial. Gastric Cancer. 2021;24(2):492&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33200303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japanese Gastric Cancer Association Japanese gastric cancer treatment guidelines 2018 (5th edition) Gastric Cancer. 2021;24(1):1&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7790804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32060757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Batran S.E., Homann N., Pauligk C., et al. Perioperative chemotherapy with fluorouracil plus leucovorin, oxaliplatin, and docetaxel versus fluorouracil or capecitabine plus cisplatin and epirubicin for locally advanced, resectable gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma (FLOT4): a randomised, phase 2/3 trial. Lancet. 2019;393(10184):1948&#x2013;1957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30982686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janjigian Y.Y., Al-Batran S.E., Wainberg Z.A., et al. Pathological complete response (pCR) to durvalumab plus 5-fluorouracil, leucovorin, oxaliplatin and docetaxel (FLOT) in resectable gastric and gastroesophageal junction cancer (GC/GEJC): interim results of the global, phase III MATTERHORN study. Ann Oncol. 2023;34:S1315&#x2013;S1316. (LBA 1373)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakuramoto S., Sasako M., Yamaguchi T., et al. Adjuvant chemotherapy for gastric cancer with S-1, an oral fluoropyrimidine. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2007;357(18):1810&#x2013;1820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17978289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang Y.J., Kim Y.W., Yang H.K., et al. Adjuvant capecitabine and oxaliplatin for gastric cancer after D2 gastrectomy (CLASSIC): a phase 3 open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2012;379(9813):315&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22226517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noh S.H., Park S.R., Yang H.K., et al. Adjuvant capecitabine plus oxaliplatin for gastric cancer after D2 gastrectomy (CLASSIC): 5-year follow-up of an open-label, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2014;15(12):1389&#x2013;1396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25439693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshida K., Kodera Y., Kochi M., et al. Addition of docetaxel to oral fluoropyrimidine improves efficacy in patients with stage iii gastric cancer: interim analysis of JACCRO GC-07, a randomized controlled trial. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2019;37(15):1296&#x2013;1304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524985</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30925125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eom S.S., Choi W., Eom B.W., et al. A&#xa0;comprehensive and comparative review of global gastric cancer treatment guidelines. J&#xa0;Gastric Cancer. 2022;22(1):3&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8980601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35425651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guideline Committee of the Korean Gastric Cancer Association (KGCA), Development Working Group &amp; Review Panel. Korean Practice Guideline for Gastric Cancer 2018: an evidence-based, multi-disciplinary approach. J&#xa0;Gastric Cancer. 2019;19(1):1&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6441770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S.H., Lim D.H., Sohn T.S., et al. A&#xa0;randomized phase III trial comparing adjuvant single-agent S1, S-1 with oxaliplatin, and postoperative chemoradiation with S-1 and oxaliplatin in patients with node-positive gastric cancer after D2 resection: the ARTIST 2 trial. Ann Oncol. 2021;32(3):368&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Y., Zhang Z., Meng Q., et al. Efficacy of different number of XELOX or SOX chemotherapy cycles after D2 resection for stage III gastric cancer. J&#xa0;Gastric Cancer. 2022;22(2):107&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9091457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35534448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaanan A., Bouche O., de la Fouchardiere C., et al. 5-Fluorouracil and oxaliplatin with or without docetaxel in the first-line treatment of HER2 negative locally advanced (LA) unresectable or metastatic gastric or gastro-esophageal junction (GEJ) adenocarcinoma (GASTFOX-PRODIGE 51): a randomized phase III trial sponsored by the FFCD. Ann Oncol. 2023;34:S1318. (LBA 1377)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada Y., Boku N., Mizusawa J., et al. Phase III study comparing triplet chemotherapy with S-1 and cisplatin plus docetaxel versus doublet chemotherapy with S-1 and cisplatin for advanced gastric cancer. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2018;36(suppl):abstr 4009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janjigian Y.Y., Shitara K., Moehler M., et al. First-line nivolumab plus chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone for advanced gastric, gastro-oesophageal junction, and oesophageal adenocarcinoma (CheckMate 649): a randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2021;398(10294):27&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8436782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun J.M., Shen L., Shah M.A., et al. Pembrolizumab plus chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone for first-line treatment of advanced oesophageal cancer (KEYNOTE-590): a randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 study. Lancet. 2021;398(10302):759&#x2013;771.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rha S.Y., Oh D.Y., Yahez P., et al. Pembrolizumab plus chemotherapy versus placebo plus chemotherapy for HER2-negative advanced gastric cancer (KEYNOTE-859): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2023;24:1181&#x2013;1185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37875143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao J., Fuchs C.S., Shitara K., et al. Assessment of pembrolizumab therapy for the treatment of microsatellite instability-high gastric or gastroesophageal junction cancer among patients in the KEYNOTE-059, KEYNOTE-061, and KEYNOTE-062 clinical trials. JAMA Oncol. 2021;7(6):895&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8017478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pietrantonio F., Randon G., Di Bartolomeo M., et al. Predictive role of microsatellite instability for PD-1 blockade in patients with advanced gastric cancer: a meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. ESMO Open. 2021;6(1)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7815473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33460964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bang Y.J., van Cutsem E., Feyereislova A., et al. Trastuzumab in combination with chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone for treatment of HER2-positive advanced gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction cancer (ToGA): a phase 3, open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2010;376(9742):687&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20728210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janjigian Y.Y., Kawazoe A., Bai Y., et al. Pembrolizumab plus trastuzumab and chemotherapy for HER2-positive gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma: interim analyses from the phase 3 KEYNOTE-811 randomised placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2023;402(10418):2197&#x2013;2208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37871604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujitani K., Yang H.K., Mizusawa J., et al. Gastrectomy plus chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone for advanced gastric cancer with a single non-curable factor (REGATTA): a phase 3, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Oncol. 2016;17(3):309&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26822397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Batran S.E., Homann N., Pauligk C., et al. Effect of neoadjuvant chemotherapy followed by surgical resection on survival in patients with limited metastatic gastric or gastroesophageal junction cancer: the AIO-FLOT3 trial. JAMA Oncol. 2017;3(9):1237&#x2013;1244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5824287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28448662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kataoka K., Kinoshita T., Moehler M., et al. Current management of liver metastases from gastric cancer: what is common practice? New challenge of EORTC and JCOG. Gastric Cancer. 2017;20(5):904&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28150070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnot P.E., Lintis A., Mercier F., et al. Prognosis of poorly cohesive gastric cancer after complete cytoreductive surgery with or without hyperthermic intraperitoneal chemotherapy (CYTO-CHIP study) Br J Surg. 2021;108(10):1225&#x2013;1235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34498666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnot P.E., Piessen G., Kepenekian V., et al. Cytoreductive surgery with or without hyperthermic intraperitoneal chemotherapy for gastric cancer with peritoneal metastases (CYTO-CHIP study): a propensity score analysis. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2019;37(23):2028&#x2013;2040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31084544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rau B., Lang H., K&#xf6;nigsrainer A., et al. The effect of hyperthermic intraperitoneal chemotherapy (HIPEC) upon cytoreductive surgery (CRS) in gastric cancer (GC) with synchronous peritoneal metastasis (PM): a randomized multicentre phase III trial (GASTRIPEC-I-trial) Ann Oncol. 2021;32(suppl 5):S1040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner A.D., Syn N.L., Moehler M., et al. Chemotherapy for advanced gastric cancer. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;8(8):CD004064.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6483552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28850174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilke H., Muro K., van Cutsem E., et al. Ramucirumab plus paclitaxel versus placebo plus paclitaxel in patients with previously treated advanced gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma (RAINBOW): a double-blind, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2014;15(11):1224&#x2013;1235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25240821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marabelle A., Le D.T., Ascierto P.A., et al. Efficacy of pembrolizumab in patients with noncolorectal high microsatellite instability/mismatch repair-deficient cancer: results from the phase II KEYNOTE-158 study. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2020;38(1):1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8184060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31682550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shitara K., Bang Y.J., Iwasa S., et al. Trastuzumab deruxtecan in previously treated HER2-positive gastric cancer. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2020;382(25):2419&#x2013;2430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Cutsem E., Di Bartolomeo M., Smyth E., et al. Primary analysis of a phase II single-arm trial of trastuzumab deruxtecan (T-DXd) in western patients (Pts) with HER2-positive (HER2+) unresectable or metastatic gastric or gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) cancer who progressed on or after a trastuzumab-containing regimen. Ann Oncol. 2021;32:S1332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku G.Y., Di Bartolomeo M., Smyth E., et al. Updated analysis of DESTINY-Gastric02: a phase II single-arm trial of trastuzumab deruxtecan (T-DXd) in western patients (Pts) with HER2-positive (HER2+) unresectable/metastatic gastric/gastroesophageal junction (GEJ) cancer who progressed on or after trastuzumab-containing regimen. Ann Oncol. 2022;33:S1100.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shitara K., Doi T., Dvorkin M., et al. Trifluridine/tipiracil versus placebo in patients with heavily pretreated metastatic gastric cancer (TAGS): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2018;19:1437&#x2013;1448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y.K., Boku N., Satoh T., et al. Nivolumab in patients with advanced gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction cancer refractory to, or intolerant of, at least two previous chemotherapy regimens (ONO-4538-12, ATTRACTION-2): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2017;390(10111):2461&#x2013;2471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28993052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li J., Qin S., Xu J., et al. Randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase III trial of apatinib in patients with chemotherapy-refractory advanced or metastatic adenocarcinoma of the stomach or gastroesophageal junction. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2016;34(13):1448&#x2013;1454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26884585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang Y., Kang W.K., Di Bartolomeo M., et al. Randomized phase 3 ANGEL study of rivoceranib (apatinib)&#xa0;+ best supportive care (BSC) vs placebo&#xa0;+ BSC in patients with advanced/metastatic gastric cancer who failed _2 prior chemotherapy regimens. Ann Oncol. 2019;30:v851&#x2013;v934.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu Z., Fang Y., Liu C., et al. Early interdisciplinary supportive care in patients with previously untreated metastatic esophagogastric cancer: a phase III randomized controlled trial. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2021;39(7):748&#x2013;756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8078238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33417481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandhya L., Devi Sreenivasan N., Goenka L., et al. Randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study of olanzapine for chemotherapy-related anorexia in patients with locally advanced or metastatic gastric, hepatopancreaticobiliary, and lung cancer. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2023;41(14):2617&#x2013;2627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36977285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pimentel-Nunes P., Dinis-Ribeiro M., Ponchon T., et al. Endoscopic submucosal dissection: European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE) Guideline. Endoscopy. 2015;47(9):829&#x2013;854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26317585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherny N.I., Dafni U., Bogaerts J., et al. ESMO-magnitude of clinical benefit scale version 1.1. Ann Oncol. 2017;28(10):2340&#x2013;2366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28945867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mateo J., Chakravarty D., Dienstmann R., et al. A&#xa0;framework to rank genomic alterations as targets for cancer precision medicine: the ESMO Scale for Clinical Actionability of molecular Targets (ESCAT) Ann Oncol. 2018;29(9):1895&#x2013;1902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6158764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30137196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao J.J., Yap D.W.T., Chan Y.H., et al. Low programmed death-ligand 1-expressing subgroup outcomes of first-line immune checkpoint inhibitors in gastric or esophageal adenocarcinoma. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2022;40(4):392&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34860570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoon H.H., Jin Z., Kour O., et al. Association of PD-L1 expression and other variables with benefit from immune checkpoint inhibition in advanced gastroesophageal cancer: systematic review and meta-analysis of 17 phase 3 randomized clinical trials. JAMA Oncol. 2022;8(10):1456&#x2013;1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9412834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36006624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>