<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38651033</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-3643</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JTO clinical and research reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JTO Clin Res Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Tumor Immune Microenvironment Is Associated With Recurrence in Early-Stage Lung Adenocarcinoma.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100658</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100658</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100658</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2024.100658</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Immune checkpoint inhibitors have recently been approved for the treatment of early-stage NSCLC in the perioperative setting on the basis of phase 3 trials. However, the characteristics of such patients who are susceptible to recurrence after adjuvant chemotherapy or who are likely to benefit from postoperative immunotherapy have remained unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This biomarker study (WJOG12219LTR) was designed to evaluate cancer stem cell markers (CD44 and CD133), programmed death-ligand 1 (PD-L1) expression on tumor cells, CD8 expression on tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes, and tumor mutation burden in completely resected stage II to IIIA NSCLC with the use of archived DNA and tissue samples from the prospective WJOG4107 trial. Tumors were classified as inflamed or noninflamed on the basis of the PD-L1 tumor proportion score and CD8<sup>+</sup> tumor-infiltrating lymphocyte density. The association between each potential biomarker and relapse-free survival (RFS) during adjuvant chemotherapy was assessed by Kaplan-Meier analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 117 patients were included in this study. The median RFS was not reached (95% confidence intervals [CI]: 22.4 mo-not reached; n&#xa0;= 39) and 23.7 months (95% CI: 14.5-43.6; n&#xa0;= 41) in patients with inflamed or noninflamed adenocarcinoma, respectively (log-rank <i>p</i>&#xa0;= 0.02, hazard ratio of 0.52 [95% CI: 0.29-0.93]). Analysis of the combination of tumor inflammation category and <i>TP53</i> mutation status revealed that inflamed tumors without <i>TP53</i> mutations were associated with the longest RFS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PD-L1 expression on tumor cells, CD8<sup>+</sup> T cell infiltration, and <i>TP53</i> mutation status may help identify patients with early-stage NSCLC susceptible to recurrence after adjuvant chemotherapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanemura</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokoyama</LastName><ForeName>Toshihide</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kurashiki Central Hospital, Kurashiki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakajima</LastName><ForeName>Ryu</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Thoracic Surgery, Osaka City General Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Atsushi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, Sendai, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuroda</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, Aichi Cancer Center Hospital, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kitamura</LastName><ForeName>Yoshitaka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Chest Surgery, Hyogo Cancer Center, Akashi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoda</LastName><ForeName>Hiroyasu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hiroshima City Hiroshima Citizen Hospital, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamesaya</LastName><ForeName>Nobuaki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Shizuoka Cancer Center, Shizuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyata</LastName><ForeName>Yoshihiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okamoto</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, NHO Kyushu Cancer Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okishio</LastName><ForeName>Kyoichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research Center, NHO Kinki Chuo Chest Medical Center, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oki</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, NHO Nagoya Medical Center, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakairi</LastName><ForeName>Yuichi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Thoracic Surgery, Chiba University Graduate School of Medicine, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen-Yoshikawa</LastName><ForeName>Toyofumi Fengshi</ForeName><Initials>TF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, Nagoya University Graduate School of Medicine, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aoki</LastName><ForeName>Tadashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chest Surgery, Niigata Cancer Center Hospital, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohira</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Tokyo Medical University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Isao</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, Kanazawa University, Kanazawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ueno</LastName><ForeName>Kiyonobu</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Osaka General Medical Center, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyazaki</LastName><ForeName>Takuro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Nagasaki University Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Nagasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsuguma</LastName><ForeName>Haruhisa</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, Tochigi Cancer Center, Utsunomiya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokouchi</LastName><ForeName>Hideoki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Suita Municipal Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otani</LastName><ForeName>Tomoyuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ito</LastName><ForeName>Akihiko</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakai</LastName><ForeName>Kazuko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiba</LastName><ForeName>Yasutaka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Center, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okamoto</LastName><ForeName>Isamu</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takeda</LastName><ForeName>Masayuki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cancer Genomics and Medical Oncology, Nara Medical University, Nara, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JTO Clin Res Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101769967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-3643</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adjuvant chemotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer stem cell</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor immune microenvironment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Dr. Kanemura has received grants or funding from 10.13039/100010795Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; honoraria for lectures from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., and Daiichi Sankyo Co. Ltd. Dr. Yokoyama has received grants or funding from 10.13039/100009947Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, 10.13039/100010795Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 10.13039/100002491Bristol-Myers Squibb, 10.13039/100017346Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Takeda Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Delta-Fly Pharma, 10.13039/100020707Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K, AbbVie G.K., 10.13039/501100002973Daiichi-Sankyo, and 10.13039/100016751Parexel International; honoraria for lectures from AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. Ltd., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co. Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, and Merck Biopharma Co. Ltd. Dr. Mamesaya has received grants or funding from Boehringer Ingelheim, 10.13039/100012781Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., and Arrivent Biopharma; honoraria for lectures from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Boehringer Ingelheim, AstraZeneca K.K., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., and Novartis Pharma K.K. Dr. T. Okamoto has received grants or funding from 10.13039/100018046Nippon Kayaku and 10.13039/100009954Taiho Pharmaceutical; honoraria for lectures from Nippon Kayaku and Taiho Pharmaceutical. Dr. Okishio has received honoraria for lectures from Bristol-Myers Squibb K.K., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, AstraZeneca K.K., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Sawai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd. Dr. Oki has received grants or funding from 10.13039/100006483AbbVie Inc., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 10.13039/100015542GlaxoSmithKline K.K., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., 10.13039/100016751Parexel International Corporation., 10.13039/100015990Sanofi K.K., 10.13039/100020869AstraZeneca KK, 10.13039/501100019949Fujifilm Toyama Chemical Co., Ltd., 10.13039/100020707Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K, 10.13039/501100013170Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 10.13039/100010793Pfizer Japan Inc., Kaneka Medix Corp., 10.13039/100005564Gilead Sciences, Inc., and 10.13039/501100002973Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd.; honoraria for lectures from AMCO Inc., Canon Medical Systems Corp., Fujifilm Corp., Merit Medical Japan K.K., Olympus Marketing, Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kaneka Medix Corp., Novartis Pharma K.K., Sanofi K.K., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Intuitive Surgical G.K., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., and Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd. Dr. Sakai has received honoraria for lectures from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Yodosha Co., Ltd., Qiagen, Inc., and Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd. Dr. Nishio has received grants or funding from 10.13039/100017346Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, West Japan Oncology Group, Clinical Research Support Center Kyushu, Nichirei Biosciences Inc., 10.13039/100014422Eli Lilly Japan, 10.13039/100008238Hitachi, 10.13039/100017981Sysmex, and 10.13039/501100007132Otsuka Pharmaceutical.; consulting fees from Symbio Pharmaceuticals, Eli Lilly Japan, and Otsuka Pharmaceutical; honoraria for lectures from Chugai, Pfizer, Eli Lilly Japan, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis Pharma, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Merck Biopharma, Yakult Honsha, Guardant Health, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, FujireBio, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Ono Pharmaceutical, Invitae Japan, and Nichirei. Dr. Yamamoto has received grants or funding from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, 10.13039/100004336Novartis, AbbVie, 10.13039/100002429Amgen, Asahi Kasei, Janssen, Bristol-Myers Squibb Japan, IQVIA, EPS Corporation, 10.13039/100002429Amgen, A2 Healthcare, Mebix, and Ono Pharmaceutical; consulting fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Lilly Japan, Amgen, Novartis, and Ono Pharmaceutical; honoraria for lectures from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Takeda, Accuray, AbbVie, Amgen, Ono Pharmaceutical, Guardant Health, Kyorin, Daiichi Sankyo, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Tsumura &amp; Co., Terumo, Lilly Japan, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Novartis, Pfizer, Miyarisan Pharmaceutical, Merck Biopharma, and Janssen. Dr. I. Okamoto has received honoraria for lectures from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co. Ltd., AstraZeneca plc, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., and Novartis Pharma K.K. Dr. Nakagawa has received grants or funding from 10.13039/100002429Amgen Inc., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Bristol-Myers Squibb Company, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., 10.13039/100016751Parexel International Corp., PRA Health Sciences, EPS Corporation., 10.13039/100016288Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., EPS Corporation., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., PPD-SNBL K.K, 10.13039/501100013172Symbio Pharmaceuticals Limited., IQVIA Services Japan K.K., Syneos Health Clinical K.K., 10.13039/100018046Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., EP-CRSU Co., Ltd., Mebix, Inc., 10.13039/100020707Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., 10.13039/501100004948Astellas Pharma Inc., 10.13039/100015731Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., 10.13039/501100023368Eisai Co., Ltd., Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Labcorp Development Japan K.K. (Covance Japan Inc.), Japan Clinical Research Operations, Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 10.13039/100015542GlaxoSmithKline K.K., 10.13039/100015990Sanofi K.K., 10.13039/100017981Sysmex Corporation, Medical Research Support, Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., SRL, Inc., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., CMIC Co., Ltd., Eisai Inc., 10.13039/501100005612Shionogi &amp; Co., Ltd., Kobayashi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Ascent Development Services; consulting fees from Eli Lilly Japan K.K. and Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; honoraria for lectures from Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Amgen Inc., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., CMIC Shiftzero K.K., Life Technologies Japan Ltd., Neo Communication, Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Incyte biosciences Japan, Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Kyowa Kirin Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 3H Clinical Trial Inc., Care Net, Inc., Medical Review Co., Ltd., Medical Mobile Communications co., Ltd., Yodosha Co., Ltd., Nikkei Business Publications, Inc., Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Taiyo Pharma Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., and Bristol-Myers Squibb K.K.; patent planned, issued or pending from Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. Dr. Takeda has received honoraria for lectures from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., Bristol-Myers Squibb Company, Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Boehringer Ingelheim, and Takeda Pharma Ltd. The remaining authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38651033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11033192</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2024.100658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-3643(24)00028-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Goldstraw P., Chansky K., Crowley J., et al. The IASLC lung cancer staging project: proposals for revision of the TNM stage groupings in the forthcoming (eighth) edition of the TNM classification for lung cancer. J&#xa0;Thorac Oncol. 2016;11:39&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26762738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pignon J.P., Tribodet H., Scagliotti G.V., et al. Lung adjuvant cisplatin evaluation: a pooled analysis by the LACE Collaborative Group. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2008;26:3552&#x2013;3559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18506026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaft J.E., Rimner A., Weder W., Azzoli C.G., Kris M.G., Cascone T. Evolution of systemic therapy for stages I&#x2013;III non-metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2021;18:547&#x2013;557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9447511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33911215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felip E., Altorki N., Zhou C., et al. Adjuvant atezolizumab after adjuvant chemotherapy in resected stage IB-IIIA non-small-cell lung cancer (IMpower010): a randomised, multicentre, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2021;398:1344&#x2013;1357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34555333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien M., Paz-Ares L., Marreaud S., et al. Pembrolizumab versus placebo as adjuvant therapy for completely resected stage IB-IIIA non-small-cell lung cancer (PEARLS/KEYNOTE-091): an interim analysis of a randomised, triple-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2022;23:1274&#x2013;1286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36108662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seymour L., Le Teuff G., Brambilla E., et al. LACE-Bio: validation of Predictive and/or Prognostic immunohistochemistry/Histochemistry-based Biomarkers in Resected non-small-cell Lung Cancer. Clin Lung Cancer. 2019;20:66&#x2013;73.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30414783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devarakonda S., Rotolo F., Tsao M.S., et al. Tumor mutation burden as a biomarker in resected non-small-cell lung cancer. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2018;36:2995&#x2013;3006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6804865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30106638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsao M.S., Le Teuff G., Shepherd F.A., et al. PD-L1 protein expression assessed by immunohistochemistry is neither prognostic nor predictive of benefit from adjuvant chemotherapy in resected non-small cell lung cancer. Ann Oncol. 2017;28:882&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5834092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28137741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brambilla E., Le Teuff G., Marguet S., et al. Prognostic effect of tumor lymphocytic infiltration in resectable non-small-cell lung cancer. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2016;34:1223&#x2013;1230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4872323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26834066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mountzios G., Remon J., Hendriks L.E.L., et al. Immune-checkpoint inhibition for resectable non-small-cell lung cancer - opportunities and challenges. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2023;20:664&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37488229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batlle E., Clevers H. Cancer stem cells revisited. Nat Med. 2017;23:1124&#x2013;1134.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28985214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clara J.A., Monge C., Yang Y., Takebe N. Targeting signalling pathways and the immune microenvironment of cancer stem cells - a clinical update. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2020;17:204&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31792354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayik D., Lathia J.D. Cancer stem cell-immune cell crosstalk in tumour progression. Nat Rev Cancer. 2021;21:526&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34103704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kammer M.N., Mori H., Rowe D.J., et al. Tumoral densities of T-cells and mast cells are associated with recurrence in early-stage lung adenocarcinoma. JTO Clin Res Rep. 2023;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10477685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37674811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwamoto Y., Mitsudomi T., Sakai K., et al. Randomized phase II study of adjuvant chemotherapy with long-term S-1 versus cisplatin+S-1 in completely resected stage II-IIIA non-small cell lung cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2015;21:5245&#x2013;5252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26253869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamgeer M., Ganju V., Szczepny A., et al. The prognostic significance of aldehyde dehydrogenase 1A1 (ALDH1A1) and CD133 expression in early stage non-small cell lung cancer. Thorax. 2013;68:1095&#x2013;1104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3841805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23878161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borghaei H., Paz-Ares L., Horn L., et al. Nivolumab versus docetaxel in advanced nonsquamous non-small-cell lung cancer. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2015;373:1627&#x2013;1639.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5705936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26412456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanemura H., Hayashi H., Tomida S., et al. The tumor immune microenvironment and frameshift neoantigen load determine response to PD-L1 blockade in extensive-stage SCLC. JTO Clin Res Rep. 2022;3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9356091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35941997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakai K., Tsuboi M., Kenmotsu H., et al. Tumor mutation burden as a biomarker for lung cancer patients treated with pemetrexed and cisplatin (the JIPANG-TR) Cancer Sci. 2021;112:388&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7780021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33185928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hothorn T., Lausen B. On the exact distribution of maximally selected rank statistics. Comp Stat Data Anal. 2003;43:121&#x2013;137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taube J.M., Anders R.A., Young G.D., et al. Colocalization of inflammatory response with B7-H1 expression in human melanocytic lesions supports an adaptive resistance mechanism of immune escape. Sci Transl Med. 2012;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3568523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22461641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teng M.W., Ngiow S.F., Ribas A., Smyth M.J. Classifying cancers based on T-cell infiltration and PD-L1. Cancer Res. 2015;75:2139&#x2013;2145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4452411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25977340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takada K., Okamoto T., Shoji F., et al. Clinical significance of PD-L1 protein expression in surgically resected primary lung adenocarcinoma. J&#xa0;Thorac Oncol. 2016;11:1879&#x2013;1890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27346415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shepherd F.A., Lacas B., Le Teuff G., et al. Pooled analysis of the prognostic and predictive effects of TP53 comutation status combined with KRAS or EGFR mutation in early-stage resected non-small-cell lung cancer in four trials of adjuvant chemotherapy. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2017;35:2018&#x2013;2027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6075828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28453411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Rousseau V., Sun H., et al. Significance of TP53 mutations as predictive markers of adjuvant cisplatin-based chemotherapy in completely resected non-small-cell lung cancer. Mol Oncol. 2014;8:555&#x2013;564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5528648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24495481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X., Le Teuff G., Lacas B., et al. Prognostic and predictive effect of TP53 mutations in patients with non-small cell lung cancer from adjuvant cisplatin-based therapy randomized trials: a LACE-bio pooled analysis. J&#xa0;Thorac Oncol. 2016;11:850&#x2013;861.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26899019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clevers H. The cancer stem cell: premises, promises and challenges. Nat Med. 2011;17:313&#x2013;319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21386835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walcher L., Kistenmacher A.K., Suo H., et al. Cancer stem cells-origins and biomarkers: perspectives for targeted personalized therapies. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32849491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagano O., Saya H. Mechanism and biological significance of CD44 cleavage. Cancer Sci. 2004;95:930&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11159127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15596040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko Y.H., Won H.S., Jeon E.K., et al. Prognostic significance of CD44s expression in resected non-small cell lung cancer. BMC Cancer. 2011;11:340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3164633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21819617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong P., Xiong Y., Yue J., Hanley S.J.B., Watari H. Tumor-intrinsic PD-L1 signaling in cancer initiation, development and treatment: beyond immune evasion. Front Oncol. 2018;8:386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6156376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30283733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong T., Ahn R., Yang K., et al. CD44 promotes PD-L1 expression and its tumor-intrinsic function in breast and lung cancers. Cancer Res. 2020;80:444&#x2013;457.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31722999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azuma K., Ota K., Kawahara A., et al. Association of PD-L1 Overexpression with activating EGFR mutations in surgically resected nonsmall-cell lung cancer. Ann Oncol. 2014;25:1935&#x2013;1940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25009014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S., Ock C.Y., Kim H., et al. Artificial intelligence&#x2013;powered spatial analysis of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes as complementary biomarker for immune checkpoint inhibition in non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2022;40:1916&#x2013;1928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9177249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Magraner L., Gumuzio J., Miles J., et al. Functional engagement of the PD-1/PD-L1 complex but not PD-L1 expression is highly predictive of patient response to immunotherapy in non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2023;41:2561&#x2013;2570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10414696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36821809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>