<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39392339</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2767-9764</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cancer research communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cancer Res Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Association between Immune-Related Adverse Events and Atezolizumab in Previously Treated Patients with Unresectable Advanced or Recurrent Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2858</StartPage><EndPage>2867</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2858-2867</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1158/2767-9764.CRC-24-0212</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">Real-world, large-scale studies on the association between immune-related adverse events (irAE) and immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy effectiveness are limited. We evaluated overall survival (OS) and progression-free survival based on the occurrence and grade of irAEs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS">We used data from Japanese patients with unresectable advanced or recurrent non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) who received atezolizumab and were enrolled in J-TAIL, a multicenter, prospective, single-arm observational study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Among the 1,002 patients, 190 (19.0%) developed irAEs. The most common irAEs were skin disorders (3.8%) of any grade and interstitial lung disease (1.5%) of grade &#x2265;3. Patients who developed irAEs within 4 or 6 weeks of treatment initiation had higher baseline C-reactive protein levels than those without irAEs. OS was longer in patients with irAEs [HR, 0.66; 95% confidence interval (CI), 0.54-0.82], particularly in those with low-grade irAEs (HR, 0.45; 95% CI, 0.33-0.62), than in patients without irAEs. The HR (95% CI) for OS in patients with low-grade and high-grade skin or endocrine disorder-related irAEs was 0.42 (0.28-0.64) and 0.37 (0.15-0.88), respectively. The HR (95% CI) for OS in patients with low-grade and high-grade irAEs other than skin or endocrine disorders was 0.44 (0.30-0.65) and 1.27 (0.96-1.69), respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">In patients with unresectable advanced or recurrent NSCLC treated with atezolizumab in real-world settings, irAEs are associated with a clinical benefit except in those with high-grade irAEs other than skin and endocrine disorders.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE">Immune checkpoint inhibitors are useful for treating NSCLC but can cause life-threatening irAEs. This study had a large sample size and stratified the analysis by irAE type and grade. The results suggest that improved management of irAEs may improve the therapeutic effect of atezolizumab.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;2024 The Authors; Published by the American Association for Cancer Research.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8787-5587</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Faculty of Medicine, Kindai University, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Makoto</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4969-4165</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medical Oncology, The Cancer Institute Hospital of Japanese Foundation for Cancer Research, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akamatsu</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5856-5512</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goto</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7437-5054</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miura</LastName><ForeName>Satoru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7868-6661</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Niigata Cancer Center Hospital, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gemma</LastName><ForeName>Akihiko</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0762-2737</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine and Oncology, Nippon Medical School, Graduate School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshino</LastName><ForeName>Ichiro</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-4007-9606</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Thoracic Surgery, Chiba University Graduate School of Medicine, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Misumi</LastName><ForeName>Toshihiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8339-2895</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Yokohama City University School of Medicine, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kijima</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4249-4021</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine and Hematology, Hyogo Medical University, School of Medicine, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takase</LastName><ForeName>Naoto</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-6484-7301</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Takarazuka City Hospital, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujita</LastName><ForeName>Masaki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1209-1272</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Fukuoka University Hospital, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tasaka</LastName><ForeName>Sadatomo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4861-4143</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, Aomori, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mouri</LastName><ForeName>Atsuto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8704-8151</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, International Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kondo</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4388-4814</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Kanagawa Cancer Center, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takamura</LastName><ForeName>Kei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2707-5355</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Obihiro-Kosei General Hospital, Hokkaido, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawashima</LastName><ForeName>Yosuke</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9824-6572</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, Miyagi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imaizumi</LastName><ForeName>Kazuyoshi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3790-8691</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Fujita Health University School of Medicine, Toyoake, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwasawa</LastName><ForeName>Shunichiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-1366-9676</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Shintaro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-8433-6801</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitsudomi</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9860-8505</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kindai Hospital Global Research Alliance Center and Thoracic Surgery, Kindai University, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cancer Res Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918281580506676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2767-9764</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>52CMI0WC3Y</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000594389">atezolizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000082082">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000082082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009364" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Recurrence, Local</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077982" MajorTopicYN="N">Progression-Free Survival</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>H. Hayashi reports grants from IQVIA Services JAPAN K.K., Eisai Co., Ltd., SYNEOS HEALTH CLINICAL K.K., EP-CRSU Co., Ltd., EPS Corporation. Shionogi &amp; Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., MSD K.K., Sanofi K.K., Amgen Inc., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, SRL Medisearch Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., PRA Health Sciences Inc., CMIC Co., Ltd., Astellas Pharma Inc., Pfizer, R&amp;D Japan G.K., Ascent Development Services, Labcorp Development Japan K.K., Eisai Inc., Kobayashi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., AbbVie Inc., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., A2 Healthcare Corp., Novartis Pharma K.K., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Medpace Japan K.K., Kyowa Kirin Co., Ltd., Japanese Gastric Cancer Association, Thoracic Oncology Research Group, Clinical Research Support Center, Kyushu West Japan Oncology Group Japan, Clinical Cancer Research Organization, Comprehensive Support Project for Oncological Research of Breast Cancer, EPS International Co., Ltd., Mebix, Inc., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Covance Japan Inc., Japan Clinical Research Operations, and Medical Research Support and personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., 3H Clinical Trial Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., Novartis Pharma K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Amgen Inc., MSD K.K., Sysmex Corporation, Pfizer Japan Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., and Guardant Health Japan Corp. outside the submitted work. M. Nishio reports personal fees from Ono Pharmaceuticals, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly and Company, AstraZeneca, MSD, AbbVie, Takeda, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, and Nippon Kayaku outside the submitted work. H. Akamatsu reports grants and personal fees from Amgen Inc, AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., and MSD K.K, personal fees from Boehringer Ingelheim Japan Inc., Bristol Myers Squibb, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Nippon Kayaku. Co. Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., and Pfizer Inc outside the submitted work. Y. Goto reports grants and personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, MSD, Eli Lilly and Company, Bristol Myers and Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, Novartis, Guardant Health, Amgen, Daiichi Sankyo, Takeda, and Janssen, personal fees from Roche, Merck, Towa, and Sandoz, and grants from AbbVie and Asteras outside the submitted work. S. Miura reports personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study, as well as personal fees from Taiho Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, and Takeda Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. A. Gemma reports personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study, as well as personal fees from Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca, and Nippon Kayaku outside the submitted work. I. Yoshino reports personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, and Covidien Japan outside the submitted work, as well as reports being a steering committee member of Japan Lung Cancer Society. T. Kijima reports personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. during the conduct of the study. N. Takase reports grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. during the conduct of the study. A. Mouri reports personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly and Company, Ono pharmaceutical, and Bristol Myers and Squibb outside the submitted work. T. Kondo reports personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Takeda, Daiichi Sankyo, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, and Ono Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Y. Kawashima reports personal fees from Taiho Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly and Company, Life Technologies Japan Ltd, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co, AstraZeneca, and Kyowa Kirin Co., Ltd outside the submitted work. K. Imaizumi reports grants from Chugai pharmaceutical Co. Ltd and Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd outside the submitted work. S. Iwasawa reports personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. during the conduct of the study, as well as personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. outside the submitted work. T. Mitsudomi reports grants and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Eli Lilly and Company, Chugai Pharmaceutical, grants from Taiho and Bridge Bio, and personal fees from Pfizer, Bristol Myers and Squibb, Novartis, Amgen, Novocure, Janssen, and Regeneron outside the submitted work. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39392339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11528261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/2767-9764.CRC-24-0212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">749047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Borghaei H, Paz-Ares L, Horn L, Spigel DR, Steins M, Ready NE, et al. Nivolumab versus docetaxel in advanced nonsquamous non-small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med 2015;373:1627&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5705936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26412456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reck M, Rodr&#xed;guez-Abreu D, Robinson AG, Hui R, Cs&#x151;szi T, F&#xfc;l&#xf6;p A, et al. Pembrolizumab versus chemotherapy for PD-L1-positive non-small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med 2016;375:1823&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27718847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rittmeyer A, Barlesi F, Waterkamp D, Park K, Ciardiello F, von Pawel J, et al. Atezolizumab versus docetaxel in patients with previously treated non-small-cell lung cancer (OAK): a phase 3, open-label, multicentre randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2017;389:255&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6886121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27979383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hellmann MD, Ciuleanu TE, Pluzanski A, Lee JS, Otterson GA, Audigier-Valette C, et al. Nivolumab plus ipilimumab in lung cancer with a high tumor mutational burden. N Engl J Med 2018;378:2093&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7193684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boutros C, Tarhini A, Routier E, Lambotte O, Ladurie FL, Carbonnel F, et al. Safety profiles of anti-CTLA-4 and anti-PD-1 antibodies alone and in combination. Nat Rev Clin Oncol 2016;13:473&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27141885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman CF, Proverbs-Singh TA, Postow MA. Treatment of the immune-related adverse effects of immune checkpoint inhibitors: a review. JAMA Oncol 2016;2:1346&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27367787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pillai RN, Behera M, Owonikoko TK, Kamphorst AO, Pakkala S, Belani CP, et al. Comparison of the toxicity profile of PD-1 versus PD-L1 inhibitors in non-small cell lung cancer: a systematic analysis of the literature. Cancer 2018;124:271&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5761314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28960263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar V, Chaudhary N, Garg M, Floudas CS, Soni P, Chandra AB. Current diagnosis and management of immune related adverse events (irAEs) induced by immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy. Front Pharmacol 2017;8:49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28228726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mezquita L, Auclin E, Ferrara R, Charrier M, Remon J, Planchard D, et al. Association of the lung immune prognostic index with immune checkpoint inhibitor outcomes in patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer. JAMA Oncol 2018;4:351&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5885829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29327044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanizaki J, Haratani K, Hayashi H, Chiba Y, Nakamura Y, Yonesaka K, et al. Peripheral blood biomarkers associated with clinical outcome in non-small cell lung cancer patients treated with nivolumab. J Thorac Oncol 2018;13:97&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29170120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakata Y, Kawamura K, Ichikado K, Shingu N, Yasuda Y, Eguchi Y, et al. Comparisons between tumor burden and other prognostic factors that influence survival of patients with non-small cell lung cancer treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors. Thorac Cancer 2019;10:2259&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6885438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31679185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Stein JE, Rimm DL, Wang DW, Bell JM, Johnson DB, et al. Comparison of biomarker modalities for predicting response to PD-1/PD-L1 checkpoint blockade: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Oncol 2019;5:1195&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6646995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31318407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keenan TE, Burke KP, Van Allen EM. Genomic correlates of response to immune checkpoint blockade. Nat Med 2019;25:389&#x2013;402.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6599710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30842677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iivanainen S, Ahvonen J, Knuuttila A, Tiainen S, Koivunen JP. Elevated CRP levels indicate poor progression-free and overall survival on cancer patients treated with PD-1 inhibitors. ESMO Open 2019;4:e000531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6735669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31555483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber JS, Yang JC, Atkins MB, Disis ML. Toxicities of immunotherapy for the practitioner. J Clin Oncol 2015;33:2092&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4881375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25918278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan S, Khan SA, Luo X, Fattah FJ, Saltarski J, Gloria-McCutchen Y, et al. Immune dysregulation in cancer patients developing immune-related adverse events. Br J Cancer 2019;120:63&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6325132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30377338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua C, Boussemart L, Mateus C, Routier E, Boutros C, Cazenave H, et al. Association of vitiligo with tumor response in patients with metastatic melanoma treated with pembrolizumab. JAMA Dermatol 2016;152:45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26501224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman-Keller M, Kim Y, Cronin H, Richards A, Gibney G, Weber JS. Nivolumab in resected and unresectable metastatic melanoma: characteristics of immune-related adverse events and association with outcomes. Clin Cancer Res 2016;22:886&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4755809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26446948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AS, Goutam S, Stukalin I, Ewanchuk BW, Sander M, Meyers DE, et al. Association of immune-related adverse events, hospitalization, and therapy resumption with survival among patients with metastatic melanoma receiving single-agent or combination immunotherapy. JAMA Netw Open 2022;5:e2245596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9856439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36480204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teraoka S, Fujimoto D, Morimoto T, Kawachi H, Ito M, Sato Y, et al. Early immune-related adverse events and association with outcome in advanced non-small cell lung cancer patients treated with nivolumab: a prospective cohort study. J Thorac Oncol 2017;12:1798&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28939128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toi Y, Sugawara S, Kawashima Y, Aiba T, Kawana S, Saito R, et al. Association of immune-related adverse events with clinical benefit in patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer treated with nivolumab. Oncologist 2018;23:1358&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6291330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29934411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato K, Akamatsu H, Murakami E, Sasaki S, Kanai K, Hayata A, et al. Correlation between immune-related adverse events and efficacy in non-small cell lung cancer treated with nivolumab. Lung Cancer 2018;115:71&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29290265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricciuti B, Genova C, De Giglio A, Bassanelli M, Dal Bello MG, Metro G, et al. Impact of immune-related adverse events on survival in patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer treated with nivolumab: long-term outcomes from a multi-institutional analysis. J Cancer Res Clin Oncol 2019;145:479&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11810236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30506406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haratani K, Hayashi H, Chiba Y, Kudo K, Yonesaka K, Kato R, et al. Association of immune-related adverse events with nivolumab efficacy in non-small-cell lung cancer. JAMA Oncol 2018;4:374&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28975219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lisberg A, Tucker DA, Goldman JW, Wolf B, Carroll J, Hardy A, et al. Treatment-related adverse events predict improved clinical outcome in NSCLC patients on KEYNOTE-001 at a single center. Cancer Immunol Res 2018;6:288&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6066474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29382669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan Ali O, Diem S, Markert E, Jochum W, Kerl K, French LE, et al. Characterization of nivolumab-associated skin reactions in patients with metastatic non-small cell lung cancer. Oncoimmunology 2016;5:e1231292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5139632</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27999741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn BC, Pyo KH, Xin CF, Jung D, Shim HS, Lee CY, et al. Comprehensive analysis of the characteristics and treatment outcomes of patients with non-small cell lung cancer treated with anti-PD-1 therapy in real-world practice. J Cancer Res Clin Oncol 2019;145:1613&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6527531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30911841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosoya K, Fujimoto D, Morimoto T, Kumagai T, Tamiya A, Taniguchi Y, et al. Association between early immune-related adverse events and clinical outcomes in patients with non-small cell lung cancer treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors. Clin Lung Cancer 2020;21:e315&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32113737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aso M, Toi Y, Sugisaka J, Aiba T, Kawana S, Saito R, et al. Association between skin reaction and clinical benefit in patients treated with anti-programmed cell death 1 monotherapy for advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Oncologist 2020;25:e536&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7066688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32162801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osorio JC, Ni A, Chaft JE, Pollina R, Kasler MK, Stephens D, et al. Antibody-mediated thyroid dysfunction during T-cell checkpoint blockade in patients with non-small-cell lung cancer. Ann Oncol 2017;28:583&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5834017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27998967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HI, Kim M, Lee SH, Park SY, Kim YN, Kim H, et al. Development of thyroid dysfunction is associated with clinical response to PD-1 blockade treatment in patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Oncoimmunology 2017;7:e1375642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5739550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29296533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thuillier P, Joly C, Alavi Z, Crouzeix G, Descourt R, Quere G, et al. Thyroid dysfunction induced by immune checkpoint inhibitors is associated with a better progression-free survival and overall survival in non-small cell lung cancer: an original cohort study. Cancer Immunol Immunother 2021;70:2023&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10991310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33423089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suresh K, Psoter KJ, Voong KR, Shankar B, Forde PM, Ettinger DS, et al. Impact of checkpoint inhibitor pneumonitis on survival in NSCLC patients receiving immune checkpoint immunotherapy. J Thorac Oncol 2019;14:494&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30503891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukihara J, Sakamoto K, Koyama J, Ito T, Iwano S, Morise M, et al. Prognostic impact and risk factors of immune-related pneumonitis in patients with non-small-cell lung cancer who received programmed death 1 inhibitors. Clin Lung Cancer 2019;20:442&#x2013;50.e4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31446020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortellini A, Friedlaender A, Banna GL, Porzio G, Bersanelli M, Cappuzzo F, et al. Immune-related adverse events of pembrolizumab in a large real-world cohort of patients with NSCLC with a PD-L1 expression &#x2265;50% and their relationship with clinical outcomes. Clin Lung Cancer 2020;21:498&#x2013;508.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Yao Z, Yang H, Liang N, Zhang X, Zhang F. Are immune-related adverse events associated with the efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitors in patients with cancer? A systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Med 2020;18:87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7169020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32306958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang D, Chen C, Gu Y, Lu W, Zhan P, Liu H, et al. Immune-related adverse events predict the efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitors in lung cancer patients: a meta-analysis. Front Oncol 2021;11:631949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7958877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33732650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Socinski MA, Jotte RM, Cappuzzo F, Nishio M, Mok TSK, Reck M, et al. Association of immune-related adverse events with efficacy of atezolizumab in patients with non-small cell lung cancer: pooled analyses of the phase 3 IMpower130, IMpower132, and IMpower150 randomized clinical trials. JAMA Oncol 2023;9:527&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9936386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36795388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miura S, Nishio M, Akamatsu H, Goto Y, Hayashi H, Gemma A, et al. Effectiveness and safety of atezolizumab monotherapy in previously treated Japanese patients with unresectable advanced or recurrent NSCLC: a multicenter, prospective, observational study (J-TAIL). JTO Clin Res Rep 2023;4:100484.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10074249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37034464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenhauer EA, Therasse P, Bogaerts J, Schwartz LH, Sargent D, Ford R, et al. New response evaluation criteria in solid tumours: revised RECIST guideline (version 1.1). Eur J Cancer 2009;45:228&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19097774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavallari I, Ruff CT, Nordio F, Deenadayalu N, Shi M, Lanz H, et al. Clinical events after interruption of anticoagulation in patients with atrial fibrillation: an analysis from the ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48 trial. Int J Cardiol 2018;257:102&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29395361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider BJ, Naidoo J, Santomasso BD, Lacchetti C, Adkins S, Anadkat M, et al. Management of immune-related adverse events in patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy: ASCO Guideline update. J Clin Oncol 2021;39:4073&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34724392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haanen J, Obeid M, Spain L, Carbonnel F, Wang Y, Robert C, et al. Management of toxicities from immunotherapy: ESMO Clinical Practice Guideline for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann Oncol 2022;33:1217&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36270461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maher VE, Fernandes LL, Weinstock C, Tang S, Agarwal S, Brave M, et al. Analysis of the association between adverse events and outcome in patients receiving a programmed death protein 1 or programmed death ligand 1 antibody. J Clin Oncol 2019;37:2730&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31116675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haanen J, Ernstoff M, Wang Y, Menzies A, Puzanov I, Grivas P, et al. Rechallenge patients with immune checkpoint inhibitors following severe immune-related adverse events: review of the literature and suggested prophylactic strategy. J Immunother Cancer 2020;8:e000604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7295425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32532839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baba T, Sakai F, Kato T, Kusumoto M, Kenmotsu H, Sugiura H, et al. Radiologic features of pneumonitis associated with nivolumab in non-small-cell lung cancer and malignant melanoma. Future Oncol 2019;15:1911&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka K, Yanagihara T, Ikematsu Y, Inoue H, Ota K, Kashiwagi E, et al. Detection of identical T cell clones in peritumoral pleural effusion and pneumonitis lesions in a cancer patient during immune-checkpoint blockade. Oncotarget 2018;9:30587&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6078130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30093971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kato R, Hayashi H, Tanizaki J, Tanaka K, Takeda M, Nakagawa K. Peritumoural ground-glass opacity associated with tumour pseudoprogression in a patient with non-small cell lung cancer treated with nivolumab. ESMO Open 2017;2:e000145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5519799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28761729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>