<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39571250</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-8332</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>198</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lung cancer (Amsterdam, Netherlands)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lung Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comprehensive serum biomarker analysis reveals IL-8 changes as the only predictor of the effectiveness of immune checkpoint inhibitors for patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108017</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108017</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lungcan.2024.108017</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0169-5002(24)00551-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1) expression is widely used to predict the effectiveness of PD-(L)1 inhibitors despite its imperfection. Previous studies suggested the utilization of various serum biomarkers; nonetheless, findings are inconclusive because of limited sample sizes or the focus on a single biomarker in many of these studies. This study analyzed multiplex serum biomarkers to explore their predictive ability in a large cohort of patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC) treated with a PD-L1 inhibitor in a real-world setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a sub-study of J-TAIL, a prospective observational study of atezolizumab monotherapy in pre-treated patients with advanced NSCLC. From April to October 2019, 262 patients were enrolled from 73 sites in Japan. Serum samples were collected at baseline and at the second dose of atezolizumab. Quantification of the 51 serum cytokines, chemokines, growth factors, and vascular endothelial growth factors was performed using the Luminex platform. Baseline values and fold changes of the time of the second dose to the baseline were examined in association with the effectiveness of atezolizumab.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among the 51 proteins assessed, a higher baseline interleukin (IL)-12 level, a higher soluble CD40 ligand fold change, a lower IL-8 fold change were associated with higher objective response rate (ORR). Of these, only the lower IL-8 fold change was associated with better progression-free survival (PFS) (adjusted hazard ratio, 1.98; 95&#xa0;% confidence interval, 1.45-2.70; P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.01). Multivariate analysis demonstrated that the lower IL-8 fold change was an independent factor for both the ORR and PFS. The IL-8 fold change was independent of the neutrophil/lymphocyte ratio, and durable PFS was observed in patients with both low.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Comprehensive serum biomarker analysis revealed that a lower fold change in serum IL-8 was associated with better outcomes in pre-treated patients with advanced NSCLC receiving atezolizumab.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akamatsu</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koh</LastName><ForeName>Yasuhiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan; Center for Biomedical Sciences, CIMS, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Makoto</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medical Oncology, The Cancer Institute Hospital of Japanese Foundation for Cancer Research, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goto</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Faculty of Medicine, Kindai University, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miura</LastName><ForeName>Satoru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Niigata Cancer Center Hospital, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tamada</LastName><ForeName>Koji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Yamaguchi University Graduate School of Medicine, Yamaguchi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kagamu</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, International Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gemma</LastName><ForeName>Akihiko</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine and Oncology, Nippon Medical School, Graduate School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshino</LastName><ForeName>Ichiro</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General Thoracic Surgery, Chiba University Graduate School of Medicine, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Misumi</LastName><ForeName>Toshihiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Yokohama City University School of Medicine, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mouri</LastName><ForeName>Atsuto</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, International Medical Center, Saitama Medical University, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saito</LastName><ForeName>Ryota</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Tohoku University Hospital, Miyagi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takase</LastName><ForeName>Naoto</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Takarazuka City Hospital, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yanagitani</LastName><ForeName>Noriko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medical Oncology, The Cancer Institute Hospital of Japanese Foundation for Cancer Research, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nokihara</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine and Rheumatology, Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences, Tokushima University, Tokushima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seike</LastName><ForeName>Masahiro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine and Oncology, Nippon Medical School, Graduate School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takamura</LastName><ForeName>Kei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Obihiro-Kosei General Hospital, Hokkaido, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, NHO Osaka Toneyama Medical Center, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Iwasawa</LastName><ForeName>Shunichiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Shintaro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mitsudomi</LastName><ForeName>Tetsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kindai Hospital Global Research Alliance Center and Thoracic Surgery, Kindai University, 377-2 Ohno-Higashi, Osaka-Sayama, Osaka 589-8511, Japan. Electronic address: mitsudom@med.kindai.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Ireland</Country><MedlineTA>Lung Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8800805</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0169-5002</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014408">Biomarkers, Tumor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000082082">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016209">Interleukin-8</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>52CMI0WC3Y</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000594389">atezolizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C508606">CXCL8 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014408" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biomarkers, Tumor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000082082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016209" MajorTopicYN="Y">Interleukin-8</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atezolizumab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemokine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cytokine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immune checkpoint inhibitor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Interleukin-8</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-small cell lung cancer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Hiroaki Akamatsu has received grants or contracts from Amgen, Eli Lilly, and Chugai; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speaker&#x2019;s bureau, manuscript writing, or educational events from Amgen, Ono, AstraZeneca, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Takeda, Bristol Myers Squibb, Taiho, Chugai, Eli Lilly, MSD, Nippon Kayaku, and Novartis; and has participated in Data Safety Monitoring Boards or Advisory Boards for Amgen and Janssen. Yasuhiro Koh has received grants or contracts from Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Takeda, Zeon, and Chugai; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speaker&#x2019;s bureau, manuscript writing, or educational events from Amgen, Takeda, Chugai, Guardant Health, CytoGen, Tosoh, and Novartis; and has participated in Data Safety Monitoring Boards or Advisory Boards for Tosoh. Makoto Nishio has received payment or honoraria for lectures from Ono, Chugai, Taiho, Bristol Myers Squibb, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, AstraZeneca, MSD, AbbVie, Takeda, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Nippon Kayaku, Merck, and Janssen. Yasushi Goto has received grants or contracts from AstraZeneca, and Pfizer; grants for the institution from AbbVie, Eli Lilly, Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono, Novartis, Kyorin, Daiichi Sankyo, Novartis, and Preferred Network; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speaker&#x2019;s bureau, manuscript writing, or educational events from Eli Lilly, Chugai, Taiho, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono, Bristol Myers Squibb, Pfizer, MSD, Novartis, Merck, and Thermo Fisher; has participated in Data Safety Monitoring Boards or Advisory Boards for AstraZeneca, Chugai, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Taiho, Pfizer, Novartis, Guardant Health, Illumina, Daiichi Sankyo, Ono, Bristol Myers Squibb, and MSD; and had a leadership or fiduciary role in Cancer Net Japan and JAMT. Hidetoshi Hayashi has received grants or contracts from IQVIA Services, Syneos Health, EPS Corporation, Nippon Kayaku, Takeda, MSD, Amgen, Taiho, Bristol Myers Squibb, Janssen, CMIC, Pfizer, Labcorp Drug Development, Kobayashi, Eisai, EP-CRSU, Shionogi, Otsuka, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Chugai, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, SRL Medisearch, PRA Health Sciences, Astellas Pharma, Ascent Development Services, Bayer Yakuhin, Parexel, Kissei, EPS Corporation, Daiichi Sankyo, Ono, PPD-SNBL, SymBio, Mebix, AstraZeneca, Mochida, Japan Clinical Research Operations, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Otsuka, and SRL; payment or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speaker&#x2019;s bureau, manuscript writing, or educational events from Ono, Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Chugai Pharmaceutical, MSD, Pfizer, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Merck, 3H Clinical Trial, Novartis, Bristol Myers Squibb, Amgen, Sysmex Corporation, Takeda, and Guardant Health. Satoru Miura has received payment or honoraria for lectures from Chugai, Taiho, Ono, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Boehringer Ingelheim, and Takeda. Hiroshi Kagamu has received payment or honoraria for lectures from Chugai, Ono, AstraZeneca, and Bristol Myers Squibb. Ichiro Yoshino has received grants or contracts from AstraZeneca, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, and Taiho; consulting fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai, Covidien, and Johnson &amp; Johnson; and payment or honoraria for lectures from AstraZeneca, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Covidien, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Taiho, Amgen, MSD, CSL Behring, KM Biologics, Intuitive Surgical, Shionogi, Tsumura, and Takeda. Toshihiro Misumi has received honoraria for lectures, presentations, speaker&#x2019;s bureau, manuscript writing, or educational events from Chugai, AstraZeneca, and Miyarisan. Atsuto Mouri has received payment or honoraria for lectures from Chugai. Noriko Yanagitani has received consulting fee from Chugai and payment or honoraria for lectures from AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Pfizer, Chugai, Takeda, Bayer Yakuhin, Ono, and Bristol Myers Squibb. Hiroshi Nokihara has received payment or honoraria for lectures from MSD, Ono, AstraZeneca, and Chugai. Masahiro Seike has received payment or honoraria for lectures from Chugai, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Pfizer, Takeda, Nippon Kayaku, Merck Biopharma, MSD, Taiho, Ono, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Kyowa-Kirin, and Daiichi-Sankyo. Masahide Mori has received research funding from Chugai, Ono, MSD, and Delta-fly; and payment or honoraria for lectures from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, MSD, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Chugai, Taiho, Kyowa-Kirin, Ono, Otsuka, Nihon-Kayaku, Pfizer, Daiichi Sankyo, Takeda, and Shionogi. Tetsuya Mitsudomi has received grants or contracts from MSD, Ono, AstraZeneca, and Chugai; payment or honoraria for speaker&#x2019;s bureau from MSD, Ono, Bristol Myers Squibb, AstraZeneca, and Chugai; has participated in Advisory Boards for MSD, Ono, Bristol Myers Squibb, AstraZeneca, and Chugai; and has been a President at IASLC. The remaining authors have no conflict of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39571250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2024.108017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0169-5002(24)00551-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>