<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39694703</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2051-1426</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>18</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal for immunotherapy of cancer</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Immunother Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of immune checkpoint inhibitor efficacy for solid tumors with <i>CD274</i> (PD-L1 gene) amplification identified by comprehensive genomic profiling: retrospective study based on a nationwide database.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e010130</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1136/jitc-2024-010130</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Amplification of the programmed cell death-ligand 1 gene (<i>CD274</i>) is highly prevalent and associated with a high response rate to immune checkpoint inhibitors (ICIs) in lymphomas, and is also a potential biomarker for ICI treatment of solid tumors. However, the efficacy of ICIs for solid tumors with <i>CD274</i> amplification identified by comprehensive genomic profiling (CGP) has been unclear. We here examined ICI efficacy for solid tumors with <i>CD274</i> amplification identified by CGP in a national database.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We retrospectively analyzed data from the Center for Cancer Genomics and Advanced Therapeutics database containing 60,155 CGP test results for individuals with solid tumors. Only clinical data from patients treated with ICIs alone (not those undergoing concomitant therapy with molecularly targeted or cytotoxic chemotherapeutic agents) were evaluated. We matched 48 patients in the <i>CD274</i> amplification-positive group with 170 patients in the <i>CD274</i> amplification-negative group in a 1:4 ratio based on tumor type, histology, treatment, and age. Overall survival (OS), time to next treatment (TTNT), and response rate were evaluated as treatment outcomes in the two groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">OS was similar in the <i>CD274</i>-amplified and matched <i>CD274</i>-non-amplified groups (median of 22.1 vs 26.3 months, respectively; HR of 0.92 with a 95% CI of 0.55 to 1.54; p=0.075). TTNT tended to be longer in the <i>CD274</i>-amplified group than in the matched <i>CD274</i>-non-amplified group (median of 16.5 vs 14.0 months; HR of 0.63 with a 95%&#x2009;CI of 0.37 to 1.08; p=0.091). The objective response rate was 33.3% and 18.4% (difference of 14.9%, with a 95%&#x2009;CI of -0.2% to 31.6%), and the disease control rate was 63.9% and 41.1% (difference of 22.8%, with a 95%&#x2009;CI of 5.1% to 40.4%), in the <i>CD274</i>-amplified and matched <i>CD274</i>-non-amplified groups, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The number of patients with solid tumors positive for <i>CD274</i> amplification in this analysis is the largest to date, and our results suggest that such gene amplification may be associated with the outcome of ICI treatment in such individuals. <i>CD274</i> amplification identified by CGP may therefore be a predictor of ICI efficacy for solid tumors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">UMIN000029779.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; Author(s) (or their employer(s)) 2024. Re-use permitted under CC BY-NC. No commercial re-use. See rights and permissions. Published by BMJ Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakayama</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Oncology, Kishiwada City Hospital, Kishiwada, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahama</LastName><ForeName>Takayuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0321-6718</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan takahama_t@med.kindai.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genome Medical Center, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiba</LastName><ForeName>Yasutaka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Center, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiraishi</LastName><ForeName>Naoki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genome Medical Center, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawakami</LastName><ForeName>Hisato</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3280-4850</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yonesaka</LastName><ForeName>Kimio</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genome Medical Center, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cancer Center, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8787-5587</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Immunother Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101620585</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2051-1426</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000082082">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060890">B7-H1 Antigen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C423236">CD274 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000082082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060890" MajorTopicYN="Y">B7-H1 Antigen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005784" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Amplification</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D023281" MajorTopicYN="N">Genomics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarker</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Solid tumor</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: TN has received honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, and Daiichi Sankyo. TT has received grant or contracts from Pfizer Japan and Takeda Pharmaceutical; and honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Takeda Pharmaceutical, MSD, Roche Diagnostics and Novartis Pharma. NS has received honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Novartis Pharma and Life Technologies Japan. HK has received grant or contracts from Eisai, Bristol Myers Squibb and Kobayashi Pharmaceutical; royalties or licenses from Medical &amp; Biological Laboratories; consulting fees from Daiichi Sankyo, Astellas Pharma, AbbVie; and honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb, Bayer Yakuhin, Eli Lilly Japan, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Merck Biopharma, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Yakult Pharmaceutical Industry, Teijin Pharma, Taiho Pharmaceutical, GlaxoSmithKline, Amgen and Novartis International. KY has received honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical and MSD; and Patents planned, issued or pending from Daiichi Sankyo. KN has received grant or contracts from IQVIA Services Japan, Syneos Health Clinical, EPS Corporation, Nippon Kayaku, EPS International, Daiichi Sankyo, Takeda Pharmaceutical, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Amgen, Taiho Pharmaceutical, EP-CRSU, Mebix, Bristol Myers Squibb, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G K, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical, Pfizer Japan, Astellas Pharma, Eisai, AstraZeneca, Mochida Pharmaceutical, Labcorp Development Japan (Covance Japan), Japan Clinical Research Operations, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, SRL, Medical Research Support, Eli Lilly Japan, Novartis Pharma, CMIC, Bayer Yakuhin, Shionogi &amp; Co, PRA Health Sciences and Ascent Development Services; consulting fees from Eli Lilly Japan and Ono Pharmaceutical; payment or honoraria from Ono Pharmaceutical, Amgen, Nippon Kayaku, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, MSD, Pfizer Japan, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bayer Yakuhin, Daiichi Sankyo, Incyte Biosciences Japan, M3, Global Health Consulting Japan, The Yomiuri Shimbun, Merck Biopharma, Taiyo Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Life Technologies Japan, Neo Communication, Novartis Pharma, Medical Mobile Communications, YODOSHA, CMIC Shift Zero, Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Ostuka Pharmaceutical Factory and Hisamitsu Pharmaceutics; and Patents planned, issued or pending from Daiichi Sankyo. HH has received grants or contracts from IQVIA Services Japan, Eisai, Syneos Health Clinical, EP-CRSU, EPS Corporation, Shionogi &amp; Co, Nippon Kayaku, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical, GlaxoSmithKline, MSD, Sanofi, Amgen, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, PRA Health Sciences, CMIC, Astellas Pharma, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan, Ascent Development Services, Labcorp Development Japan, Eisai, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical, Bayer Yakuhin, Pfizer Japan, AstraZeneca, AbbVie, Daiichi Sankyo, A2 Healthcare, Novartis Pharma, Eli Lilly Japan, Merck Biopharma, Medpace Japan, Kyowa Kirin, Japanese Gastric Cancer Association, Thoracic Oncology Research Group, Clinical Research Support Center Kyushu, West Japan Oncology Group, Japan Clinical Cancer Research Organization, Comprehensive Support Project for Oncological Research of Breast Cancer, EPS International, Mebix, Ono Pharmaceutical, Mochida Pharmaceutical, Covance Japan, Japan Clinical Research Operations and Medical Research Support; payment or honoraria from Ono Pharmaceutical, Merck Biopharma, Daiichi Sankyo, 3H Clinical Trial, AstraZeneca, Novartis Pharma, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Eli Lilly Japan, Amgen, MSD, Sysmex Corporation, Pfizer Japan, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Janssen Pharmaceutical and Guardant Health Japan; and has participated on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board of Bristol Myers Squibb Company, AbbVie, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Novocure, AstraZeneca, Daiichi Sankyo, Janssen Pharmaceutical. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39694703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11667388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jitc-2024-010130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jitc-2024-010130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Le DT, Uram JN, Wang H, et al. PD-1 Blockade in Tumors with Mismatch-Repair Deficiency. N Engl J Med. 2015;372:2509&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1500596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1500596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4481136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26028255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan TA, Yarchoan M, Jaffee E, et al. Development of tumor mutation burden as an immunotherapy biomarker: utility for the oncology clinic. Ann Oncol. 2019;30:44&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdy495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdy495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6336005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30395155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roemer MGM, Advani RH, Ligon AH, et al. PD-L1 and PD-L2 Genetic Alterations Define Classical Hodgkin Lymphoma and Predict Outcome. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34:2690&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2016.66.4482.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2016.66.4482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5019753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27069084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ansell SM, Lesokhin AM, Borrello I, et al. PD-1 blockade with nivolumab in relapsed or refractory Hodgkin&#x2019;s lymphoma. N Engl J Med. 2015;372:311&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1411087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1411087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4348009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25482239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armand P, Shipp MA, Ribrag V, et al. Programmed Death-1 Blockade With Pembrolizumab in Patients With Classical Hodgkin Lymphoma After Brentuximab Vedotin Failure. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34:3733&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2016.67.3467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2016.67.3467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5791838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27354476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi M, Roemer MGM, Chapuy B, et al. Expression of programmed cell death 1 ligand 2 (PD-L2) is a distinguishing feature of primary mediastinal (thymic) large B-cell lymphoma and associated with PDCD1LG2 copy gain. Am J Surg Pathol. 2014;38:1715&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1097/PAS.0000000000000297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PAS.0000000000000297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4994970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25025450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapuy B, Roemer MGM, Stewart C, et al. Targetable genetic features of primary testicular and primary central nervous system lymphomas. Blood. 2016;127:869&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1182/blood-2015-10-673236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2015-10-673236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26702065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zinzani PL, Thieblemont C, Melnichenko V, et al. Pembrolizumab in relapsed or refractory primary mediastinal large B-cell lymphoma: final analysis of KEYNOTE-170. Blood. 2023;142:141&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1182/blood.2022019340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2022019340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10651864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37130017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nayak L, Iwamoto FM, LaCasce A, et al. PD-1 blockade with nivolumab in relapsed/refractory primary central nervous system and testicular lymphoma. Blood. 2017;129:3071&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1182/blood-2017-01-764209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2017-01-764209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5766844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28356247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman AM, Piccioni D, Kato S, et al. Prevalence of PDL1 Amplification and Preliminary Response to Immune Checkpoint Blockade in Solid Tumors. JAMA Oncol. 2018;4:1237&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2018.1701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2018.1701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6139049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29902298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang RSP, Haberberger J, Severson E, et al. A pan-cancer analysis of PD-L1 immunohistochemistry and gene amplification, tumor mutation burden and microsatellite instability in 48,782 cases. Mod Pathol. 2021;34:252&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1038/s41379-020-00664-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41379-020-00664-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32884129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang RSP, Murugesan K, Montesion M, et al. Pan-cancer landscape of CD274 (PD-L1) copy number changes in 244 584 patient samples and the correlation with PD-L1 protein expression. J Immunother Cancer. 2021;9:e002680. doi: 10.1136/jitc-2021-002680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jitc-2021-002680</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33972391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorscher S, Resnick J, Goodman M. First Case Report of a Dramatic Radiographic Response to a Checkpoint Inhibitor in a Patient With Proficient Mismatch Repair Gene Expressing Metastatic Colorectal Cancer. JCO Precis Oncol. 2017;1:1&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1200/PO.16.00005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/PO.16.00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35172480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikeda S, Goodman AM, Cohen PR, et al. Metastatic basal cell carcinoma with amplification of PD-L1: exceptional response to anti-PD1 therapy. NPJ Genom Med. 2016;1:16037. doi: 10.1038/npjgenmed.2016.37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/npjgenmed.2016.37</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5142752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27942391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue Y, Yoshimura K, Nishimoto K, et al. Evaluation of Programmed Death Ligand 1 (PD-L1) Gene Amplification and Response to Nivolumab Monotherapy in Non-small Cell Lung Cancer. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3:e2011818. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.11818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2020.11818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7506518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32955570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murugesan K, Jin DX, Comment LA, et al. Association of CD274 (PD-L1) Copy Number Changes with Immune Checkpoint Inhibitor Clinical Benefit in Non-Squamous Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer. Oncologist. 2022;27:732&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1093/oncolo/oyac096.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oncolo/oyac096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9438920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35598202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA  Summary of safety and effectiveness data (ssed) for p170019s048: &#x201c;Essure system". 2023. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/cdrh_docs/pdf17/P170019S048B.pdf Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PMDA  Approval information for medical device: &#x201c;Product code: 23000bzx00398000. 2023. https://www.pmda.go.jp/PmdaSearch/kikiDetail/ResultDataSetPDF/480585_23000BZX00398000_A_05_01 Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA  FDA approves pembrolizumab for adults and children with tmb-h solid tumors. 2020. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/drug-approvals-and-databases/fda-approves-pembrolizumab-adults-and-children-tmb-h-solid-tumors Available.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanda Y. Investigation of the freely available easy-to-use software &#x201c;EZR&#x201d; for medical statistics. Bone Marrow Transplant. 2013;48:452&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1038/bmt.2012.244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bmt.2012.244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3590441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23208313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohno T, Kato M, Kohsaka S, et al. C-CAT: The National Datacenter for Cancer Genomic Medicine in Japan. Cancer Discov. 2022;12:2509&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1158/2159-8290.CD-22-0417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/2159-8290.CD-22-0417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9762342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36321305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>