<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40743487</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2332-7812</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurology(R) neuroimmunology &amp; neuroinflammation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-Term Efficacy and Safety of Satralizumab in Patients With Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum Disorder From the SAkuraMoon Open-Label Extension Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e200450</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e200450</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e200450</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1212/NXI.0000000000200450</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Satralizumab (SAT), an interleukin-6 receptor inhibitor, reduced the risk of protocol-defined relapse (PDR) vs placebo (PBO) with a favorable safety profile in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD) in 2 pivotal phase 3 trials, SAkuraSky and SAkuraStar. We evaluated the long-term safety and efficacy of SAT in patients with NMOSD in the single-arm, open-label, rollover study SAkuraMoon.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients who completed the double-blind periods (DBPs) and open-label extensions (OLEs) of SAkuraSky and SAkuraStar were enrolled in SAkuraMoon, where they continued receiving subcutaneous SAT 120 mg 4 times a week (Q4W) &#xb1; immunosuppressive therapy. Safety analyses included all patients who received &#x2265;1 dose of SAT in the overall SAT treatment (OST) period. The rates of adverse events (AEs) and infections per 100 patient-years (PYs) in the OST vs the DBPs were compared. Efficacy analyses were performed in the aquaporin-4 immunoglobulin-G-seropositive (AQP4-IgG+) population. Annualized investigator-assessed PDR rate (i.e., annualized relapse rate, ARR), time to first investigator-reported PDR (iPDR), severe iPDR (increase of &#x2265;2 points in the Expanded Disability Status Scale [EDSS] score), and sustained EDSS score worsening were reported. The data cutoff date of these analyses was May 28, 2024.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Overall, 166 patients with NMOSD were included in the analysis. The median (range) SAT exposure in the OST period was 6.9 years (0-10). Rates of AEs and serious AEs (95% CI) in the OST period (AEs: 299.4 (288.8-310.2)/100 PYs; serious AEs: 8.1 (6.4-10.0)/100 PYs) were lower compared with the DBP. Rates of infections (87.5 [81.9-93.5]/100 PYs) and serious infections (2.4 [1.5-3.5]/100 PYs) in the OST period were comparable with those of the DBP and did not increase over time. No fatalities occurred. In the AQP4-IgG+ population (n = 111), the overall adjusted ARR (95% CI) was 0.07 (0.05-0.10). At Week 456 (8.8 years), 67% (56%-76%), 89% (80%-94%), and 82% (72%-89%) of SAT-treated patients were free from iPDR, severe iPDR, and sustained EDSS score worsening, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The safety and efficacy of SAT (&#xb1;IST) is sustained with long-term treatment, supporting SAT as an effective maintenance therapy option for patients with AQP4-IgG+ NMOSD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION INFORMATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ClinicalTrials.gov registration numbers: NCT02028884 (SAkuraSky), NCT02073279 (SAkuraStar), and NCT04660539 (SAkuraMoon); EudraCT: 2020-003413-35 (SAkuraMoon).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLASSIFICATION OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study provides Class IV evidence that SAT is safe and effective in patients with NMOSD.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bennett</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3346-1394</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Neurology and Ophthalmology, University of Colorado School of Medicine, Aurora, CO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujihara</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3096-4156</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Multiple Sclerosis Therapeutics, Fukushima Medical University School of Medicine, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multiple Sclerosis and Neuromyelitis Optica Center, Southern TOHOKU Research Institute for Neuroscience, Fukushima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saiz</LastName><ForeName>Albert</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5793-8791</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service of Neurology, Hospital Clinic de Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Traboulsee</LastName><ForeName>Anthony L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0351-9639</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greenberg</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin M</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2091-8201</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weinshenker</LastName><ForeName>Brian G</ForeName><Initials>BG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5806-6203</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Virginia, Charlottesville.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patti</LastName><ForeName>Francesco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6923-0846</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AOU Policlinico Vittorio Emanuele, Universit&#xe0; di Catania, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kleiter</LastName><ForeName>Ingo</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8249-4408</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Marianne-Strau&#xdf;-Klinik, Behandlungszentrum Kempfenhausen f&#xfc;r Multiple Sklerose Kranke GmbH, Berg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ruhr University Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palace</LastName><ForeName>Jacqueline</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4779-6133</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>John Radcliffe Hospital, Oxford, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De Seze</LastName><ForeName>Jerome</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7197-7578</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>H&#xf4;pital de Hautepierre, Strasbourg, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Evans</LastName><ForeName>Rachael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Roche Products Ltd, Welwyn Garden City, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blondeau</LastName><ForeName>Kathleen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-1482-2420</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klingelschmitt</LastName><ForeName>Ga&#xeb;lle</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vodopivec</LastName><ForeName>Ivana</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-9746-2974</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd, Basel, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rahim</LastName><ForeName>Masouda</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-8036-232X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ApotheCom, London, United Kingdom; and.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamura</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9048-0375</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02028884</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT02073279</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT04660539</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101636388</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2332-7812</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>YB18NF020M</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000655944">satralizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007155">Immunologic Factors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2025 Nov;12(6):e200494. doi: 10.1212/NXI.0000000000200494.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41052377</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009471" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuromyelitis Optica</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007155" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immunologic Factors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>J.L. Bennett has performed consultative services for Amgen, Genentech, TG Therapeutics, Alexion, Reistone Bio, Roche, Antigenomycs, Chugai, Mitsubishi Tanabe, EMD Serono, Beigene, Novartis, CorEvitas, Immpact Bio, and ImCyse. He has served on Scientific Advisory or Data Safety Monitoring boards for Clene Nanomedicine and Roche. He has served on a speaker's bureau for Alexion; has received research support from the NIH and the National MS Society; and has received intellectual property interests from a patent on Aquaporumab. K. Fujhara received grants from Ministry of Health, Welfare and Labour of Japan; received personal fees from Roche/Chugai, Alexion, Argenx, Amgen, Biogen, Eisai, Mitsubishi-Tanabe, Novartis, UCB, Sanofi, Teijin, and Asahi Kasei Medical. A. Saiz received personal compensation for consulting, serving on a scientific advisory board, speaking, or other activities with Merck, Sanofi, Biogen, Roche, Novartis, Janssen, and Horizon Therapeutics. A. Traboulsee received consulting fees from Genzyme, Roche, and Novartis and is part of a speakers bureau for Genzyme and Roche. B.M. Greenberg received consulting fees from Alexion, Novartis, EMD Serono, Amgen, Abcuro, Genentech/Roche, Signant, IQVIA, Sandoz, Sanofi/Genzyme, Immunovant, TG Therapeutics, Clene, Arialys, and Syneos. He receives royalties from UpToDate. He has received research grants from Anokion and Regeneron; has received speaker honoraria from PRIME; and holds a patent for GenrAb. He has equity in Clene Nanomedicine and GenrAb. He is a board member of the Siegel Rare Neuroimmune Association. B. Weinshenker reports consulting fees from UCB Biosciences, Horizon, Mitsubishi Tanabe, Genentech, and Roche, and speaking fees from Genentech, Roche, and Novartis; he participated or participates on the Attack Adjudication Committee for Alexion, Horizon Therapeutics (formerly MedImmune/Viela Bio) and UCB Biosciences. He has a patent NMO-IgG for diagnosis of neuromyelitis optica with royalties received from RSR Ltd., Oxford University, Hospices Civils de Lyon, and MVZ Labor PD Dr Volkmann und Kollegen GbR. F. Patti received research grants, fees for speaking activities, consultation or serving on advisory boards from Alexion, Amirall, Biogen, Bristol Meyers, and Squibb, Janssen, Merck, Novartis, Roche, and Sanofi. I. Kleiter has received personal compensation for consulting, serving on a scientific advisory board, speaking or other activities from Alexion, Almirall, Biogen, GlaxoSmithKline, Hexal, Horizon, Merck, Neuraxpharm, Roche/Chugai, and Sanofi. J. Palace has received support for scientific meetings and honorariums for advisory work from Merck Serono, Novartis, Chugai, Alexion, Roche, Medimmune/Horizon, Argenx, Sanofi, UCB, Mitsubishi, Amplo Biotechnology, and Janssen; and research grants from Alexion, Argenx, Roche, Medimmune, UCB, and Amplo biotechnology, Patent ref P37347WO and licence agreement Numares multimarker MS diagnostics. She acknowledges partial funding to the trust by highly specialized services from National Health Service (NHS) England. She is on the medical advisory boards of the Sumaira Foundation and MOG Project charities, is a member of the Guthy Jackon Foundation Charity, and is on the Board of the European Charcot Foundation, a member of MAGNIMS (steering member until February 2024) and the UK NHS England IVIG Committee, and chairman of the NHS England neuroimmunology patient pathway and ECTRIMS Council member on the educational committee since June 2023, current Association of British Neurologists (ABN) advisory groups for MS and neuroinflammation and previous neuromuscular diseases ABN advisory member until April 2024. J. De Seze received grants and personal fees from Roche, received personal fees from Chugai, and has served on advisory boards in the expert committee for the clinical trial conducted by Chugai. R. Evans is an employee of Roche Products Ltd. K. Blondeau is an employee of F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd and Parexel Belgium SRL. G. Klingelschmitt and I. Vodopivec are employees of F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd. M. Rahim is an employee of ApotheCom, London, United Kingdom, who received funding from F. Hoffman-La Roche for medical writing assistance. T. Yamamura served on scientific advisory boards for Chugai, Roche, Biogen Japan, Biogen Massachusetts, Novartis, and Mitsubishi Tanabe; received research grants from Chugai, Novartis, Biogen Japan, Chiome Bioscience, Sanofi, UCB Japan, and Mebix; received speaker honoraria from Chugai, Biogen Japan, Novartis, Mitsubishi Tanabe, Takeda, Miyarisan, Alexion, Sumitomo, and Teijin. Go to Neurology.org/NN for full disclosures.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40743487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12316463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000200450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wingerchuk DM, Banwell B, Bennett JL, et al. International consensus diagnostic criteria for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Neurology. 2015;85(2):177-189. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000001729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4515040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawachi I, Lassmann H. Neurodegeneration in multiple sclerosis and neuromyelitis optica. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2017;88(2):137-145. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2016-313300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2016-313300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27671902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noori H, Marsool MDM, Gohil KM, et al. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: exploring the diverse clinical manifestations and the need for further exploration. Brain Behav. 2024;14(8):e3644. doi: 10.1002/brb3.3644</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.3644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11319236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39135307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berthele A, Levy M, Wingerchuk DM, et al. A single relapse induces worsening of disability and health-related quality of life in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Front Neurol. 2023;14:141099376. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2023.1099376</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2023.1099376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10126826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37114235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costello F, Burton JM. Contemporary management challenges in seropositive NMOSD. J Neurol. 2022;269(10):5674-5681. doi: 10.1007/s00415-022-11241-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-022-11241-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9272395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35816205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes MTG, Adam RJ, McCombe PA, Walsh M, Blum S. Long-term efficacy and safety of rituximab in the treatment of neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum disorder. Mult Scler J Exp Transl Clin. 2024;10(2):20552173241257876. doi: 10.1177/20552173241257876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552173241257876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11131406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38807849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu YC, Huang TL. What's new in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder treatment? Taiwan J Ophthalmol. 2022;12(3):249-263. doi: 10.4103/2211-5056.355617</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2211-5056.355617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9558477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36248092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thon JM, Sharkus R, Thakkar R, Hunter K, Siegler JE, Thon OR. Utilization of FDA approved treatments for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder in clinical practice: a survey study of academic neuroimmunologists. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2023;80:80105076. doi: 10.1016/j.msard.2023.105076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2023.105076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37866024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pittock SJ, Barnett M, Bennett JL, et al. Ravulizumab in aquaporin-4-positive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Ann Neurol. 2023;93(6):1053-1068. doi: 10.1002/ana.26626</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.26626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36866852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujihara K, Bennett JL, de Seze J, et al. Interleukin-6 in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder pathophysiology. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2020;7(5):e841. doi: 10.1212/NXI.0000000000000841</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000000841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7455314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32820020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Held F, Klein AK, Berthele A. Drug treatment of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: out with the old, in with the new? Immunotargets Ther. 2021;10:1087-1101. doi: 10.2147/ITT.S287652</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/ITT.S287652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7989551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33777853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meher BR, Mohanty RR, Dash A. Review of satralizumab for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a new biologic agent targeting the interleukin-6 receptor. Cureus. 2024;16(2):e55100. doi: 10.7759/cureus.55100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.55100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10978816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38558672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamura T, Kleiter I, Fujihara K, et al. Trial of satralizumab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. N Engl J Med. 2019;381(22):2114-2124. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1901747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1901747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31774956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traboulsee A, Greenberg BM, Bennett JL, et al. Safety and efficacy of satralizumab monotherapy in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a randomised, double-blind, multicentre, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19(5):402-412. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30078-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30078-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7935419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamura T, Weinshenker B, Yeaman MR, et al. Long-term safety of satralizumab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD) from SAkuraSky and SAkuraStar. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;66:66104025. doi: 10.1016/j.msard.2022.104025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2022.104025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36007339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleiter I, Traboulsee A, Palace J, et al. Long-term efficacy of satralizumab in AQP4-IgG-seropositive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder from SAkuraSky and SAkuraStar. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2023;10(1):e200071. doi: 10.1212/NXI.0000000000200071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000200071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9756307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36724181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McElvaney OJ, Curley GF, Rose-John S, McElvaney NG. Interleukin-6: obstacles to targeting a complex cytokine in critical illness. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(6):643-654. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00103-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(21)00103-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8051931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33872590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choy EH, De Benedetti F, Takeuchi T, Hashizume M, John MR, Kishimoto T. Translating IL-6 biology into effective treatments. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2020;16(6):335-345. doi: 10.1038/s41584-020-0419-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41584-020-0419-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7178926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32327746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abna Z, Fazeli SA, Khanmoradi Z, Sahraian MA. Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum Disorders (NMOSD) and structural renal diseases: a literature review. Neuroimmunology Rep. 2024;6:100220. doi: 10.1016/j.nerep.2024.100220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nerep.2024.100220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Carvalho FL, Gomes CM, Apostolos-Pereira SL, et al. Voiding dysfunction in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Neurourol Urodyn. 2016;35(1):39-43. doi: 10.1002/nau.22667</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nau.22667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25212666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enspyng PI. 2020. Accessed March 2022. accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2020/761149s000lbl.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy M, Haycox AR, Becker U, et al. Quantifying the relationship between disability progression and quality of life in patients treated for NMOSD: insights from the SAkura studies. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;57:57103332. doi: 10.1016/j.msard.2021.103332</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2021.103332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35158426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palace J, Lin DY, Zeng D, et al. Outcome prediction models in AQP4-IgG positive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Brain. 2019;142(5):1310-1323. doi: 10.1093/brain/awz054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awz054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6487334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30938427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RA, Mealy MA, Levy M. Early indicators of relapses vs pseudorelapses in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2016;3(5):e269. doi: 10.1212/NXI.0000000000000269</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000000269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4966291</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27508210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamid SHM, Whittam D, Mutch K, et al. What proportion of AQP4-IgG-negative NMO spectrum disorder patients are MOG-IgG positive? A cross sectional study of 132 patients. J Neurol. 2017;264(10):2088-2094. doi: 10.1007/s00415-017-8596-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-017-8596-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5617862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28840314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lennon VA, Wingerchuk DM, Kryzer TJ, et al. A serum autoantibody marker of neuromyelitis optica: distinction from multiple sclerosis. Lancet. 2004;364(9451):2106-2112. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(04)17551-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(04)17551-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15589308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>