<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37265862</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2634-3916</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European heart journal. Digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Heart J Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A prospective, randomized, controlled, multicentre trial for secondary prevention in patients with chronic coronary syndrome using a smartphone application for digital therapy: the CHANGE study protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>207</StartPage><EndPage>215</EndPage><MedlinePgn>207-215</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/ehjdh/ztad012</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Coronary artery disease (CAD) remains the leading cause of death worldwide. 'Stable' CAD is a chronic progressive condition, which recent European guidelines recommend referring to as 'chronic coronary syndrome' (CCS). Despite therapeutic advances, morbidity and mortality among patients with CCS remain high. Optimal secondary prevention in patients with CCS includes optimization of modifiable risk factors with behavioural changes and pharmacological therapy. The CHANGE study aims to provide evidence for optimization of secondary prevention in CCS patients by using a smartphone application (app).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS AND RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The CHANGE study is designed as a prospective, randomized, controlled trial with a 1:1 allocation ratio, which is currently performed in nine centres in Germany in a parallel group design. 210 patients with CCS will be randomly allocated either to the control group (standard-of-care) or to the intervention group, who will be provided the VantisTherapy* app in addition to standard-of-care to incorporate secondary prevention into their daily life. The study will be performed in an open design. Outcomes will be assessed using objective data from three in-person visits (0, 12, and 24 weeks). Primary outcomes will involve adherence to secondary prevention recommendations and quality of life (QoL). The recruitment process started in July 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The CHANGE study will investigate whether a smartphone-guided secondary prevention app, combined with a monitor function compared with standard-of-care, has beneficial effects on overall adherence to secondary prevention guidelines and QoL in patients with CCS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study is listed at the German study registry (DRKS) under the registered number DRKS00028081.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the European Society of Cardiology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>D&#xfc;sing</LastName><ForeName>Philip</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1394-6471</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine II, Heart Center, University Hospital Bonn, Venusberg Campus 1, 53127 Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eckardt</LastName><ForeName>Irina</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine II, Heart Center, University Hospital Bonn, Venusberg Campus 1, 53127 Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schirmer</LastName><ForeName>Stephan H</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kardiopraxis Schirmer, Am Altenhof 8, 67655 Kaiserslautern, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sinning</LastName><ForeName>Jan-Malte</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, St. Vinzenz Hospital Cologne, Mehrheimer Str. 221-223, 50733 Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Werner</LastName><ForeName>Nikos</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Department III, Heart Center Trier, Krankenhaus der Barmherzigen Br&#xfc;der, Nordallee 1, 54292 Trier, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>B&#xf6;nner</LastName><ForeName>Florian</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Pulmonology, and Vascular Medicine, Medical Faculty of Heinrich Heine University, University Hospital D&#xfc;sseldorf, Moorenstr 5, 40225 D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krogmann</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kardio-Lev, Kardiologische Gemeinschaftspraxis Dr. P. Son, Dr. M. P&#xe4;sler, Dr. A. Krogmann, Friedrich-Ebert-Str. 17, 51373 Leverkusen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sch&#xe4;fer</LastName><ForeName>Sebastian</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Praxis Rheingalerie Rodenkirchen, Hauptstr 39-41, 50996 Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sedaghat</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rhein-Ahr-Cardio, Praxis f&#xfc;r Kardiologie, Wilhelmstr 14, 53474 Bad Neuenahr-Ahrweiler, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;ller</LastName><ForeName>Cornelius</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kardio Bonn, Gemeinschaftspraxis Dr. La Ros&#xe9;e &amp; Prof. M&#xfc;ller, Baumschulallee 1, 53115 Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nickenig</LastName><ForeName>Georg</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine II, Heart Center, University Hospital Bonn, Venusberg Campus 1, 53127 Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zietzer</LastName><ForeName>Andreas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5759-7627</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine II, Heart Center, University Hospital Bonn, Venusberg Campus 1, 53127 Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Heart J Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101778323</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2634-3916</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic coronary syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Secondary prevention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest: A.Z. received a lecture fee from Vantis GmbH on one occasion. The authors declare no conflicts of interest. The authors are not employees or beneficiaries of the Vantis GmbH.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37265862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10232292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ehjdh/ztad012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ztad012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ross R. Atherosclerosis&#x2014;an inflammatory disease. N Engl J Med 1999;340:115&#x2013;126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9887164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knuuti J, Wijns W, Saraste A, Capodanno D, Barbato E, Funck-Brentano C, et al. 2019 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and management of chronic coronary syndromes. Eur Heart J 2020;41:407&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Deutscher Herzbericht 2020 (German Heart Report 2020)&#x2014;Deutsche Herzstiftung. https://www.herzstiftung.de/system/files/2021-06/Deutscher-Herzbericht-2020.pdf (13 January).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization . The top 10 causes of death. 2020. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/the-top-10-causes-of-death (2 September 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmis A, Vardas P, Townsend N, Torbica A, Katus H, De Smedt D, et al. European Society of Cardiology: cardiovascular disease statistics 2021. Eur Heart J 2022;43:ehab892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35016208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth GA, Mensah GA, Johnson CO, Addolorato G, Ammirati E, Baddour LM, et al. Global burden of cardiovascular diseases and risk factors, 1990&#x2013;2019. J Am Coll Cardiol 2020;76:2982&#x2013;3021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7755038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33309175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booth JN, Levitan EB, Brown TM, Farkouh ME, Safford MM, Muntner P. Effect of sustaining lifestyle modifications (nonsmoking, weight reduction, physical activity, and Mediterranean diet) after healing of myocardial infarction, percutaneous intervention, or coronary bypass (from the REasons for Geographic and Racial Differences in Stroke Study). Am J Cardiol 2014;113:1933&#x2013;1940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4348576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24793668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelliccia A, Sharma S, Gati S, B&#xe4;ck M, B&#xf6;rjesson M, Caselli S, et al. 2020 ESC guidelines on sports cardiology and exercise in patients with cardiovascular disease. Eur Heart J 2021;42:17&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusuf S, Hawken S, &#xd4;unpuu S, Dans T, Avezum A, Lanas F, et al. Effect of potentially modifiable risk factors associated with myocardial infarction in 52 countries (the INTERHEART study): case-control study. Lancet 2004;364:937&#x2013;952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15364185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow CK, Jolly S, Rao-Melacini P, Fox KAA, Anand SS, Yusuf S. Association of diet, exercise, and smoking modification with risk of early cardiovascular events after acute coronary syndromes. Circulation 2010;121:750&#x2013;758.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20124123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avis SR, Vernon ST, Hagstr&#xf6;m E, Figtree GA. Coronary artery disease in the absence of traditional risk factors: a call for action. Eur Heart J 2021;42:3822&#x2013;3824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34293105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collet JP, Thiele H, Barbato E, Barth&#xe9;l&#xe9;my O, Bauersachs J, Bhatt DL, et al. 2020 ESC guidelines for the management of acute coronary syndromes in patients presenting without persistent ST-segment elevation. Eur Heart J 2021;42:1289&#x2013;1367.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibanez B, James S, Agewall S, Antunes MJ, Bucciarelli-Ducci C, Bueno H, et al. 2017 ESC guidelines for the management of acute myocardial infarction in patients presenting with ST-segment elevation. Eur Heart J 2018;39:119&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28886621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visseren FLJ, Mach F, Smulders YM, Carballo D, Koskinas KC, B&#xe4;ck M, et al. 2021 ESC guidelines on cardiovascular disease prevention in clinical practice. Eur Heart J 2021;42:3227&#x2013;3337.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34458905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotseva K, Wood D, De Bacquer D, De Backer G, Ryd&#xe9;n L, Jennings C, et al. EUROASPIRE IV: a European Society of Cardiology survey on the lifestyle, risk factor and therapeutic management of coronary patients from 24 European countries. Eur J Prev Cardiol 2016;23:636&#x2013;648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25687109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood D, Kotseva K, Connolly S, Jennings C, Mead A, Jones J, et al. Nurse-coordinated multidisciplinary, family-based cardiovascular disease prevention programme (EUROACTION) for patients with coronary heart disease and asymptomatic individuals at high risk of cardiovascular disease: a paired, cluster-randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2008;371:1999&#x2013;2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18555911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckardt I, Buschhaus C, Nickenig G, Jansen F. Smartphone-guided secondary prevention for patients with coronary artery disease. J Rehabil Assist Technol Eng 2021;8:205566832199657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970225</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33796334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark AM, Hartling L, Vandermeer B, McAlister FA. Meta-analysis: secondary prevention programs for patients with coronary artery disease. Ann Intern Med 2005;143:659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16263889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters AE, Keeley EC. Trends and predictors of participation in cardiac rehabilitation following acute myocardial infarction: data from the behavioral risk factor surveillance system. J Am Heart Assoc 2018;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5778971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29288154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizas KD, Freyer L, Sappler N, von St&#xfc;lpnagel L, Spielbichler P, Krasniqi A, et al. Smartphone-based screening for atrial fibrillation: a pragmatic randomized clinical trial. Nat Med 2022;28:1823&#x2013;1830.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36031651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akinosun AS, Polson R, Diaz Skeete Y, De Kock JH, Carragher L, Leslie S, et al. Digital technology interventions for risk factor modification in patients with cardiovascular disease: systematic review and meta-analysis. JMIR MHealth UHealth 2021;9:e21061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7970167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33656444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yun YH, Kang E, Cho YM, Park SM, Kim YJ, Lee HY, et al. Efficacy of an electronic health management program for patients with cardiovascular risk: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res 2020;22:e15057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32012053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin K, Khonsari S, Gallagher R, Gallagher P, Clark AM, Freedman B, et al. Telehealth interventions for the secondary prevention of coronary heart disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Cardiovasc Nurs 2019;18:260&#x2013;271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30667278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelsen H&#xd6;, Sj&#xf6;lin I, B&#xe4;ck M, Gonzalez Garcia M, Olsson A, Sandberg C, et al. Effect of a lifestyle-focused web-based application on risk factor management in patients who have had a myocardial infarction: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res 2022;24:e25224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9015765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35357316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marvel FA, Spaulding EM, Lee MA, Yang WE, Demo R, Ding J, et al. Digital health intervention in acute myocardial infarction. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes 2021;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8288197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34261332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xf8;rs G, Pettersen TR, Hansen TB, Fridlund B, H&#xf8;lvold LB, Lund H, et al. Modes of e-Health delivery in secondary prevention programmes for patients with coronary artery disease: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res 2019;19:364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6558849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31182100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher R, Chow CK, Parker H, Neubeck L, Celermajer DS, Redfern J, et al. The effect of a game-based mobile app &#x2018;MyHeartMate&#x2019; to promote lifestyle change in coronary disease patients: a randomized controlled trial. Eur Heart J Digit Health 2023;4:33&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9890079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36743873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fogg B. A behavior model for persuasive design. In: Proceedings of the 4th International Conference on Persuasive Technology&#x2014;Persuasive &#x2018;09. Claremont, CA: ACM Press; 2009, p1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig CL, Marshall AL, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m M, Bauman AE, Booth ML, Ainsworth BE, et al. International Physical Activity Questionnaire: 12-country reliability and validity. Med Sci Sports Exerc 2003;35:1381&#x2013;1395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der H, Fit&#xf3; M, Estruch R, Mart&#xed;nez-Gonz&#xe1;lez MA, Corella D, Salas-Salvad&#xf3; J, et al. A short screener is valid for assessing Mediterranean diet adherence among older Spanish men and women. J Nutr 2011;141:1140&#x2013;1145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21508208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebestreit K, Yahiaoui-Doktor M, Engel C, Vetter W, Siniatchkin M, Erickson N, et al. Validation of the German version of the Mediterranean Diet Adherence Screener (MEDAS) questionnaire. BMC Cancer 2017;17:341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5437541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28521737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisky DE, Green LW, Levine DM. Concurrent and predictive validity of a self-reported measure of medication adherence. Med Care 1986;24:67&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3945130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisky DE, Malotte CK, Choi P, Davidson P, Rigler S, Sugland B, et al. A patient education program to improve adherence rates with antituberculosis drug regimens. Health Educ Q 1990;17:253&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2228629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisky DE, DiMatteo MR. Improving the measurement of self-reported medication nonadherence: response to authors. J Clin Epidemiol 2011;64:255&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3109729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21144706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huber A, Oldridge N, Benzer W, Saner H, H&#xf6;fer S. Validation of the German HeartQoL: a short health-related quality of life questionnaire for cardiac patients. Qual Life Res 2020;29:1093&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7142053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31832979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stergiou GS, Palatini P, Parati G, O&#x2019;Brien E, Januszewicz A, Lurbe E, et al. 2021 European Society of Hypertension practice guidelines for office and out-of-office blood pressure measurement. J Hypertens 2021;39:1293&#x2013;1302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33710173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;fer S, Kullich W, Graninger U, Wonisch M, Ga&#xdf;ner A, Klicpera M, et al. Cardiac rehabilitation in Austria: long term health-related quality of life outcomes. Health Qual Life Outcomes 2009;7:99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3224906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19995445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoeppe S, Alley S, Van Lippevelde W, Bray NA, Williams SL, Duncan MJ, et al. Efficacy of interventions that use apps to improve diet, physical activity and sedentary behaviour: a systematic review. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 2016;13:127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5142356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27927218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lally P, van Jaarsveld CHM, Potts HWW, Wardle J. How are habits formed: modelling habit formation in the real world. Eur J Soc Psychol 2010;40:998&#x2013;1009.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>