<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37316206</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-0480</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>57</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of sports medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Sports Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Child SCOAT6.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>672</StartPage><EndPage>688</EndPage><MedlinePgn>672-688</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106984</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>Gavin A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8293-4496</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Murdoch Children's Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia gavin.davis@me.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cabrini Health, Malvern, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patricios</LastName><ForeName>Jon S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6829-4098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wits Sport and Health (WiSH), School of Clinical Medicine, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of the Witwatersrand, Johannesburg-Braamfontein, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Purcell</LastName><ForeName>Laura K</ForeName><Initials>LK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderson</LastName><ForeName>Vicki</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Child Neuropsychology, Murdoch Childrens Research Institute, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychology, University of Melbourne, Parkville, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gioia</LastName><ForeName>Gerry</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's National Health System, Washington, District of Columbia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giza</LastName><ForeName>Christopher C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosurgery, UCLA Steve Tisch BrainSPORT Program, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatrics / Pediatric Neurology, Mattel Children's Hospital UCLA, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeates</LastName><ForeName>Keith Owen</ForeName><Initials>KO</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7680-2892</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Osman Hassan</ForeName><Initials>OH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1439-0076</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physiotherapy Department, University Hospitals Dorset NHS Foundation Trust, Poole, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The FA Centre for Para Football Research, The Football Association, Burton-Upon-Trent, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blauwet</LastName><ForeName>Cheri</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8568-1009</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Spaulding Rehabilitation/Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corwin</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Master</LastName><ForeName>Christina L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6717-4270</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics and Sports Medicine, Pediatrics, Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Geoff</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4485-1769</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van Ierssel</LastName><ForeName>Jacqueline</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5519-8526</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario Research Institute, Ottawa, Ontatio, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Echemendia</LastName><ForeName>Ruben J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6116-8462</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychology, University of Missouri Kansas City, Kansas City, Missouri, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychological and Neurobehavioral Associates, Inc, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fremont</LastName><ForeName>Pierre</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2810-8382</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehabilitation, Laval University, Quebec, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fuller</LastName><ForeName>Gordon Ward</ForeName><Initials>GW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8532-3500</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Related Research, University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harmon</LastName><ForeName>Kimberly G</ForeName><Initials>KG</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3670-6609</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Family Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herring</LastName><ForeName>Stanley A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Rehabilitation Medicine, Orthopaedics and Sports Medicine and Neurological Surgery, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Holte</LastName><ForeName>Kirsten</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loosemore</LastName><ForeName>Mike</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4855-0744</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Sport Exercise and Health, University Collage Hospital London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Makdissi</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Florey Institute of Neuroscience and Mental Health - Austin Campus, Heidelberg, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>La Trobe Sport and Exercise Medicine Research Centre, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCrea</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9791-9475</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurosurgery, Medical College of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meehan</LastName><ForeName>William P</ForeName><Initials>WP</Initials><Suffix>3rd</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sports Medicine, Children's Hospital Boston, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency Medicine, Children's Hospital Boston, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Halloran</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1185-3485</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Musculoskeletal Medicine, Royal Orthopaedic Hospital, Birmingham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Premji</LastName><ForeName>Zahra</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6899-0528</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Libraries, University of Victoria, Victoria, British Columbia, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Putukian</LastName><ForeName>Margot</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Major League Soccer, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shill</LastName><ForeName>Isla Jordan</ForeName><Initials>IJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Injury Prevention Research Centre, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turner</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2323-2456</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Concussion and Head Injury Research Foundation, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaandering</LastName><ForeName>Kenzie</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2342-5373</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Calgary Faculty of Kinesiology, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Webborn</LastName><ForeName>Nick</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3636-5557</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Loughborough University, Loughborough, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Kathryn J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5951-5899</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sport Injury Prevention Research Centre, Faculty of Kinesiology, University of Calgary, Calgary, Alberta, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Sports Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0432520</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0306-3674</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain Concussion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Child</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: GAD is a member of the Scientific Committee of the 6th International Consensus Conference on Concussion in Sport; an honorary member of the AFL Concussion Scientific Committee; Section Editor, Sport and Rehabilitation, NEUROSURGERY; and has attended meetings organised by sporting organisations including the NFL, NRL, IIHF, IOC and FIFA; however has not received any payment, research funding, or other monies from these groups other than for travel costs. Dr JSP, Editor BJSM (honorarium), Member of World Rugby Concussion Advisory Group (unpaid), Independent Concussion Consultant for World Rugby (fee per consultation), Medical consultant to South African Rugby (unpaid), Co-chair of the Scienti&#xfb01;c Committee, 6th International Conference on Concussion in Sport (unpaid), Board member of the Concussion in Sport Group (unpaid), Scienti&#xfb01;c Board member, EyeGuideTM (unpaid). Dr LP CASEM Board Member, President-Elect 2022-2023NIH R34 Grant for EPICC Study (Eye Problems In Concussed Children), Site PI Speaker at various conferences. Dr VA Financial: Australian National Health and Medical Research Council and Medical Research Future fund: research grants. Royalties: Pearson Publishing (Test of Everyday Attention) Collaboration: Australian Football League (Partnership agreement to fund research &#x2013; funds go to my institute). Boards: Editorship: Journal of Neuropsychology, Neuropsychology, Journal of Clinical NIH NINDS (R01 NS110757 2019-2024); NINDS(U54 NS121688 2021-2026); UCLA Brain Injury Research Center, UCLA Steve Tisch Brain SPORT program, Easton Clinic for Brain Health Clinical Consultant (provide clinical care to athletes): NBA, NFL-Neurological Care Program,NHL/NHLPA, Los Angeles Lakers Advisory Board (Non compensated): Major League Soccer, National Basketball Association, US Soccer Federation. Advisory Board (Compensated): Highmark Interactive Medicolegal: One or two cases annually Speaker&#x2019;s Bureau: None. Stock Shareholder: Highmark Interactive stock options (2018). Other Financial or Material Support: Book royalties &#x2013; Blackwell/Wiley Publishing: Prioritized Neurological Differential Diagnosis Other: None. Dr KOY: is Editor-in-Chief of the journal Neuropsychology and receive an editorial stipend from the American Psychological Association. I am an unpaid consulting editor for the journals Archives of Clinical Neuropsychology and Journal of Head Trauma Rehabilitation. I am an unpaid member of the Scientific Advisory Committee for Brain Injury Canada. I am the chair of the Canadian Concussion Network, which is funded by a grant from Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR) to my institution; I am principal applicant on the grant but receive no income from it. I am a principal investigator on another grant from CIHR from which I derive no income. I am a co-investigator on research grants from CIHR, the US National Institutes of Health (NIH), Brain Canada Foundation and National Football League Scientific Advisory Board; I derive income only from the grant from NIH. I serve as a member of a CIHR grant review panelfor which I receive a small honorarium. I receive book royalties from Guilford Press and Cambridge University Press. I have received travel support and honorarium for presentations to multiple organisations. I served or serve on the following committees/boards for which I receive(d) honorarium: 1. Independent Data Monitoring Committee (IDMC), Care for Post-Concussive Symptoms E&#xfb00;ectiveness (CARE4PCS-2) Trial, National Institute for Child Health and Human Development 2. Observational Study Monitoring Board (OSMB), Approaches and Decisions in Acute PediatricTBI (ADAPT) Trial, National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke National Research Advisory Council, National Pediatric Rehabilitation Resource Center, Center for Pediatric Rehabilitation: Growing Research, Education and Sharing Science (C-PROGRESS), Virginia Tech University. Dr OHA is a Senior Physiotherapist at University Hospitals Dorset NHS Foundation Trust (England) and is Para Football Physiotherapy Lead/Para Football Classification Lead at the Football Association (England). He also works on a consultancy basis with the Football Association as the squad physiotherapist to the England Cerebral Palsy Football squad and teaches on the Football Association&#x2019;s Advanced Trauma and Medical Management in Football course on a consultancy basis. He has a Visiting Senior Lecturer position at the University of Portsmouth, England (unpaid). He sits on several disability sport committees including Para Football Foundation as Medical Unit Co-Lead (unpaid), the International Federation of Cerebral Palsy Football as Medical and Sports Science Director (unpaid) and the International Blind Sports Association as Medical Committee member (unpaid). He has Associate Editor positionsat the British Journal of Sports Medicine (unpaid) and BMJ Open Sports my time is supported by National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke of the National Institutes of Health under award number K23NS128275-01Dr. Christina Master reports no financial COI Volunteer positions: Concussion team physician, Shipley School Board of Trustees, American College of Sports Medicine Board of Directors, American Medical Society for Sports Medicine Board of Directors, Pediatric Research in Sports Medicine Executive Committee, Council on Sports Medicine and Fitness, American Academy of Pediatrics Advisory Board, Untold Foundation, Pink Concussions, Headway Foundation Editorial Board, Journal of Adolescent Health, Frontiers in Neuroergonomics, Exercise, Sport, and Movement. Dr Geoff Schneider is an owner of a multidisciplinary practice (managing patients with MSK pain disorders). He is a board member of Hockey Calgary (Calgary, AB, Canada) and Chair of the Alberta Association of Physiotherapy. He received funding for the administrative aspects of the writing of two of the systematic reviews that informed the consensus process. Dr JVI is the founder of R2P Concussion Management. Dr RJE is a paid consultant for the NHL and cochair of the NHL/ NHLPA Concussion Subcommittee. He is also a paid consultant and chair of the Major League Soccer concussion committee and a consultant to the US Soccer Federation. He previously served as a neuropsychology consultant to Princeton University Athletic Medicine and Eye Guide. He is currently a co-PI for a grant funded by the NFL (NFL-Long) through Boston Children&#x2019;s Hospital. He occasionally provides expert testimony in matters related to MTBI and sports concussion and occasionally receives honoraria and travel support/reimbursement for professional meetings. Dr PF is a co-investigator on a research grant from the NFL&#x2019;s &#x201c;Play Smart. PlaySafe.&#x201d; Initiative and an Executive committee member of the Canadian Concussion Network (financed by the Canadian Institute of Health Research). He received honorarium for an Expertgroup discussion on blood biomarkers for concussion in December 2020. Dr GWF has received travel expenses to attend academic meetings from World Rugby. He has also collaborated on research projects with World Rugby as chief or co-investigator. He is previous associate editor of the British Journal of Sports Medicine. He has not received any other payments or support from any sporting or commercial bodies. He has no other conflicts of interest. Dr Stanley A Herring Co-founder and senior advisor, The Sports Institute at UW Medicine (unpaid) Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and National Center for Injury Prevention and Control Board Pediatric Mild Traumatic Brain Injury Guideline Workgroup (unpaid) CISG (travel support) NCAA Concussion Safety Advisory Group (unpaid) Team Physician, Seattle Mariners Former Team Physician, Seattle Seahawks occasional payment for expert testimony travel support for professional meetings. Dr KGH Research Development Director, Pac-12 Conference Member, Pac-12 Brain Trauma Task Force Member, NFL Head Neck and Spine Committee Deputy Editor, British Journal of Sports Medicine Head Football Physician, University of Washington. Ms Holte received an honorarium for administrative aspects of the reviews. Dr ML is the CMO GB Boxing, CMO GB Snowsports. NE Director GB Taekwondo. NE Director SWA (share options). Director Active Movement. Director GB Obstacle course racing. Founder and medical board member of Safe MMA. Director of Marylebone Health Group.Private medical practice at ISEH 170 Tottenham Court Road. Private medical practice Marylebone Health Group. Dr MM Sport and exercise medicine physician working in private consulting practice. Shareholder of Olympic Park Sports Medicine Centre in Melbourne. Ex-senior physician at the Hawthorn Football Club (AFL) Ex-Chief Executive Officer of the AFL Doctors Association. Research grants received from the Australian Football League, outside the submitted work. Travel support received from the Australian Football League, FIFA and the International Olympic Committee to attend and present at international conferences. Member of the Scientific Committee for the 6th International Consensus Conference on Concussion in Sport. Honorary member of the International Concussion in Sport Group. Honorary member of the Australian Rugby Union Concussion Advisory Group. Independent Concussion Consultant for World Rugby. Dr MM has received research funding to the Medical College of Wisconsin from the National Institutes of Health, Department of Veterans Affairs, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Department of Defense, National Collegiate Athletic Association, National FootballLeague and Abbott Laboratories. He receives book royalties from Oxford University Press. He serves as clinical consultant to Milwaukee Bucks, Milwaukee Brewers, and Green Bay Packers and is Co-Director of the NFL Neuropsychology Consultants without compensation. He serves as consultant for Neurotrauma Sciences, Inc. He receives travel support and speaker honorariums for professional activities. WPM - I receive royalties from ABC-Clio publishing for the sale of the books, Kids, Sports and Concussion: A guide for coaches and parents and Concussions; from Springer International for the book Head and Neck Injuries in Young Athlete; and from Wolters Kluwer for working as an author for UpTo Date. My research is funded, in part, by philanthropic support from the National Hockey League Alumni Association through the CCG Pro-Am Tournament and a grant from a grant from the National Football League. POH - is an employee of Marker Diagnostics UK Ltd. He has worked on a sessional basis for the English RFU and FA. He has previously received research funding from the English RFU, ECB and The Drake Foundation. Dr ZP No COI to declare. Dr MP declares the following: Consultant, CMO, Major League Soccer, Senior Advisor, NFL Head, Neck NCAA-CARE-DoD 2.0, ended 2020. Have received honoraria and reimbursement for travel for speaking and conferences attended. Have written chapters for UpToDate and received royalties for the Netter&#x2019;s Sports Medicine textbook. Have provided work as an expert for cases involving concussion, team physician and other sports medicine topics. IJS - does not have any conflicts of interest to disclose. Dr MT is employed full-time as the CEO and Medical Director of ICHIRF &#x2013; a paid post he has held since April 2015. Hon Medical Adviser to the Professional Riders Insurance Scheme (PRIS) &#x2013; discretionary honorarium Member of the Premier League Head Injury Advisory Group (HIAG) &#x2013; no remuneration Director of ICHIRF Ireland Ltd &#x2013; no remuneration Honorary Medical Adviser to the Concussion Foundation Ltd &#x2013; no remuneration Member of the expert panel for the Dept of Digital, Culture, Media and Sport review into concussion in amateur sport &#x2013; no remuneration. Attendance at conferences or meetings as a guest speaker &#x2013; reimbursement of travel expenses, complimentary registration and payment of hotel accommodation and meals by the organising committee. No stocks or options in any concussion-related company. No consultancies, board or editorial positions related to concussion. KV - has no conflicts of interest to disclose. Dr NW Chair, British Paralympic Association (voluntary) IPC Medical Committee Member (voluntary) Concussion in Para Sports (CIPS), founding member (voluntary) BJSM Editorial Board member (voluntary) Sports Horizon, Board of Directors &#x2013; equity share &#x2013; see https://www.sportshorizon.co.uk. KJS has received grant funding from the Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR), NFL Scientific Advisory Board, International Olympic Committee Medical and Scientific Research Fund, World Rugby, Mitacs Accelerate, University of Calgary, with funds paid to her institution and not to her personally. She is an Associate Editor of BJSM (unpaid), Independent consultant to World Rugby and has received travel and accommodation support for meetings where she has presented. She coordinated the writing of the systematic reviews that informed Amsterdam International Consensus on Concussion in Sport, for which she has received an educational grant to assist with the administrative costs associated with the writing of the reviews (with funds paid to her institution). She is a member of the AFL Concussion Scientific Committee (unpaid position), Brain Canada (unpaid positions) and Board member of the Concussion in Sport Group (CISG)(unpaid). She works as a physiotherapy consultant and treats athletes of all levels of sport from grass roots to professional.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37316206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2023-106984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">57/11/672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>