<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">30940341</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1866-0452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>116</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Deutsches Arzteblatt international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dtsch Arztebl Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Effectiveness of an Internet Intervention Aimed at Reducing Alcohol Consumption in Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>127</StartPage><EndPage>133</EndPage><MedlinePgn>127-133</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3238/arztebl.2019.0127</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">arztebl.2019.0127</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">In 2012, approximately 3.38 million people in Germany had an alcoholrelated disorder. Internet interventions can help lower alcohol consumption, albeit with mostly small effect sizes. It is still unclear whether the effectiveness of programs aimed at lowering alcohol consumption can be improved by individually adjusting program content for each participant. We studied the effectiveness of Vorvida, a new cognitive-behavioral internet intervention with individual adjustment of content.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A randomized controlled trial was conducted on 608 adults with problematic alcohol consumption. The primary outcome was self-reported alcohol con - sumption in the past 30 days (as determined by the Quantity-Frequency-Index, QFI) and in the past 7 days (using the Timeline Follow-Back method, TFB). The secondary outcomes were drinking behavior (binge drinking/drunkenness) and satisfaction with Vorvida. Data were collected at three time points: at baseline (t0) and three and six months later (t1, t2). Trial registration: DRKS00006104.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The intention-to-treat (ITT) analysis revealed significant differences between groups at time t1 with respect to alcohol consumption (QFI: d = 0.28; TFB: d = 0.42), binge drinking (d = 0.87), and drunkenness (d = 0.39). Satisfaction with the intervention was high (27.4 [standard deviation, SD: 5.3] out of 32 points). All effects persisted, or were stronger, at time t2. Alcohol consumption, as measured by the QFI, declined over the interval from t0 to t2 in both groups: from 63.69 g/day (SD: 61.4) to 32.67 g/day (SD: 39.78) in the intervention group, and from 61.64 g/day (SD: 58.84) to 43.75 g/day (SD: 43.68) in the control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Vorvida was found to be effective in persons with risky, problematic alcohol consumption. Further studies should determine which elements of the program contribute most to effectiveness in routine clinical practice, and what long-term effects can be achieved.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zill</LastName><ForeName>J&#xf6;rdis M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute and Outpatient Clinic of Medical Psychology, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf; GAIA AG, Hamburg, and Department of Psychology, City, University of London.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christalle</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyer</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>H&#xe4;rter</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dirmaier</LastName><ForeName>J&#xf6;rg</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Dtsch Arztebl Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101475967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1866-0452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000428" MajorTopicYN="N">Alcohol Drinking</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="Y">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015928" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020407" MajorTopicYN="Y">Internet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30940341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6454801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3238/arztebl.2019.0127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">arztebl.2019.0127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Global status on alcohol and health 2018. Geneva: World Health Organization 2018.  http://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/274603/9789241565639-eng.pdf (last accessed on 28 September 2018) </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutsche Hauptstelle f&#xfc;r Suchtfragen (DHS) e. V. DHS Jahrbuch Sucht 2018. Lengerich: Pabst Science Publishers. 2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pabst A, Kraus L, Matos EGD, Piontek D. Substanzkonsum und substanzbezogene St&#xf6;rungen in Deutschland im Jahr 2012. Sucht. 2013;59:321&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Matos EG, Atzendorf J, Kraus L, Piontek D. Substanzkonsum in der Allgemeinbev&#xf6;lkerung in Deutschland. Sucht. 2016;62:271&#x2013;281.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>John U, Hanke M. Alcohol-attributable mortality in a high per capita consumption country - Germany. Alcohol Alcohol. 2002;37:581&#x2013;585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistisches Bundesamt (Destatis) Diagnosedaten der Patienten und Patientinnen in Krankenh&#xe4;usern (einschl. Sterbe- und Stundenf&#xe4;lle) 2016. Fachserie 12 Reihe 621. Wiesbaden: Statistisches Bundesamt (Destatis) 2017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundeszentrale f&#xfc;r gesundheitliche Aufkl&#xe4;rung. Alkohol? Kenn dein Limit.  www.kenn-dein-limit.de/alkohol/riskanter-konsum/ (last accessed on 27 September 2018) </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooke S, Thorsteinsson E, Karpin A, Copeland J, Allsop D. Computer-delivered interventions for alcohol and tobacco use: a meta-analysis. Addiction. 2010;105:1381&#x2013;1390.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20528806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstrom C, Blankers M, Khadjesari Z. Computer-based interventions for problematic alcohol use: a review of systematic reviews. Int J Behav Med. 2017;24:646&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5608865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27757844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dedert EA, McDuffie JR, Stein R, et al. Electronic interventions for alcohol misuse and alcohol use disorders: a systematic review. Ann Intern Med. 2015;163:205&#x2013;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4837467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26237752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaner EF, Beyer FR, Garnett C, et al. Personalised digital interventions for reducing hazardous and harmful alcohol consumption in community-dwelling populations. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6483779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28944453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs P, Prochaska JO, Rossi JS. A meta-analysis of computer-tailored interventions for health behavior change. Prev Med. 2010;51:214&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2939185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20558196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lustria MLA, Noar SM, Cortese J, Van Stee SK, Glueckauf RL, Lee J. A meta-analysis of web-delivered tailored health behavior change interventions. J Health Commun. 2013;18:1039&#x2013;1069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23750972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noar SM, Benac CN, Harris MS. Does tailoring matter? Meta-analytic review of tailored print health behavior change interventions. Psychol Bull. 2007;133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17592961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson R, Sj&#xf6;berg E, Sj&#xf6;gren M, et al. Tailored vs standardized internet-based cognitive behavior therapy for depression and comorbid symptoms: a randomized controlled trial. PloS one. 2012;7 e36905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3352859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22615841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Boettcher J, Caspar F. Internet-based guided self-help for several anxiety disorders: a randomized controlled trial comparing a tailored with a standardized disorder-specific approach. Psychotherapy. 2014;51</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24041199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T. Internetbasierte Interventionen bei psychischen. St&#xf6;rungen: Hogrefe Verlag. 2015</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treweek S, Zwarenstein M. Making trials matter: pragmatic and explanatory trials and the problem of applicability. Trials. 2009;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19493350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zill JM, Meyer B, Topp J, Daubmann A, H&#xe4;rter M, Dirmaier J. Vorvida: study protocol of a randomized controlled trial testing the effectiveness of internet-based self-help program for the reduction of alcohol consumption for adults. BMC Psychiatry. 20161;6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4731898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26822579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berner MM, Kriston L, Bentele M, Ha&#xa8;rter M. The alcohol use disorders identification test for detecting at-risk drinking:a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Stud Alcohol Drugs. 2007;68:461&#x2013;473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17446987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bloomfield K, Hope A, Kraus L. Alcohol survey measures for Europe: a literature review. Drugs Educ Prev Polic. 2013;20:348&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus L, Piontek D, Pabst A, Gomes de Matos E. Studiendesign und Methodik des Epidemiologischen Suchtsurveys 2012. Sucht. 2013;59:309&#x2013;320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell LC, Sobell MB. Litten RZ, Allen JP, editors. Timeline Follow-Back: a technique for assessing self-reported alcohol consumption Measuring alcohol consumption: psychosocial and biochemical methods. Humana Press. 1992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieroslawski J, Foster J, Moskalewicz J. Survey of European drinking surveys Alcohol survey experiences of 22 European countries. Drugs Educ Prev Polic. 2013;20:383&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt J, Lamprecht F, Wittmann W. Satisfaction with inpatient management Development of a questionnaire and initial validity studies. Psychother Psychosom Med Psychol. 1989;39:248&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2762479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postel MG, de Haan HA, ter Huurne ED, van der Palen J, Becker ES, de Jong CA. Attrition in web-based treatment for problem drinkers. J Med Internet Res. 2011;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22201703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riper H, Blankers M, Hadiwijaya H, et al. Effectiveness of guided and unguided low-intensity internet interventions for adult alcohol misuse: a meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2014;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4061051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24937483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furtw&#xe6;ngler NA, de Visser RO. Lack of international consensus in low-risk drinking guidelines. Drug Alcohol Rev. 2013;32:11&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22672631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J, Paganini S, Sander L, et al. An internet-based intervention for chronic pain: a three-arm randomized controlled study of the effectiveness of guided and unguided acceptance and commitment therapy. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2017;114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundstr&#xf6;m C, Gajecki M, Johansson M, et al. Guided and unguided internet-based treatment for problematic alcohol use-a randomized controlled pilot trial. PloS One. 2016;11 e0157817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4934861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27383389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenna H, Treanor C, O&#x2019;Reilly D, Donnelly M. Evaluation of the psychometric properties of self-reported measures of alcohol consumption: a COSMIN systematic review. Subst Abuse Treat Prev Policy. 2018;13</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5797334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29394950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirsch I, Wampold B, Kelley JM. Controlling for the placebo effect in psychotherapy: noble quest or tilting at windmills? Psychol Conscious. 2016;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahm ES, Bausell B, Resnick B, et al. Online research in older adults: lessons learned from conducting an online randomized controlled trial. Appl Nurs Res. 2011;24:269&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3029500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20974077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahm ES, Resnick B, Brown C, et al. The effects of an online theory-based bone health program for older adults. J Appl Gerontol. 2017;36:1117&#x2013;1144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5388589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SurveyMonkey Europe UC. SurveyMonkey.  https:// de.surveymonkey.com/ (last accessed on 27 September 2018) </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Urech A, Krieger T, et al. Effects of a transdiagnostic unguided internet intervention (&#x2018;velibra&#x2019;) for anxiety disorders in primary care: results of a randomized controlled trial. Psychol Med. 2016:1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27655039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O&#x2018;Reilly G, Meyer B. Effectiveness of an individually-tailored computerised CBT programme (Deprexis) for depression: a meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2017;256:371&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dilling H, Mombour W, Schmidt MH , World Health Organization Internationale Klassifikation psychischer St&#xf6;rungen: ICD-10, Kapitel V (F), klinisch-diagnostische Leitlinien. 1991</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osman A, Bagge CL, Gutierrez PM, Konick LC, Kopper BA, Barrios FX. The Suicidal Behaviors Questionnaire-Revised (SBQ-R): validation with clinical and nonclinical samples. Assessment. 2001;8:443&#x2013;454.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11785588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G* Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Donker T, Johansson R, Mohr DC, van Straten A, Andersson G. Self-guided psychological treatment for depressive symptoms: a meta-analysis. PloS One. 2011;6 e21274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21712998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences 2nd ed. Hillsdale, NJ: Erlbaum. 1988</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>