<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">29664187</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2018</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exercise interventions and patient beliefs for people with hip, knee or hip and knee osteoarthritis: a mixed methods review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>CD010842</StartPage><MedlinePgn>CD010842</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD010842</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD010842.pub2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Chronic peripheral joint pain due to osteoarthritis (OA) is extremely prevalent and a major cause of physical dysfunction and psychosocial distress. Exercise is recommended to reduce joint pain and improve physical function, but the effect of exercise on psychosocial function (health beliefs, depression, anxiety and quality of life) in this population is unknown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To improve our understanding of the complex inter-relationship between pain, psychosocial effects, physical function and exercise.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">Review authors searched 23 clinical, public health, psychology and social care databases and 25 other relevant resources including trials registers up to March 2016. We checked reference lists of included studies for relevant studies. We contacted key experts about unpublished studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA">To be included in the quantitative synthesis, studies had to be randomised controlled trials of land- or water-based exercise programmes compared with a control group consisting of no treatment or non-exercise intervention (such as medication, patient education) that measured either pain or function and at least one psychosocial outcome (self-efficacy, depression, anxiety, quality of life). Participants had to be aged 45 years or older, with a clinical diagnosis of OA (as defined by the study) or self-reported chronic hip or knee (or both) pain (defined as more than six months' duration).To be included in the qualitative synthesis, studies had to have reported people's opinions and experiences of exercise-based programmes (e.g. their views, understanding, experiences and beliefs about the utility of exercise in the management of chronic pain/OA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS">We used standard methodology recommended by Cochrane for the quantitative analysis. For the qualitative analysis, we extracted verbatim quotes from study participants and synthesised studies of patients' views using framework synthesis. We then conducted an integrative review, synthesising the quantitative and qualitative data together.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">Twenty-one trials (2372 participants) met the inclusion criteria for quantitative synthesis. There were large variations in the exercise programme's content, mode of delivery, frequency and duration, participant's symptoms, duration of symptoms, outcomes measured, methodological quality and reporting. Comparator groups were varied and included normal care; education; and attention controls such as home visits, sham gel and wait list controls. Risk of bias was high in one and unclear risk in five studies regarding the randomisation process, high for 11 studies regarding allocation concealment, high for all 21 studies regarding blinding, and high for three studies and unclear for five studies regarding attrition. Studies did not provide information on adverse effects.There was moderate quality evidence that exercise reduced pain by an absolute percent reduction of 6% (95% confidence interval (CI) -9% to -4%, (9 studies, 1058 participants), equivalent to reducing (improving) pain by 1.25 points from 6.5 to 5.3 on a 0 to 20 scale and moderate quality evidence that exercise improved physical function by an absolute percent of 5.6% (95% CI -7.6% to 2.0%; standardised mean difference (SMD) -0.27, 95% CI -0.37 to -0.17, equivalent to reducing (improving) WOMAC (Western Ontario and McMaster Universities Osteoarthritis Index) function on a 0 to 100 scale from 49.9 to 44.3) (13 studies, 1599 participants)). Self-efficacy was increased by an absolute percent of 1.66% (95% CI 1.08% to 2.20%), although evidence was low quality (SMD 0.46, 95% CI 0.34 to 0.58, equivalent to improving the ExBeliefs score on a 17 to 85 scale from 64.3 to 65.4), with small benefits for depression from moderate quality evidence indicating an absolute percent reduction of 2.4% (95% CI -0.47% to 0.5%) (SMD -0.16, 95% CI -0.29 to -0.02, equivalent to improving depression measured using HADS (Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale) on a 0 to 21 scale from 3.5 to 3.0) but no clinically or statistically significant effect on anxiety (SMD -0.11, 95% CI -0.26 to 0.05, 2% absolute improvement, 95% CI -5% to 1% equivalent to improving HADS anxiety on a 0 to 21 scale from 5.8 to 5.4; moderate quality evidence). Five studies measured the effect of exercise on health-related quality of life using the 36-item Short Form (SF-36) with statistically significant benefits for social function, increasing it by an absolute percent of 7.9% (95% CI 4.1% to 11.6%), equivalent to increasing SF-36 social function on a 0 to 100 scale from 73.6 to 81.5, although the evidence was low quality. Evidence was downgraded due to heterogeneity of measures, limitations with blinding and lack of detail regarding interventions. For 20/21 studies, there was a high risk of bias with blinding as participants self-reported and were not blinded to their participation in an exercise intervention.Twelve studies (with 6 to 29 participants) met inclusion criteria for qualitative synthesis. Their methodological rigour and quality was generally good. From the patients' perspectives, ways to improve the delivery of exercise interventions included: provide better information and advice about the safety and value of exercise; provide exercise tailored to individual's preferences, abilities and needs; challenge inappropriate health beliefs and provide better support.An integrative review, which compared the findings from quantitative trials with low risk of bias and the implications derived from the high-quality studies in the qualitative synthesis, confirmed the importance of these implications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">Chronic hip and knee pain affects all domains of people's lives. People's beliefs about chronic pain shape their attitudes and behaviours about how to manage their pain. People are confused about the cause of their pain, and bewildered by its variability and randomness. Without adequate information and advice from healthcare professionals, people do not know what they should and should not do, and, as a consequence, avoid activity for fear of causing harm. Participation in exercise programmes may slightly improve physical function, depression and pain. It may slightly improve self-efficacy and social function, although there is probably little or no difference in anxiety. Providing reassurance and clear advice about the value of exercise in controlling symptoms, and opportunities to participate in exercise programmes that people regard as enjoyable and relevant, may encourage greater exercise participation, which brings a range of health benefits to a large population of people.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hurley</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Rehabilitation Sciences, Faculty of Health, Social Care and Education, St George's, University of London and Kingston University, 2nd Floor Grosvenor Wing, Crammer Terrace, Tooting, London, UK, SW17 0RE.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dickson</LastName><ForeName>Kelly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hallett</LastName><ForeName>Rachel</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grant</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hauari</LastName><ForeName>Hanan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walsh</LastName><ForeName>Nicola</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stansfield</LastName><ForeName>Claire</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oliver</LastName><ForeName>Sandy</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Prim Health Care. 2018 Jun;10(2):181-182. doi: 10.1071/HC15935.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">30068476</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Musculoskelet Sci Pract. 2019 Dec;44:102041. doi: 10.1016/j.msksp.2019.07.005.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">31377189</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018771" MajorTopicYN="N">Arthralgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="Y">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059350" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007722" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Knowledge, Attitudes, Practice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015207" MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoarthritis, Hip</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="Y">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020370" MajorTopicYN="N">Osteoarthritis, Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="Y">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020377" MajorTopicYN="N">Self Efficacy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058992" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Participation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063189" MajorTopicYN="N">Symptom Assessment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>MH: no conflicting interests to declare. KD: no conflicting interests to declare. RH: no conflicting interests to declare. RG: no conflicting interests to declare. HH: no conflicting interests to declare. NW: no conflicting interests to declare. CS: no conflicting interests to declare. SO: no conflicting interests to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29664187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD010842.pub2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies included in this review</Title><Reference><Citation>Aglamis B, Toraman NF, Yamanc H. The effect of a 12&#x2010;week supervised multi&#x2010;component exercise program on knee OA in Turkish women. Journal of Back and Musculoskeletal Rehabilitation 2008;21:121&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker KR, Nelson ME, Felson DT, Layne J, Sarno R, Roubenoff R. The efficacy of home based progressive strength training in older adults with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Rheumatology 2001;28:1655&#x2010;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11469475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell KL, Egerton T, Martin J, Abbott JH, Metcalf B, McManus F, et al. Effect of physical therapy on pain and function in patients with hip osteoarthritis: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2014;311(19):1987&#x2010;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24846036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell KL, Ahamed Y, Jull G, Bryant C, Hunt MA, Forbes AB, et al. Physical therapist&#x2010;delivered pain coping skills training and exercise for knee osteoarthritis: randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2016;68(5):590&#x2010;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26417720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung C, Wyman JF, Resnick B, Savik K. Yoga for managing knee osteoarthritis in older women: a pilot randomized controlled trial. BMC Complementary and Alternative Medicine 2014;14:160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4038088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24886638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes L, Storheimyz K, Sandvik L, Nordsletten L, Risberg MA. Efficacy of patient education and supervised exercise vs patient education alone in patients with hip osteoarthritis: a single blind randomized clinical trial. Osteoarthritis and Cartilage 2010;18:1237&#x2010;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20633669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Focht BA, Rejeski WJ, Ambrosius WT, Katula JA, Messier SP. Exercise, self&#x2010;efficacy, and mobility performance in overweight and obese older adults with knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2005;53(5):659&#x2010;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16208674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fransen M, Nairn L, Winstanley J, Lam P, Edmonds J. Physical activity for osteoarthritis management: a randomized controlled clinical trial evaluating hydrotherapy or Tai Chi classes. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2007;57:407&#x2010;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17443749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>French H, Cusack T, Brennan A, Caffrey A, Conroy R, Cuddy V, et al. Exercise and Manual Physiotherapy Arthritis Research Trial (EMPART) for osteoarthritis of the hip: a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2013;94:302&#x2010;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23084955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopman&#x2010;Rock M, Westhoff MH. The effects of a health educational and exercise program for older adults with osteoarthritis for the hip or knee. Journal of Rheumatology 2000;27:1947&#x2010;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10955337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley MV, Walsh NE, Mitchell HL, Pimm TJ, Patel A, Williamson E, et al. Clinical effectiveness of a rehabilitation program integrating exercise, self&#x2010;management, and active coping strategies for chronic knee pain: a cluster randomized trial. Arthritis Research 2007;57:1211&#x2010;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2673355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17907147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao MJ, Wu MP, Tsai MW, Chang WW, Wu SF. The effectiveness of a self&#x2010;management program on quality of life for knee osteoarthritis (OA) patients. Archives of Gerontology and Geriatrics 2012;54:317&#x2010;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21726907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keefe FJ, Blumenthal J, Baucom D, Affleck G, Waugh R, Caldwell DS, et al. Effects of spouse&#x2010;assisted coping skills training and exercise training in patients with osteoarthritic knee pain: a randomized controlled study. Pain 2004;110:539&#x2010;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15288394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim IS, Chung HS, Park YJ, Kang HY. The effectiveness of an aquarobic exercise program for patients with osteoarthritis. Applied Nursing Research 2012;25:181&#x2010;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikesky AE, Mazzuca SA, Brandt KD, Perkins SM, Damush T, Lane KA. Effects of strength training on the incidence and progression of knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2006;55(5):690&#x2010;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17013851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park J, McCaffrey R, Newman D, Cheung C, Hagen D. The effect of sit 'n' fit chair yoga among community&#x2010;dwelling older adults with osteoarthritis. Holistic Nursing Practice 2014;28(4):247&#x2010;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24919095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;loquin L, Bravo G, Gauthier P, Lacombe G, Billiard JS. Effects of a cross&#x2010;training exercise program in persons with osteoarthritis of the knee a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Clinical Rheumatology 1999;5:126&#x2010;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19078371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlenk EA, Lias JL, Sereika SM, Dunbar&#x2010;Jacob J, Kwoh CK. Improving physical activity and function in overweight and obese older adults with osteoarthritis of the knee: a feasibility study. Rehabilitation Nursing 2011;36(1):32&#x2010;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3052988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21290963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan T, Allegrante JP, Peterson MG, Kovar PA, MacKenzie CR. One&#x2010;year followup of patients with osteoarthritis of the knee who participated in a program of supervised fitness walking and supportive patient education. Arthritis and Rheumatism 1998;11:228&#x2010;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9791321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang C, Schmid CH, Hibberd PL, Kalish R, Roubenoff R, Rones R, et al. Tai Chi is effective in treating knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2009;61(11):1545&#x2010;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3023169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19877092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip YB, Sit JW, Fung KK, Wong DY, Chong SY, Chung LH, et al. Effects of a self&#x2010;management arthritis programme with an added exercise component for osteoarthritic knee: randomized controlled trial. Journal of Advanced Nursing 2007;59:20&#x2010;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17559610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>References to studies excluded from this review</Title><Reference><Citation>Arnold CM, Faulkner RA. The effect of aquatic exercise and education on lowering fall risk in older adults with hip osteoarthritis [corrected] [published erratum appears in Journal of Aging &amp; Physical Activity 2010;18(4):477&#x2010;9]. Journal of Aging &amp; Physical Activity 2010;18:245&#x2010;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20651413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautch JC, Malone DG, Vailas AC. Effects of exercise on knee joints with osteoarthritis: a pilot study of biologic markers. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 1997;10(1):48&#x2010;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9313390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell KL, Hunt MA, Wrigley TV, Hunter DJ, McManus FJ, Hodges PW. Hip strengthening reduces symptoms but not knee load in people with medial knee osteoarthritis and varus malalignment: a randomised controlled trial. Osteoarthritis and Cartilage 2010;18:621&#x2010;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20175973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bezalel T, Carmeli E, Katz&#x2010;Leurer M. The effect of a group education programme on pain and function through knowledge acquisition and home&#x2010;based exercise among patients with knee osteoarthritis: a parallel randomised single&#x2010;blind clinical trial. Physiotherapy 2010;96:137&#x2010;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20420960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brismee JM, Paige RL, Chyu MC, Boatright JD, Hagar JM. Group and home&#x2010;based Tai Chi in elderly subjects with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial [with consumer summary]. Clinical Rehabilitation 2007;21:99&#x2010;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17264104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruce&#x2010;Brand RA, Walls RJ, Ong JC, Emerson BS, O'Byrne JM, Moyna NM. Effects of home&#x2010;based resistance training and neuromuscular electrical stimulation in knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders 2012;13:118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3493368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22759883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cadmus L, Patrick MB, Maciejewski ML, Topolski T, Belza B, Patrick DL. Community&#x2010;based aquatic exercise and quality of life in persons with osteoarthritis. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise 2010;42:8&#x2010;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20010135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callaghan MJ, Oldham JA, Hunt J. An evaluation of exercise regimes for patients with osteoarthritis of the knee: a single&#x2010;blind randomized controlled trial. Clinical Rehabilitation 1995;9:213&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deyle GD, Henderson NE, Matekel RL, Ryder MG, Garber MB, Allison SC. Effectiveness of manual physical therapy and exercise in osteoarthritis of the knee. A randomized, controlled trial. Annals of Internal Medicine 2000;132:173&#x2010;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10651597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias RC, Dias JM, Ramos LR. Impact of an exercise and walking protocol on quality of life for elderly people with OA of the knee. Physiotherapy Research International 2003;8:121&#x2010;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14533368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebnezar J, Nagarathna R, Yogitha B, Nagendra HR. Effects of an integrated approach of hatha yoga therapy on functional disability, pain, and flexibility in osteoarthritis of the knee joint: a randomized controlled study. Journal of Alternative and Complementary Medicine 2012;18:463&#x2010;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22537508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettinger WH, Burns R, Messier SP, Applegate W, Rejeski WJ. A randomized trial comparing aerobic exercise and resistance exercise with a health education program in older adults with knee osteoarthritis. The Fitness Arthritis and Seniors Trial (FAST). JAMA 1997;277:25&#x2010;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8980206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyigor S. A comparison of muscle training methods in patients with knee osteoarthritis. Clinical Rheumatology 2004;23:109&#x2010;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15045623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley A, Halbert J, Hewitt T, Crotty M. Does hydrotherapy improve strength and physical function in patients with osteoarthritis &#x2010; a randomised controlled trial comparing a gym based and a hydrotherapy based strengthening programme. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 2003;62:1162&#x2010;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1754378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14644853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fransen M, Crosbie J, Edmonds J. Physical therapy is effective for patients with osteoarthritis of the knee: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Journal of Rheumatology 2001;28:156&#x2010;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11196518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes WF, Lacerda AC, Mendonca VA, Arrieiro AN, Fonseca SF, Amorim MR, et al. Effect of aerobic training on plasma cytokines and soluble receptors in elderly women with knee osteoarthritis, in response to acute exercise. Clinical Rheumatology 2012;31:759&#x2010;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22215119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gur H, Cakin N, Akova B, Okay E, Kucukoglu S. Concentric versus combined concentric&#x2010;eccentric isokinetic training: effects on functional capacity and symptoms in patients with osteoarthrosis of the knee. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2002;83:308&#x2010;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11887109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halbert J, Crotty M, Weller D, Ahern M, Silagy C. Primary care&#x2010;based physical activity programs: effectiveness in sedentary older patients with osteoarthritis symptoms. Arthritis and Rheumatism 2001;45:228&#x2010;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11409662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart LE. Combination of manual physical therapy and exercises for osteoarthritis of the knee. Clinical Journal of Sport Medicine 2000;10:305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11086762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa M, Yamazaki S, Kimura M, Nakano K, Yasumura S. Community&#x2010;based exercise program reduces chronic knee pain in elderly Japanese women at high risk of requiring long&#x2010;term care: a non&#x2010;randomized controlled trial. Geriatrics &amp; Gerontology International 2013;13:167&#x2010;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22686463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hay EM, Foster NE, Thomas E, Peat G, Phelan M, Yates HE. Effectiveness of community physiotherapy and enhanced pharmacy review for knee pain in people aged over 55 presenting to primary care: pragmatic randomised trial. BMJ 2006;333:995&#x2010;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1635605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17056608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinman RS, Heywood SE, Day AR. Aquatic physical therapy for hip and knee osteoarthritis: results of a single&#x2010;blind randomized controlled trial. Physical Therapy 2007;87:32&#x2010;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17142642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiyama Y, Yamada M, Kitagawa A, Tei N, Okada S. A four&#x2010;week walking exercise programme in patients with knee osteoarthritis improves the ability of dual&#x2010;task performance: a randomized controlled trial. Clinical Rehabilitation 2012;26:403&#x2010;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21975468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoeksma HL, Dekker J, Ronday HK, Breedveld FC, Ende CH. Manual therapy in osteoarthritis of the hip: outcome in subgroups of patients. Rheumatology 2005;44:461&#x2010;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15695307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang MH, Lin YS, Yang RC, Lee CL. A comparison of various therapeutic exercises on the functional status of patients with knee osteoarthritis. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism 2003;32:398&#x2010;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12833248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang MH, Yang RC, Lee CL, Chen TW, Wang MC. Preliminary results of integrated therapy for patients with knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis and Rheumatism 2005;53:812&#x2010;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16342083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes SL, Seymour RB, Campbell R, Pollak N, Huber G, Sharma L. Impact of the fit and strong intervention on older adults with osteoarthritis. Gerontologist 2004;44:217&#x2010;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15075418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson CM, Doherty M, Avery AJ, Read A, Taylor MA, Sach TH. Effects of dietary intervention and quadriceps strengthening exercises on pain and function in overweight people with knee pain: randomised controlled trial [with consumer summary]. BMJ 2009;339:b3170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19690345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juhakoski R, Tenhonen S, Malmivaara A, Kiviniemi V, Anttonen T, Arokoski JP. A pragmatic randomized controlled study of the effectiveness and cost consequences of exercise therapy in hip osteoarthritis. Clinical Rehabilitation 2011;25:370&#x2010;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21078702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawasaki T, Kurosawa H, Ikeda H, Takazawa Y, Ishijima M, Kubota M, et al. Therapeutic home exercise versus intraarticular hyaluronate injection for osteoarthritis of the knee: 6&#x2010;month prospective randomized open&#x2010;labeled trial. Journal of Orthopaedic Science 2009;14:182&#x2010;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19337810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kostopoulos D. Comparative Effects of Aquatic Recreational and Aquatic Exercise Programs on Mobility, Pain Perception, and Treatment Satisfaction Among Elderly Persons with Osteoarthritis of the Knee. Dissertation2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovar PA, Allegrante JP, MacKenzie CR, Peterson MG, Gutin B, Charlson ME. Supervised fitness walking in patients with osteoarthritis of the knee. A randomized, controlled trial. Annals of Internal Medicine 1992;116:529&#x2010;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1543305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HJ, Park HJ, Chae Y, Kim SY, Kim SN, Kim ST. Tai Chi Qigong for the quality of life of patients with knee osteoarthritis: a pilot, randomized, waiting list controlled trial. Clinical Rehabilitation 2009;23:504&#x2010;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19389743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim JY, Tchai E, Jang SN. Effectiveness of aquatic exercise for obese patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. PM &amp; R : the Journal of Injury, Function, and Rehabilitation 2010;2:723&#x2010;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20709301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangione KK, McCully K, Gloviak A, Lefebvre I, Hofmann M, Craik R. The effects of high&#x2010;intensity and low&#x2010;intensity cycle ergometry in older adults with knee osteoarthritis. Journals of Gerontology: Series A: Biological Sciences and Medical Sciences 1999;54A:M184&#x2010;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10219009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy C, Pullen R, Mills P, Roberts C, Silman A, Oldham J. Supplementing home exercise with class&#x2010;based exercise leads to reductions in pain in knee osteoarthritis, but no greater muscle strength or compliance with home exercise at long term follow&#x2010;up. Rheumatology 2003;42:17&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Loeser RF, Miller GD, Morgan TM, Rejeski WJ, Sevick MA. Exercise and dietary weight loss in overweight and obese older adults with knee osteoarthritis: the arthritis, diet, and activity promotion trial. Arthritis and Rheumatism 2004;50:1501&#x2010;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15146420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy SL, Lyden AK, Smith DM, Dong Q, Koliba JF. Effects of a tailored activity pacing intervention on pain and fatigue for adults with osteoarthritis. American Journal of Occupational Therapy 2010;64:869&#x2010;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3655423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21218677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Reilly SC, Muir KR, Doherty M. Effectiveness of home exercise on pain and disability from osteoarthritis of the knee. Annals of Rheumatic Diseases 1999;58:15&#x2010;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1752761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10343535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrella R J, Bartha C. Home based exercise therapy for older patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized clinical trial. Journal of Rheumatology 2000;27:2215&#x2010;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10990236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisters MF, Veenhof C, Schellevis FG, De Bakker, DH, Dekker J. Long&#x2010;term effectiveness of exercise therapy in patients with osteoarthritis of the hip or knee: a randomized controlled trial comparing two different physical therapy interventions. Osteoarthritis and Cartilage 2010;18:1019&#x2010;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20488250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollard H, Ward G, Hoskins W, Hardy K. The effect of a manual therapy knee protocol on osteoarthritic knee pain: a randomised controlled trial. Journal of the Canadian Chiropractic Association 2008;52:229&#x2010;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2597887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19066697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quilty B, Tucker M, Campbell R, Dieppe P. Physiotherapy, including quadriceps exercises and patellar taping, for knee osteoarthritis with predominant patello&#x2010;femoral joint involvement: randomized controlled trial. Journal of Rheumatology 2003;30:1311&#x2010;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12784408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravaud P, Giraudeau B, Logeart I, Larguier JS, Rolland D, Treves R, et al. Management of osteoarthritis (OA) with an unsupervised home based exercise programme and/or patient administered assessment tools. A cluster randomised controlled trial with a 2x2 factorial design. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 2004;63:703&#x2010;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1755039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15140778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>R&#xf8;gind H, Bibow&#x2010;Nielsen B, Jensen B, M&#xf8;ller HC, Frimodt&#x2010;M&#xf8;ller H, Bliddal H. The effects of a physical training program on patients with osteoarthritis of the knees. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 1998;79:1421&#x2010;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9821904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salli A, Sahin N, Baskent A, Ugurlu H. The effect of two exercise programs on various functional outcome measures in patients with osteoarthritis of the knee: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Isokinetics and Exercise Science 2010;18:201&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schilke JM, Johnson GO, Housh TJ, O'Dell JR. Effects of muscle&#x2010;strength training on the functional status of patients with osteoarthritis of the knee joint. Nursing Research 1996;45:68&#x2010;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8604366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekir U, Gur H. A multi&#x2010;station proprioceptive exercise program in patients with bilateral knee osteoarthrosis: functional capacity, pain and sensoriomotor function. A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Sports Science and Medicine 2005;4:590&#x2010;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3899676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24501572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shakoor MA, Taslim MA, Hossain MS. Effects of activity modification on the patients with osteoarthritis of the knee. Bangladesh Medical Research Council Bulletin 2007;33:55&#x2010;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18481439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva LE, Valim V, Pessanha AP, Oliveira LM, Myamoto S, Jones A. Hydrotherapy versus conventional land&#x2010;based exercise for the management of patients with osteoarthritis of the knee: a randomized clinical trial. Physical Therapy 2008;88:12&#x2010;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17986497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simao AP, Avelar NC, Tossige&#x2010;Gomes R, Neves CD, Mendonca VA, Miranda AS. Functional performance and inflammatory cytokines after squat exercises and whole&#x2010;body vibration in elderly individuals with knee osteoarthritis. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2012;93:1692&#x2010;700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22546535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song R, Lee EO, Lam P, Bae SC. Effects of Tai Chi exercise on pain, balance, muscle strength, and perceived difficulties in physical functioning in older women with osteoarthritis: a randomized clinical trial. Journal of Rheumatology 2003;30:2039&#x2010;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12966613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoneman PD. Effect of Manual Therapy and Exercise on Pain, Stiffness and Function in Persons with Knee Osteoarthritis. Dissertation2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tak E, Staats P, Van Hespen, A, Hopman&#x2010;Rock M. The effects of an exercise program for older adults with osteoarthritis of the hip. Journal of Rheumatology 2005;32:1106&#x2010;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15940775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talbot LA, Gaines JM, Huynh TN, Metter EJ. A home&#x2010;based pedometer&#x2010;driven walking program to increase physical activity in older adults with osteoarthritis of the knee: a preliminary study. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society 2003;51:387&#x2010;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12588583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas KS, Muir KR, Doherty M, Jones AC, O'Reilly SC, Bassey EJ, et al. Home based exercise programme for knee pain and knee osteoarthritis: randomised controlled trial. BMJ 2002;325:752&#x2010;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC128377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12364304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorstensson CA, Roos EM, Petersson IF, Ekdahl C. Six&#x2010;week high&#x2010;intensity exercise program for middle&#x2010;aged patients with knee osteoarthritis: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders 2005;6:27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1187893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15924620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topp R, Woolley S, Hornyak J, Khuder S, Kahaleh B. The effect of dynamic versus isometric resistance training on pain and functioning among adults with osteoarthritis of the knee. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2002;83:1187&#x2010;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12235596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baar ME, Dekker J, Oostendorp R, Bijl D, Voorn T. The effectiveness of exercise therapy in patients with osteoarthritis of the hip or knee: a randomized clinical trial. Journal of Rheumatology 1998;25:2432&#x2010;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9858441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veenhof C, Koke AJ, Dekker J, Oostendorp RA, Bijlsma JW, van Tulder, et al. Effectiveness of behavioral graded activity in patients with osteoarthritis of the hip and/or knee: a randomized clinical trial. Arthritis and Rheumatism 2006;55:925&#x2010;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17139639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Additional references</Title><Reference><Citation>American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM&#x2019;s guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Vol. 7, Philadelphia: Lippincott Williams and Wilkins, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AGS. Exercise Prescription for Older Adults with Osteoarthritis Pain: Consensus Practice Recommendations. Journal of the American Geriatrics Society 2001;49:808&#x2010;823.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11480416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman RD, Asch E, Bloch D, Bole G, Borenstein D, Brandt K, et al. Development criteria for the classification and reporting of osteoarthritis &#x2013; classification of osteoarthritis of the knee. Arthritis and Rheumatism 1986;29:1039&#x2013;1049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3741515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman R, Alarcon G, Appelrouth D, Bloch D, Borenstein D, Brandt K, et al. The American College of Rheumatology criteria for the classification and reporting of osteoarthritis of the hip. Arthritis Rheum. 1991;34(5):505&#x2010;514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2025304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthritis Research UK. 
Musculoskeletal health, 2017. 
www.arthritisresearchuk.org/arthritis&#x2010;information/data&#x2010;and&#x2010;statistics/state&#x2010;of&#x2010;musculoskeletal&#x2010;health.aspx (accessed prior to 12 March 2018).
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self&#x2010;efficacy: towards a unifying theory of behaviour change. Psychological Review 1977;84:191&#x2010;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">847061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartels Em, Lund H, Hagen KB, Dagfinrud H, Christensen R, Danneskiold&#x2010;Sams&#xf8;e B. Aquatic exercise for the treatment of knee and hip osteoarthritis. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2007, Issue 4. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD005523.pub2; CD005523]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD005523.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17943863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedson J, McCarney R, Croft P. Labelling chronic illness in primary care: a good or a bad thing?. British Journal of General Practice 2004;54:932&#x2010;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1326113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15588540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijsterbosch J, Sharloo M, Visser AW, Watt I, Meulenbelt I, Huizinga TW, et al. Illness perceptions in patients with osteoarthritis: change over time and association with disability. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2009;61:1054&#x2010;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19644904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulton MR, Fitzpatrick R, Swinburn C. Qualitative research in health care II: a structured review and evaluation of studies. Journal of Evaluation of Clinical Practice 1996;2:171&#x2010;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9238586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell R, Evans M, Tucker M, Quilty B, Dieppe P, Donovan JL. Why don't patients do their exercises? Understanding non&#x2010;compliance with physiotherapy in patients with osteoarthritis of the knee. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health 2001;55:132&#x2010;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1731838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11154253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Candy B, King M, Jones L, Oliver S. Using qualitative synthesis to explore heterogeneity of complex interventions. BMC Medical Research Methodology 2011;11:124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3178541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21871083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter J, Kenward M. Missing Data in Randomised Controlled Trials &#x2010; a Practical Guide. Birmingham (UK): National Institute for Health Research, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cobb AK, Hagemaster JN. Ten criteria for evaluating qualitative research proposals. Journal of Nursing Education 1987;26:138&#x2010;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3035126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson J, Linsell L, Zondervan Z, Rose P, Carr A, Randall T, et al. Impact of persistent hip or knee pain on overall health status in elderly people: a longitudinal population study. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2005;53:368&#x2010;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15934104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dekker J, Bott B, Woude LH, Bijlsma JW. Pain and disability in osteoarthritis: a review of biobehavioral mechanisms. Journal of Behavioral Medicine 1992;15:189&#x2010;214.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1533877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan J, Blake D, Fleming W. The patient is not a blank sheet: lay beliefs and their relevance to patient education. British Journal of Rheumatology 1989;28:58&#x2010;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2917230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes L, Hagen KB, Bijlsma JW, Andreassen O, Christensen P, Conaghan PG, et al. EULAR recommendations for the non&#x2010;pharmacological core management of hip and knee osteoarthritis. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 2013;72:1125&#x2010;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23595142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisken AL, Waters DL, Hing WA, Keogh JW. Perceptions towards aqua&#x2010;based exercise among older adults with osteoarthritis who have discontinued participation in this exercise mode. Australasian Journal on Ageing 2016;35(1):12&#x2010;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26616132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folstein MF, Folstein SE, McHugh PR. Mini&#x2010;mental state: A practical method for grading the cognitive state of patients for the clinician. Journal of Psychiatric Research 1975;12:189&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1202204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fransen M, McConnell S, Hernandez&#x2010;Molina G, Reichenbach S. Exercise for osteoarthritis of the hip. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2014, Issue 4. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD007912.pub2; Art. No. CD007912]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD007912.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10898220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24756895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fransen M, McConnell S, Harmer AR, Esch M, Simic M, Bennell KL. Exercise for osteoarthritis of the knee. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2015, Issue 1. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD004376.pub3]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD004376.pub3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10094004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25569281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GRADE Working Group, McMaster University. GRADEpro. Version 3.2 for Windows. Hamilton (ON): GRADE Working Group, McMaster University, 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths C, Foster G, Ramsay J, Eldridge S, Taylor S. How effective are expert patient (lay led) education programmes for chronic disease?. BMJ 2007;334:1254&#x2010;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1892511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17569933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Hawker GA, Laporte A, Croxford R, Coyte PC. The economic burden of disabling hip and knee osteoarthritis (OA) from the perspective of individuals living with this condition. Rheumatology 2005;44:1531&#x2010;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16091394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampson SE, Glasgow RE, Zeiss AM. Personal models of osteoarthritis and their relation to self&#x2010;management activities and quality of life. Journal of Behavioural Medicine 1994;17:143&#x2010;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8035449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hannes K. Chapter 4: critical appraisal of qualitative research, 2011. Supplementary Guidance for Inclusion of Qualitative Research in Cochrane Systematic Reviews of Interventions. Version 1 (updated August 2011). cqrmg.cochrane.org/supplemental&#x2010;handbook&#x2010;guidance (last accessed prior to 12 March 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harden A, Garcia J, Oliver S, Rees R, Shepherd J, Brunton G, et al. Applying systematic review methods to studies of people's views: an example from public health research. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health 2004;58:794&#x2010;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1732892</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15310807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hawker G, Gignac M, Badley E, Davis A, French M, Li Y, et al. A longitudinal study to explain the pain&#x2010;depression link in older adults with osteoarthritis. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2011;63:1382&#x2010;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20662042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendry M, Williams NH, Markland D, Wilkinson C, Maddison P. Why should we exercise when our knees hurt? A qualitative study of primary care patients with osteoarthritis of the knee. Family Practice 2006;23:558&#x2010;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16731544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins J, Thompson S, Deeks J, Altman D. Measuring inconsistency in meta&#x2010;analyses. BMJ 2003;327:557&#x2010;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC192859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12958120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, Sterne JA. Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in included studies. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinman RS, Delany CM, Campbell PK, Gale J, Bennell KL. Physical therapists, telephone coaches, and patients with knee osteoarthritis: qualitative study about working together to promote exercise adherence. Physical Therapy 2016;96(4):479&#x2010;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hochberg MC, Altman RD, April KT, Benkhalti M, Guyatt GH, McGowan J, et al. American College of Rheumatology 2012 recommendations for the use of nonpharmacologic and pharmacologic therapies in osteoarthritis of the hand, hip, and knee. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2012;64:465&#x2010;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22563589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden MA, Nicholls EE, Hay EM, Foster NE. Physical therapists&#x2019; use of therapeutic exercise for patients with clinical knee osteoarthritis in the United Kingdom: in line with current recommendations?. Physical Therapy 2008;88:1109&#x2010;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2557052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18703675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopkins J. 2002. 
Arthritis provides clinical classification criteria and management guidelines. 
www.hopkinsarthritis.som.jhmi.edu (accessed on May 21 2002 by Yip et al. Webpage no longer available at time of review).
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley MV. The role of muscle weakness in the pathogenesis of osteoarthritis. Rheumatic Diseases Clinics of North America 1999;25:283&#x2010;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10356418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley MV, Mitchell HL, Walsh N. In osteoarthritis, the psychosocial benefits of exercise are as important as physiological improvements. Exercise and Sports Science Review 2003;31:138&#x2010;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12882480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley MV, Walsh NE. Effectiveness and clinical applicability of integrated rehabilitation programs for knee osteoarthritis. Current Opinion in Rheumatology 2009;21:171&#x2010;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19339929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley M, Walsh N, Bhavnani V, Britten N, Stevenson F. Health beliefs before and after participation on an exercised&#x2010;based rehabilitation programme for chronic knee pain: doing is believing. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders 2010;11:31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2828988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20149236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley MV, Walsh NE, Mitchell H, Nicholas J, Patel A. Long&#x2010;term outcomes and costs of an integrated rehabilitation program for chronic knee pain: a pragmatic, cluster randomized, controlled trial. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2012;64:238&#x2010;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21954131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jinks C, Jordan K, Ong BN, Croft P. A brief screening tool for knee pain in primary care (KNEST). 2. Results from a survey in the general population aged 50 and over. Rheumatology 2004;43:55&#x2010;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12923283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan JL, Holden MA, Mason EE, Foster NE. Interventions to improve adherence to exercise for chronic musculoskeletal pain in adults. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2010, Issue 1. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD005956.pub2]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD005956.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6769154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20091582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juhl C, Christensen R, Roos EM, Zhang W, Lund H. Impact of exercise type and dose on pain and disability in knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;regression analysis of randomized controlled trials. Arthritis and Rheumatology 2014;66:622&#x2010;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24574223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavanagh J, Oliver S, Lorenc T. Reflections on developing and using PROGRESSPlus. Cochrane Health Equity Field and Campbell Equity Methods Group Equity Update. March 2008. Equity Update2008; Vol. 2, issue 1:1&#x2010;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keefe FJ, Beaupre PM, Gil KN. Group therapy for patients with chronic pain. In: Gatchel RJ, Turk DC editor(s). Psychological Approaches to Pain Management: a Practitioner's Handbook. New York (NY): Guildford Press, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keefe FJ, Kashikar&#x2010;Zuck S, Opiteck J, Hage E, Dalrymple L, Blumenthal JA. Pain in arthritis and musculoskeletal disorders: the role of coping skills training and exercise interventions. Journal of Orthopedics &amp; Sports Physical Therapy 1996;24:278&#x2010;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8892142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroon FP, Burg LR, Buchbinder R, Osborne R, Johnston R, Pitt V. Self&#x2010;management education programmes for osteoarthritis. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2014, Issue 1. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD008963.pub2]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD008963.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11104559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24425500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larmer PJ, Reay ND, Aubert ER, Kersten P. Systematic review of guidelines for the physical management of osteoarthritis. Archives of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation 2014;95:375&#x2010;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24184307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larmer P, Kersten P, Dangan J. Patient reported benefits of hydrotherapy for arthritis. New Zealand Journal of Physiotherapy 2014;42(2):89&#x2010;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leardini G, Salaffi F, Caporali R, Canesi B, Rovati L, Montanelli R, et al. Direct and indirect costs of osteoarthritis of the knee. Clinical and Experimental Rheumatology 2004;22:699&#x2010;706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15638043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leeuwa M, Houben RM, Severeijns R, Picavet HS, Schouten EG, Vlaeyena JW. Pain&#x2010;related fear in low back pain: a prospective study in the general population. European Journal of Pain 2007;11:256&#x2010;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16546425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenc T, Brunton G, Oliver S, Oliver K, Oakley A. Attitudes to walking and cycling among children, young people and parents: a systematic review. Journal of Epidemiology and Community Health 2008;62:852&#x2010;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18791040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Main C, Watson P. Psychological aspects of pain. Manual Therapy 2002;4:203&#x2010;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10593109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maly MR, Cott CA. Being careful: a grounded theory of emergent chronic knee problems. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2009;61:937&#x2010;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>March LM, Bachmeier CJ. Economics of osteoarthritis: a global perspective. Bailliere's Clinical Rheumatology 1997;11:817&#x2010;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9429738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mays N, Pope C. Rigor and qualitative research. BMJ 1995;311:109&#x2010;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2550154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7613363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAlindon TE, Bannuru RR, Sullivan MC, Arden NK, Berenbaum F, Bierma&#x2010;Zeinstra SM, et al. OARSI guidelines for the non&#x2010;surgical management of knee osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis and Cartilage 2014;22:363&#x2010;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24462672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E. The role of efficacy cognitions in the prediction of exercise behavior in middle&#x2010;aged adults. Journal of Behavioral Medicine 1992;15:65&#x2010;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1583674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E, Lox C, Duncan TE. Long&#x2010;term maintenance of exercise, self&#x2010;efficacy, and physiological change in older adults. Journal of Gerontology (Psychological Sciences) 1993;48:218&#x2010;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8315239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAuley E, Konopack JF, Morris KS, Motl RW, Hu L, Doerksen SE, et al. Physical activity and functional limitations in older women: influence of self&#x2010;efficacy. Journal of Gerontology 2006;61B:270&#x2010;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles CL, Pincus T, Carnes D, Homer KE, Taylor SJ, Bremner SA, et al. Can we identify how programmes aimed at promoting self&#x2010;management in musculoskeletal pain work and who benefits? A systematic review of sub&#x2010;group analysis within RCTs. European Journal of Pain 2011;15:775.e1&#x2010;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21354838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moody J, Hale L, Waters D. Perceptions of a water&#x2010;based exercise programme to improve physical function and falls risk in older adults with lower extremity osteoarthritis: barriers, motivators and sustainability. New Zealand Journal of Physiotherapy 2012;40(2):64&#x2010;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morden A, Jinks C, Ong BN. Lay models of self&#x2010;management: how do people manage knee osteoarthritis in context?. Chronic Illness 2011;7(3):185&#x2010;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21343222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newman PS, Steed L, Mulligan K. Self&#x2010;management interventions for chronic illness. Lancet 2004;364:1523&#x2010;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15500899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. 
Osteoarthritis: the care and management of osteoarthritis in adults. NICE clinical guideline 59. 
www.nice.org.uk/nicemedia/pdf/cg59niceguideline.pdf. Accessed prior to 12 March 2018.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. 
Osteoarthritis: care and management in adults. NICE clinical guideline 177. 
www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg177. Accessed prior to 12 March 2018.
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliver S, Harden A, Rees R, Shepherd J, Brunton G, Oakley A. Young people and mental health: novel methods for systematic review of research on barriers and facilitators. Health Education Research 2008;23:770&#x2010;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17984295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peat G, McCarney R, Croft P. Knee pain and osteoarthritis in older adults: a review of community burden and current use of primary health care. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases 2001;60:91&#x2010;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1753462</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11156538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penninx BW, Rejeski WJ, Pandya J, Miller ME, Bari M, Applegate WB, et al. Exercise and depressive symptoms: a comparison of aerobic and resistance exercise effects on emotional and physical function in older persons with high and low depressive symptomatology. Journals of Gerontology Series B: Psychological Sciences &amp; Social Sciences 2002;57:124&#x2010;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11867660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petursdottir U, Arnadottir SA, Halldorsdottir S. Facilitators and barriers to exercising among people with osteoarthritis: a phenomenological study. Physical Therapy 2010;90:1014&#x2010;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20466741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phyomaung PP, Dubowitz J, Cicuttini FM, Fernando S, Wluka AE, Raaijmaakers P, et al. Are depression, anxiety and poor mental health risk factors for knee pain? A systematic review. BMC Musculoskeletal Disorders 2014;15:10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3907141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24405725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisters MF, Veenhof C, Meeteren NL, Ostelo RW, Bakker DH, Schellevis FG, et al. Long&#x2010;Term effectiveness of exercise therapy in patients with osteoarthritis of the hip or knee: a systematic review. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2007;57:1245&#x2010;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17907210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popay J, Rogers A, Williams G. Rationale and standards for the systematic review of qualitative literature in health services research. Qualitative Health Research 1998;8:341&#x2010;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10558335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rees R, Kavanagh J, Harden A, Shepherd J, Brunton G, Oliver S, et al. Young people and physical activity: a systematic review matching their views to effective interventions. Health Education Research 2006;21:806&#x2010;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17041020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rejeski WJ, Ettigner WH, Martin K, Morgan T. Treating disability in knee osteoarthritis with exercise: a central role for self&#x2010;efficacy and pain. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 1998;11:94&#x2010;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9668732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Nordic Cochrane Centre, The Cochrane Collaboration. Review Manager (RevMan). Version 5.3. Copenhagen: The Nordic Cochrane Centre, The Cochrane Collaboration, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roddy E, Zhang W, Doherty M, Arden NK, Barlow J, Birrell F, et al. Evidence&#x2010;based recommendations for the role of exercise in the management of osteoarthritis of the hip or knee &#x2010; the MOVE consensus. Rheumatology 2005;44:67&#x2010;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15353613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ, Oxman AD, Higgins JP, Vist GE, Glasziou P, Guyatt GH. Chapter 11: Presenting results and 'Summary of findings' tables. In: Higgins JP, Green S, editor(s), Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from handbook.cochrane.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TO, Purdy R, Lister S, Salter C, Fleetcroft R, Conaghan PG. Attitudes of people with osteoarthritis towards their conservative management: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;ethnography. Rheumatology International 2014;34:299&#x2010;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24306266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TO, Purdy R, Lister S, Salter C, Fleetcroft R, Conaghan P. Living with osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;ethnography. Scandinavian Journal of Rheumatology 2014;43:441&#x2010;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24882107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Harbord RM. Funnel plots in meta&#x2010;analysis. Stata Journal 2004;4(2):127&#x2010;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone RC, Baker J. Painful choices: a qualitative exploration of facilitators and barriers to active lifestyles among adults with osteoarthritis. Journal of Applied Gerontology 2015;36(9):1091&#x2010;116. [DOI: 10.1177/0733464815602114]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0733464815602114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stretton CM, Latham NK, Carter KN, Lee AC, Anderson CS. Determinants of physical health in frail older people: the importance of self efficacy. Clinical Rehabilitation 2005;20:357&#x2010;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16719034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor AH, Cable NT, Faulkner G, Hillsdon M, Narici M, Bij AK. Physical activity and older adults: a review of health benefits and the effectiveness of interventions. Journal of Sports Science 2004;22:703&#x2010;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15370483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas J, Harden A, Oakley A, Oliver S, Sutcliffe K, Rees R, et al. Integrating qualitative research with trials in systematic reviews. BMJ 2004;328:1010&#x2010;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC404509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15105329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorstensson CA, Roos EM, Petersson IF, Arvidsson B. How do middle&#x2010;aged patients conceive exercise as a form of treatment for knee osteoarthritis?. Disability and Rehabilitation 2006;28(1):51&#x2010;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16393833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turk DC. Biopsychosocial perspectives on chronic pain. Psychological Approaches to Pain Management: a Practitioner's Handbook. New York (NY): Guildford Press, 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Underwood M. Community management of knee pain in older people: is knee pain the new back pain?. Rheumatology 2004;43:2&#x2010;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12923284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uthman OA, Windt DA, Jordan JL, Dziedzic KS, Healey EL, Peat GM, et al. Exercise for lower limb osteoarthritis: systematic review incorporating trial sequential analysis and network meta&#x2010;analysis. BMJ 2013;347:f5555.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3779121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24055922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baar ME, Dekker J, Lemmens JA, Oostendorp RA, Bijlsma JW. Pain and disability in patients with osteoarthritis of hip or knee: the relationship with articular, kinesiological, and psychological characteristics. Journal of Rheumatology 1998;25:125&#x2010;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9458215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veenhof C, Hasselt TJ, Koke AJ, Dekker J, Bijlsma JW, Ende CH. Active involvement and long&#x2010;term goals influence long&#x2010;term adherence to behavioural graded activity in patients with osteoarthritis: a qualitative study. Australian Journal of Physiotherapy 2006;52(4):273&#x2010;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17132122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vos T, Flaxman AD, Naghavi M, Lozano R, Michaud C, Ezzati M, et al. Years lived with disability (YLDs) for 1160 sequelae of 289 diseases and injuries 1990&#x2010;2010: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. Lancet 2012;380:2163&#x2010;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6350784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh NE, Hurley MV. Evidence based guidelines and current practice for physiotherapy management of knee osteoarthritis. Musculoskeletal Care 2009;7:45&#x2010;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18972322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Division of Mental Health and Prevention of Substance Abuse, 
World Health Organization. 
WHOQOL measuring quality of life. 
www.who.int/mental_health/media/68.pdf (accessed prior to 12 March 2018).
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woolf AD, Pfleger B. Burden of major musculoskeletal conditions. Bulletin of the World Health Organization 2003;81:646&#x2010;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2572542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14710506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Moskowitz RW, Nuki G, Abramson S, Altman RD, Arden N, et al. OARSI recommendations for the management of hip and knee osteoarthritis. Part II: OARSI evidence&#x2010;based, expert consensus guidelines. Osteoarthritis and Cartilage 2008;16:137&#x2010;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18279766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>