<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">34215712</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2093-758X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of Korean Academy of Nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Korean Acad Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>[Effects of a Cognitive Behavior Therapy Program for Patients with Fibromyalgia Syndrome: A Randomized Controlled Trial].</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>347</StartPage><EndPage>362</EndPage><MedlinePgn>347-362</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4040/jkan.21025</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study developed a cognitive behavioral therapy program aimed at altering the physical condition, emotions, and behaviors of fibromyalgia patients, and confirmed the program's clinical applicability. The program was developed by analyzing previous studies conducting in-depth interviews with fibromyalgia patients, drawing on cognitive behavior theory to establish the program contents, recruiting experts to test its validity, and conducting a preliminary survey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">To confirm the program's effect, this study used a randomized controlled trial design. The participants were outpatients diagnosed with fibromyalgia in Dong-A University Hospital, Busan. The 30 patients in the experimental group took part in the program, which comprised 8 sessions (90 to 120 minutes) based on cognitive behavior theory, delivered over 8 weeks. Hypothesis testing was carried out using the repeated measures ANOVA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The analysis revealed significant differences between the experimental and control groups in positive automatic thoughts, pain, fatigue, depression, and interpersonal relationships. However, there was no significant difference between the groups in terms of sleep disorders and negative automatic thoughts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This program is a positive effect on physical condition, emotions, and behaviors. It is thus expected to be used to help fibromyalgia patients improve their disease conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Korean Society of Nursing Science.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kong</LastName><ForeName>Kyoung Ran</ForeName><Initials>KR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2694-7185</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Ulsan College, Ulsan, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Eun Nam</ForeName><Initials>EN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9421-0118</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Nursing, Dong-A University, Busan, Korea. enlee@dau.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>kor</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>J Korean Acad Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101488689</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2005-3673</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015928" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005356" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibromyalgia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010146" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010147" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Measurement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015397" MajorTopicYN="N">Program Evaluation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Behavior Therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibromyalgia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34215712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4040/jkan.21025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">51.347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mease P, Arnold LM, Choy EH, Clauw DJ, Crofford LJ, Glass JM, et al. Fibromyalgia syndrome module at OMERACT 9: Domain construct. Journal of Rheumatology 2009;36(10):2318&#x2013;2329.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe F, Clauw DJ, Fitzcharles MA, Goldenberg DL, Katz RS, Mease P, et al. The American College of Rheumatology preliminary diagnostic criteria for fibromyalgia and measurement of symptom severity. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2010;62(5):600&#x2013;610.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Branco JC, Bannwarth B, Failde I, Abello Carbonell J, Blotman F, Spaeth M, et al. Prevalence of fibromyalgia: A survey in five European countries. Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism 2010;39(6):448&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19250656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones GT, Atzeni F, Beasley M, Fl&#xfc;&#xdf; E, Sarzi-Puttini P, Macfarlane GJ. The prevalence of fibromyalgia in the general population: A comparison of the American College of Rheumatology 1990, 2010, and modified 2010 classification criteria. Arthritis &amp; Rheumatology 2015;67(2):568&#x2013;575.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfe F, Br&#xe4;hler E, Hinz A, H&#xe4;user W. Fibromyalgia prevalence, somatic symptom reporting, and the dimensionality of polysymptomatic distress: Results from a survey of the general population. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2013;65(5):777&#x2013;785.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauw DJ. Fibromyalgia: An overview. The American Journal of Medicine 2009;122 12 Suppl:S3&#x2013;S13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19962494</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bj&#xf6;rkegren K, Wallander MA, Johansson S, Sv&#xe4;rdsudd K. General symptom reporting in female fibromyalgia patients and referents: A population-based case-referent study. BMC Public Health 2009;9:402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spaeth M, Rizzi M, Sarzi-Puttini P. Fibromyalgia and sleep. Best Practice &amp; Research. Clinical Rheumatology 2011;25(2):227&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22094198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solano C, Martinez A, Becerril L, Vargas A, Figueroa J, Navarro C, et al. Autonomic dysfunction in fibromyalgia assessed by the Composite Autonomic Symptoms Scale (COMPASS). Journal of Clinical Rheumatology 2009;15(4):172&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19342959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karlsson B, Burell G, Anderberg UM, Sv&#xe4;rdsudd K. Cognitive behaviour therapy in women with fibromyalgia: A randomized clinical trial. Scandinavian Journal of Pain 2015;9(1):11&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29911653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarzi-Puttini P, Atzeni F, Salaffi F, Cazzola M, Benucci M, Mease PJ. Multidisciplinary approach to fibromyalgia: What is the teaching? Best Practice &amp; Research. Clinical Rheumatology 2011;25(2):311&#x2013;319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SS. Diagnosis and treatment of fibromyalgia syndrome. The Korean Journal of Medicine 2013;84(5):650&#x2013;658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verbunt JA, Pernot DH, Smeets RJ. Disability and quality of life in patients with fibromyalgia. Health and Quality of Life Outcomes 2008;6:8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2265693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18211701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarzi-Puttini P, Buskila D, Carrabba M, Doria A, Atzeni F. Treatment strategy in fibromyalgia syndrome: Where are we now? Seminars in Arthritis and Rheumatism 2008;37(6):353&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17976693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger A, Dukes E, Martin S, Edelsberg J, Oster G. Characteristics and healthcare costs of patients with fibromyalgia syndrome. International Journal of Clinical Practice 2007;61(9):1498&#x2013;1508.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2040193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17655684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han SS, Bak WS, Yang HI. The effect of a Tai-Chi self-helf program for fibromyalgia patient. Journal of Muscle and Joint Health 2007;14(2):169&#x2013;180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernardy K, F&#xfc;ber N, K&#xf6;llner V, H&#xe4;user W. Efficacy of cognitive-behavioral therapies in fibromyalgia syndrome: A systematic review and metaanalysis of randomized controlled trials. The Journal of Rheumatology 2010;37(10):1991&#x2013;2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20682676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thieme K, Flor H, Turk DC. Psychological pain treatment in fibromyalgia syndrome: Efficacy of operant behavioural and cognitive behavioural treatments. Arthritis Research &amp; Therapy 2006;8(4):R121.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friesen LN, Hadjistavropoulos HD, Schneider LH, Alberts NM, Titov N, Dear BF. Examination of an Internet-delivered cognitive behavioural pain management course for adults with fibromyalgia: A randomized controlled trial. Pain 2017;158(4):593&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27984490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castel A, Fontova R, Montull S, Peri&#xf1;&#xe1;n R, Poveda MJ, Miralles I, et al. Efficacy of a multidisciplinary fibromyalgia treatment adapted for women with low educational levels: A randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2013;65(3):421&#x2013;431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck JS. In: Cognitive therapy: Basics and beyond. New York (NY): Guilford Press; 1995. pp. 71-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vallejo MA, Ortega J, Rivera J, Comeche MI, Vallejo-Slocker L. Internet versus face-to-face group cognitive-behavioral therapy for fibromyalgia: A randomized control trial. Journal of Psychiatric Research 2015;68:106&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26228408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ingram RE, Wisnicki KS. Assessment of positive automatic cognition. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology 1988;56(6):898&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3204200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JY, Kim JH. Assessment of positive cognition: A standardization study of Korean Automatic Thought Questionnaire - Positive: ATQ-P. Korean Journal of Clinical Psychology 2002;21(3):647&#x2013;664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollon SD, Kendall PC. Cognitive self-statements in depression: Development of an automatic thoughts questionnaire. Cognitive Therapy and Research 1980;4(4):383&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon SM. Reliability, validity and factor structure of the Korean version of dysfunctional attitude scale. Psychological Science 1994;3(1):100&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smets EM, Garssen B, Bonke B, De Haes JC. The Multidimensional Fatigue Inventory (MFI) psychometric qualities of an instrument to assess fatigue. Journal of Psychosomatic Research 1995;39(3):315&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7636775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlein SP, Guerney B, Stover L. The interpersonal telationship scale (IRS). In: Guerney BG, editor. Relationship enhancement. San Francisco (CA): Jossey-Bass; 1977. pp. 349-354.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun SK. The social skills training for social adjustment of the schizophrenic patients. Mental Health &amp; Social Work 1995;2:33&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorn BE, Kuhajda MC. Group cognitive therapy for chronic pain. Journal of Clinical Psychology 2006;62(11):1355&#x2013;1366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16937348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbonell-Baeza A, Aparicio VA, Chill&#xf3;n P, Femia P, Delgado-Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Ruiz JR. Effectiveness of multidisciplinary therapy on symptomatology and quality of life in women with fibromyalgia. Clinical and Experimental Rheumatology 2011;29(6 Suppl 69):S97&#x2013;S103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22243556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edinger JD, Wohlgemuth WK, Krystal AD, Rice JR. Behavioral insomnia therapy for fibromyalgia patients: A randomized clinical trial. Archives of Internal Medicine 2005;165(21):2527&#x2013;2535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16314551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazaridou A, Kim J, Cahalan CM, Loggia ML, Franceschelli O, Berna C, et al. Effects of cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT) on brain connectivity supporting catastrophizing in fibromyalgia. The Clinical Journal of Pain 2017;33(3):215&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27518491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n J, Torre F, Padierna A, Aguirre U, Gonz&#xe1;lez N, Garc&#xed;a S, et al. Six-and 12-month follow-up of an interdisciplinary fibromyalgia treatment programme: Results of a randomised trial. Clinical and Experimental Rheumatology 2012;30(6 Suppl 74):103&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe1;zquez-Rivera S, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Blanch C, Rodr&#xed;guez-Moya L, Mor&#xf3;n D, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Vives S, Carrasco JL. Brief cognitive-behavioral therapy with fibromyalgia patients in routine care. Comprehensive Psychiatry 2009;50(6):517&#x2013;525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez MP, Mir&#xf3; E, S&#xe1;nchez AI, D&#xed;az-Piedra C, C&#xe1;liz R, Vlaeyen JW, et al. Cognitive-behavioral therapy for insomnia and sleep hygiene in fibromyalgia: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Behavioral Medicine 2014;37(4):683&#x2013;697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salaffi F, Ciapetti A, Gasparini S, Atzeni F, Sarzi-Puttini P, Baroni M. Web/Internet-based telemonitoring of a randomized controlled trial evaluating the time-integrated effects of a 24-week multicomponent intervention on key health outcomes in patients with fibromyalgia. Clinical and Experimental Rheumatology 2015;33(1 Suppl 88):S93&#x2013;S101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25786050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luciano JV, Sabes-Figuera R, Carde&#xf1;osa E, T Pe&#xf1;arrubia-Mar&#xed;a M, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Vergel R, Garc&#xed;a-Campayo J, et al. Cost-utility of a psychoeducational intervention in fibromyalgia patients compared with usual care: An economic evaluation alongside a 12-month randomized controlled trial. The Clinical Journal of Pain 2013;29(8):702&#x2013;711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23328339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HY, Kim JM, Lee MY. Development and its effect of empathy training program based on the cognitive behavior therapy for the student nurses. Cognitive Behavior Therapy in Korea 2016;16(4):567&#x2013;594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang EY, Kim JM, Jeong HN. The development and effect of cognitive behavioral therapy program for psychosocial adjustment of infertile women. Korean Journal of Counseling 2015;16(3):451&#x2013;471.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim SH, Lee MY, Kim JM. Cognitive-behavioral grief therapy for middle-aged women after spousal bereavement. Cognitive Behavior Therapy in Korea 2013;13(2):173&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinrich S, Rozental A, Carlbring P, Andersson G, Cotter K, Weise C. Treating tinnitus distress via the Internet: A mixed methods approach of what makes patients seek help and stay motivated during Internet-based cognitive behavior therapy. Internet Interventions 2016;4:120&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menga G, Ing S, Khan O, Dupre B, Dornelles AC, Alarakhia A, et al. Fibromyalgia: Can online cognitive behavioral therapy help? The Ochsner Journal 2014;14(3):343&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4171792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redondo JR, Justo CM, Moraleda FV, Velayos YG, Puche JJ, Zubero JR, et al. Long-term efficacy of therapy in patients with fibromyalgia: A physical exercise-based program and a cognitive-behavioral approach. Arthritis Care &amp; Research 2004;51(2):184&#x2013;192.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castel A, Casc&#xf3;n R, Padrol A, Sala J, Rull M. Multicomponent cognitive-behavioral group therapy with hypnosis for the treatment of fibromyalgia: Long-term outcome. The Journal of Pain 2012;13(3):255&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22285609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lami MJ, Mart&#xed;nez MP, S&#xe1;nchez AI, Mir&#xf3; E, Diener FN, Prados G, et al. Gender differences in patients with fibromyalgia undergoing cognitive-behavioral therapy for insomnia: Preliminary data. Pain Practice 2016;16(2):E23&#x2013;E34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26841198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang NK. Cognitive-behavioral therapy for sleep abnormalities of chronic pain patients. Current Rheumatology Reports 2009;11(6):451&#x2013;460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saral I, Sindel D, Esmaeilzadeh S, Sertel-Berk HO, Oral A. The effects of long- and short-term interdisciplinary treatment approaches in women with fibromyalgia: A randomized controlled trial. Rheumatology International 2016;36(10):1379&#x2013;1389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27055444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson FJ, Winkler AE. Benefits of long-term fibromyalgia syndrome treatment with a multidisciplinary program. Journal of Musculoskeletal Pain 2006;14(4):11&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>