<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35246982</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1746-1561</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>92</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of school health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Sch Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Before-School Physical Activity Program's Impact on Social and Emotional Learning.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>674</StartPage><EndPage>680</EndPage><MedlinePgn>674-680</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/josh.13167</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Despite the positive impact of social and emotional learning (SEL) on the emotional well-being of children, literature on physical activity engagement and SEL among this population has been limited. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to examine whether school students' SEL would improve after participation in a before-school physical activity program.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 138 fourth and sixth grade students from 1 elementary school and 1 middle school participated in this study. Seventy-five students participated in the before-school physical activity program, while 63 students were in the control group. The physical education teachers implemented the program 3&#x2009;days per week, for 3&#x2009;weeks. The participants completed a 10-question adapted Devereux Student Strengths Assessment-Mini before and after the program. Repeated measures ANOVA was run to determine the effects of the program on SEL competence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The fourth and sixth grade students who participated in the program reported a 7 and 10% improvement in pre- versus post-intervention SEL competence, respectively. Students in the control group reported no change in their SEL competence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Considering the benefits of a before-school physical activity program on students' SEL, stakeholders should consider including more physical activity programming within school policies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 American School Health Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goh</LastName><ForeName>Tan Leng</ForeName><Initials>TL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5007-2665</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Human Performance, Central Connecticut State University, 1615 Stanley Street, New Britain, CT, 06050, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leong</LastName><ForeName>Chee Hoi</ForeName><Initials>CH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Human Performance, Central Connecticut State University, 1615 Stanley Street, New Britain, CT, 06050, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fede</LastName><ForeName>Marybeth</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health and Movement Sciences, Southern Connecticut State University, 501 Crescent Street, New Haven, CT, 06515, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ciotto</LastName><ForeName>Carol</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Education and Professional Studies, Central Connecticut State University, 1615 Stanley Street, New Britain, CT, 06050, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Sch Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0376370</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-4391</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004644" MajorTopicYN="N">Emotions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012574" MajorTopicYN="Y">Schools</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066107" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Skills</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elementary school</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">middle school</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social-emotional competence</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35246982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/josh.13167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. 2018 physical activity guidelines advisory committee scientific report. 2018. Available at: https://health.gov/sites/default/files/2019-09/PAG_Advisory_Committee_Report.pdf. Accessed January 03, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Comprehensive school physical activity programs: a guide for schools. 2013. https://www.cdc.gov/healthyschools/physicalactivity/pdf/13_242620-A_CSPAP_SchoolPhysActivityPrograms_Final_508_12192013.pdf. Accessed January 03, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan NA, Hillman CH. The relation of childhood physical activity and aerobic fitness to brain function and cognition: a review. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2014;26(2):138-146. https://doi.org/10.1123/pes.2013-0125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Lambourne K. Classroom-based physical activity, cognition, and academic achievement. Prev Med. 2011;52(suppl 1):S36-S42. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2011.01.021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullender-Wijnsma MJ, Hartman E, de Greeff JW, Bosker RJ, Doolaard S, Visscher C. Improving academic performance of school-age children by physical activity in the classroom: 1-year program evaluation. J Sch Health. 2015;85(6):365-371. https://doi.org/10.1111/josh.12259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Greene JL, Gibson CA, et al. Physical Activity Across the Curriculum (PAAC): a randomized controlled trial to promote physical activity and diminish overweight and obesity in elementary school children. Prev Med. 2009;49(4):336-341. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2009.07.022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlson JA, Engelberg JK, Cain KL, et al. Implementing classroom physical activity breaks: associations with student physical activity and classroom behavior. Prev Med. 2015;81:67-72. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2015.08.006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goh TL, Hannon J, Webster C, Podlog L, Newton M. Effects of a TAKE 10! Classroom-based physical activity intervention on third- to fifth-grade children's on-task behavior. J Phys Act Health. 2016;13(7):712-718. https://doi.org/10.1123/jpah.2015-0238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grieco LA, Jowers EM, Bartholomew JB. Physically active academic lessons and time on task: the moderating effect of body mass index. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2009;41(10):1921-1926. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181a61495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahar MT, Murphy SK, Rowe DA, Golden J, Shields AT, Raedeke TD. Effects of a classroom-based program on physical activity and on-task behavior. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2006;38(12):2086-2094. https://doi.org/10.1249/01.mss.0000235359.16685.a3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok MMC, Chin MK, Korcz A, et al. Brain breaks&#xae; physical activity solutions in the classroom and on attitudes toward physical activity: a randomized controlled trial among primary students from eight countries. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17(5):1666. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17051666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finkelstein EA, Fiebelkorn IC, Wang G. State-level estimates of annual medical expenditures attributable to obesity. Obes Res. 2004;12(1):18-24. https://doi.org/10.1038/oby.2004.4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stylianou M, van der Mars H, Kulinna PH, Adams MA, Mahar M, Amazeen E. Before-school running/walking club and student physical activity levels: an efficacy study. Res Q Exerc Sport. 2016;87(4):342-353. https://doi.org/10.1080/02701367.2016.1214665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cradock AL, Barrett JL, Taveras EM, et al. Effects of a before-school program on student physical activity levels. Prev Med Rep. 2019;15:100940. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmedr.2019.100940.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whooten RC, Perkins ME, Gerber MW, Taveras EM. Effects of before-school physical activity on obesity prevention and wellness. Am J Prev Med. 2018;54(4):510-518. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.amepre.2018.01.017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westcott W, Puhala K, Colligan A, Loud RL, Cobbett R. Physiological effects of the BOKS before-school physical activity program for preadolescent youth. J Exerc Sports Orthop. 2015;2(2):1-7. https://doi.org/10.15226/2374-6904/2/2/00129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Hermoso A, Hormaz&#xe1;bal-Aguayo I, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Vergara O, et al. A before-school physical activity intervention to improve cognitive parameters in children: the Active-Start study. Scand J Med Sci Sports. 2020;30(1):108-116. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.13537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garnett BR, Becker K, Vierling D, Gleason C, DiCenzo D, Mongeon L. A mixed-methods evaluation of the Move it Move it! before-school incentive-based physical activity programme. Health Educ J. 2017;76(1):89-101. https://doi.org/10.1177/0017896916652432.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahar MT, Vuchenich ML, Golden J, DuBose KD, Raedeke TD. Effects of a before-school physical activity program on physical activity and on-task behavior. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(5):24. https://doi.org/10.1249/01.MSS.0000402740.12322.07.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaborative for Academic, Social, and Emotional Learning. Safe and sound: an educational leader's guide to evidence-based social and emotional learning (SEL) programs. 2003. Available at: https://casel.org/safe-and-sound-guide-to-sel-programs/. Accessed January 03, 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collaborative for Academic, Social, and Emotional Learning (CASEL). What is the CASEL framework?. Available at: https://casel.org/fundamentals-of-sel/what-is-the-casel-framework/. Accessed December 15, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harlacher JE, Merrell KW. Social and emotional learning as a universal level of student support: evaluating the follow-up effect of Strong Kids on social and emotional outcomes. J Appl Sch Psychol. 2010;26(3):212-229. https://doi.org/10.1080/15377903.2010.495903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low S, Cook CR, Smolkowski K, Buntain-Ricklefs J. Promoting social-emotional competence: an evaluation of the elementary version of Second Step&#xae;. J Sch Psychol. 2015;53(6):463-477. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsp.2015.09.002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upshur CC, Heyman M, Wenz-Gross M. Efficacy trial of the Second Step Early Learning (SSEL) curriculum: preliminary outcomes. J Appl Dev Psychol. 2017;50:15-25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.appdev.2017.03.004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schonfeld DJ, Adams RE, Fredstrom BK, et al. Cluster-randomized trial demonstrating impact on academic achievement of elementary social-emotional learning. Sch Psychol Q. 2015;30(3):406-420. https://doi.org/10.1037/spq0000099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor RD, Oberle E, Durlak JA, Weissberg RP. Promoting positive youth development through school-based social and emotional learning interventions: a meta-analysis of follow-up effects. Child Dev. 2017;88(4):1156-1171. https://doi.org/10.1111/cdev.12864.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith BH, Low S. The role of social-emotional learning in bullying prevention efforts. Theory Pract. 2013;52(4):280-287. https://doi.org/10.1080/00405841.2013.829731.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eklund K, Kilpatrick KD, Kilgus SP, Haider A. A systematic review of state-level social-emotional learning standards: implications for practice and research. Sch Psychol Rev. 2018;47(3):316-326. https://doi.org/10.17105/SPR-2017.0116.V47-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards KAR, Ivy VN, Wright PM, Jerris E. Combining the skill themes approach with teaching personal and social responsibility to teach social and emotional learning in elementary physical education. J Phys Educ Recreat Dance. 2019;90(3):35-44. https://doi.org/10.1080/07303084.2018.1559665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyson B, Howley D, Wright PM. A scoping review critically examining research connecting social and emotional learning with three model-based practices in physical education: have we been doing this all along? Eur Phy Educ Rev. 2021;27(1):76-95. https://doi.org/10.1177/1356336X20923710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luna P, Guerrero J, Cejudo J. Improving adolescents' subjective well-being, trait emotional intelligence and social anxiety through a programme based on the sport education model. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(10):1821. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph16101821.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grim M, Petosa R, Hortz B, Hunt L. Formative evaluation of MyFit: a curriculum to promote self-regulation of physical activity among middle school students. Am J Health Educ. 2013;44(2):81-87. https://doi.org/10.1080/19325037.2013.764238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall G, Poston KF, Harris S. Before the school bell rings: how a before-school physical activity program improves executive functions. Afterschool Matters. 2015;22:54-58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Education Statistics. CCD Public School Data 2019-2020 School Year: West Woods School. https://nces.ed.gov/ccd/schoolsearch/school_detail.asp?Search=1&amp;DistrictID=0901860&amp;ID=090186000349. Accessed June 18, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Education Statistics. CCD Public School Data 2019-2020 School Year: McGee Middle School. https://nces.ed.gov/ccd/schoolsearch/school_detail.asp?ID=090021000017. Accessed June 18, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro VB, Kim BKE, Robitaille JL, LeBuffe PA. Protective factor screening for prevention practice: sensitivity and specificity of the DESSA-Mini. Sch Psychol Q. 2017;32(4):449-464. https://doi.org/10.1037/spq0000181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott SN, Lei PW, Anthony Christopher J, DiPerna JC. Screening the whole social-emotional child: expanding a brief SEL assessment to include emotional behavior concerns. Sch Psychol Rev. 2021:1-15. https://doi.org/10.1080/2372966X.2020.1857659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakeman R. Recommended effect size statistics for repeated measures designs. Behav Res Methods. 2005;37(3):379-384. https://doi.org/10.3758/BF03192707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. New York, NY: Academic Press; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunton GF, Huh J, Leventhal AM, et al. Momentary assessment of affect, physical feeling states, and physical activity in children. Health Psychol. 2014;33(3):255-263. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0032640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romer N, Ravitch NK, Tom K, Merrell KW, Wesley KL. Gender differences in positive social-emotional functioning: gender and social and emotional strengths. Psychol Sch. 2011;48(10):958-970. https://doi.org/10.1002/pits.20604.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>