<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35735784</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-5065</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Women's health (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Womens Health (Lond)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nurses' strategies to provide emotional and practical support to the mothers of preterm infants in the neonatal intensive care unit: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>17455057221104674</StartPage><MedlinePgn>17455057221104674</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">17455057221104674</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/17455057221104674</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM">To synthesize and integrate current international knowledge regarding nursing strategies for the provision of emotional and practical support to the mothers of preterm infants in the neonatal intensive care unit.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A systematic review and meta-analysis was undertaken. Four English-language databases including EMBASE, PubMed (including MEDLINE), Scopus, and Web of Science were searched from January 2010 to October 2021. Original quantitative studies that were written in English and focused on nursing strategies for the provision of emotional and practical support to the mothers of preterm infants in the neonatal intensive care unit were included. Eligibility assessment, data extraction, and methodological quality appraisal were conducted independently by the review authors. A narrative synthesis of the review results and a meta-analysis were performed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Twenty studies that were published from 2010 to 2021 were included in the review. Three categories concerning the review aims were identified: 'nursing strategies related to mothers' emotions and infant-mother attachment', 'nursing strategies related to mothers' empowerment', and 'nursing strategies related to mothers' participation in care process and support'. Eight interventional studies that reported mothers' stress as the study outcome were entered into the meta-analysis. Interventions consisted of the educational programme, spiritual care, telenursing, parent support programme, skin-to-skin care, and guided family centred care. Significantly lower maternal stress was found in the intervention group compared with that of the control group (<i>g</i>: -1.06; 95% confidence interval: -1.64, -0.49; Z = 3.62, <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This review identified and highlighted key nursing strategies used to provide emotional and practical support to the mothers of preterm infants in the neonatal intensive care unit. They included family centred care, skin-to-skin care, parent support and education programmes, interpersonal psychotherapy, spiritual care, newborn individualized developmental care and assessment programme, and telenursing.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maleki</LastName><ForeName>Maryam</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric and Neonatal Intensive Care Nursing Education Department, School of Nursing &amp; Midwifery, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mardani</LastName><ForeName>Abbas</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2861-6037</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nursing Care Research Center, Department of Medical Surgical Nursing, School of Nursing &amp; Midwifery, Iran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harding</LastName><ForeName>Celia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5192-2027</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Language and Communication Science, City, University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Basirinezhad</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad Hasan</ForeName><Initials>MH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, School of Public Health, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vaismoradi</LastName><ForeName>Mojtaba</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5157-4886</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Nursing and Health Sciences, Nord University, Bod&#xf8;, Norway; Faculty of Science and Health, Charles Sturt University, Orange NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Womens Health (Lond)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101271249</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-5057</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004644" MajorTopicYN="N">Emotions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007234" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Premature</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007363" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intensive Care Units, Neonatal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009035" MajorTopicYN="N">Mothers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009726" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nurses</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emotional support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">infant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mother</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neonatal intensive care unit</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nursing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">premature</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Declaration of conflicting interests:</b> The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35735784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9234836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17455057221104674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Akkoyun S, Tas Arslan F. Investigation of stress and nursing support in mothers of preterm infants in neonatal intensive care units. Scand J Caring Sci 2019; 33(2): 351&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30427555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organization (WHO). Preterm birth, 2018, https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/preterm-birth (accessed 20 December 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes ELFD, Dos Santos CM, Santos ACS, et al. Autonomic responses of premature newborns to body position and environmental noise in the neonatal intensive care unit. Rev Bras Ter Intensiva 2019; 31(3): 296&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7005950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31618347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ba&#xed;a I, Amorim M, Silva S, et al. Parenting very preterm infants and stress in Neonatal Intensive Care Units. Early Hum Dev 2016; 101: 3&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27393922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Im M, Oh J. Nursing support perceived by mothers of preterm infants in a neonatal intensive care unit in South Korea. Child Health Nurs Res 2021; 27(2): 146&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8650908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35004505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Im M, Oh J. The development and validation of a perceived nursing support scale for mothers of preterm infants. Asian Nurs Res 2021; 15(5): 317&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34748998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brett J, Staniszewska S, Newburn M, et al. A systematic mapping review of effective interventions for communicating with, supporting and providing information to parents of preterm infants. BMJ Open 2011; 1: e000023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3191395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22021730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boucher CA, Brazal PM, Graham-Certosini C, et al. Mothers&#x2019; breastfeeding experiences in the NICU. Neonatal Netw 2011; 30: 21&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21317094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs D, Odeh N, Theron M, et al. Level 1 neonatal nursing staff perceptions of their role: a qualitative Framework Analysis study investigating the complex and diverse workload undertaken by nurses in special care baby units. J Neonatal Nurs 2021; 27: 244&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aagaard H, Hall EO. Mothers&#x2019; experiences of having a preterm infant in the neonatal care unit: a meta-synthesis. J Pediatr Nurs 2008; 23(3): e26&#x2013;e36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18492543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith GC, Gutovich J, Smyser C, et al. Neonatal intensive care unit stress is associated with brain development in preterm infants. Ann Neurol 2011; 70(4): 541&#x2013;549.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4627473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21976396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdeyazdan Z, Shahkolahi Z, Mehrabi T, et al. A family support intervention to reduce stress among parents of preterm infants in neonatal intensive care unit. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res 2014; 19(4): 349&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4145487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25183973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinemann AB, Hellstr&#xf6;m-Westas L, Hedberg Nyqvist K. Factors affecting parents&#x2019; presence with their extremely preterm infants in a neonatal intensive care room. Acta Paediatr 2013; 102(7): 695&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23590800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheeran N, Jones L, Rowe J. The relationship between maternal age, communication and supportive relationships in the neonatal nursery for mothers of preterm infants. J Neonatal Nurs 2013; 19: 327&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner M, Chur-Hansen A, Winefield H. The neonatal nurses&#x2019; view of their role in emotional support of parents and its complexities. J Clin Nurs 2014; 23(21&#x2013;22): 3156&#x2013;3165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24575971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomqvist YT, Rubertsson C, Kylberg E, et al. Kangaroo Mother Care helps fathers of preterm infants gain confidence in the paternal role. J Adv Nurs 2012; 68(9): 1988&#x2013;1996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22111919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flacking R, Ewald U, Nyqvist KH, et al. Trustful bonds: a key to &#x2018;becoming a mother&#x2019; and to reciprocal breastfeeding. Stories of mothers of very preterm infants at a neonatal unit. Soc Sci Med 2006; 62(1): 70&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15992983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths N, Spence K, Loughran-Fowlds A, et al. Individualised developmental care for babies and parents in the NICU: evidence-based best practice guideline recommendations. Early Hum Dev 2019; 139: 104840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31445697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prouhet PM, Gregory MR, Russell CL, et al. Fathers&#x2019; stress in the neonatal intensive care unit: a systematic review. Adv Neonatal Care 2018; 18: 105&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29595549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boix-Amor&#xf3;s A, Collado MC, Van&#x2019;t Land B, et al. Reviewing the evidence on breast milk composition and immunological outcomes. Nutr Rev 2019; 77: 541&#x2013;556.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31111150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Hopewell S, Schulz KF, et al. CONSORT 2010 explanation and elaboration: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomised trials. Int J Surg 2012; 10: 28&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22036893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wells GA, Shea B, O&#x2019;Connell D, et al. The Newcastle-Ottawa Scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses, http://www.ohri.ca/programs/clinical_epidemiology/oxford.asp (accessed 16 December 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Higgins JPT, Altman DG. Assessing risk of bias in included studies, 2008, https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/9780470712184.ch8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9780470712184.ch8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Reeves BC, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ 2016; 355: i4919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herzog R, &#xc1;lvarez-Pasquin MJ, D&#xed;az C, et al. Are healthcare workers&#x2019; intentions to vaccinate related to their knowledge, beliefs and attitudes? A systematic review. BMC Public Health 2013; 13: 154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3602084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23421987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green S, Higgins JPE. Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions. London: The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, et al. Introduction to meta-analysis. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wataker H, Meberg A, Nestaas E. Neonatal family care for 24 hours per day: effects on maternal confidence and breast-feeding. J Perinat Neonatal Nurs 2012; 26(4): 336&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23111722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaffer L, Jallo N, Howland L, et al. Guided imagery: an innovative approach to improving maternal sleep quality. J Perinat Neonatal Nurs 2013; 27(2): 151&#x2013;159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23618936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weis J, Zoffmann V, Greisen G, et al. The effect of person-centred communication on parental stress in a NICU: a randomized clinical trial. Acta Paediatr 2013; 102(12): 1130&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23980925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beheshtipour N, Baharlu SM, Montaseri S, et al. The effect of the educational program on Iranian premature infants&#x2019; parental stress in a neonatal intensive care unit: a double-blind randomized controlled trial. Int J Community Based Nurs Midwifery 2014; 2(4): 240&#x2013;250.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4201207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25349867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe9;on M, Goulet C, Garofalo C, et al. Acceptability and feasibility of a breast milk expression education and support intervention in mothers of preterm infants. Adv Neonatal Care 2014; 14(4): E9&#x2013;E19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25075927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samra HA, Dutcher J, McGrath JM, et al. Effect of skin-to-skin holding on stress in mothers of late-preterm infants. Adv Neonatal Care 2015; 15(5): 354&#x2013;364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26356086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho ES, Kim SJ, Kwon MS, et al. The effects of kangaroo care in the neonatal intensive care unit on the physiological functions of preterm infants, maternal-infant attachment, and maternal stress. J Pediatr Nurs 2016; 31(4): 430&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26975461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyrovi H, Mosayebi Z, Mohammad-Doost F, et al. The effect of empowerment program on &#x2018;perceived readiness for discharge&#x2019; of mothers of premature infants. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med 2016; 29(5): 752&#x2013;757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25758633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sannino P, Giann&#xec; ML, De Bon G, et al. Support to mothers of premature babies using NIDCAP method: a non-randomized controlled trial. Early Hum Dev 2016; 95: 15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26900776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alemdar KD, &#xd6;zdemir FK, T&#xfc;fekci FG. The effect of spiritual care on stress levels of mothers in NICU. West J Nurs Res 2018; 40(7): 997&#x2013;1011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28322651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu A, Mori A. Maternal perceptions of family-centred support and their associations with the mother-nurse relationship in the neonatal intensive care unit. J Clin Nurs 2018; 27(7&#x2013;8): e1589&#x2013;e1599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29266474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tandberg BS, Fr&#xf8;slie KF, Flacking R, et al. Parent-infant closeness, parents&#x2019; participation, and nursing support in single-family room and open bay NICUs. J Perinat Neonatal Nurs 2018; 32(4): E22&#x2013;E32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30358674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buil A, Caeymaex L, Mero S, et al. Kangaroo supported diagonal flexion positioning: positive impact on maternal stress and postpartum depression risk and on skin-to-skin practice with very preterm infants. J Neonatal Nurs 2019; 25: 86&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo YJ, Oh WO. The effectiveness of a parent participation improvement program for parents on partnership, attachment infant growth in a neonatal intensive care unit: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Nurs Stud 2019; 95: 19&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31005676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafarzadeh ZA, Maghsoudi J, Barekatain B, et al. Effect of telenursing on attachment and stress in mothers of preterm infants. Iran J Neonatol 2019; 10: 65&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe5;nsson C, Sivberg B, Selander B, et al. The impact of an individualised neonatal parent support programme on parental stress: a quasi-experimental study. Scand J Caring Sci 2019; 33(3): 677&#x2013;687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30735266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moudi Z, Molashahi B, Ansari H, et al. The effect of a care program and social support on anxiety level in mothers of late preterm infants in Sistan and Baluchestan, Iran. Women Health 2019; 59(5): 569&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30422094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouyan F, Kamrani MA, Rahimzadeh M, et al. Effect of interpersonal psychotherapy oriented child birth education on stress and role adaptation in mothers with premature birth: a randomized clinical trial. Iran J Psychiatry Behav Sci 2019; 13: e86645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Maghaireh DF, Khalaf IA, Abdullah KL, et al. The effect of an emotional support training program on acute stress disorder among mothers of preterm infants hospitalized in neonatal intensive care units. J Neonatal Nurs 2020; 26: 273&#x2013;277.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eskandari S, Mirhaghjou SN, Maleki M, et al. Identification of the range of nursing skills used to provide social support for mothers of preterm infants in neonatal intensive care. Crit Care Res Pract 2021; 2021: 6697659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7810543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33505719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu PF, Lee MY, Chen YC, et al. Experiences of parents providing kangaroo care to a premature infant: a qualitative systematic review. Nurs Health Sci 2020; 22: 149&#x2013;161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31430017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dipietro JA. Maternal stress in pregnancy: considerations for fetal development. J Adolesc Health 2012; 51(2 suppl.): S3&#x2013;S8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3402207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22794531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabnis A, Fojo S, Nayak SS, et al. Reducing parental trauma and stress in neonatal intensive care: systematic review and meta-analysis of hospital interventions. J Perinatol 2019; 39(3): 375&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7067599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30659239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding X, Zhu L, Zhang R, et al. Effects of family-centred care interventions on preterm infants and parents in neonatal intensive care units: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Aust Crit Care 2019; 32(1): 63&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athanasopoulou E, Fox JR. Effects of kangaroo mother care on maternal mood and interaction patterns between parents and their preterm, low birth weight infants: a systematic review. Infant Ment Health J 2014; 35(3): 245&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25798479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scime NV, Gavarkovs AG, Chaput KH. The effect of skin-to-skin care on postpartum depression among mothers of preterm or low birthweight infants: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord 2019; 253: 376&#x2013;384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moura D, Canavarro MC, Figueiredo-Braga M. Oxytocin and depression in the perinatal period-a systematic review. Arch Womens Ment Health 2016; 19(4): 561&#x2013;570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27295067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooding JS, Cooper LG, Blaine AI, et al. Family support and family-centered care in the neonatal intensive care unit: origins, advances, impact. Semin Perinatol 2011; 35(1): 20&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21255703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi Z, Mokhtari Nouri J, Khademolhoseyni SM, et al. The effects of nursing interventions on mothers&#x2019; empowerment regarding improvement of the care of preterm infant in NICU: a systematic review. Int J Med Rev 2014; 1: 25&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davanzo R, Merewood A, Manzoni P. Skin-to-skin contact at birth in the COVID-19 era: in need of help! Am J Perinatol 2020; 37(S02): S1&#x2013;S4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson AM, Bedford PJ. Mothering a preterm infant receiving NIDCAP care in a level III newborn intensive care unit. J Pediatr Nurs 2016; 31(4): e271&#x2013;e782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26883058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernecker SL, Constantino MJ, Pazzaglia AM, et al. Patient interpersonal and cognitive changes and their relation to outcome in interpersonal psychotherapy for depression. J Clin Psychol 2014; 70(6): 518&#x2013;527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24002972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao LL, Xie W, Yang X, et al. Effects of an interpersonal-psychotherapy-oriented postnatal programme for Chinese first-time mothers: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Nurs Stud 2015; 52(1): 22&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24994573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman R, Eidelman AI. Maternal postpartum behavior and the emergence of infant-mother and infant-father synchrony in preterm and full-term infants: the role of neonatal vagal tone. Dev Psychobiol 2007; 49(3): 290&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17380505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buil A, Carchon I, Apter G, et al. Kangaroo supported diagonal flexion positioning: new insights into skin-to-skin contact for communication between mothers and very preterm infants. Arch Pediatr 2016; 23(9): 913&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27388909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umberger E, Canvasser J, Hall SL. Enhancing NICU parent engagement and empowerment. Semin Pediatr Surg 2018; 27(1): 19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29275811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis L, Mohay H, Edwards H. Mothers&#x2019; involvement in caring for their premature infants: an historical overview. J Adv Nurs 2003; 42(6): 578&#x2013;586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12787231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ericson J, Flacking R, Udo C. Mothers&#x2019; experiences of a telephone based breastfeeding support intervention after discharge from neonatal intensive care units: a mixed-method study. Int Breastfeed J 2017; 12: 50&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5735875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29270208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradi S, Arshdi-Bostanabad M, Seyedrasooli A, et al. The effect of empowerment program on maternal discharge preparation and neonatal length of hospital stay: a randomized controlled trial. Iran J Nurs Midwifery Res 2018; 23(3): 172&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5954636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29861753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Veenendaal NR, Van Kempen AAMW, Franck LS, et al. Hospitalising preterm infants in single family rooms versus open bay units: a systematic review and meta-analysis of impact on parents. EClinicalMedicine 2020; 23: 100388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7284081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32548575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Veenendaal NR, Heideman WH, Limpens J, et al. Hospitalising preterm infants in single family rooms versus open bay units: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Child Adolesc Health 2019; 3: 147&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30630745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>