<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36579440</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-108X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>56</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The International journal of eating disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Eat Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preventing eating disorders and disordered eating in genetically vulnerable, high-risk families.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>523</StartPage><EndPage>534</EndPage><MedlinePgn>523-534</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/eat.23887</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To close the chasm between theory about families containing a parent with an eating disorders (EDs) history and lack of selective or indicated prevention programming for such families with an older child or adolescent who is, genetically, at high risk.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">A search of four major databases for January 2000 through September 2022 yielded no publications that (a) identified genetically high-risk families with offspring ages 10 through 18; (b) devised a prevention program for the family; and (c) evaluated program effects on risk/protective factors. To rectify this gap, research on three lines of family-based prevention is reviewed: (1) programs for adolescents at genetic risk for depression or anxiety; (2) the Stanford-Dresden project for adolescents at high risk for anorexia nervosa; and (3) Sadeh-Sharvit et al.'s work concerning the Parent-Based Prevention program for mothers with an EDs history and a child under age 5.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The significant challenges for innovative prevention programming should be addressed by experts in effective EDs, depression, and anxiety prevention, and in family-based treatment (FBT) for EDs, collaborating with people from genetically vulnerable families. Innovative programming should focus on robust risk factors for EDs, adaptive expression of non-specific risk factors (e.g., temperament), and strengthening family functioning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">The field is overdue for development of prevention programs designed for older children or adolescents who are at risk because a parent has an ED. Evidence-based prevention programs for EDs and for depression and anxiety, as well as parent-based prevention informed by FBT, provide a springboard for addressing this gap.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PUBLIC SIGNIFICANCE">The foundation of theory and research is available for stakeholders to develop prevention programming that closes the huge gap between theory and research about families that are genetically vulnerable for eating disorders versus the complete lack of prevention programming for such families that have an older child or adolescent at high risk.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. International Journal of Eating Disorders published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levine</LastName><ForeName>Michael P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Kenyon College, Gambier, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadeh-Sharvit</LastName><ForeName>Shiri</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6499-9034</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for m2Health, Palo Alto University, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Eat Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8111226</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0276-3478</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Int J Eat Disord. 2023 Mar;56(3):535-537. doi: 10.1002/eat.23914.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36772968</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001068" MajorTopicYN="Y">Feeding and Eating Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000856" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anorexia Nervosa</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001008" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety Disorders</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescents at risk</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eating disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">family-based interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genetically vulnerable families</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk factors</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36579440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/eat.23887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Albee, G. W., &amp; Gullotta, T. P. (1997). Primary prevention's evolution. In G. W. Albee &amp; T. P. Gullotta (Eds.), Primary prevention works (Issues in children and families' lives) (Vol. 6, pp. 3-22). Sage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen, K. L., Gibson, L. Y., McLean, N. J., Davis, E. A., &amp; Byrne, S. M. (2014). Maternal and family factors and child eating pathology: Risk and protective relationships. Journal of Eating Disorders, 2, 11. https://doi.org/10.1186/2050-2974-2-11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baudinet, J., Simic, M., &amp; Eisler, I. (2021). Formulation in eating disorder focused family therapy: Why, when and how? Journal of Eating Disorders, 9, 97. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40337-021-00451-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beardslee, W. R., Salt, P., Porterfied, K., Rothberg, P. C., Van De Velde, P., Swatling, S., &#x2026; Wheelock, I. (1993). Comparison of preventive interventions for families with parental affective disorder. Journal of the American Academy of Child &amp; Adolescent Psychiatry, 32(2), 254-262. https://doi.org/10.1097/00004583-199303000-00004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beardslee, W. R., Versage, E. M., &amp; Gladstone, T. R. (1998). Children of affectively ill parents: A review of the past 10&#x2009;years. Journal of the American Academy of Child &amp; Adolescent Psychiatry, 37(11), 1134-1141. https://doi.org/10.1097/00004583-199811000-00012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beardslee, W. R., Wright, E. J., Salt, P., Drezner, K., Gladstone, T. R., Versage, E. M., &amp; Rothberg, P. C. (1997). Examination of children's responses to two preventive intervention strategies over time. Journal of the American Academy of Child &amp; Adolescent Psychiatry, 36(2), 196-204. https://doi.org/10.1097/00004583-199702000-00010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker, C. B., &amp; Stice, E. (2017). From efficacy to effectiveness to broad implementation: Evolution of the body project. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 85(8), 767-782. https://doi.org/10.1037/ccp0000204</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beintner, I., Jacobi, C., &amp; Taylor, C. B. (2012). Effects of an internet-based prevention programme for eating disorders in the USA and Germany-A meta-analytic review. European Eating Disorders Review, 20(1), 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1002/erv.1130</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bould, H., Sovio, U., Koupil, I., Dalman, C., Micali, N., Lewis, G., &amp; Magnusson, C. (2015). Do eating disorders in parents predict eating disorders in children? Evidence from a Swedish cohort. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica, 132(1), 51-59. https://doi.org/10.1111/acps.12389</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breslend, N. L., Parent, J., Forehand, R., Peisch, V., &amp; Compas, B. (2019). Children of parents with a history of depression: The impact of a preventive intervention on youth social problems through reductions in internalizing problems. Development and Psychopathology, 31(1), 219-231. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0954579417001821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, T. A., Klein, K., &amp; Keel, P. K. (2015). The &#x201c;natural&#x201d; course of eating disorders. In L. Smolak &amp; M. P. Levine (Eds.), The Wiley handbook of eating disorders, volume II: Assessment, prevention, treatment, policy, and future directions (pp. 757-769). Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulik, C. M. (2004). Genetic and biological risk factors. In J. K. Thompson (Ed.), Handbook of eating disorders and obesity (pp. 3-16). Wiley.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulik, C. M., Blake, L., &amp; Austin, J. (2019). Genetics of eating disorders: What the clinician needs to know. Psychiatric Clinics of North America, 42(1), 59-73. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psc.2018.10.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bulik, C. M., Sullivan, P. F., Fear, J. I., &amp; Joyce, P. R. (1997). Eating disorders and antecedent anxiety disorders: A controlled study. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica, 96(2), 101-107. https://doi.org/10.1111/acps.12389</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman, L., Cartwright-Hatton, S., Thomson, A., &amp; Lester, K. J. (2021). Parental eating disorders: A systematic review of parenting attitudes, behaviours, and parent-child interactions. Clinical Psychology Review, 88, 102031. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2021.102031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cimino, S., Cerniglia, L., Porreca, A., Simonelli, A., Ronconi, L., &amp; Ballarotto, G. (2016). Mothers and fathers with binge eating disorder and their 18-36 months old children: A longitudinal study on parent-infant interactions and offspring's emotional-behavioral profiles. Frontiers in Psychology, 5, 80. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2016.00580</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compas, B. E., Forehand, R., Keller, G., Champion, J. E., Rakow, A., Reeslund, K. L., McKee, L., Fear, J. M., Colletti, C. J. M., Hardcastle, E., Merchant, M. J., Roberts, L., Potts, J., Garai, E., Coffelt, N., Roland, E., Sterba, S. K., &amp; Cole, D. A. (2009). Randomized controlled trial of a family cognitive-behavioral preventive intervention for children of depressed parents. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 77(6), 1007-1020. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0016930</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Compas, B. E., Forehand, R., Thigpen, J., Hardcastle, E., Garai, E., McKee, L., Keller, G., Dunbar, J. P., Watson, K. H., Rakow, A., Bettis, A., Reising, M., Cole, D., &amp; Sterba, S. (2015). Efficacy and moderators of a family group cognitive-behavioral preventive intervention for children of depressed parents. Consulting Clinical Psychology, 83(3), 541-553. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0039053</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costin, C., &amp; Grabb, G. S. (2012). 8 keys to recovery from an eating disorder: Effective strategies from therapeutic practice and personal experience. W. W. Norton.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Culbert, K. M., Racine, S. E., &amp; Klump, K. L. (2015). Research review: What we have learned about the cause of eating disorders-A synthesis of sociocultural, psychological, and biological research. Journal of Child Psychology and Psychiatry, 56(11), 1141-1164. https://doi.org/10.1111/jcpp.12441</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinkler, L., Lichtenstein, P., Lundstr&#xf6;m, S., Larrson, H., Micali, N., Taylor, M. J., &amp; Bulik, C. M. (2022). Genetic and environmental etiology of the broad avoidant restrictive food intake disorder phenotype in 6- to-12-year-old Swedish twins. PsyArXiv (unpublished preprint). https://doi.org/10.1101/2022.09.08.22279706</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fichter, M. M., &amp; Quadflieg, N. (2021). How precisely can psychotherapists predict the long- term outcome of anorexia nervosa and bulimia nervosa at the end of inpatient treatment? International Journal of Eating Disorders, 54(4), 535-544. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.23443</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzsimmons-Craft, E. E., Balantekin, K. N., Eichen, D. M., Graham, A. K., Monterubio, G. E., Sadeh-Sharvit, S., Goel, N. J., Flatt, R. E., Saffran, K., Karam, A. M., Firebaugh, M.-L., Trockel, M., Taylor, C. B., &amp; Wilfley, D. E. (2019). Screening and offering online programs for eating disorders: Reach, pathology, and differences across eating disorder status groups at 28&#x2009;U.S. universities. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 52(10), 1125-1136. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.23134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giannakopoulos, G., Solantaus, S., Tzavara, C., &amp; Kolaitis, G. (2021). Mental health promotion and prevention interventions in families with parental depression: A randomized controlled trial. Journal of Affective Disorders, 278, 114-121. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jad.2020.09.070</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, P. (2013). Depression: The challenges of an integrative, biopsychosocial evolutionary approach. In M. Power (Ed.), The Wiley-Blackwell handbook of mood disorders (2nd ed., pp. 229-288). Wiley Blackwell. https://doi.org/10.1002/9781118316153</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giles, E. M., Cross, A. S., Matthews, R. V., &amp; Lacey, J. H. (2022). Disturbed families or families disturbed: A reconsideration. Eating and Weight Disorders, 27(1), 11-19. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40519-021-01160-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginsburg, G. S. (2009). The child anxiety prevention study: Intervention model and primary outcomes. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 77(3), 580-587. https://doi.org/10.1037/a00144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginsburg, G. S., Drake, K. L., Tein, J.-Y., Teetsel, R., &amp; Riddle, M. A. (2015). Preventing onset of anxiety disorders in offspring of anxious parents: A randomized controlled trial of a family-based intervention. American Journal of Psychiatry, 172(12), 1207-1214. https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ajp.2015.14091178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ginsburg, G. S., Tein, J.-Y., &amp; Riddle, M. A. (2021). Preventing the onset of anxiety disorders in offspring of anxious parents: A six-year follow-up. Child Psychiatry &amp; Human Development, 52(4), 751-760. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10578-020-01080-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorrell, S., Loeb, K. L., &amp; Le Grange, D. (2019). Family-based treatment of eating disorders: A narrative review. Psychiatric Clinics of North America, 42(2), 193-204. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psc.2019.01.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grigoroiu-Serbanescu, M., Magureanu, S., Milea, S., Dobrescu, I., &amp; Marinescu, E. (2003). Modest familial aggregation of eating disorders in restrictive anorexia nervosa with adolescent onset in a Romanian sample. European Child &amp; Adolescent Psychiatry, 12(Suppl. 1), 47-53. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00787-003-1107-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hammen, C., Brennan, P., &amp; Keenan-Miller, D. (2008). Patterns of adolescent depression to age 20: The role of maternal depression and youth interpersonal dysfunction. Journal of Abnormal Child Psychology, 36(8), 1189-1198. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10802-008-9241-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart, L. M., Cornell, C., Damiano, S. R., &amp; Paxton, S. J. (2015). Parents and prevention: A systematic review of interventions involving parents that aim to prevent body dissatisfaction or eating disorders. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 48(2), 157-169. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.22284</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Havinga, P. J., Maciejewski, D. F., Hartman, C. A., Hillegers, M. H. J., Schoever, R. A., &amp; Penninx, B. W. J. H. (2021). Prevention programmes for children of parents with a mood/anxiety disorder: Systematic review of existing programmes and meta-analysis of their efficacy. British Journal of Clinical Psychology, 60(2), 212-251. https://doi.org/10.1111/bjc.12277</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herle, M., De Stavola, B., H&#xfc;bel, C., Abdulkadir, M., Ferreira, D. S., Loos, R. J. F., Bryant-Waugh, R., Bulik, C. M., &amp; Micali, N. (2020). A longitudinal study of eating behaviours in childhood and later eating disorder behaviours and diagnoses. The British Journal of Psychiatry, 216(2), 113-119. https://doi.org/10.1192/bjp.2019.174</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hickey, G., McGilloway, S., O'Brien, M., Leckey, Y., Devlin, M., &amp; Donnelly, M. (2018). Strengthening stakeholder buy-in and engagement for successful exploration and installation: A case study of the development of an area-wide, evidence-based prevention and early intervention strategy. Children and Youth Services Review, 91, 185-195. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.childyouth.2018.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill, K. E., Hart, L. M., &amp; Paxton, S. J. (2020). Confident body, confident child: Outcomes for children of parents receiving a universal parenting program to promote healthful eating patterns and positive body image in their pre-schoolers-An exploratory RCT extension. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 17(3), 891. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17030891</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill, L., Peck, S. K., &amp; Wierenga, C. E. (2022). Temperament based therapy with support for anorexia nervosa: A novel treatment. Cambridge University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xfc;bel, C., Abdulkadir, M., Herle, M., Loos, R. J. F., Breen, G., Bulik, C. M., &amp; Micali, N. (2021). One size does not fit all. Genomics differentiates among anorexia nervosa, bulimia nervosa, and binge-eating disorder. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 54(5), 785-793. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.23481</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi, C., Hayward, C., de Zwaan, M., Kraemer, H. C., &amp; Agras, W. S. (2004). Coming to terms with risk factors for eating disorders: Application of risk terminology and suggestions for a general taxonomy. Psychological Bulletin, 130(1), 19-65. https://doi.org/10.1037/0033-2909.130.1.19</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi, C., H&#xfc;tter, K., V&#xf6;lker, U., M&#xf6;bius, K., Richter, R., Trockel, M., Bell, M. J., Lock, J., &amp; Taylor, C. B. (2018). Efficacy of a parent-based, indicated prevention for anorexia nervosa: Randomized controlled trial. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 20(12), e296. https://doi.org/10.2196/jmir.9464</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, M., Volker, U., Lock, J., Taylor, C. B., &amp; Jacobi, C. (2012). Family-based early intervention for anorexia nervosa. European Eating Disorders Review, 20(3), e137-e143. https://doi.org/10.1002/erv.2167</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendler, K. S., Ohlsson, H., Sundquist, J., &amp; Sundquist, K. (2021). The patterns of family genetic risk scores for eleven major psychiatric and substance use disorders in a Swedish national sample. Translational Psychiatry, 11, 326. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41398-021-01454-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler, R. C., Amminger, G. P., Aguilar-Gaxiola, S., Alonso, J., Lee, S., &amp; Ustun, T. B. (2007). Age of onset of mental disorders: A review of recent literature. Current Opinion in Psychiatry, 20(4), 359-364. https://doi.org/10.1097/YCO.0b013e32816ebc8c</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen, P. S., Strandberg-Larsen, K., Olsen, E. M., Micali, N., &amp; Anderson, A.-M. N. (2018). Parental characteristics in association with disordered eating in 11- to 12-year-olds: A study within the Danish National Birth Cohort. European Eating Disorders Review, 26(4), 315-328. https://doi.org/10.1002/erv.2599</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, M. P. (1987). How schools can help combat student eating disorders. National Education Association.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, M. P., &amp; Smolak, L. (2014). Paradigm clash in the field of eating disorders: A critical examination of the biopsychiatric model from a sociocultural perspective. Advances in Eating Disorders: Theory, Research and Practice, 2(2), 158-170. https://doi.org/10.1080/21662630.2013.839202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levine, M. P., &amp; Smolak, L. (2021). The prevention of eating problems and eating disorders: Theories, research, and applications (2nd ed.). Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lock, J., &amp; Nicholls, D. (2020). Toward a greater understanding of the ways family-based treatment addresses the full range of psychopathology of adolescent anorexia nervosa. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 10, 968. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00968</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lock, J. D., &amp; Fitzpatrick, K. K. (2009). Anorexia nervosa. BMJ Clinical Evidence, 1011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loeb, K. L., Weissman, R. S., Marcus, S., Pattanayak, C., Hail, L., Kung, K. C., Schron, D., Zucker, N., Le Grange, D., Lock, J., Newcorn, J. H., Taylor, C. B., &amp; Walsh, B. T. (2020). Family-based treatment for anorexia nervosa symptoms in high-risk youth: A partially-randomized preference-design study. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 10, 985. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00985</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loechner, J., Starman, K., Galuschka, K., Tamm, J., Schulte-K&#xf6;rne, G., Rubel, J., &amp; Platt, B. (2018). Preventing depression in the offspring of parents with depression: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Clinical Psychology Review, 60, 1-18. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2017.11.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lydecker, J. A., &amp; Grilo, C. M. (2016). Fathers and mothers with eating-disorder psychopathology: Associations with child eating-disorder behaviors. Journal of Pychosomatic Research, 86(1), 63-69. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpsychores.2016.05.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mangweth, B., Hudson, J. I., Pope, H. G., Jr., Hausmann, A., de Col, C., Laird, N. M., Beibl, W., &amp; Tsuang, M. T. (2003). Family study of the aggregation of eating disorders and mood disorders. Psychological Medicine, 33(7), 1319-1323. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291703008250</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;n, J., Padierna, A., Loro&#xf1;o, A., Mu&#xf1;oz, P., &amp; Quintana, J. M. (2017). Predictors of quality of life in patients with eating disorders. European Psychiatry, 45, 182-189. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eurpsy.2017.07.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews, A., Peterson, C. M., Lenz, K., Kramer, R. A., Mara, C., Copps, E., &amp; Mitan, L. (2021). Modifiable factors associated with mental health symptoms in siblings of adolescents with anorexia nervosa. Eating and Weight Disorders, 26(6), 1757-1765. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40519-020-00993-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Micali, N., De Stavola, B., Ploubidis, G. B., Simonoff, E., &amp; Treasure, J. (2014). The effects of maternal eating disorders on offspring childhood and early adolescent psychiatric disorders. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 47(4), 385-393. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.22216</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neumark-Sztainer, D., Levine, M. P., Paxton, S. J., Smolak, L., Piran, N., &amp; Wertheim, E. H. (2006). Prevention of body dissatisfaction and disordered eating: What next? Eating Disorders: Journal of Treatment &amp; Prevention, 14(4), 265-285. https://doi.org/10.1080/10640260600796184</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piran, N. (2010). A feminist perspective on risk factor research and on the prevention of eating disorders. Eating Disorders: The Journal of Treatment &amp; Prevention, 18(3), 183-198. https://doi.org/10.1080/10640261003719435</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasic, D., Hajek, T., Alda, M., &amp; Uher, R. (2014). Risk of mental illness in offspring of parents with schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, and major depressive disorder: A meta-analysis of family high-risk studies. Schizophrenia Bulletin, 40(1), 28-38. https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/sbt114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratheesh, A., Cotton, S. M., Davey, C. G., Adams, S., Bechdolf, A., Macneil, C., Berk, M., &amp; McGorry, P. D. (2017). Ethical considerations in preventive interventions for bipolar disorder. Early Intervention in Psychiatry, 11, 104-112. https://doi.org/10.1111/eip.12340</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regan, P., Cachelin, F. M., &amp; Minnick, A. M. (2017). Initial treatment seeking from professional health care providers for eating disorders: A review and synthesis of potential barriers to and facilitators of &#x2018;first contact&#x2019;. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 50(3), 190-209. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.22683</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rienecke, R. D. (2018). Expressed emotion and eating disorders: An updated review. Current Psychiatry Reviews, 14(2), 84-98. https://doi.org/10.2174/1573400514666180808115637</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rienecke, R. D., &amp; Le Grange, D. (2022). The five tenets of family-based treatment for adolescent eating disorders. Journal of Eating Disorders, 10, 60. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40337-022-00585-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodgers, R. F., Simone, M., Franko, D. L., Eisenberg, M. E., Loth, K., &amp; Neumark-Sztainer, D. (2021). The longitudinal relationship between family and peer teasing in young adulthood and later unhealthy weight control behaviors: The mediating role of body image. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 54(5), 831-840. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.23492</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Runfola, C. D., Zucker, N. L., Von Holle, A., Mazzeo, S., Hodges, E. A., Perrin, E. M., Bentley, M. E., Ulman, T. F., Hoffman, E. R., Forsberg, &#xc5;lgars, M., Zerwas, S., Pisetsky, E. M., Taico, C., Kuhns, R. A., Hamer, R. M., &amp; Bulik, C. M. (2014). NURTURE: Development and pilot testing of a novel parenting intervention for mothers with histories of an eating disorder. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 47(1), 1-12. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.22178</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh-Sharvit, S., Arnow, K. D., Osipov, L., Lock, J. D., Jo, B., Pajarito, S., Brandt, H., Dodge, E., Halmi, K. A., Johnson, C., Kaye, W., Wilfley, D. E., &amp; Agras, W. S. (2018). Are parental self-efficacy and family flexibility mediators of treatment for anorexia nervosa? International Journal of Eating Disorders, 51(3), 275-280. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.22826</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh-Sharvit, S., Levy-Shiff, R., Feldman, T., Ram, A., Gur, E., Zubery, E., Steiner, E., Latzer, Y., &amp; Lock, J. (2015). Child feeding perceptions among mothers with eating disorders. Appetite, 95, 67-73. https://doi.org/10.1015/j.appet.2015.06.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh-Sharvit, S., &amp; Lock, J. D. (2018). Parents with eating disorders: An intervention guide. Routledge.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh-Sharvit, S., Runfola, C. D., Welch, H., Gibbs, E. L., Dickens, C. E., Lock, J., &amp; Safer, D. L. (2020a). Parent-based prevention following parental weight loss surgery: A pilot case-series trial. Surgery for Obesity and Related Diseases, 16(9), 1321-1327. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soard.2020.05.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh-Sharvit, S., Sacks, M. R., Runfola, C., Bulik, C. M., &amp; Lock, J. D. (2020b). Interventions to empower adults with eating disorders and their partners around the transition to parenthood. Family Process, 59(4), 1407-1422. https://doi.org/10.1111/famp.12510</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadeh-Sharvit, S., Zubery, E., Mankovski, E., Steiner, E., &amp; Lock, J. D. (2016). Parent-based prevention program for the children of mothers with eating disorders: Feasibility and preliminary outcomes. Eating Disorders: Journal of Treatment &amp; Prevention, 24(4), 312-325. https://doi.org/10.1080/10640266.2016.115340</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schaumberg, K., Welch, E., Breithaupt, L., H&#xfc;bel, C., Baker, J. H., Munn-Chernoff, M. A., Yilmaz, Z., Ehrlich, S., Mustelin, L., Ghaderi, A., Hardaway, J. A., Bulik-Sullivan, E. C., Hedman, A. M., Jangmo, A., Nilsson, I. A. K., Wiklund, C., Yao, S., Seidel, M., &amp; Bulik, C. M. (2017). The science behind the academy for eating Disorders' nine truths about eating disorders [invited review]. European Eating Disorders Review, 25(6), 432-450. https://doi.org/10.1002/erv.2553</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solmi, M., Radua, J., Olivola, M., Croce, E., Soardo, L., de Pablo, G. S., Shin, J. I., Kirkbride, J. B., Jones, P., Kim, J. H., Kim, J. Y., Carvalho, A. F., Seeman, M. V., Correll, C. U., &amp; Fusar-Poli, P. (2022). Age at onset of mental disorders worldwide: Large-scale meta-analysis of 192 epidemiological studies. Molecular Psychiatry, 27(1), 281-295. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41380-021-01161-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, A., Woolley, H., Cooper, S., Winterbottom, J., Fairburn, C. G., &amp; Cortina-Borja, M. (2006). Eating habits and attitudes among 10-year-old children of mothers with eating disorders: Longitudinal study. British Journal of Psychiatry, 189, 324-329. https://doi.org/10.1192/bjp.bp.105.014316</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein, D., Lilenfeld, L. R., Plotnicov, K., Pollice, C., Rao, R., Strober, M., &amp; Kaye, W. H. (1999). Familial aggregation of eating disorders: Results from a controlled family study of bulimia nervosa. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 26(2), 211-215. https://doi.org/10.1002/(sici)1098-108x(199909)26:2&lt;211::aid-eat11&gt;3.0.co;2-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinberg, L. (2001). We know some things: Parent-adolescent relationships in retrospect and prospect. Journal of Research on Adolescence, 11(1), 1-19. https://doi.org/10.1111/1532-7795.00001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinhausen, H.-C., Jakobsen, H., Helenius, D., Munk-J&#xf8;rgensen, P., &amp; Strober, M. (2015). A nation-wide study of the family aggregation and risk factors in anorexia nervosa over three generations. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 48(1), 1-8. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.22293</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stice, E., Onipede, Z. A., &amp; Marti, N. (2021). A meta-analytic review of trials that tested whether eating disorder prevention programs prevent eating disorder onset. Clinical Psychology Review, 87, 102046. https://doi.org/10.1016/J.cpr.2021.102046</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stice, E., Shaw, H., Bohon, C., Marti, C. N., &amp; Rohde, P. (2009). A meta-analytic review of depression prevention programs for children and adolescents: Factors that predict magnitude of intervention effects. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 77(3), 486-503. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0015168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stice, E., Yokum, S., Rohde, P., Cloud, K., &amp; Desjardins, C. D. (2019). Comparing healthy adolescent females with and without parental history of eating pathology on neural responsivity to food and thin models and other potential risk factors. Journal of Abnormal Psychology, 130(6), 608-619. https://doi.org/10.1037/abn0000686</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strober, M., Freeman, R., Lampert, C., Diamond, J., &amp; Kaye, W. (2000). Controlled family study of anorexia and bulimia nervosa: Evidence of shared liability and transmission of partial syndromes. American Journal of Psychiatry, 157(3), 393-401. https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ajp.157.3.393</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strober, M., Lampert, C., Morrell, W., Burroughs, J., &amp; Jacobs, C. (1990). A controlled family study of anorexia nervosa: Evidence of familial aggregation and lack of shared transmission with affective disorders. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 9(3), 239-253. https://doi.org/10.1002/1098-108X(199005)9:3&lt;239::AID-EAT2260090302&gt;3.0.CO;2-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trace, S. E., Baker, J. H., Penas-Lledo, E., &amp; Bulik, C. M. (2013). The genetics of eating disorders. Annual Review of Clinical Psychology, 9, 589-620. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-050212-185546</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eeden, A. E., Oldehinkel, A. J., van Hoeken, D., &amp; Hoek, H. W. (2021). Risk factors in preadolescent boys and girls for the development of eating pathology in young adulthood. International Journal of Eating Disorders, 54(7), 1147-1159. https://doi.org/10.1002/eat.23496</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson, H. J., O'Brien, A., &amp; Sadeh-Sharvit, S. (2018). Children of parents with eating disorders. Current Psychiatry Reports, 20(11), 101. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11920-018-0970-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodside, D. B., Field, L. L., Garfinkel, P., &amp; Heinmaa, M. (1998). Specificity of eating disorders diagnoses in families of probands with anorexia nervosa and bulimia nervosa. Comprehensive Psychiatry, 39(5), 261-264. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0010-440x(98)90033-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz, Z., Hardaway, J. A., &amp; Bulik, C. M. (2015). Genetics and epigenetics of eating disorders. Advances in Genomics and Genetics, 5, 131-150. https://doi.org/10.2147/AGG.S55776</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziobrowski, H. N., Sonneville, K. R., Eddy, K. T., Crosby, R. D., Micali, N., Horton, N. J., &amp; Field, A. (2019). Maternal eating disorders and eating disorder treatment among girls in the growing up today study. Journal of Adolescent Health, 65(4), 469-475. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jadohealth.2019.04.031</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>