<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36947553</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cultivating well-being in engineering graduate students through mindfulness training.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0281994</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0281994</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0281994</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0281994</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The mental health crisis in graduate education combined with low treatment rates among engineering graduate students underscores the need for engineering graduate programs to provide effective methods to promote well-being. There is an extensive body of neuroscience research showing that contemplative practices, such as mindfulness, produce measurable effects on brain function and overall well-being. We hypothesized that a mindfulness-based training program designed for engineering graduate students would improve emotional well-being and, secondarily, enhance research capacity. An initial pilot study was conducted at a single institution (Phase 1), followed by a larger study conducted at both the original and a second institution (Phase 2) to gather additional data and show the program's transferability. The program comprised eight weekly mindfulness training sessions. Individuals in the study were randomly assigned to either an intervention group or wait-list control group. We administered pre- and post-test surveys with quantitative measures designed to assess emotional and physical well-being, as well as creativity, research satisfaction, and desire to contribute to the betterment of society. Participants also completed a summative survey to evaluate the impact of the program on their well-being and research. Analysis revealed statistically significant findings: improved emotional health, decreased neuroticism, increased positive affect, decreased negative affect, and increased mindfulness in the intervention groups compared to the control groups. Intervention groups in Phase 2 also reported statistically significant improvement in satisfaction with their research. Our findings suggest that mindfulness training has the potential to play a vital professional and personal development role in graduate engineering education.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 Crone et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Crone</LastName><ForeName>Wendy C</ForeName><Initials>WC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6956-4221</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Engineering Physics, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kesebir</LastName><ForeName>Pelin</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Healthy Minds, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hays</LastName><ForeName>Beverly</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthy Minds Innovations, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mirgain</LastName><ForeName>Shilagh A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthy Minds Innovations, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics and Rehabilitation, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davidson</LastName><ForeName>Richard J</ForeName><Initials>RJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Healthy Minds, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Healthy Minds Innovations, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hagness</LastName><ForeName>Susan C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, Wisconsin, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004644" MajorTopicYN="N">Emotions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064866" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mindfulness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="N">Students</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>I have read the journal&#x2019;s policy and the authors of this manuscript have the following competing interests: Dr. Richard J. Davidson is the founder, president, and serves on the board of directors for the non-profit organization, Healthy Minds Innovations, Inc. (HMI), and served as an unfunded collaborator on the project. HMI is focused on the dissemination of tools and services developed through research conducted at the University of Wisconsin-Madison and promoting well-being in the world. No donors, either anonymous or identified, have participated in the design, conduct, or reporting of research results in this manuscript. In addition, Dr. Davidson served on the board of directors for the Mind &amp; Life Institute from 1992-2017. Dr. Shilagh A. Mirgain and Beverly Hays were hired through HMI to serve as experienced trainers/facilitators as part of the NSF funded research. This does not alter our adherence to PLOS ONE policies on sharing data and materials.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10032494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0281994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PONE-D-22-14829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hyun JK, Quinn BC, Madon T, Lustig S. Graduate student mental health: Needs assessment and utilization of counseling services. Journal of College Student Development. 2006;47(3):247&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans TM, Bira L, Gastelum JB, Weiss LT, Vanderford NL. Evidence for a mental health crisis in graduate education. Nat Biotechnol. 2018;36(3):282. doi: 10.1038/nbt.4089</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nbt.4089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29509732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences E, and Medicine. Mental Health, Substance Use, and Wellbeing in Higher Education: Supporting the Whole Student. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press., 2021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33460324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Council of Graduate Schools TJF. Supporting graduate student mental health and well-being: Evidence-informed recommendations for the graduate community. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panger G, Janell T. Graduate student happiness &amp; well&#x2010;being report. The Graduate Assembly, University of California Berkeley. 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stillwell SB, Vermeesch AL, Scott JG. Interventions to Reduce Perceived Stress Among Graduate Students: A Systematic Review With Implications for Evidence&#x2010;Based Practice. Worldviews on Evidence&#x2010;Based Nursing. 2017;14(6):507&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1111/wvn.12250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/wvn.12250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28795775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin MM, Goodboy AK, Johnson ZD. When professors bully graduate students: Effects on student interest, instructional dissent, and intentions to leave graduate education. Communication Education. 2015;64(4):438&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tompkins KA, Brecht K, Tucker B, Neander LL, Swift JK. Who matters most? The contribution of faculty, student-peers, and outside support in predicting graduate student satisfaction. Training and Education in Professional Psychology. 2016;10(2):102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sverdlik A, Hall NC, McAlpine L, Hubbard K. The PhD experience: A review of the factors influencing doctoral students&#x2019; completion, achievement, and well-being. International Journal of Doctoral Studies. 2018;13:361&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacey K, Zaharia M, Griffiths J, Ravindran A, Merali Z, Anisman H. A prospective study of neuroendocrine and immune alterations associated with the stress of an oral academic examination among graduate students. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 2000;25(4):339&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1016/s0306-4530(99)00059-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0306-4530(99)00059-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10725611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipson SK, Zhou S, Wagner B III, Beck K, Eisenberg D. Major differences: Variations in undergraduate and graduate student mental health and treatment utilization across academic disciplines. Journal of College Student Psychotherapy. 2016;30(1):23&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stixrud WR. Why stress is such a big deal. Journal of Management Education. 2012:1052562911430317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cassuto L. The graduate school mess: What caused it and how we can fix it: Harvard University Press; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loss CP, Ryan J, Christopher J. The Dissertation Dilemma and the Challenge of American Graduate Education. The Good Society. 2017;25(2&#x2013;3):313&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosch G, Casadevall A. Graduate biomedical science education needs a new philosophy. MBio. 2017;8(6):e01539&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1128/mBio.01539-17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/mBio.01539-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5736909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29259084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabat-Zinn J, Hanh TN. Full catastrophe living: Using the wisdom of your body and mind to face stress, pain, and illness: Delta; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishop SR, Lau M, Shapiro S, Carlson L, Anderson ND, Carmody J, et al. Mindfulness: A proposed operational definition. Clinical psychology: Science and practice. 2004;11(3):230&#x2013;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunaratana B, Gunaratana H. Mindfulness in plain English: Simon and Schuster; 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiken LG, Garland EL, Bluth K, Palsson OS, Gaylord SA. From a state to a trait: Trajectories of state mindfulness in meditation during intervention predict changes in trait mindfulness. Pers Individ Dif. 2015;81:41&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.paid.2014.12.044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2014.12.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4404745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25914434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baer RA. Mindfulness-based treatment approaches: Clinician&#x2019;s guide to evidence base and applications: Elsevier; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fjorback LO, Arendt M, &#xd8;rnb&#xf8;l E, Fink P, Walach H. Mindfulness&#x2010;Based Stress Reduction and Mindfulness&#x2010;Based Cognitive Therapy&#x2013;a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2011;124(2):102&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0447.2011.01704.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0447.2011.01704.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21534932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jha AP, Krompinger J, Baime MJ. Mindfulness training modifies subsystems of attention. Cognitive, Affective, &amp; Behavioral Neuroscience. 2007;7(2):109&#x2013;19. doi: 10.3758/cabn.7.2.109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/cabn.7.2.109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17672382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman P, Niemann L, Schmidt S, Walach H. Mindfulness-based stress reduction and health benefits: A meta-analysis. J Psychosom Res. 2004;57(1):35&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15256293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wielgosz J, Goldberg SB, Kral TR, Dunne JD, Davidson RJ. Mindfulness meditation and psychopathology. Ann Rev Clin Psych. 2019;15:285&#x2013;316. doi: 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-021815-093423</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-021815-093423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6597263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30525995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birnie K, Speca M, Carlson LE. Exploring self&#x2010;compassion and empathy in the context of mindfulness&#x2010;based stress reduction (MBSR). Stress Health. 2010;26(5):359&#x2013;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiesa A, Serretti A. Mindfulness-based stress reduction for stress management in healthy people: a review and meta-analysis. The journal of alternative and complementary medicine. 2009;15(5):593&#x2013;600. doi: 10.1089/acm.2008.0495</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/acm.2008.0495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19432513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro SL, Brown KW, Biegel GM. Teaching self-care to caregivers: Effects of mindfulness-based stress reduction on the mental health of therapists in training. Training and education in professional psychology. 2007;1(2):105.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang Y-Y, Ma Y, Wang J, Fan Y, Feng S, Lu Q, et al. Short-term meditation training improves attention and self-regulation. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 2007;104(43):17152&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1073/pnas.0707678104</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.0707678104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2040428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17940025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson RJ, Kabat-Zinn J, Schumacher J, Rosenkranz M, Muller D, Santorelli SF, et al. Alterations in brain and immune function produced by mindfulness meditation. Psychosom Med. 2003;65(4):564&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1097/01.psy.0000077505.67574.e3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.psy.0000077505.67574.e3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12883106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eberth J, Sedlmeier P. The effects of mindfulness meditation: a meta-analysis. Mindfulness. 2012;3(3):174&#x2013;89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flook L, Goldberg SB, Pinger L, Davidson RJ. Promoting prosocial behavior and self-regulatory skills in preschool children through a mindfulness-based kindness curriculum. Dev Psychol. 2015;51(1):44. doi: 10.1037/a0038256</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0038256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4485612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25383689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shapiro SL, Schwartz GE, Bonner G. Effects of mindfulness-based stress reduction on medical and premedical students. J Behav Med. 1998;21(6):581&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1023/a:1018700829825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/a:1018700829825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9891256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa P, Raymond G, Zlotnick C, Wilk J, Toomey R III, Mitchell J III. Mindfulness-based stress reduction training is associated with greater empathy and reduced anxiety for graduate healthcare students. Education for health. 2013;26(1):9. doi: 10.4103/1357-6283.112794</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1357-6283.112794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23823667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schure MB, Christopher J, Christopher S. Mind&#x2013;body medicine and the art of self&#x2010;care: teaching mindfulness to counseling students through yoga, meditation, and qigong. Journal of Counseling &amp; Development. 2008;86(1):47&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen JS, Miller LJ. Interpersonal mindfulness training for well-being: A pilot study with psychology graduate students. Teachers College Rec. 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warnecke E, Quinn S, Ogden K, Towle N, Nelson MR. A randomised controlled trial of the effects of mindfulness practice on medical student stress levels. Med Educ. 2011;45(4):381&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2923.2010.03877.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2923.2010.03877.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21401686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May Barry K, Woods M, Martin A, Stirling C, Warnecke E. A randomized controlled trial of the effects of mindfulness practice on doctoral candidate psychological status. J Am Coll Health. 2018:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30388950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamber MD, Schneider JK. Mindfulness-based meditation to decrease stress and anxiety in college students: A narrative synthesis of the research. Educational Research Review. 2016;18:1&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jewell J.
American Evaluation Association AEA365 A Tip a Day by and for Evaluators [Internet]2011. Available from: http://aea365.org/blog/jeremy-jewell-on-using-wait-list-control-groups-in-evaluation/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson RJ, Begley S. The emotional life of your brain: How its unique patterns affect the way you think, feel, and live&#x2014;and how you can change them: Penguin; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bamber MD, Morpeth E. Effects of mindfulness meditation on college student anxiety: A meta-analysis. Mindfulness. 2019;10(2):203&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesebir P, Gasiorowska A, Goldman R, Hirshberg M, Davidson R. Emotional Style Questionnaire: A multidimensional measure of healthy emotionality. Psychol Assess. 2019. doi: 10.1037/pas0000745</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pas0000745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6776667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31259572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gosling SD, Rentfrow PJ, Swann WB Jr. A very brief measure of the Big-Five personality domains. Journal of Research in personality. 2003;37(6):504&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson D, Clark LA, Tellegen A. Development and validation of brief measures of positive and negative affect: the PANAS scales. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1988;54(6):1063. doi: 10.1037//0022-3514.54.6.1063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0022-3514.54.6.1063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3397865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Hoberman HM. Positive events and social supports as buffers of life change stress. J Appl Soc Psychol. 1983;13(2):99&#x2013;125.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown KW, Ryan RM. The benefits of being present: mindfulness and its role in psychological well-being. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2003;84(4):822. doi: 10.1037/0022-3514.84.4.822</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.84.4.822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12703651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bohlmeijer E, ten Klooster PM, Fledderus M, Veehof M, Baer R. Psychometric properties of the five facet mindfulness questionnaire in depressed adults and development of a short form. Assessment. 2011;18(3):308&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1177/1073191111408231</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1073191111408231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21586480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker BJ. Synthesizing standardized mean&#x2010;change measures. Br J Math Stat Psychol. 1988;41(2):257&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz D, Toner B. A systematic review of gender differences in the effectiveness of mindfulness-based treatments for substance use disorders. Mindfulness. 2013;4(4):318&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rojiani R, Santoyo JF, Rahrig H, Roth HD, Britton WB. Women benefit more than men in response to college-based meditation training. Front Psychol. 2017;8:551. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00551</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5397480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28473783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson RJ, Kaszniak AW. Conceptual and methodological issues in research on mindfulness and meditation. Am Psychol. 2015;70(7):581. doi: 10.1037/a0039512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0039512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4627495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26436310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacCoon DG, Imel ZE, Rosenkranz MA, Sheftel JG, Weng HY, Sullivan JC, et al. The validation of an active control intervention for Mindfulness Based Stress Reduction (MBSR). Behav Res Ther. 2012;50(1):3&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2011.10.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2011.10.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3257026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22137364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>