<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37072901</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-6984</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>58</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Sep-Oct</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of language &amp; communication disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Lang Commun Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>'Sometimes I feel sad': A qualitative study on children's perceptions with cleft palate speech and language therapy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1526</StartPage><EndPage>1538</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1526-1538</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1460-6984.12879</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Evidence-based speech therapy involves the integration of (1) the scientific evidence for therapy with (2) the perspectives of clinicians concerning therapy and (3) the perspectives of patients about therapy. The cleft literature has already paid attention to the first two cornerstones of evidence-based speech therapy. Much less is known about how children perceive cleft speech therapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="AIMS">The purpose of the current qualitative study was to investigate the perceptions, emotions and expectations of Flemish-speaking Dutch children with a cleft (lip and) palate (CP &#xb1; L), aged 5-12 years, with regard to the speech therapy they receive. In this study, a focus was made on speech therapy to eliminate compensatory cleft speech errors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS &amp; PROCEDURES">Six children with a CP &#xb1; L, aged between 5 and 12 years, were included in this study. Child-friendly semi-structured interviews were conducted using a participatory, art-based qualitative approach. This means that the 'play and puppets technique' and 'draw-write and photo-elicitation technique' were used to guide the children through the interviews. Data derived from these interviews were analysed using an inductive thematic approach. Trustworthiness of the data was achieved by applying researcher triangulation, negative case analysis and an audit trail.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OUTCOMES &amp; RESULTS">Analyses of the interviews revealed three major themes of importance to the children: (1) treatment values, (2) treatment practices and (3) treatment outcomes. Each theme was divided into different subthemes. The theme 'treatment values' consisted of the subthemes expectations and emotions around therapy and interference with daily living. Information flow, therapy content, confirmation and rewards, parents' attendance, therapy intensity, and homework were subthemes of the major theme 'treatment practices'. The theme 'treatment outcomes' was divided into two subthemes, namely speech improvement and peers' reactions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS &amp; IMPLICATIONS">Most children had positive attitudes towards speech therapy: it was 'something they liked' and 'something fun'. If children had negative attitudes they were related to having a fear of making mistakes during therapy. Children had clear expectations of the purpose of speech therapy. Speech therapy should 'help' improve their speech and make it more understandable to others. The children in this sample made some suggestions to decrease the experienced burden related to speech therapy. The results of this study will help to better tailor speech therapy programmes to the needs and experiences of children with a CP &#xb1; L.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="WHAT THIS PAPER ADDS">What is already known on the subject Evidence-based speech therapy involves the integration of (1) the scientific evidence for therapy with (2) the perspectives of clinicians concerning therapy and (3) the perspectives of patients and their families about therapy. The cleft literature has already paid attention to the first two cornerstones of evidence-based speech therapy. Different studies investigated the perspectives of SLPs and parents with regard to cleft palate speech therapy. However, much less is known about the children's own experiences with and perceptions around this speech therapy. What this study adds to existing knowledge This study used a qualitative research design to investigate the perceptions, emotions and expectations of children with a cleft (lip and) palate, aged 5-12 years, with regard to the speech therapy they receive. Speech therapy needed to focus on the elimination of compensatory speech errors. This study provides knowledge on the speech therapy-related experiences of children with a cleft palate. What are the potential or actual clinical implications of this work? Children in this sample made some concrete suggestions to decrease the experienced burden related to cleft speech therapy, for example, integration of school work during therapy sessions and practising on the level of spontaneous speech. The results of this study help us to better tailor speech therapy programmes to the needs and experiences of children with a CP &#xb1; L.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Royal College of Speech and Language Therapists.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alighieri</LastName><ForeName>Cassandra</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7593-8595</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Centre of Speech and Language Sciences Ghent University, Gent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bettens</LastName><ForeName>Kim</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5546-5997</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Centre of Speech and Language Sciences Ghent University, Gent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Verbeke</LastName><ForeName>Jolien</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Centre of Speech and Language Sciences Ghent University, Gent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Lierde</LastName><ForeName>Kristiane</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Sciences, Centre of Speech and Language Sciences Ghent University, Gent, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Lang Commun Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9803709</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1368-2822</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Int J Lang Commun Disord. 2024 May-Jun;59(3):1253. doi: 10.1111/1460-6984.12997.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">38126699</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002972" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cleft Palate</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013070" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013060" MajorTopicYN="N">Speech</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007808" MajorTopicYN="N">Language Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cleft Lip</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036301" MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004644" MajorTopicYN="N">Emotions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cleft lip and palate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative research</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37072901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1460-6984.12879</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Albery, L. &amp; Enderby, P. (1984) Intensive speech therapy for cleft palate children. British Journal of Disorders of Communication, 19(2), 115-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Bettens, K., Bruneel, L., D'haeseleer, E., Van Gaever, E. &amp; Van Lierde, K. (2020) Effectiveness of speech intervention in patients with a cleft palate: comparison of motor-phonetic versus linguistic-phonological speech therapy approaches. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 63, 3909-3933. doi:https://doi.org/10.1044/2020_JSLHR-20-00129</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Bettens, K., Bruneel, L., Vandormael, C., Musasizi, D., Ojok, I., et&#xa0;al. (2019) Intensive speech therapy in Ugandan patients with cleft (lip and) palate: a pilot-study assessing long-term effectiveness. International Journal of Pediatric Otorhinolaryngology, 123, 156-167. doi:https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijporl.2019.05.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Bettens, K., Vanoost, L., Demuynck, K., Verhaeghe, S. &amp; Van Lierde, K. (2021) Parents&#x2019; perceptions on speech therapy delivery models in children with a cleft palate: a mixed methods study. International Journal of Pediatric Otorhinolaryngology, 151, 110958. doi:https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijporl.2021.110958</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Bettens, K., Vanoost, L., Verhaeghe, S. &amp; Van Lierde, K. (forthcoming 2023). Parents&#x2019; perceptions on speech therapy delivery models in children with a cleft palate: a mixed methods study. International Journal of Pediatric Otorhinolaryngology, 00.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Bettens, K., Verhaeghe, S. &amp; Van Lierde, K. (2021a) From excitement to self-doubt and insecurity: speech-language pathologists&#x2019; perceptions and experiences when treating children with a cleft palate. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 56, 739-753. https://doi.org/10.1111/1460-6984.12624</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Bettens, K., Verhaeghe, S. &amp; Van Lierde, K. (2021b) Speech diagnosis and intervention in children with a cleft palate: a qualitative study of Flemish private community speech-language pathologists' practices. International Journal of Speech-Language Pathology, 6, 1-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Peersman, W., Bettens, K., Van Herreweghe, V. &amp; Van Lierde, K. (2020) Parental perceptions and expectations concerning speech therapy-related cleft care-A qualitative study. Journal of Communication Disorders, 87, e106028. doi:https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcomdis.2020.106028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Van Lierde, K., Cammu, H., Vanoost, L. &amp; Bettens, K. (2022) The retrospective acceptability of high intensity versus low intensity speech intervention in children with a cleft palate: a qualitative study from the parents&#x2019; point of view using the Theoretical Framework of Acceptability. International Journal of Language Communication Disorders, 58(2), 326-341.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alighieri, C., Van Lierde, K., De Caesemaecker, A., Demuynck, K., Bruneel, L., D'haeseleer, E., et&#xa0;al. (2021) Is high intensity speech intervention better? - A comparison of high intensity intervention versus low intensity intervention in children with a cleft palate. Journal of Speech, Language, and Hearing Research, 25, 1-18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Cleft Palate-Craniofacial Association, A. (2016) Standards for cleft palate and craniofacial teams. NC: Chapel Hill: Author.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson, J.C., Funk, J.B., Elliott, R. &amp; Smith, P.H. (2003) Parental support and pressure and children's extracurricular activities: relationships with amount of involvement and affective experience of participation. Journal of Applied Developmental Psychology, 24(2), 241-257. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0193-3973(03)00046-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker, E. &amp; Williams, A. (2011) Intervention intensity for Speech Sound Disorders: how much and for how long?</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun, V. &amp; Clarke, V. (2006) Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qualitative Research in Psychology, 3(2), 77-101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter, B. &amp; Ford, K. (2013) Researching children's health experiences: the place for participatory, child-centered, arts-based approaches. Research in nursing &amp; health, 36(1), 95-107. https://doi.org/10.1002/nur.21517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellingsen, I., Thorsen, A. &amp; St&#xf8;rksen, I. (2014) Revealing Children's Experiences and Emotions through Q Methodology. Child Development Research, 1-9, 2014. https://doi.org/10.1155/2014/910529</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everhart, S.A., Cochran, K., Lambrou, N., Davies, W. &amp; Marik, P. (2022) Psychosocial experiences that support positive self-concept in children with cleft lip and palate adopted from China. The Cleft Palate Craniofacial Journal, 59(12), 1509-1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson, F., Aldiss, S., Horstman, M., Kumpunen, S. &amp; Richardson, A. (2010) Children and young people's experiences of cancer care: a qualitative research study using participatory methods. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 47(11), 1397-1407. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2010.03.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobo, G. &amp; Mauceri, S. (2014) Constructing survey data: An interactional approach. In. London: SAGE Publications Ltd. Retrieved from https://methods.sagepub.com/book/constructing-survey-data-a-critical-approach. https://doi.org/10.4135/9781446288481</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Golding-Kushner, K., (2004) Treatment of sound system disorders associated with cleft palate speech. Perspectives on Speech Science Orofacial Disorders, 14(2): p. 16-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha, S. (2015) Effectiveness of a parent-implemented intervention program for young children with cleft palate. International Journal of Pediatric Otorhinolaryngology, 79(5), 707-715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haerens, L., Bettens, K., Van Lierde, K. &amp; Aelterman, N. (2021) The promise of self-determination theory to study the therapist-client relationship in speech-language treatment. Journal of Communication Disorders, 89, 106059. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcomdis.2020.106059</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, M., Gibson, B., James, A. &amp; Rodd, H.D. (2012) Children's experiences of participation in the cleft lip and palate care pathway. International Journal of Paediatric Dentistry, 22(6), 442-450. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-263X.2011.01214.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson, A. (2017) Negative case analysis. The International Encyclopedia of. Communication Research Methods, 1-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardin-Jones, M., Jones, D. &amp; Dolezal, R. (2020) Opinions of speech-language pathologists regarding speech management for children with cleft lip and palate. The Cleft Palate-Craniofacial Journal, 57, 55-64. https://doi.org/10.1177/1055665619857000</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harding, A. &amp; Grunwell, P. (1998) Active versus passive cleft-type speech characteristics. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders, 33(3), 329-352.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegarty, N., Titterington, J., McLeod, S. &amp; Taggart, L. (2018) Intervention for children with phonological impairment: knowledge, practices and intervention intensity in the UK. International Journal of Language and Communication Disorders, 53(5), 995-1006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holloway, I. &amp; Galvin, K. (2016) Qualitative research in nursing and healthcare: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klatte, I., Lyons, R., Davies, K., Harding, S., Marshall, J., McKean, C., et&#xa0;al. (2020) Collaboration between parents and SLTs produces optimal outcomes for children attending speech and language therapy: gathering the evidence. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders, 55(4), 618-628. https://doi.org/10.1111/1460-6984.12538</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln, Y. (2007) Naturalistic inquiry. The Blackwell Encyclopedia of Sociology.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindeborg, M., Shakya, P., Pradhan, B., Rai, S., Gurung, K., Niroula, S., et&#xa0;al. (2020) A task-shifted speech therapy program for cleft palate patients in rural Nepal: evaluating impact and associated healthcare barriers. International Journal of Pediatric Otorhinolaryngology, 134, 110026. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijporl.2020.110026</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mashima, P.A. &amp; Doarn, C.R. (2008) Overview of telehealth activities in speech-language pathology. Telemedicine e-Health, 14(10), 1101-1117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mossey, P. (2003) Global strategies to reduce the healthcare burden of craniofacial anomalies. British Dental Journal, 195(10), 613-613.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mossey, P.A. &amp; Catilla, E.E. (2003) Global registry and database on craniofacial anomalies: Report of a WHO Registry Meeting on Craniofacial Anomalies.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NVivo. (2018) NVivo qualitative data analysis software; Version 12, 2018.: QSR International Pty Ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owen, R., Hayett, L. &amp; Roulstone, S. (2004) Children's views of speech and language therapy in school: consulting children with communication difficulties. Child Language Teaching Therapy, 20(1), 55-73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherer, N.J., D'Antonio, L.L. &amp; McGahey, H. (2008) Early intervention for speech impairment in children with cleft palate. The Cleft Palate-Craniofacial Journal, 45(1), 18-31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer, C.L., Wankier, A.P., Obiri-Yeboah, S., Gyamfi, S., Frimpong, B.A. &amp; Dickerson, T. (2021) A qualitative analysis of factors impacting comprehensive cleft lip and palate care in Ghana. The Cleft Palate-Craniofacial Journal: Official Publication of the American Cleft Palate-Craniofacial Association, 58(6), 746-754. https://doi.org/10.1177/1055665620959995</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steglitz, J., Warnick, J.L., Hoffman, S.A., Johnston, W. &amp; Spring, B. (2015) Evidence-based practice. International Encyclopedia of the Social Behavioral Sciences, 8, 332-338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeney, T., Hegarty, F., Powell, K., Deasy, L., Regan, M. &amp; Sell, D. (2020) Randomized controlled trial comparing Parent Led Therapist Supervised Articulation Therapy (PLAT) with routine intervention for children with speech disorders associated with cleft palate. International Journal of Language &amp; Communication Disorders, 55(5), 639-660. https://doi.org/10.1111/1460-6984.12542</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toki, E.I. &amp; Pange, J. (2010) E-learning activities for articulation in speech language therapy and learning for preschool children. Procedia-Social Behavioral Sciences, 2(2), 4274-4278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, A., Sainsbury, P. &amp; Craig, J. (2007) Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. International journal for quality in health care.International Journal for Quality in Health Care, 19(6), 349-357. https://doi.org/10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Lierde, K.M., Dhaeseleer, E., Luyten, A., Van De Woestijne, K., Vermeersch, H. &amp; Roche, N. (2012) Parent and child ratings of satisfaction with speech and facial appearance in Flemish pre-pubescent boys and girls with unilateral cleft lip and palate. International Journal of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, 41(2), 192-199. doi:https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijom.2011.10.030</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Riper, C. (1972) Speech correction. Prentice-Hall.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vansteenkiste, M. &amp; Sheldon, K.M. (2006) There's nothing more practical than a good theory: integrating motivational interviewing and self-determination theory. British Journal of Clinical Psychology, 45(1), 63-82.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>