<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37553813</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1447-0349</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of mental health nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Ment Health Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of family interventions for patients with schizophrenia: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1598</StartPage><EndPage>1615</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1598-1615</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/inm.13198</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The family is the primary caregiver for most patients with schizophrenia, and their roles are essential in patients' illness trajectories and outcomes. Due to this, various family interventions for schizophrenia have been developed and applied to the relatives who take care of their family members with schizophrenia. This study examined the effectiveness of existing family interventions for schizophrenia in achieving their target outcomes at both the family and patient levels by utilizing a systematic review and meta-analysis. Combinations of terms were used to search for relevant studies from the databases. Thirty-seven randomized controlled trials that met the inclusion criteria were included in the analysis. Based on the pooled result of the included studies, the programmes significantly improved the targeted outcomes with large effect size. The programmes' impacts on family-related outcomes were higher than those on patients. Among the targeted outcomes, patients' treatment satisfaction and adherence and family caregivers' mental health were the most remarkable outcomes that had improved from the included programmes. Conversely, outcomes related to family relationships, caregiving experiences, perceived social support of family caregivers, and patients' medication use did not see significant improvements. The programmes delivered to individual family units and only to the family caregivers were more effective than those delivered to groups of caregivers and caregivers and patients together, respectively. Programme-focused interventions were more effective than emotion-focused ones. Based on these findings, an in-home visiting nurse programme or advanced technology is suggested when applying family interventions for schizophrenia in practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Sin-Hyang</ForeName><Initials>SH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8900-1733</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Shinsung University, Dangjin-Si, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Sihyun</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1808-345X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Chung-Ang University, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Ment Health Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101140527</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1445-8330</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Schizophrenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012944" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Support</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005190" MajorTopicYN="N">Family</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010361" MajorTopicYN="N">Patients</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004644" MajorTopicYN="N">Emotions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017028" MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">caregiver burden</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">family</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychosocial intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">schizophrenia</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37553813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/inm.13198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Badamli, K. &amp; Duman, Z.&#xc7;. (2014) Effects of a family-to-family support program on the mental health and coping strategies of caregivers of adults with mental illness: a randomized controlled study. Archives of Psychiatric Nursing, 28, 392-398. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apnu.2014.08.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudoin, M., Hudon, A., Gigu&#xe8;re, C.E., Potvin, S. &amp; Dumais, A. (2022) Prediction of quality of life in schizophrenia using machine learning models on data from clinical antipsychotic trials of intervention effectiveness (CATIE) schizophrenia trial. Schizophrenia, 8(1), 29. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1038/s41537-022-00236-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrouian, M., Ramezani, T., Dehghan, M., Sabahi, A. &amp; Ebrahimnejad Zarandi, B. (2020) The effect of emotion regulation training on stress, anxiety, and depression in family caregivers of patients with schizophrenia: a randomized controlled trial. Community Mental Health Journal, 56(6), 1095-1102. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1007/s10597-020-00574-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behrouian, M., Ramezani, T., Dehghan, M., Sabahi, A. &amp; Ebrahimnejad Zarandi, B. (2021) The effect of the emotion regulation training on the resilience of caregivers of patients with schizophrenia: a parallel randomized controlled trial. BMC Psychology, 9(1), 1095-1102. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1186/s40359-021-00542-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein, M., Hedges, L.V., Higgins, J.P.T. &amp; Rothstein, H.R. (2009) Introduction to meta-analysis, 1st edition. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley, G.M., Couchman, G.M., Perlesz, A., Nguyen, A.T., Singh, B. &amp; Riess, C. (2006) Multiple-family group treatment for English- and Vietnamese-speaking families living with schizophrenia. Psychiatric Services, 57(4), 521-530. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1176/ps.2006.57.4.521</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budiono, W., Kantono, K., Kristianto, F.C., Avanti, C. &amp; Herawati, F. (2021) Psychoeducation improved illness perception and expressed emotion of family caregivers of patients with schizophrenia. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 18(14), 7522. Available from: https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph18147522</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camacho-Gomez, M. &amp; Castellvi, P. (2020) Effectiveness of family intervention for preventing relapse in first-episode psychosis until 24 months of follow-up: a systematic review with meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Schizophrenia Bulletin, 46(1), 98-109. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/sbz038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caqueo-Ur&#xed;zar, A., Rus-Calafell, M., Craig, T.K.J., Irarrazaval, M., Urz&#xfa;a, A., Boyer, L. et al. (2017) Schizophrenia: impact on family dynamics. Current Psychiatry Reports, 19(1), 2. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1007/s11920-017-0756-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan, S.W., Yip, B., Tso, S., Cheng, B.S. &amp; Tam, W. (2009) Evaluation of a psychoeducation program for Chinese clients with schizophrenia and their family caregivers. Patient Education and Counseling, 75(1), 67-76. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pec.2008.08.028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y., Lam, C.S., Deng, H., Yau, E. &amp; Ko, K.Y. (2021) The effectiveness of a community psychiatric rehabilitation program led by laypeople in China: a randomized controlled pilot study. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 12, 671217. Available from: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2021.671217</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T., Bressington, D. &amp; Chan, S.W.C. (2018) A randomized controlled trial on mutual support group intervention for families of people with recent-onset psychosis: a four-year follow-up. Frontiers in Psychiatry, 9, 710. Available from: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyt.2018.00710</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T., Bressington, D., Lubman, D.I. &amp; Karatzias, T. (2020) A randomised controlled trial of a caregiver-facilitated problem-solving based self-learning program for family carers of people with early psychosis. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 17(24), 1-22. Available from: https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17249343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T. &amp; Chan, S.W. (2004) One-year follow-up of a multiple-family-group intervention for Chinese families of patients with schizophrenia. Psychiatric Services, 55(11), 1276-1284. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ps.55.11.1276</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T. &amp; Chan, S.W.C. (2013) The effectiveness of mutual support group intervention for Chinese families of people with schizophrenia: a randomised controlled trial with 24-month follow-up. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 50(10), 1326-1340. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2013.01.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T., Chan, S., Morrissey, J. &amp; Thompson, D. (2005) Effectiveness of a mutual support group for families of patients with schizophrenia. Journal of Advanced Nursing, 51(6), 595-608. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2648.2005.03545.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T., Chan, S.W.C. &amp; Thompson, D.R. (2006) Effects of a mutual support group for families of Chinese people with schizophrenia - 18-month follow-up. British Journal of Psychiatry, 189, 41-49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T. &amp; Thompson, D.R. (2013) An RCT with three-year follow-up of peer support groups for Chinese families of persons with schizophrenia. Psychiatric Services, 64(10), 997-1005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T., Thompson, D.R. &amp; Norman, I. (2008) Evaluation of a peer-led mutual support group for Chinese families of people with schizophrenia. American Journal of Community Psychology, 42(1-2), 122-134. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1007/s10464-008-9178-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T. &amp; Wong, K.-F. (2007) A family psychoeducation group program for Chinese people with schizophrenia in Hong Kong. Psychiatric Services, 58(7), 1003-1006. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1176/appi.ps.58.7.1003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chien, W.T., Yip, A.L.K., Liu, J.Y.W. &amp; McMaster, T.W. (2016) The effectiveness of manual-guided, problem-solving-based self-learning programme for family caregivers of people with recent-onset psychosis: a randomised controlled trial with 6-month follow-up. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 59, 141-155. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2016.03.018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Citrome, L., Belcher, E., Stacy, S., Suett, M., Mychaskiw, M. &amp; Salinas, G.D. (2022) Perceived burdens and educational needs of caregivers of people with schizophrenia: results of a national survey study. Patient Preference and Adherence, 16, 159-168. Available from: https://doi.org/10.2147/ppa.s326290</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claxton, M., Onwumere, J. &amp; Fornells-Ambrojo, M. (2017) Do family interventions improve outcomes in early psychosis? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Frontiers in Psychology, 8, 371. Available from: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00371</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, J. (1992) A power primer. Psychological Bulletin, 112(1), 155-159. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1037//0033-2909.112.1.155</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper, H. (2017) Research synthesis and meta-analysis: a step-by-step approach. In: Fargotstein, L., Ancheta, K. &amp; Larson, L. (Eds.) Applied social research methods series, 5th edition. Thousand Oaks, CA: Sage Publications, Inc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattani, S., Ritchie, H. &amp; Rosers, M. (2021) Mental health. Our world in data. Available from: https://ourworldindata.org/mental-health [Accessed 01st December 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deane, F.P., Marshall, S., Crowe, T., White, A. &amp; Kavanagh, D. (2015) A randomized controlled trial of a correspondence-based intervention for carers of relatives with psychosis. Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, 22(2), 142-152. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1002/cpp.1880</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durmaz, H. &amp; Okanli, A. (2021) Effects of interpersonal psychotherapy (IPT) techniques and psychoeducation on self-efficacy and care burden in families of patients with schizophrenia. American Journal of Family Therapy, 49(4), 373-391. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1080/01926187.2020.1820401</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallahi Khoshknab, M., Sheikhona, M., Rahgouy, A., Rahgozar, M. &amp; Sodagari, F. (2013) The effects of group psychoeducational programme on family burden in caregivers of Iranian patients with schizophrenia. Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing, 21(5), 438-446. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/jpm.12107</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta, S., Isherwood, G., Jones, K. &amp; Van Impe, K. (2015) Assessing health status in informal schizophrenia caregivers compared with health status in non-caregivers and caregivers of other conditions. BMC Psychiatry, 15(1), 1-11. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-015-0547-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez, D.A.V., Saldivia, S., Fern&#xe1;ndez, P.G. &amp; Rovegno, C.I. (2019) Effectiveness of behavioral family therapy in people with schizophrenia: a randomized, controlled clinical trial. Salud Mental, 42(2), 65-74. Available from: https://doi.org/10.17711/SM.0185-3325.2019.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Maldonado, J. &amp; Caqueo-Ur&#xed;zar, A. (2007) Effectiveness of a psycho-educational intervention for reducing burden in Latin American families of patients with schizophrenia. Quality of Life Research, 16(5), 739-747. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1007/s11136-007-9173-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Maldonado, J., Caqueo-Ur&#xed;zar, A. &amp; Ferrer-Garc&#xed;a, M. (2009) Effects of a psychoeducational intervention program on the attitudes and health perceptions of relatives of patients with schizophrenia. Social Psychiatry and Psychiatric Epidemiology, 44(5), 343-348. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1007/s00127-008-0451-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan, A.A., Callaghan, P. &amp; Lymn, J.S. (2015) Evaluation of the impact of a psycho-educational intervention for people diagnosed with schizophrenia and their primary caregivers in Jordan: a randomized controlled trial. BMC Psychiatry, 15(1), 1-11. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1186/s12888-015-0444-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi, K., Medic, G., Littlewood, K.J., Diez, T., Granstr&#xf6;m, O. &amp; de Hert, M. (2013) Medication adherence in schizophrenia: factors influencing adherence and consequences of nonadherence, a systematic literature review. Therapeutic Advances in Psychopharmacology, 3(4), 200-218. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1177/2045125312474019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, J.P., Thompson, S.G., Deeks, J.J. &amp; Altman, D.G. (2003) Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ: British Medical Journal, 327(7414), 557-560. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.327.7414.557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins, J.P.T., Savovi&#x107;, E., Page, M.J. &amp; Sterne, J.A.C. (2020) Revised Cochrane risk of bias tool for randomized trials (RoB 2.0): additional considerations for cluster-randomized trials. Cochrane Methods March, 1-6. Available from: https://sites.google.com/site/riskofbiastool/welcome/rob-2-0-tool/rob-2-for-crossover-trials?authuser=0.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalil, A.H., ELNahas, G., Ramy, H., Abdel Aziz, K., Elkholy, H. &amp; El-Ghamry, R. (2019) Impact of a culturally adapted behavioural family psychoeducational programme in patients with schizophrenia in Egypt. International Journal of Psychiatry in Clinical Practice, 23(1), 62-71. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1080/13651501.2018.1480786</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khodabakhshi-Koolaee, A. &amp; Manoochehri, M. (2021) Improving resilience in mothers with schizophrenic sons: a group movie analysis. International Journal of Social Psychiatry, 69(1), 63-69. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1177/00207640211067677</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko, Y. &amp; Park, S. (2021) Life after hospital discharge for people with long-term mental disorders in South Korea: focusing on the &#x201c;revolving door phenomenon&#x201d;. Perspectives in Psychiatric Care, 57(2), 531-538. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/ppc.12575</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ko&#xe7;, M., Tel, H. &amp; Karak&#xfc;lah, K. (2021) Determining care burden and psychiatric symptom level in caregiver of schizophrenia patient. Perspectives in Psychiatric Care, 57(2), 642-647. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/ppc.12588</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koolaee, A.K. &amp; Etemadi, A. (2010) The outcome of family interventions for the mothers of schizophrenia patients in Iran. International Journal of Social Psychiatry, 56(6), 634-646. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1177/0020764009344144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuipers, E. (2006) Family interventions in schizophrenia: evidence for efficacy and proposed mechanisms of change. Journal of Family Therapy, 28(1), 73-80. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1467-6427.2006.00338.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulhara, P., Chakrabarti, S., Avasthi, A., Sharma, A. &amp; Sharma, S. (2009) Psychoeducational intervention for caregivers of Indian patients with schizophrenia: a randomised-controlled trial. Acta Psychiatrica Scandinavica, 119(6), 472-483. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0447.2008.01304.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lasebikan, V.O. &amp; Ayinde, O.O. (2013) Family burden in caregivers of schizophrenia patients: prevalence and socio-demographic correlates. Indian Journal of Psychological Medicine, 35(1), 60-66. Available from: https://doi.org/10.4103/0253-7176.112205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, Z. &amp; Authur, D. (2005) Family education for people with schizophrenia in Beijing, China. British Journal of Psychiatry, 187, 339-345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lippi, G. (2016) Schizophrenia in a member of the family: burden, expressed emotion and addressing the needs of the whole family. South African Journal of Psychiatry, 22(1), 1-7. Available from: https://doi.org/10.4102/sajpsychiatry.v22i1.922</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, C.F., Chan, S.K.W., Chien, W.T., Bressington, D., Mui, E.Y.W., Lee, E.H.M. et al. (2020) Cognitive behavioural family intervention for people diagnosed with severe mental illness and their families: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Journal of Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing, 27(2), 128-139. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/jpm.12567</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, C.F., Chan, S.K.W., Chung, Y.L., Ng, S.M., Hui, C.L.M., Suen, Y.N. et al. (2021) The predictive power of expressed emotion and its components in relapse of schizophrenia: a meta-analysis and meta-regression. Psychological Medicine, 51(3), 365-375. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291721000209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma, C.F., Chien, W.T. &amp; Bressington, D.T. (2018) Family intervention for caregivers of people with recent-onset psychosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Early Intervention in Psychiatry, 12(4), 535-560. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/eip.12494</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magliano, L., Fiorillo, A., Malangone, C., de Rosa, C., Maj, M. &amp; the Family Intervention Working Group. (2006) Patient functioning and family burden in a controlled, real-world trial of family psychoeducation for schizophrenia. Psychiatric Services, 57(12), 12-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marchira, C.R., Supriyanto, I., Subandi, S., Good, M.J.D. &amp; Good, B.J. (2019) Brief interactive psychoeducation for caregivers of patients with early phase psychosis in Yogyakarta, Indonesia. Early Intervention in Psychiatry, 13(3), 469-476. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/eip.12506</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayoral, F., Berrozpe, A., de la Higuera, J., Martinez-Jambrina, J.J., de Dios Luna, J. &amp; Torres-Gonzalez, F. (2015) Efficacy of a family intervention programme for prevention of hospitalisation in patients with schizophrenia. A naturalistic multicenter controlled and randomised study in Spain. Revista de Psiquiatr&#xed;a y Salud Mental, 8(2), 83-91. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rpsmen.2015.04.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonell, M.G., Short, R.A., Hazel, N.A., Berry, C.M. &amp; Dyck, D.G. (2006) Multiple-family group treatment of outpatients with schizophrenia: impact on service utilization. Family Process, 45(3), 359-372. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1545-5300.2006.00176.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher, D., Liberati, A., Tetzlaff, J. &amp; Altman, D.G. (2009) Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. Annals of Internal Medicine, 151(4), 264-269. Available from: https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-151-4-200908180-00135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueser, K.T., Achtyes, E.D., Gogate, J., Mancevski, B., Kim, E. &amp; Starr, H.L. (2022) Telehealth-based psychoeducation for caregivers: the family intervention in recent-onset schizophrenia treatment study. JMIR Mental Health, 9(4), e32492. Available from: https://doi.org/10.2196/32492</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muhi&#x107;, M., Jankovi&#x107;, S., Sikira, H., Slatina Murga, S., McGrath, M., Fung, C. et al. (2022) Multifamily groups for patients with schizophrenia: an exploratory randomised controlled trial in Bosnia and Herzegovina. Social Psychiatry and Psychiatric Epidemiology, 57(7), 1357-1364. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1007/s00127-022-02227-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasir, A. &amp; Rizal, C. (2021) The relationship of family roles to medication adherence in schizophrenia patient. Journal of Vocational Nursing, 2(2), 113-118. Available from: www.e-journal.unair.ac.id/JoViN/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasr, T. &amp; Kausar, R. (2009) Psychoeducation and the family burden in schizophrenia: a randomized controlled trial. Annals of General Psychiatry, 8(17), 1-6. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1186/1744-859X-8-17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute of Mental Health. (2022) Schizophrenia. Available from: https://www.nimh.nih.gov/health/topics/schizophrenia [Accessed 01st December 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>NICE. (2014) Psychosis and schizophrenia in adults. National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg178 [Accessed 01st December 2022].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raeisi, M., Navidian, A. &amp; Rezaee, N. (2020) Comparison of the effect of nurses&#x2019; education on stress, anxiety and depression of family caregivers of patients hospitalized with schizophrenia disorder. Archives of Pharmacy Practice, 11(1), 82-87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajai, N., Lami, B., Pishgooie, A.H., Habibi, H. &amp; Alavizerang, F. (2021) Evaluating the effect of peer-assisted education on the functioning in family caregivers of patients with schizophrenia: a clinical trial study. Korean Journal of Family Medicine, 42(5), 356-362. Available from: https://doi.org/10.4082/kjfm.20.0098</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rami, H., Hussien, H., Rabie, M., Sabry, W., El Missiry, M. &amp; Ghamry, R.E. (2018) Evaluating the effectiveness of a culturally adapted behavioral family psycho-educational program for Egyptian patients with schizophrenia. Transcultural Psychiatry, 55(5), 601-622. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1177/1363461518782520</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee, T.G.R. &amp; Rosenheck, R.A. (2019) Does improvement in symptoms and quality of life in chronic schizophrenia reduce family caregiver burden? Psychiatry Research, 271, 402-404. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psychres.2018.12.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodolico, A., Bighelli, I., Avanzato, C., Concerto, C., Cutrufelli, P., Mineo, L. et al. (2022) Family interventions for relapse prevention in schizophrenia: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. The Lancet Psychiatry, 9(3), 211-221. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/S2215-0366(21)00437-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim, S.R. &amp; Kim, S.J. (2019) Intervention meta-analysis: application and practice using R software. Epidemiology and Health, 41, e2019008. Available from: https://doi.org/10.4178/epih.e2019008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sin, J., Gillard, S., Spain, D., Cornelius, V., Chen, T. &amp; Henderson, C. (2017) Effectiveness of psychoeducational interventions for family carers of people with psychosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clinical Psychology Review, 56, 13-24. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cpr.2017.05.002</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thimmajja, S.G. &amp; Rathinasamy, E.V.L. (2019) Effectiveness of psycho-education on knowledge regarding schizophrenia and caregivers&#x2019; burden among caregivers of patients with schizophrenia - a randomized controlled trial. Family Medicine and Primary Care Review, 21(2), 104-111. Available from: https://doi.org/10.5114/fmpcr.2019.84552</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viechtbauer, W. &amp; Cheung, M.W.-L. (2010) Outlier and influence diagnostics for meta-analysis. Research Synthesis Methods, 1(2), 112-125. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1002/jrsm.11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan, K.-F. &amp; Wong, M.M.C. (2019) Stress and burden faced by family caregivers of people with schizophrenia and early psychosis in Hong Kong. Internal Medicine Journal, 49(Suppl 1), 9-15. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1111/imj.14166</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, Y.-Z., Weng, X., Zhang, T.-M., Li, M., Luo, W., Wong, Y.-L.I. et al. (2022) Effectiveness of enhancing contact model on reducing family caregiving burden and improving psychological wellbeing among caregivers of persons with schizophrenia in rural China. Psychological Medicine, 1-11. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1017/s0033291722002987</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, D.H.R., Chiu, Y.L.M., Lo, T.L.W., Lo, W.F.A., Wong, S.S., Luk, K.L. et al. (2020) Outside-in or inside-out? A randomized controlled trial of two empowerment approaches for family caregivers of people with schizophrenia. Issues in Mental Health Nursing, 41(9), 761-772. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1080/01612840.2020.173499</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>