<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">23888191</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2013</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1949-8462</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Atrial fibrillation in heart failure: The sword of Damocles revisited.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>215</StartPage><EndPage>227</EndPage><MedlinePgn>215-27</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4330/wjc.v5.i7.215</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Heart failure (HF) and atrial fibrillation (AF) frequently coexist and have emerged as major cardiovascular epidemics. There is growing evidence that AF is an independent prognostic marker in HF and affects patients with both reduced as well as preserved LV systolic function. There has been a general move in clinical practice from a rhythm control to a rate control strategy in HF patients with AF, although recent data suggests that rhythm control strategies may provide better outcomes in selected subgroups of HF patients. Furthermore, various therapeutic modalities including pace and ablate strategies with cardiac resynchronisation or radiofrequency ablation have become increasingly adopted, although their role in the management of AF in patients with HF remains uncertain. This article presents an overview of the multidimensional impact of AF in patients with HF. Relevant literature is highlighted and the effect of various therapeutic modalities on prognosis is discussed. Finally, while novel anticoagulants usher in a new era in thromboprophylaxis, research continues in a variety of new pathways including selective atrial anti-arrhythmic agents and genomic polymorphisms in AF with HF.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khan</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Muhammad A Khan, Fozia Ahmed, Ludwig Neyses, Mamas A Mamas, Manchester Heart Centre, Manchester Royal Infirmary, Manchester, M13 9WL, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmed</LastName><ForeName>Fozia</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neyses</LastName><ForeName>Ludwig</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamas</LastName><ForeName>Mamas A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101537090</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atrial fibrillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heart failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thromboprophylaxis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2013</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23888191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3722419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4330/wjc.v5.i7.215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Braunwald E. Shattuck lecture--cardiovascular medicine at the turn of the millennium: triumphs, concerns, and opportunities. N Engl J Med. 1997;337:1360&#x2013;1369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9358131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell JC, Mamas MA. Heart failure, diastolic dysfunction and atrial fibrillation; mechanistic insight of a complex inter-relationship. Heart Fail Rev. 2012;17:27&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21103928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deedwania PC, Lardizabal JA. Atrial fibrillation in heart failure: a comprehensive review. Am J Med. 2010;123:198&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20193823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams KF, Fonarow GC, Emerman CL, LeJemtel TH, Costanzo MR, Abraham WT, Berkowitz RL, Galvao M, Horton DP. Characteristics and outcomes of patients hospitalized for heart failure in the United States: rationale, design, and preliminary observations from the first 100,000 cases in the Acute Decompensated Heart Failure National Registry (ADHERE) Am Heart J. 2005;149:209&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15846257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivero-Ayerza M, Scholte Op Reimer W, Lenzen M, Theuns DA, Jordaens L, Komajda M, Follath F, Swedberg K, Cleland JG. New-onset atrial fibrillation is an independent predictor of in-hospital mortality in hospitalized heart failure patients: results of the EuroHeart Failure Survey. Eur Heart J. 2008;29:1618&#x2013;1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18515809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia RS, Tu JV, Lee DS, Austin PC, Fang J, Haouzi A, Gong Y, Liu PP. Outcome of heart failure with preserved ejection fraction in a population-based study. N Engl J Med. 2006;355:260&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Owan TE, Hodge DO, Herges RM, Jacobsen SJ, Roger VL, Redfield MM. Trends in prevalence and outcome of heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. N Engl J Med. 2006;355:251&#x2013;259.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogg K, Swedberg K, McMurray J. Heart failure with preserved left ventricular systolic function; epidemiology, clinical characteristics, and prognosis. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;43:317&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15013109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maisel WH, Stevenson LW. Atrial fibrillation in heart failure: epidemiology, pathophysiology, and rationale for therapy. Am J Cardiol. 2003;91:2D&#x2013;8D.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12670636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Ferrari GM, Klersy C, Ferrero P, Fantoni C, Salerno-Uriarte D, Manca L, Devecchi P, Molon G, Revera M, Curnis A, et al. Atrial fibrillation in heart failure patients: prevalence in daily practice and effect on the severity of symptoms. Data from the ALPHA study registry. Eur J Heart Fail. 2007;9:502&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17174599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anter E, Jessup M, Callans DJ. Atrial fibrillation and heart failure: treatment considerations for a dual epidemic. Circulation. 2009;119:2516&#x2013;2525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19433768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark DM, Plumb VJ, Epstein AE, Kay GN. Hemodynamic effects of an irregular sequence of ventricular cycle lengths during atrial fibrillation. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1997;30:1039&#x2013;1045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9316536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pozzoli M, Cioffi G, Traversi E, Pinna GD, Cobelli F, Tavazzi L. Predictors of primary atrial fibrillation and concomitant clinical and hemodynamic changes in patients with chronic heart failure: a prospective study in 344 patients with baseline sinus rhythm. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1998;32:197&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9669270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubitz SA, Benjamin EJ, Ellinor PT. Atrial fibrillation in congestive heart failure. Heart Fail Clin. 2010;6:187&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20347787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roger VL, Go AS, Lloyd-Jones DM, Benjamin EJ, Berry JD, Borden WB, Bravata DM, Dai S, Ford ES, Fox CS, et al. Executive summary: heart disease and stroke statistics--2012 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2012;125:188&#x2013;197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22215894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray JJ, Petrie MC, Murdoch DR, Davie AP. Clinical epidemiology of heart failure: public and private health burden. Eur Heart J. 1998;19 Suppl P:P9&#x2013;P16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9886707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bleumink GS, Knetsch AM, Sturkenboom MC, Straus SM, Hofman A, Deckers JW, Witteman JC, Stricker BH. Quantifying the heart failure epidemic: prevalence, incidence rate, lifetime risk and prognosis of heart failure The Rotterdam Study. Eur Heart J. 2004;25:1614&#x2013;1619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15351160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kannel WB, Benjamin EJ. Status of the epidemiology of atrial fibrillation. Med Clin North Am. 2008;92:17&#x2013;40, ix.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2245891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18060995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go AS, Hylek EM, Phillips KA, Chang Y, Henault LE, Selby JV, Singer DE. Prevalence of diagnosed atrial fibrillation in adults: national implications for rhythm management and stroke prevention: the AnTicoagulation and Risk Factors in Atrial Fibrillation (ATRIA) Study. JAMA. 2001;285:2370&#x2013;2375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11343485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heeringa J, van der Kuip DA, Hofman A, Kors JA, van Herpen G, Stricker BH, Stijnen T, Lip GY, Witteman JC. Prevalence, incidence and lifetime risk of atrial fibrillation: the Rotterdam study. Eur Heart J. 2006;27:949&#x2013;953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16527828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Jones DM, Larson MG, Leip EP, Beiser A, D&#x2019;Agostino RB, Kannel WB, Murabito JM, Vasan RS, Benjamin EJ, Levy D. Lifetime risk for developing congestive heart failure: the Framingham Heart Study. Circulation. 2002;106:3068&#x2013;3072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12473553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magnani JW, Rienstra M, Lin H, Sinner MF, Lubitz SA, McManus DD, Dupuis J, Ellinor PT, Benjamin EJ. Atrial fibrillation: current knowledge and future directions in epidemiology and genomics. Circulation. 2011;124:1982&#x2013;1993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3208425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22042927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mountantonakis SE, Grau-Sepulveda MV, Bhatt DL, Hernandez AF, Peterson ED, Fonarow GC. Presence of atrial fibrillation is independently associated with adverse outcomes in patients hospitalized with heart failure: an analysis of get with the guidelines-heart failure. Circ Heart Fail. 2012;5:191&#x2013;201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22361078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mentz RJ, Chung MJ, Gheorghiade M, Pang PS, Kwasny MJ, Ambrosy AP, Vaduganathan M, O&#x2019;Connor CM, Swedberg K, Zannad F, et al. Atrial fibrillation or flutter on initial electrocardiogram is associated with worse outcomes in patients admitted for worsening heart failure with reduced ejection fraction: findings from the EVEREST Trial. Am Heart J. 2012;164:884&#x2013;892.e2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23194489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dries DL, Exner DV, Gersh BJ, Domanski MJ, Waclawiw MA, Stevenson LW. Atrial fibrillation is associated with an increased risk for mortality and heart failure progression in patients with asymptomatic and symptomatic left ventricular systolic dysfunction: a retrospective analysis of the SOLVD trials. Studies of Left Ventricular Dysfunction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1998;32:695&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9741514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsson LG, Swedberg K, Ducharme A, Granger CB, Michelson EL, McMurray JJ, Puu M, Yusuf S, Pfeffer MA. Atrial fibrillation and risk of clinical events in chronic heart failure with and without left ventricular systolic dysfunction: results from the Candesartan in Heart failure-Assessment of Reduction in Mortality and morbidity (CHARM) program. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;47:1997&#x2013;2004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16697316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mamas MA, Caldwell JC, Chacko S, Garratt CJ, Fath-Ordoubadi F, Neyses L. A meta-analysis of the prognostic significance of atrial fibrillation in chronic heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. 2009;11:676&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19553398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed A, Thornton P, Perry GJ, Allman RM, DeLong JF. Impact of atrial fibrillation on mortality and readmission in older adults hospitalized with heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. 2004;6:421&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15182766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell JC, Contractor H, Petkar S, Ali R, Clarke B, Garratt CJ, Neyses L, Mamas MA. Atrial fibrillation is under-recognized in chronic heart failure: insights from a heart failure cohort treated with cardiac resynchronization therapy. Europace. 2009;11:1295&#x2013;1300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19648586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf8;ber L, Swedberg K, McMurray JJ, Pfeffer MA, Velazquez EJ, Diaz R, Maggioni AP, Mareev V, Opolski G, Van de Werf F, et al. Previously known and newly diagnosed atrial fibrillation: a major risk indicator after a myocardial infarction complicated by heart failure or left ventricular dysfunction. Eur J Heart Fail. 2006;8:591&#x2013;598.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16507350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen OD, S&#xf8;ndergaard P, Nielsen T, Nielsen SJ, Nielsen ES, Falstie-Jensen N, Nielsen I, K&#xf8;ber L, Burchardt H, Seibaek M, et al. Atrial fibrillation, ischaemic heart disease, and the risk of death in patients with heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2006;27:2866&#x2013;2870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17101637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Range FT, Sch&#xe4;fers M, Acil T, Sch&#xe4;fers KP, Kies P, Paul M, Hermann S, Brisse B, Breithardt G, Schober O, et al. Impaired myocardial perfusion and perfusion reserve associated with increased coronary resistance in persistent idiopathic atrial fibrillation. Eur Heart J. 2007;28:2223&#x2013;2230.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17604290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauns&#xf8; J, Pedersen OD, Dominguez H, Hansen ML, M&#xf8;ller JE, Kjaergaard J, Hassager C, Torp-Pedersen C, K&#xf8;ber L. Atrial fibrillation in heart failure is associated with an increased risk of death only in patients with ischaemic heart disease. Eur J Heart Fail. 2010;12:692&#x2013;697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20403817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamberlain AM, Redfield MM, Alonso A, Weston SA, Roger VL. Atrial fibrillation and mortality in heart failure: a community study. Circ Heart Fail. 2011;4:740&#x2013;746.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3222889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21920917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smit MD, Moes ML, Maass AH, Achekar ID, Van Geel PP, Hillege HL, van Veldhuisen DJ, Van Gelder IC. The importance of whether atrial fibrillation or heart failure develops first. Eur J Heart Fail. 2012;14:1030&#x2013;1040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22733981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus DD, Saczynski JS, Lessard D, Kinno M, Pidikiti R, Esa N, Harrington J, Goldberg RJ. Recent trends in the incidence, treatment, and prognosis of patients with heart failure and atrial fibrillation (the Worcester Heart Failure Study) Am J Cardiol. 2013;111:1460&#x2013;1465.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4127486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23465093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahoney P, Kimmel S, DeNofrio D, Wahl P, Loh E. Prognostic significance of atrial fibrillation in patients at a tertiary medical center referred for heart transplantation because of severe heart failure. Am J Cardiol. 1999;83:1544&#x2013;1547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10363868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swedberg K, Olsson LG, Charlesworth A, Cleland J, Hanrath P, Komajda M, Metra M, Torp-Pedersen C, Poole-Wilson P. Prognostic relevance of atrial fibrillation in patients with chronic heart failure on long-term treatment with beta-blockers: results from COMET. Eur Heart J. 2005;26:1303&#x2013;1308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15767288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang TJ, Larson MG, Levy D, Vasan RS, Leip EP, Wolf PA, D&#x2019;Agostino RB, Murabito JM, Kannel WB, Benjamin EJ. Temporal relations of atrial fibrillation and congestive heart failure and their joint influence on mortality: the Framingham Heart Study. Circulation. 2003;107:2920&#x2013;2925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12771006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieuwlaat R, Eurlings LW, Cleland JG, Cobbe SM, Vardas PE, Capucci A, L&#xf3;pez-Send&#xf2;n JL, Meeder JG, Pinto YM, Crijns HJ. Atrial fibrillation and heart failure in cardiology practice: reciprocal impact and combined management from the perspective of atrial fibrillation: results of the Euro Heart Survey on atrial fibrillation. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009;53:1690&#x2013;1698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19406345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray JJ, Adamopoulos S, Anker SD, Auricchio A, B&#xf6;hm M, Dickstein K, Falk V, Filippatos G, Fonseca C, Gomez-Sanchez MA, et al. ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure 2012: The Task Force for the Diagnosis and Treatment of Acute and Chronic Heart Failure 2012 of the European Society of Cardiology. Developed in collaboration with the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur Heart J. 2012;33:1787&#x2013;1847.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22611136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joglar JA, Acusta AP, Shusterman NH, Ramaswamy K, Kowal RC, Barbera SJ, Hamdan MH, Page RL. Effect of carvedilol on survival and hemodynamics in patients with atrial fibrillation and left ventricular dysfunction: retrospective analysis of the US Carvedilol Heart Failure Trials Program. Am Heart J. 2001;142:498&#x2013;501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11526364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effect of digoxin on mortality and morbidity in patients with heart failure. The Digitalis Investigation Group. N Engl J Med. 1997;336:525&#x2013;533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9036306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitbeck MG, Charnigo RJ, Khairy P, Ziada K, Bailey AL, Zegarra MM, Shah J, Morales G, Macaulay T, Sorrell VL, et al. Increased mortality among patients taking digoxin--analysis from the AFFIRM study. Eur Heart J. 2013;34:1481&#x2013;1488.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23186806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gheorghiade M, Fonarow GC, van Veldhuisen DJ, Cleland JG, Butler J, Epstein AE, Patel K, Aban IB, Aronow WS, Anker SD, et al. Lack of evidence of increased mortality among patients with atrial fibrillation taking digoxin: findings from post hoc propensity-matched analysis of the AFFIRM trial. Eur Heart J. 2013;34:1489&#x2013;1497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3659306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23592708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heywood JT. Calcium channel blockers for heart rate control in atrial fibrillation complicated by congestive heart failure. Can J Cardiol. 1995;11:823&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7585281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Setaro JF, Zaret BL, Schulman DS, Black HR, Soufer R. Usefulness of verapamil for congestive heart failure associated with abnormal left ventricular diastolic filling and normal left ventricular systolic performance. Am J Cardiol. 1990;66:981&#x2013;986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2220622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstein RE, Boccuzzi SJ, Cruess D, Nattel S. Diltiazem increases late-onset congestive heart failure in postinfarction patients with early reduction in ejection fraction. The Adverse Experience Committee; and the Multicenter Diltiazem Postinfarction Research Group. Circulation. 1991;83:52&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1984898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gelder IC, Groenveld HF, Crijns HJ, Tuininga YS, Tijssen JG, Alings AM, Hillege HL, Bergsma-Kadijk JA, Cornel JH, Kamp O, et al. Lenient versus strict rate control in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2010;362:1363&#x2013;1373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20231232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gelder IC, Smit MD, Alings M, Crijns HJ. Upstream therapy in patients with early atrial fibrillation: The relevance of the Routine versus Aggressive upstream rhythm Control for prevention of Early atrial fibrillation in heart failure (RACE 3) study. Neth Heart J. 2010;18:522&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2989488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21113375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deedwania PC, Singh BN, Ellenbogen K, Fisher S, Fletcher R, Singh SN. Spontaneous conversion and maintenance of sinus rhythm by amiodarone in patients with heart failure and atrial fibrillation: observations from the veterans affairs congestive heart failure survival trial of antiarrhythmic therapy (CHF-STAT). The Department of Veterans Affairs CHF-STAT Investigators. Circulation. 1998;98:2574&#x2013;2579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9843465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy D, Talajic M, Nattel S, Wyse DG, Dorian P, Lee KL, Bourassa MG, Arnold JM, Buxton AE, Camm AJ, et al. Rhythm control versus rate control for atrial fibrillation and heart failure. N Engl J Med. 2008;358:2667&#x2013;2677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18565859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen OD, Bagger H, Keller N, Marchant B, K&#xf8;ber L, Torp-Pedersen C. Efficacy of dofetilide in the treatment of atrial fibrillation-flutter in patients with reduced left ventricular function: a Danish investigations of arrhythmia and mortality on dofetilide (diamond) substudy. Circulation. 2001;104:292&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11457747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohnloser SH, Crijns HJ, van Eickels M, Gaudin C, Page RL, Torp-Pedersen C, Connolly SJ. Dronedarone in patients with congestive heart failure: insights from ATHENA. Eur Heart J. 2010;31:1717&#x2013;1721.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2903712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20436046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf8;ber L, Torp-Pedersen C, McMurray JJ, G&#xf8;tzsche O, L&#xe9;vy S, Crijns H, Amlie J, Carlsen J. Increased mortality after dronedarone therapy for severe heart failure. N Engl J Med. 2008;358:2678&#x2013;2687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18565860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyse DG, Waldo AL, DiMarco JP, Domanski MJ, Rosenberg Y, Schron EB, Kellen JC, Greene HL, Mickel MC, Dalquist JE, et al. A comparison of rate control and rhythm control in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2002;347:1825&#x2013;1833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12466506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Gelder IC, Hagens VE, Bosker HA, Kingma JH, Kamp O, Kingma T, Said SA, Darmanata JI, Timmermans AJ, Tijssen JG, et al. A comparison of rate control and rhythm control in patients with recurrent persistent atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2002;347:1834&#x2013;1840.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12466507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohnloser SH, Kuck KH, Lilienthal J. Rhythm or rate control in atrial fibrillation--Pharmacological Intervention in Atrial Fibrillation (PIAF): a randomised trial. Lancet. 2000;356:1789&#x2013;1794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11117910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlsson J, Miketic S, Windeler J, Cuneo A, Haun S, Micus S, Walter S, Tebbe U. Randomized trial of rate-control versus rhythm-control in persistent atrial fibrillation: the Strategies of Treatment of Atrial Fibrillation (STAF) study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2003;41:1690&#x2013;1696.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12767648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guglin M, Chen R, Curtis AB. Sinus rhythm is associated with fewer heart failure symptoms: insights from the AFFIRM trial. Heart Rhythm. 2010;7:596&#x2013;601.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20159046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldeira D, David C, Sampaio C. Rate vs rhythm control in patients with atrial fibrillation and heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Eur J Intern Med. 2011;22:448&#x2013;455.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21925051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasmer K, Eckardt L. Management of atrial fibrillation around the world: a comparison of current ACCF/AHA/HRS, CCS, and ESC guidelines. Europace. 2011;13:1368&#x2013;1374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21712281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamara RL, Tamariz LJ, Segal JB, Bass EB. Management of atrial fibrillation: review of the evidence for the role of pharmacologic therapy, electrical cardioversion, and echocardiography. Ann Intern Med. 2003;139:1018&#x2013;1033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14678922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart RG, Pearce LA, Aguilar MI. Meta-analysis: antithrombotic therapy to prevent stroke in patients who have nonvalvular atrial fibrillation. Ann Intern Med. 2007;146:857&#x2013;867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17577005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzeis S, Andrikopoulos G. Novel anticoagulants for atrial fibrillation: a critical appraisal. Angiology. 2012;63:164&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22007032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Connolly SJ, Ezekowitz MD, Yusuf S, Eikelboom J, Oldgren J, Parekh A, Pogue J, Reilly PA, Themeles E, Varrone J, et al. Dabigatran versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2009;361:1139&#x2013;1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19717844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camm AJ, Kirchhof P, Lip GY, Schotten U, Savelieva I, Ernst S, Van Gelder IC, Al-Attar N, Hindricks G, Prendergast B, et al. Guidelines for the management of atrial fibrillation: the Task Force for the Management of Atrial Fibrillation of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) Europace. 2010;12:1360&#x2013;1420.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20876603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson JL, Halperin JL, Albert NM, Bozkurt B, Brindis RG, Curtis LH, DeMets D, Guyton RA, Hochman JS, Kovacs RJ, et al. Management of patients with atrial fibrillation (compilation of 2006 ACCF/AHA/ESC and 2011 ACCF/AHA/HRS recommendations): a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2013;61:1935&#x2013;1944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23558044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cairns JA, Connolly S, McMurtry S, Stephenson M, Talajic M. Canadian Cardiovascular Society atrial fibrillation guidelines 2010: prevention of stroke and systemic thromboembolism in atrial fibrillation and flutter. Can J Cardiol. 2011;27:74&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21329865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel MR, Mahaffey KW, Garg J, Pan G, Singer DE, Hacke W, Breithardt G, Halperin JL, Hankey GJ, Piccini JP, et al. Rivaroxaban versus warfarin in nonvalvular atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2011;365:883&#x2013;891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21830957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes RD, Alexander JH, Al-Khatib SM, Ansell J, Diaz R, Easton JD, Gersh BJ, Granger CB, Hanna M, Horowitz J, et al. Apixaban for reduction in stroke and other ThromboemboLic events in atrial fibrillation (ARISTOTLE) trial: design and rationale. Am Heart J. 2010;159:331&#x2013;339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20211292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurita T, Motoki K, Yasuoka R, Hirota T, Akaiwa Y, Kotake Y, Miyazaki S. Rhythm control should be better for the management of patients with atrial fibrillation and heart failure--rhythm control vs. rate control: which is better in the management of atrial fibrillation? (Rhythm-side) Circ J. 2011;75:979&#x2013;985.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21415549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon AR, Greenberg JM, Kanuru N, Baker CM, Mera FV, Smith AL, Langberg JJ, DeLurgio DB. Cardiac resynchronization in patients with congestive heart failure and chronic atrial fibrillation: effect of upgrading to biventricular pacing after chronic right ventricular pacing. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2002;39:1258&#x2013;1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11955841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valls-Bertault V, Fatemi M, Gilard M, Pennec PY, Etienne Y, Blanc JJ. Assessment of upgrading to biventricular pacing in patients with right ventricular pacing and congestive heart failure after atrioventricular junctional ablation for chronic atrial fibrillation. Europace. 2004;6:438&#x2013;443.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15294269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilton SB, Leung AA, Ghali WA, Faris P, Exner DV. Outcomes of cardiac resynchronization therapy in patients with versus those without atrial fibrillation: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Heart Rhythm. 2011;8:1088&#x2013;1094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21338711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linde C, Braunschweig F, Gadler F, Bailleul C, Daubert JC. Long-term improvements in quality of life by biventricular pacing in patients with chronic heart failure: results from the Multisite Stimulation in Cardiomyopathy study (MUSTIC) Am J Cardiol. 2003;91:1090&#x2013;1095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12714152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brignole M, Gammage M, Puggioni E, Alboni P, Raviele A, Sutton R, Vardas P, Bongiorni MG, Bergfeldt L, Menozzi C, et al. Comparative assessment of right, left, and biventricular pacing in patients with permanent atrial fibrillation. Eur Heart J. 2005;26:712&#x2013;722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15618036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luedorff G, Grove R, Kowalski M, Wolff E, Thale J, Kranig W. Impact of chronic atrial fibrillation in patients with severe heart failure and indication for CRT: data of two registries with 711 patients (1999-2006 and 2007-6/2008) Herzschrittmacherther Elektrophysiol. 2011;22:226&#x2013;232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22160274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu LF, Ja&#xef;s P, Sanders P, Garrigue S, Hocini M, Sacher F, Takahashi Y, Rotter M, Pasqui&#xe9; JL, Scav&#xe9;e C, et al. Catheter ablation for atrial fibrillation in congestive heart failure. N Engl J Med. 2004;351:2373&#x2013;2383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15575053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tondo C, Mantica M, Russo G, Avella A, De Luca L, Pappalardo A, Fagundes RL, Picchio E, Laurenzi F, Piazza V, et al. Pulmonary vein vestibule ablation for the control of atrial fibrillation in patients with impaired left ventricular function. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 2006;29:962&#x2013;970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen MS, Marrouche NF, Khaykin Y, Gillinov AM, Wazni O, Martin DO, Rossillo A, Verma A, Cummings J, Erciyes D, et al. Pulmonary vein isolation for the treatment of atrial fibrillation in patients with impaired systolic function. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;43:1004&#x2013;1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15028358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentlesk PJ, Sauer WH, Gerstenfeld EP, Lin D, Dixit S, Zado E, Callans D, Marchlinski FE. Reversal of left ventricular dysfunction following ablation of atrial fibrillation. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2007;18:9&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17081210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MN, Ja&#xef;s P, Cummings J, Di Biase L, Sanders P, Martin DO, Kautzner J, Hao S, Themistoclakis S, Fanelli R, et al. Pulmonary-vein isolation for atrial fibrillation in patients with heart failure. N Engl J Med. 2008;359:1778&#x2013;1785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18946063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacDonald MR, Connelly DT, Hawkins NM, Steedman T, Payne J, Shaw M, Denvir M, Bhagra S, Small S, Martin W, et al. Radiofrequency ablation for persistent atrial fibrillation in patients with advanced heart failure and severe left ventricular systolic dysfunction: a randomised controlled trial. Heart. 2011;97:740&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21051458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagres N, Varounis C, Gaspar T, Piorkowski C, Eitel C, Iliodromitis EK, Lekakis JP, Flevari P, Simeonidou E, Rallidis LS, et al. Catheter ablation for atrial fibrillation in patients with left ventricular systolic dysfunction. A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Card Fail. 2011;17:964&#x2013;970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22041335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khargi K, Hutten BA, Lemke B, Deneke T. Surgical treatment of atrial fibrillation; a systematic review. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2005;27:258&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15691679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ad N, Henry L, Hunt S. The impact of surgical ablation in patients with low ejection fraction, heart failure, and atrial fibrillation. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2011;40:70&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21169029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallick DW, Zhang Y, Tabata T, Zhuang S, Mowrey KA, Watanabe J, Greenberg NL, Grimm RA, Mazgalev TN. Selective AV nodal vagal stimulation improves hemodynamics during acute atrial fibrillation in dogs. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2001;281:H1490&#x2013;H1497.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11557537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Yamada H, Bibevski S, Zhuang S, Mowrey KA, Wallick DW, Oh S, Mazgalev TN. Chronic atrioventricular nodal vagal stimulation: first evidence for long-term ventricular rate control in canine atrial fibrillation model. Circulation. 2005;112:2904&#x2013;2911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schauerte P, Mischke K, Plisiene J, Waldmann M, Zarse M, Stellbrink C, Schimpf T, Knackstedt C, Sinha A, Hanrath P. Catheter stimulation of cardiac parasympathetic nerves in humans: a novel approach to the cardiac autonomic nervous system. Circulation. 2001;104:2430&#x2013;2435.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11705820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobrev D, Nattel S. New antiarrhythmic drugs for treatment of atrial fibrillation. Lancet. 2010;375:1212&#x2013;1223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20334907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian D, Frishman WH. Vernakalant: a new drug to treat patients with acute onset atrial fibrillation. Cardiol Rev. 2011;19:41&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21135602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camm AJ, Capucci A, Hohnloser SH, Torp-Pedersen C, Van Gelder IC, Mangal B, Beatch G. A randomized active-controlled study comparing the efficacy and safety of vernakalant to amiodarone in recent-onset atrial fibrillation. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;57:313&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21232669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackshear JL, Odell JA. Appendage obliteration to reduce stroke in cardiac surgical patients with atrial fibrillation. Ann Thorac Surg. 1996;61:755&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8572814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewalter T, Ibrahim R, Albers B, Camm AJ. An update and current expert opinions on percutaneous left atrial appendage occlusion for stroke prevention in atrial fibrillation. Europace. 2013;15:652&#x2013;656.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23625943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes DR, Reddy VY, Turi ZG, Doshi SK, Sievert H, Buchbinder M, Mullin CM, Sick P. Percutaneous closure of the left atrial appendage versus warfarin therapy for prevention of stroke in patients with atrial fibrillation: a randomised non-inferiority trial. Lancet. 2009;374:534&#x2013;542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19683639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reddy VY, Holmes D, Doshi SK, Neuzil P, Kar S. Safety of percutaneous left atrial appendage closure: results from the Watchman Left Atrial Appendage System for Embolic Protection in Patients with AF (PROTECT AF) clinical trial and the Continued Access Registry. Circulation. 2011;123:417&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21242484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swaans MJ, Post MC, Rensing BJ, Boersma LV. Ablation for atrial fibrillation in combination with left atrial appendage closure: first results of a feasibility study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2012;1:e002212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3541623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23316289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel TK, Yancy CW, Knight BP. Left atrial appendage exclusion for stroke prevention in atrial fibrillation. Cardiol Res Pract. 2012;2012:610827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3480004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23119222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellinor PT, Lunetta KL, Albert CM, Glazer NL, Ritchie MD, Smith AV, Arking DE, M&#xfc;ller-Nurasyid M, Krijthe BP, Lubitz SA, et al. Meta-analysis identifies six new susceptibility loci for atrial fibrillation. Nat Genet. 2012;44:670&#x2013;675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3366038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22544366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JG, Melander O, Sj&#xf6;gren M, Hedblad B, Engstr&#xf6;m G, Newton-Cheh C, Platonov PG. Genetic polymorphisms confer risk of atrial fibrillation in patients with heart failure: a population-based study. Eur J Heart Fail. 2013;15:250&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3576900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23132824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nascimento BC, Pereira SB, Ribeiro GS, Mesquita ET. Beta1-adrenergic receptor polymorphisms associated with atrial fibrillation in systolic heart failure. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2012;98:384&#x2013;389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22499333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu WN, Fu KL, Gao HY, Shang YY, Wang ZH, Jiang GH, Zhang Y, Zhang W, Zhong M. &#x3b2;1 adrenergic receptor polymorphisms and heart failure: a meta-analysis on susceptibility, response to &#x3b2;-blocker therapy and prognosis. PLoS One. 2012;7:e37659.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3398943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22815685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savelieva I, Camm AJ. Polyunsaturated fatty acids for prevention of atrial fibrillation: a &#x2018;fishy&#x2019; story. Europace. 2011;13:149&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21252194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savelieva I, Camm AJ. Statins and atrial fibrillation: do we need a further study? Expert Rev Cardiovasc Ther. 2011;9:801&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21809959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savelieva I, Kakouros N, Kourliouros A, Camm AJ. Upstream therapies for management of atrial fibrillation: review of clinical evidence and implications for European Society of Cardiology guidelines. Part I: primary prevention. Europace. 2011;13:308&#x2013;328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21345926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savelieva I, Kakouros N, Kourliouros A, Camm AJ. Upstream therapies for management of atrial fibrillation: review of clinical evidence and implications for European Society of Cardiology guidelines. Part II: secondary prevention. Europace. 2011;13:610&#x2013;625.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21515595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhuriya R, Singh M, Sethi A, Molnar J, Bahekar A, Singh PP, Khosla S, Arora R. Prevention of recurrent atrial fibrillation with angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors or angiotensin receptor blockers: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized trials. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther. 2011;16:178&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21285399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson PE, Johnson GR, Dunkman WB, Fletcher RD, Farrell L, Cohn JN. The influence of atrial fibrillation on prognosis in mild to moderate heart failure. The V-HeFT Studies. The V-HeFT VA Cooperative Studies Group. Circulation. 1993;87:VI102&#x2013;VI110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8500233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathew J, Hunsberger S, Fleg J, Mc Sherry F, Williford W, Yusuf S. Incidence, predictive factors, and prognostic significance of supraventricular tachyarrhythmias in congestive heart failure. Chest. 2000;118:914&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11035656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crijns HJ, Tjeerdsma G, de Kam PJ, Boomsma F, van Gelder IC, van den Berg MP, van Veldhuisen DJ. Prognostic value of the presence and development of atrial fibrillation in patients with advanced chronic heart failure. Eur Heart J. 2000;21:1238&#x2013;1245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10924313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen OD, Brendorp B, K&#xf8;ber L, Torp-Pedersen C. Prevalence, prognostic significance, and treatment of atrial fibrillation in congestive heart failure with particular reference to the DIAMOND-CHF study. Congest Heart Fail. 2003;9:333&#x2013;340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14688506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middlekauff HR, Stevenson WG, Stevenson LW. Prognostic significance of atrial fibrillation in advanced heart failure. A study of 390 patients. Circulation. 1991;84:40&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2060110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevenson WG, Stevenson LW, Middlekauff HR, Fonarow GC, Hamilton MA, Woo MA, Saxon LA, Natterson PD, Steimle A, Walden JA, et al. Improving survival for patients with atrial fibrillation and advanced heart failure. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1996;28:1458&#x2013;1463.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8917258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojtkowska I, Sobkowicz B, Musia&#x142; WJ, Kozuch M. Persistent atrial fibrillation as a prognostic factor of outcome in patients with advanced heart failure. Kardiol Pol. 2006;64:777&#x2013;783; discussion 784-785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corell P, Gustafsson F, Schou M, Markenvard J, Nielsen T, Hildebrandt P. Prevalence and prognostic significance of atrial fibrillation in outpatients with heart failure due to left ventricular systolic dysfunction. Eur J Heart Fail. 2007;9:258&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17027330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pai RG, Varadarajan P. Prognostic significance of atrial fibrillation is a function of left ventricular ejection fraction. Clin Cardiol. 2007;30:349&#x2013;354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6653692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17674374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusinaru D, Leborgne L, Peltier M, Tribouilloy C. Effect of atrial fibrillation on long-term survival in patients hospitalised for heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. Eur J Heart Fail. 2008;10:566&#x2013;572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18456551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamaguchi S, Yokoshiki H, Kinugawa S, Tsuchihashi-Makaya M, Yokota T, Takeshita A, Tsutsui H. Effects of atrial fibrillation on long-term outcomes in patients hospitalized for heart failure in Japan: a report from the Japanese Cardiac Registry of Heart Failure in Cardiology (JCARE-CARD) Circ J. 2009;73:2084&#x2013;2090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19755750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shotan A, Garty M, Blondhein DS, Meisel SR, Lewis BS, Shochat M, Grossman E, Porath A, Boyko V, Zimlichman R, et al. Atrial fibrillation and long-term prognosis in patients hospitalized for heart failure: results from heart failure survey in Israel (HFSIS) Eur Heart J. 2010;31:309&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19837682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>