<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37569000</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1660-4601</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>15</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of environmental research and public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Environ Res Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exploring the Evidence for the Paradigms of Recovery and Social Work Converging in Mental Health Service Delivery Worldwide: Reflections from an Irish Case Study.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">6460</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ijerph20156460</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recovery within mental health service delivery is no longer a new consideration in the Western world. However, it is well-documented how challenging its implementation and translation to practice and reality have been in contemporary mental health systems. In conjunction with this, mental health social work is continuously being challenged and debated in relation to its role, responsibilities, and identity in service delivery. This is largely the consequence of the continued dominance of the biomedical model in relation to service delivery. Yet, if we critically reflect on the philosophy and ethos of recovery, it becomes very clear that social work should be the key profession to lead the development and improvement of recovery-orientated services across the globe. To illustrate this argument, the authors first draw on empirical research undertaken by the lead author within the Republic of Ireland on how recovery is socially constructed within mental health service delivery. The key stakeholders involved in the Irish study included professionals, service users, family members, and policy influencers, with participants taking part in semi-structured interviews. Secondly, the authors reflect on some of the findings from this Irish study, presenting an argument for not only a more significant role for social work in an Irish mental health context but also making comparisons from an international perspective. This includes exploring the role of critical social work traditions for supporting services to move beyond a philosophy of recovery that has, to date, overlooked the intersectional injustices and inequalities faced by hard-to-reach populations. Finally, the authors conclude by providing some possibilities for how the paradigms of social work and recovery can and should continue to converge towards each other, opening a space for social work to become a more dominant perspective within mental health systems worldwide.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Swords</LastName><ForeName>Calvin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8392-2868</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Social Studies, National University of Ireland, W23F2H6 Maynooth, Ireland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Houston</LastName><ForeName>Stan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Social Sciences, Education and Social Work, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT71HL, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Environ Res Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101238455</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1660-4601</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008605" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mental Health Services</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007494" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Ireland</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012947" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Work</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005190" MajorTopicYN="N">Family</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D036262" MajorTopicYN="N">Empirical Research</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">critical social work</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health services</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neoliberalism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recovery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social constructionism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social work</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest. The funders had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of the data; in the writing of the manuscript; or in the decision to publish the results.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37569000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10418325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20156460</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijerph20156460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Deegan P. Recovery: The lived experience of rehabilitation. Psychosoc. Rehabil. J. 1988;11:11&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1037/h0099565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0099565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swords C. Recovery and Co-Production: Understanding the Diverging Paradigms and Potential Implications for Social Workers. Ir. Soc. Work. 2019;2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swords C., Houston S. Exploring the Concept of Recovery in Irish Mental Health Services: A Case Study of Perspectives within an Inter-Professional Team.  [(accessed on 24 March 2023)];Ir. J. Appl. Soc. Stud. 2020 20:4. Available online:  https://arrow.tudublin.ie/ijass/vol20/iss1/4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton M.J., Swords C. Social Recovery: A New Interpretation to Recovery-Orientated Services&#x2014;A Critical Literature Review. J. Ment. Health Train. Educ. Pract. 2020;16:7&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1108/JMHTEP-06-2020-0035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JMHTEP-06-2020-0035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramon S., Shera W., Healy B., Lachman M., Renouf N. The Rediscovered Concept of Recovery in Mental Illness: A Multicountry Comparison of Policy and Practice. Int. J. Ment. Health. 2009;38:106&#x2013;126. doi: 10.2753/IMH0020-7411380205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2753/IMH0020-7411380205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilgrim D. &#x201c;Recovery&#x201d; and Current Mental Health Policy. Chronic Illn. 2008;4:295&#x2013;304. doi: 10.1177/1742395308097863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1742395308097863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19091938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramon S. The Place of Social Recovery in Mental Health and Related Services. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health. 2018;15:1052. doi: 10.3390/ijerph15061052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph15061052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6025044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29789511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade M., Longden E. Empirical Evidence about recovery and mental health. BMC Psychiatry. 2015;15:285. doi: 10.1186/s12888-015-0678-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-015-0678-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4647297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilgrim D., McCranie A. Recovery and Mental Health: A Critical Sociological Account. 1st ed. Palgrave Macmillan; Hampshire, UK: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pilgrim D. Co-Production and Involuntary Psychiatric Settings. Ment. Health Rev. J. 2018;23:269&#x2013;279. doi: 10.1108/MHRJ-05-2018-0012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/MHRJ-05-2018-0012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crepaz-Keay D. Improving Mental Health in Later Life: The Role of Service User Involvement. Qual. Ageing Older Adults. 2016;17:179&#x2013;188. doi: 10.1108/QAOA-09-2015-0043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/QAOA-09-2015-0043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony W.A. Recovery from Mental Illness: The Guiding Vision of the Mental Health Service System in the 1990s. Psychosoc. Rehabil. J. 1993;16:11&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1037/h0095655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0095655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brosnan L., Sapouna L. Opportunities for Social Workers&#x2019; Critical Engagement in Mental Health Care. In: Christie A., Featherstone B., Quin S., Walsh T., editors. Social Work in Ireland Changes and Continuities. Palgrave; London, UK: 2015. pp. 159&#x2013;178.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaffey K.D., Evans S., Walsh F. Knowledge and Attitudes of Irish Mental Health Professionals to the Concept of Recovery from Mental Illness&#x2014;Five Years Later. J. Psychiatr. Ment. Health Nurs. 2016;23:387&#x2013;398. doi: 10.1111/jpm.12325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jpm.12325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27440748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moth R. &#x201c;The Business End&#x201d;: Neoliberal Policy Reforms and Biomedical Residualism in Frontline Community Mental Health Practice in England. Compet. Chang. 2020;24:133&#x2013;153. doi: 10.1177/1024529418813833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1024529418813833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swords C., Houston S. Using Social Constructionism to Research the Recovery Movement in Mental Health in Ireland: A Critical Reflection on Meta-Theory Shaping the Inquiry.  [(accessed on 20 March 2023)];Ir. J. Appl. Soc. Stud. 2021 21:5. Available online:  https://arrow.tudublin.ie/ijass/vol21/iss1/5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey P.D., Bellack A.S. Toward a Terminology for Functional Recovery in Schizophrenia: Is Functional Remission a Viable Concept? Schizophr. Bull. 2009;35:300&#x2013;306. doi: 10.1093/schbul/sbn171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sbn171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2659311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leamy M., Bird V., Le Boutillier C., Williams J., Slade M. Conceptual Framework for Personal Recovery in Mental Health: A Systematic Review and Narrative Synthesis. Br. J. Psychiatry. 2011;199:445&#x2013;452. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.110.083733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.110.083733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22130746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swords C., Houston S. The &#x201c;Social&#x201d; Can Really Work in Mental Health Social Work: A Critical Review of How the Understanding of Recovery Has Evolved and Converged towards the Skillset of Social Work. Ir. Soc. Work. 2021:234&#x2013;245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sen R., Kerr C., MacIntyre G., Featherstone B., Gupta A., Quinn-Aziz A. Social Work under COVID-19: A Thematic Analysis of Articles in &#x201c;SW2020 under COVID-19 Magazine&#x201d;. Br. J. Soc. Work. 2021;52:1765&#x2013;1782. doi: 10.1093/bjsw/bcab094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjsw/bcab094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brosnan L. Service-User Involvement in Irish Mental Health Services: A Sociological Analysis of Inherent Tensions for Service-Users, Service-Providers and Social Movement Actors. 2013.  [(accessed on 28 March 2023)].  Available online:  https://ulir.ul.ie/handle/10344/4683.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S.A., Nolan M., Ryan M., Williams J., Fannon D. Delivering Recovery Focused Mental Health Care in Ireland: Implications for Services and Practice Development. Ir. J. Psychol. Med. 2016;33:121&#x2013;128. doi: 10.1017/ipm.2014.75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/ipm.2014.75</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30115137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casey B., Webb M. Imaging Journeys of Recovery and Learning: A Participatory Arts-Based Inquiry. Qual. Health Res. 2019;29:833&#x2013;845. doi: 10.1177/1049732318804832.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732318804832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30340448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford S.-B., Bowyer T., Morgan P. The Experience of Compulsory Treatment: The Implications for Recovery-Orientated Practice? Ment. Health Soc. Incl. 2015;19:126&#x2013;132. doi: 10.1108/MHSI-05-2015-0017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/MHSI-05-2015-0017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger P., Luckmann T. The Social Construction of Reality: A Treatise in the Sociology of Knowledge. Penguin Group; New York, NY, USA: 1966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burr V. Social Constructionism. 3rd ed. Routledge; London, UK: New York, NY, USA: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gergen K.J. An Invitation to Social Constructionism. 2nd ed. Sage Publications; London, UK: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Reilly M., Lester J.N. Examining Mental Health through Social Constructionism: The Language of Mental Health. Palgrave Macmillan; Cham, Switzerland: 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews T. What Is Social Constructionism? Grounded Theory Rev. 2012;11:9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen K., Praestegaard J., Holen M. The Conditions of Possibilities for Recovery: A Critical Discourse Analysis in a Danish Psychiatric Context. J. Clin. Nurs. 2020;29:3012&#x2013;3024. doi: 10.1111/jocn.15311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.15311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32353905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chowdhury M.F. Interpretivism in Aiding Our Understanding of the Contemporary Social World. Open J. Philos. 2014;4:432&#x2013;438. doi: 10.4236/ojpp.2014.43047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4236/ojpp.2014.43047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryman A. Social Research Methods. 4th ed. Oxford University Press; New York, NY, USA: 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanh N.C., Tran T.L.T. The Interconnection Between Interpretivist Paradigm and Qualitative Methods in Education. Am. J. Educ. Sci. 2015;1:24&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hancock D.R., Algozzine B. Doing Case Study Research: A Practical Guide for Beginning Researchers. Teachers College Press; New York, NY, USA: 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robson C., McCartan K. Real World Research: A Resource for Users of Social Research Methods in Applied Settings. 4th ed. John Wiley and Sons Ltd.; West Sussex, UK: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovell T., Gardner-Elahi C., Callanan M. &#x201c;My Journey through the System&#x201d;: A Grounded Theory of Service User-Perceived Experiences of Recovery in Forensic Mental Health Services. J. Forensic Psychiatry Psychol. 2020;31:292&#x2013;310. doi: 10.1080/14789949.2020.1725591.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14789949.2020.1725591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meiring L., Visser M., Themistocleous N. A Student-Facilitated Community-Based Support Group Initiative for Mental Health Care Users in a Primary Health Care Setting. Health SA Gesondheid. 2017;22:307&#x2013;315. doi: 10.1016/j.hsag.2017.04.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.hsag.2017.04.004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd8;rjas&#xe6; T., Berre K., Stickley T., Hedlund M., Ness O. Transforming Identity through Participation in Music and Theatre: Exploring Narratives of People with Mental Health Problems. Int. J. Qual. Stud. Health Well-Being. 2017;12:1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1080/17482631.2017.1379339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17482631.2017.1379339</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5654009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28956505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yin R.K. Case Study Research and Applications. 6th ed. SAGE Publications, Inc.; London, UK: 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V., Clarke V. Successful Qualitative Research: A Practical Guide for Beginners. 1st ed. Sage Publications; London, UK: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willig C. Introducing Qualitative Research in Psychology. Open University Press; Berkshire, UK: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V., Clarke V. Can I Use TA? Should I Use TA? Should I Not Use TA? Comparing Reflexive Thematic Analysis and Other Pattern-Based Qualitative Analytic Approaches. Couns. Psychother. Res. 2021;21:37&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1002/capr.12360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/capr.12360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madsen A.K.W. Ph.D. Thesis. University of Copenhagen; Copenhagen, Denmark: 2018. Recovery Orientation in Clinical Practice: How Does It Unfold in Mental Health Inpatient Settings?</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McWade B. Recovery-as-Policy as a Form of Neoliberal State Making. Intersect. Glob. J. Soc. Work. Anal. Res. Polity Pract. 2016;5:62&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogowski S. Theoretical Research: Neoliberalism and Social Work with Children and Families in the UK: On-Going Challenges and Critical Possibilities. Aotearoa N. Z. Soc. Work. 2018;30:72&#x2013;83. doi: 10.11157/anzswj-vol30iss3id519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11157/anzswj-vol30iss3id519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swords C. Why the Conversation around Mental Health Can Be Misleading.  [(accessed on 12 July 2023)].  Available online:  https://www.rte.ie/brainstorm/2022/1107/1333676-mental-health-illness-narrative-stigma-isolation/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pease B. Doing Critical Social Work: Transformative Practices for Social Justice. Routledge; London, UK: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toft J., Lightfoot E.B., Calhoun M., Choy-Brown M., Merighi J.R., Renner L.M., Soffer-Elnekave R., Mendel J., Marsalis S. Effects of Neoliberalism on Social Work Practice in the United States: A Scoping Review. Soc. Work Res. 2023;47:99&#x2013;110. doi: 10.1093/swr/svad003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/swr/svad003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee S.S., Malathesh Barikar C., Mukherjee A. Impact of COVID-19 Pandemic on Pre-Existing Mental Health Problems. Asian J. Psychiatry. 2020;51:102071. doi: 10.1016/j.ajp.2020.102071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajp.2020.102071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7165115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32334407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fook J. Social Work: A Critical Approach to Practice. 3rd ed. SAGE; London, UK: 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garrett P.M. Introduction to the Special Section on Dissent in Social Work. Aotearoa N. Z. Soc. Work. 2022;34:6&#x2013;7. doi: 10.11157/anzswj-vol34iss3id1001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11157/anzswj-vol34iss3id1001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Federation of Social Workers  Global Definition of Social Work.  [(accessed on 10 July 2023)].  Available online:  https://www.ifsw.org/what-is-social-work/global-definition-of-social-work/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swords C., Norton M.J. Individual recovery or collective recovery? Do we really consider both in current Irish mental health policy and provision? Ir. J. Psychol. Med. 2023;1:1&#x2013;2. doi: 10.1017/ipm.2023.25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/ipm.2023.25</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37259905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>