<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">34152272</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1438-8871</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jun</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical Internet research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Internet Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Comprehensive 6A Framework for Improving Patient Self-Management of Hypertension Using mHealth Services: Qualitative Thematic Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e25522</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e25522</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e25522</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/25522</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Hypertension affects over 15% of the world's population and is a significant global public health and socioeconomic challenge. Mobile health (mHealth) services have been increasingly introduced to support hypertensive patients to improve their self-management behaviors, such as adherence to pharmacotherapy and lifestyle modifications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This study aims to explore patients' perceptions of mHealth services and the mechanisms by which the services support them to self-manage their hypertension.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A semistructured, in-depth interview study was conducted with 22 outpatients of the General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University from March to May 2019. In 2015, the hospital introduced an mHealth service to support community-dwelling outpatients with self-management of hypertension. Content analysis was conducted by following a grounded theory approach for inductive thematic extraction. Constant comparison and categorization classified the first-level codes with similar meanings into higher-level themes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The patient-perceived mechanisms by which the mHealth service supported their self-management of hypertension were summarized as 6A: access, assessment, assistance, awareness, ability, and activation. With the portability of mobile phones and digitization of information, the mHealth service provided outpatients with easy access to assess their vital signs and self-management behaviors. The assessment results gave the patients real-time awareness of their health conditions and self-management performance, which activated their self-management behaviors. The mHealth service also gave outpatients access to assistance, which included health education and self-management reminders. Both types of assistance could also be activated by abnormal assessment results, that is, uncontrolled or deteriorating blood pressure values, discomfort symptoms, or not using the service for a long period. With its scalable use to handle any possible information and services, the mHealth service provided outpatients with educational materials to learn at their own pace. This led to an improvement in self-management awareness and ability, again activating their self-management behaviors. The patients would like to see further improvements in the service to provide more useful, personalized information and reliable services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">The mHealth service extended the traditional hypertension care model beyond the hospital and clinician's office. It provided outpatients with easy access to otherwise inaccessible hypertension management services. This led to process improvement for outpatients to access health assessment and health care assistance and improved their awareness and self-management ability, which activated their hypertension self-management behaviors. Future studies can apply the 6A framework to guide the design, implementation, and evaluation of mHealth services for outpatients to self-manage chronic conditions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Ting Song, Fang Liu, Ning Deng, Siyu Qian, Tingru Cui, Yingping Guan, Leonard Arnolda, Zhenyu Zhang, Ping Yu. Originally published in the Journal of Medical Internet Research (https://www.jmir.org), 21.06.2021.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Ting</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5858-6495</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Digital Transformation, School of Computing and Information Technology, Faculty of Engineering and Information Sciences, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Illawarra Health and Medical Research Institute, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Fang</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8579-5134</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Examination, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Deng</LastName><ForeName>Ning</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6573-1061</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Key Laboratory for Biomedical Engineering of Ministry of Education, College of Biomedical Engineering and Instrument Science, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qian</LastName><ForeName>Siyu</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1332-4800</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Digital Transformation, School of Computing and Information Technology, Faculty of Engineering and Information Sciences, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Illawarra Health and Medical Research Institute, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug and Alcohol Service, Illawarra Shoalhaven Local Health District, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cui</LastName><ForeName>Tingru</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7899-1372</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Computing and Information Systems, Faculty of Engineering and Information Technology, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guan</LastName><ForeName>Yingping</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8753-8844</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Examination, General Hospital of Ningxia Medical University, Yinchuan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arnolda</LastName><ForeName>Leonard</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8173-3318</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Illawarra Health and Medical Research Institute, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Zhenyu</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1853-4978</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Digital Transformation, School of Computing and Information Technology, Faculty of Engineering and Information Sciences, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Ping</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7910-9396</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Digital Transformation, School of Computing and Information Technology, Faculty of Engineering and Information Sciences, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Illawarra Health and Medical Research Institute, University of Wollongong, Wollongong, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Internet Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100959882</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1438-8871</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040421" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cell Phone</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006296" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Services</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073278" MajorTopicYN="Y">Self-Management</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic disease management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high blood pressure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile app</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile phone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient experience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-management</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34152272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/25522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v23i6e25522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Olsen MH, Angell SY, Asma S, Boutouyrie P, Burger D, Chirinos JA, Damasceno A, Delles C, Gimenez-Roqueplo A, Hering D, L&#xf3;pez-Jaramillo P, Martinez F, Perkovic V, Rietzschel ER, Schillaci G, Schutte AE, Scuteri A, Sharman JE, Wachtell K, Wang JG. A call to action and a lifecourse strategy to address the global burden of raised blood pressure on current and future generations: the Lancet Commission on hypertension. Lancet. 2016 Dec 26;388(10060):2665&#x2013;712. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)31134-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(16)31134-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27671667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hypertension. World Health Organization. 2021.  [2021-06-04].   https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/hypertension.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34370424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forouzanfar MH, Liu P, Roth GA, Ng M, Biryukov S, Marczak L, Alexander L, Estep K, Hassen AK, Akinyemiju TF, Ali R, Alvis-Guzman N, Azzopardi P, Banerjee A, B&#xe4;rnighausen T, Basu A, Bekele T, Bennett DA, Biadgilign S, Catal&#xe1;-L&#xf3;pez F, Feigin VL, Fernandes JC, Fischer F, Gebru AA, Gona P, Gupta R, Hankey GJ, Jonas JB, Judd SE, Khang Y, Khosravi A, Kim YJ, Kimokoti RW, Kokubo Y, Kolte D, Lopez A, Lotufo PA, Malekzadeh R, Melaku YA, Mensah GA, Misganaw A, Mokdad AH, Moran AE, Nawaz H, Neal B, Ngalesoni FN, Ohkubo T, Pourmalek F, Rafay A, Rai RK, Rojas-Rueda D, Sampson UK, Santos IS, Sawhney M, Schutte AE, Sepanlou SG, Shifa GT, Shiue I, Tedla BA, Thrift AG, Tonelli M, Truelsen T, Tsilimparis N, Ukwaja KN, Uthman OA, Vasankari T, Venketasubramanian N, Vlassov VV, Vos T, Westerman R, Yan LL, Yano Y, Yonemoto N, Zaki ME, Murray CJ. Global burden of hypertension and systolic blood pressure of at least 110 to 115 mm Hg, 1990-2015. J Am Med Assoc. 2017 Dec 10;317(2):165&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1001/jama.2016.19043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2016.19043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28097354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaziano TA, Bitton A, Anand S, Weinstein MC, International SO. The global cost of nonoptimal blood pressure. J Hypertens. 2009 Jul;27(7):1472&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1097/HJH.0b013e32832a9ba3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0b013e32832a9ba3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19474763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chobanian AV, Bakris GL, Black HR, Cushman WC, Green LA, Izzo JL, Jones DW, Materson BJ, Oparil S, Wright JT, Roccella EJ, Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure. National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute. National High Blood Pressure Education Program Coordinating Committee  Seventh report of the Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure. Hypertension. 2003 Dec;42(6):1206&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1161/01.HYP.0000107251.49515.c2.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.HYP.0000107251.49515.c2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14656957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magid DJ, Farmer SA. Hypertension self-management: a home run for patients and payers. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2014 Mar;7(2):205&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.114.000885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCOUTCOMES.114.000885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24619316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari F, Shahriari M, Sabouhi F, Khosravi-Farsani A, Eghbali-Babadi M. The effect of a lifestyle management educational program on blood pressure, heart rate, and body mass index in patients with hypertension. ARYA Atheroscler. 2020 Jan;16(1):7&#x2013;15. doi: 10.22122/arya.v16i1.1502.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22122/arya.v16i1.1502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7244792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32499826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill MN, Miller NH, Degeest S, American Society of Hypertension Writing Group. Materson BJ, Black HR, Izzo JL, Oparil S, Weber MA. Adherence and persistence with taking medication to control high blood pressure. J Am Soc Hypertens. 2011;5(1):56&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/j.jash.2011.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jash.2011.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21320699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burnier M, Egan BM. Adherence in hypertension: a review of prevalence, risk factors, impact, and management. Circ Res. 2019 Mar 29;124(7):1124&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1161/circresaha.118.313220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circresaha.118.313220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30920917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redon J, Brunner HR, Ferri C, Hilgers KF, Kolloch R, van Montfrans G. Practical solutions to the challenges of uncontrolled hypertension: a white paper. J Hypertens Suppl. 2008 Dec;26(4):1&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1097/01.hjh.0000343507.74401.45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.hjh.0000343507.74401.45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19096292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . mHealth: New Horizons for Health through Mobile Technologies: Second Global Survey on eHealth (Global Observatory for eHealth series - Volume 3) Geneva: World Health Organization; 2011. pp. 1&#x2013;111.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamine S, Gerth-Guyette E, Faulx D, Green BB, Ginsburg AS. Impact of mHealth chronic disease management on treatment adherence and patient outcomes: a systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2015;17(2):e52. doi: 10.2196/jmir.3951.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4376208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25803266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song T, Yu P. mHealth. In: Gu D, Dupre ME, editors. Encyclopedia of Gerontology and Population Aging. Switzerland: Springer International Publishing; 2019. pp. 1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-69892-2_452-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The rise of mHealth apps: a market snapshot. Liquid State. 2018.  [2021-06-04].   https://liquid-state.com/mhealth-apps-market-snapshot/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mann DM, Kudesia V, Reddy S, Weng M, Imler D, Quintiliani L. Development of DASH Mobile: a mHealth lifestyle change intervention for the management of hypertension. Stud Health Technol Inform. 2013;192:973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23920747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang H, Park H. A mobile app for hypertension management based on clinical practice guidelines: development and deployment. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2016 Feb 02;4(1):e12. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.4966.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.4966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4756253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26839283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant S, Hodgkinson J, Schwartz C, Bradburn P, Franssen M, Hobbs FR, Jowett S, McManus RJ, Greenfield S. Using mHealth for the management of hypertension in UK primary care: an embedded qualitative study of the TASMINH4 randomised controlled trial. Br J Gen Pract. 2019 Sep;69(686):612&#x2013;20. doi: 10.3399/bjgp19X704585.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3399/bjgp19X704585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6607844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31262847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon EW, Tan NC, Allen JC, Jafar TH. The use of wireless, smartphone app-assisted home blood pressure monitoring among hypertensive patients in Singapore: pilot randomized controlled trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019 May 28;7(5):e13153. doi: 10.2196/13153.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/13153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6658261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30905872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu X, Yang H, Xia X, Lu X, Lin J, Liu F, Gu D. Interactive mobile health intervention and blood pressure management in adults. Hypertension. 2019 Sep;74(3):697&#x2013;704. doi: 10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.119.13273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.119.13273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31327259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santo K, Redfern J. The potential of mHealth applications in improving resistant hypertension self-assessment, treatment and control. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2019 Oct 09;21(10):81. doi: 10.1007/s11906-019-0986-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11906-019-0986-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31598792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li R, Liang N, Bu F, Hesketh T. The effectiveness of self-management of hypertension in adults using mobile health: systematic review and meta-analysis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020 Mar 27;8(3):e17776. doi: 10.2196/17776.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/17776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7148553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu C, Hu Y, Xie J, Fu Q, Leigh I, Governor S, Wang G. The use of mobile health applications to improve patient experience: cross-sectional study in Chinese public hospitals. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2018 May 23;6(5):e126. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.9145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.9145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5990855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29792290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessa T, Hawley MS, Hock ES, de Witte L. Smartphone apps to support self-management of hypertension: review and content analysis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019 May 28;7(5):e13645. doi: 10.2196/13645.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/13645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6658295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31140434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song T, Qian S, Cui T, Yu P. The use of theory in mobile health interventions for patient self-management of chronic diseases. Stud Health Technol Inform. 2019 Aug 21;264:1982&#x2013;3. doi: 10.3233/SHTI190745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/SHTI190745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31438439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallberg I, Ranerup A, Kjellgren K. Supporting the self-management of hypertension: patients' experiences of using a mobile phone-based system. J Hum Hypertens. 2016 Feb;30(2):141&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1038/jhh.2015.37.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jhh.2015.37</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4705419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25903164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrissey EC, Casey M, Glynn LG, Walsh JC, Molloy GJ. Smartphone apps for improving medication adherence in hypertension: patients' perspectives. Patient Prefer Adherence. 2018;12:813&#x2013;22. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S145647. doi: 10.2147/PPA.S145647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PPA.S145647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5957057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29785096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Draucker CB, Martsolf DS, Ross R, Rusk TB. Theoretical sampling and category development in grounded theory. Qual Health Res. 2007 Oct;17(8):1137&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1177/1049732307308450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732307308450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17928484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noy C. Sampling knowledge: the hermeneutics of snowball sampling in qualitative research. Int J Soc Res Methodol. 2008 Oct;11(4):327&#x2013;44. doi: 10.1080/13645570701401305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13645570701401305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentles S, Charles C, Ploeg J, McKibbon KA. Sampling in qualitative research: insights from an overview of the methods literature. Qual Rep. 2015 Nov 7;11(4):327&#x2013;44. doi: 10.46743/2160-3715/2015.2373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46743/2160-3715/2015.2373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin PY, Turner BA. Grounded theory and organizational research. J Appl Behav Sci. 2016 Jul 26;22(2):141&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1177/002188638602200207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/002188638602200207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolb SM. Grounded theory and the constant comparative method: valid research strategies for educators. J Emerg Trends Edu Res Policy Stud. 2012;3(1):83&#x2013;6. doi: 10.10520/EJC135409.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.10520/EJC135409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strauss A, Corbin J. Grounded theory methodology. In: Denzin NK, Lincoln YS, editors. Handbook of Qualitative Research. Thousand Oaks, California, United States: Sage Publications Inc; 1994. pp. 273&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh H, Shannon SE. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qual Health Res. 2005 Nov;15(9):1277&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1177/1049732305276687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732305276687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bree R, Gallagher G. Using Microsoft Excel to code and thematically analyse qualitative data: a simple, cost-effective approach. All Ireland J High Edu. 2016;8(2):A.  </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donabedian A. Evaluating the quality of medical care. 1966. Milbank Q. 2005;83(4):691&#x2013;729. doi: 10.1111/j.1468-0009.2005.00397.x.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-0009.2005.00397.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2690293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16279964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson K, Burford O, Emmerton L. Mobile health apps to facilitate self-care: a qualitative study of user experiences. PLoS One. 2016;11(5):e0156164. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0156164.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0156164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4876999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27214203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toro-Ramos T, Kim Y, Wood M, Rajda J, Niejadlik K, Honcz J, Marrero D, Fawer A, Michaelides A. Efficacy of a mobile hypertension prevention delivery platform with human coaching. J Hum Hypertens. 2017 Dec;31(12):795&#x2013;800. doi: 10.1038/jhh.2017.69. doi: 10.1038/jhh.2017.69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jhh.2017.69</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28972573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal S, Lau CT. Remote health monitoring using mobile phones and web services. Telemed J E Health. 2010 Jun;16(5):603&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1089/tmj.2009.0165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/tmj.2009.0165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20575728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DJ, Hwang Y. A study of mobile internet user&#x2019;s service quality perceptions from a user&#x2019;s utilitarian and hedonic value tendency perspectives. Inf Syst Front. 2010 Sep 7;14(2):409&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1007/s10796-010-9267-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10796-010-9267-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Yu P, Shen J. The benefits of introducing electronic health records in residential aged care facilities: a multiple case study. Int J Med Inform. 2012 Oct;81(10):690&#x2013;704. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2012.05.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2012.05.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22749424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammenwerth E, Buchauer A, Bludau B, Haux R. Mobile information and communication tools in the hospital. Int J Med Inform. 2000 Jan;57(1):21&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1016/s1386-5056(99)00056-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1386-5056(99)00056-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10708253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers MG. Recent advances in automated blood pressure measurement. Curr Hypertens Rep. 2008 Oct;10(5):355&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1007/s11906-008-0067-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11906-008-0067-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18775111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hond ED, Celis H, Fagard R, Keary L, Leeman M, O'Brien E, Vandenhoven G, Staessen JA, THOP investigators Self-measured versus ambulatory blood pressure in the diagnosis of hypertension. J Hypertens. 2003 Apr;21(4):717&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1097/00004872-200304000-00014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004872-200304000-00014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12658017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spruill TM, Pickering TG, Schwartz JE, Mostofsky E, Ogedegbe G, Clemow L, Gerin W. The impact of perceived hypertension status on anxiety and the white coat effect. Ann Behav Med. 2007 Aug;34(1):1&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/BF02879915.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02879915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17688391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barsky J, Hunter R, McAllister C, Yeates K, Campbell N, Liu P, Perkins N, Hua-Stewart D, Maar MA, Tobe SW. Analysis of the implementation, user perspectives, and feedback from a mobile health intervention for individuals living with hypertension (DREAM-GLOBAL): mixed methods study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019 Dec 09;7(12):e12639. doi: 10.2196/12639.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/12639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6928701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31815678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamaladin H, van de Belt TH, Luijpers LC, de Graaff FR, Bredie SJ, Roeleveld N, van Gelder MM. Mobile apps for blood pressure monitoring: systematic search in app stores and content analysis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2018 Nov 14;6(11):e187. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.9888.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.9888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6262205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30429116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousins N. Anatomy of an illness (as perceived by the patient) N Engl J Med. 1976 Dec 23;295(26):1458&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1056/NEJM197612232952605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM197612232952605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">995143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight EL, Bohn RL, Wang PS, Glynn RJ, Mogun H, Avorn J. Predictors of uncontrolled hypertension in ambulatory patients. Hypertension. 2001 Oct;38(4):809&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1161/hy0901.091681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/hy0901.091681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11641291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bokhour BG, Cohn ES, Cort&#xe9;s DE, Solomon JL, Fix GM, Elwy AR, Mueller N, Katz LA, Haidet P, Green AR, Borzecki AM, Kressin NR. The role of patients' explanatory models and daily-lived experience in hypertension self-management. J Gen Intern Med. 2012 Dec;27(12):1626&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1007/s11606-012-2141-2.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-012-2141-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3509311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22821569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paterick TE, Patel N, Tajik AJ, Chandrasekaran K. Improving health outcomes through patient education and partnerships with patients. Proc (Bayl Univ Med Cent) 2017 Jan;30(1):112&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1080/08998280.2017.11929552.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08998280.2017.11929552</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5242136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28152110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salari R, Kalhori SR, Fatehi F, Ghazisaeedi M, Nazari M. Determining minimum set of features for diabetes mobile apps. J Diabetes Metab Disord. 2019 Dec;18(2):333&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1007/s40200-019-00417-y.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40200-019-00417-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6914742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31890658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J, Faust B, Ebert DD, Kr&#xe4;mer L, Baumeister H. A web-based acceptance-facilitating intervention for identifying patients' acceptance, uptake, and adherence of internet- and mobile-based pain interventions: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2018 Aug 21;20(8):e244. doi: 10.2196/jmir.9925.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.9925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6123541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30131313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garner SL, George CE, Young P, Hitchcock J, Koch H, Green G, Mahid Z, Norman G. Effectiveness of an mHealth application to improve hypertension health literacy in India. Int Nurs Rev. 2020 Dec;67(4):476&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1111/inr.12616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/inr.12616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32767464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarea V, Vishwa MV, Sattari M, Aliparasti R. High school students' perspective on the features of consumer health information websites. Webology. 2016;13(1):1&#x2013;14.  </Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Health promotion by social cognitive means. Health Educ Behav. 2004 Apr;31(2):143&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1177/1090198104263660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1090198104263660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15090118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers R, Prentice-Dunn S. Protection motivation theory. In: Gochman DS, editor. Handbook of Health Behavior Research I: Personal and Social Determinants. Switzerland: Springer; 1997. pp. 113&#x2013;32.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsang JY, Blakeman T, Hegarty J, Humphreys J, Harvey G. Understanding the implementation of interventions to improve the management of chronic kidney disease in primary care: a rapid realist review. Implement Sci. 2016 Apr 04;11:47. doi: 10.1186/s13012-016-0413-7.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-016-0413-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4820872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27044401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickson A, Knussen C, Flowers P. 'That was my old life; it's almost like a past-life now': identity crisis, loss and adjustment amongst people living with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome. Psychol Health. 2008;23(4):459&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1080/08870440701757393.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08870440701757393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25160579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song T, Qian S, Yu P. Mobile health interventions for self-control of unhealthy alcohol use: systematic review. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019 Jan 29;7(1):e10899. doi: 10.2196/10899.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6371076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30694200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barley E, Lawson V. Using health psychology to help patients: theories of behaviour change. Br J Nurs. 2016 Sep 08;25(16):924&#x2013;7. doi: 10.12968/bjon.2016.25.16.924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12968/bjon.2016.25.16.924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27615529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, van Stralen MM, West R. The behaviour change wheel: a new method for characterising and designing behaviour change interventions. Implement Sci. 2011;6:42. doi: 10.1186/1748-5908-6-42.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-6-42</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3096582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21513547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajzen I. The theory of planned behaviour: reactions and reflections. Psychol Health. 2011 Sep;26(9):1113&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1080/08870446.2011.613995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08870446.2011.613995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21929476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>