<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36071264</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2027</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PharmacoEconomics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pharmacoeconomics</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cost Effectiveness of the First-in-Class ARNI (Sacubitril/Valsartan) for the Treatment of Essential Hypertension in a Chinese Setting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1187</StartPage><EndPage>1205</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1187-1205</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40273-022-01182-2</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to model the potential long-term disease progression and pharmacoeconomic value of sacubitril/valsartan for the treatment of essential hypertension from a Chinese healthcare system perspective.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A Markov cohort model with five health states was constructed to simulate the incidence of acute cardiovascular events and cost per quality-adjusted life-year (QALY) gained with sacubitril/valsartan compared with allisartan isoproxil and valsartan over a lifetime horizon with an annual cycle. Multivariable risk regression models derived from China-PAR data accompanied by hazard ratios were used to transform the dual mechanism of sacubitril/valsartan to lower blood pressure and left ventricular mass index into long-term fatal and non-fatal cardiovascular risks. Efficacy data were calculated using a network meta-analysis integrated by the results of clinical trials. Healthcare costs were determined from a real-world study and published literature, supplemented by expert opinion. Utilities were derived from literature. Both costs and health outcomes were discounted at 5.0% annually, and prices corresponded to 2021. Model validation, deterministic and probabilistic sensitivity analyses were conducted to test the robustness of results.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">For simulated patients with hypertension, sacubitril/valsartan reduced the rates of myocardial infarction by 6.67% and 6.39%, stroke by 9.38% and 8.98%, and heart failure hospitalization by 9.92% and 9.62% relative to allisartan isoproxil and valsartan, respectively. It was also associated with gains in life expectancy among hypertensive individuals of 0.362-0.382 years. Eventually, lifetime costs per patient were CN&#xa5;59,272 (US$9187) for sacubitril/valsartan, CN&#xa5;54,783 (US$8492) for allisartan isoproxil, and CN&#xa5;56,714 (US$8791) for valsartan; total QALYs were 11.38, 11.24, and 11.25, respectively. The incremental cost-effectiveness ratio was CN&#xa5;31,805/QALY (US$4930/QALY) compared with allisartan isoproxil, and CN&#xa5;19,247/QALY (US$2983/QALY) compared with valsartan, both of which are below the one time per-capita GDP of CN&#xa5;80,976/QALY (US$12,551/QALY) in China. Similar results were obtained in various extensive sensitivity analysis scenarios.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This was the first study to evaluate the cost effectiveness of sacubitril/valsartan in the treatment of hypertension. Sacubitril/valsartan compares favorably with allisartan isoproxil and valsartan in the Chinese setting, which is mainly due to its higher efficacy resulting in fewer cardiovascular events and ultimately less related mortality over time. The results could inform deliberations regarding reimbursement and access to this treatment in China and may provide reference for facilitating more reasonable and efficient allocation of limited resources in such low- and middle-income countries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dong</LastName><ForeName>Xinyue</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmaceutical Science and Technology, Tianjin University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Social Science Survey and Data, Tianjin University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Xiaoning</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmaceutical Science and Technology, Tianjin University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Social Science Survey and Data, Tianjin University, Tianjin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Jing</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6012-2785</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Pharmaceutical Science and Technology, Tianjin University, Tianjin, China. jingwu@tju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Social Science Survey and Data, Tianjin University, Tianjin, China. jingwu@tju.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000099094">Network Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Pharmacoeconomics</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9212404</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1170-7690</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>80M03YXJ7I</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068756">Valsartan</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004338">Drug Combinations</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>17ERJ0MKGI</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000717211">sacubitril</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000613">Aminobutyrates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001713">Biphenyl Compounds</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C587132">allisartan isoproxil</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007093">Imidazoles</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000075222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Essential Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003362" MajorTopicYN="N">Cost-Benefit Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068756" MajorTopicYN="N">Valsartan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004338" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Combinations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000613" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Aminobutyrates</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001713" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Biphenyl Compounds</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007093" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Imidazoles</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36071264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40273-022-01182-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40273-022-01182-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhou B, Carrillo-Larco RM, Danaei G, et al. Worldwide trends in hypertension prevalence and progress in treatment and control from 1990 to 2019: a pooled analysis of 1201 population-representative studies with 104 million participants. The Lancet. 2021;398:957&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forouzanfar MH, Liu P, Roth GA, et al. Global burden of hypertension and systolic blood pressure of at least 110 to 115 mm Hg, 1990&#x2013;2015. JAMA. 2017;317:165&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28097354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Chen Z, Zhang L, et al. Status of hypertension in China: results from the China hypertension survey, 2012&#x2013;2015. Circulation. 2018;137:2344&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29449338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou B, et al. Long-term and recent trends in hypertension awareness, treatment, and control in 12 high-income countries: an analysis of 123 nationally representative surveys. Lancet (London, England). 2019;394:639&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner AK, Valera M, Graves AJ, et al. Costs of hospital care for hypertension in an insured population without an outpatient medicines benefit: an observational study in the Philippines. BMC Health Serv Res. 2008;8:161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18664285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2518143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CHL, CSC, CCHP, et al. Chinese guidelines for the management of hypertension. Chinese J Cardiovasc Med. 2018;2019(24):33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>JCGR. Chinese guidelines for prevention and treatment of hypertension-a report of the revision committee of Chinese guidelines for prevention and treatment of hypertension. J Geriatric Cardiol JGC. 2018;2019(16):182&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boersma C, Carides GW, Atthobari J, et al. An economic assessment of losartan-based versus atenolol-based therapy in patients with hypertension and left-ventricular hypertrophy: results from the Losartan Intervention For Endpoint reduction (LIFE) study adapted to The Netherlands. Clin Ther. 2007;29:963&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17697915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carides GW, Shahinfar S, Dasbach EJ, et al. The impact of losartan on the lifetime incidence of end-stage renal disease and costs in patients with type 2 diabetes and nephropathy. Pharmacoeconomics. 2006;24:549&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16761903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park C, Wang G, Durthaler JM, et al. Cost-effectiveness analyses of antihypertensive medicines: a systematic review. Am J Prev Med. 2017;53:S131&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29153114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5836308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J, Noe A, Chandra P, et al. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of LCZ696, a novel dual-acting angiotensin receptor-neprilysin inhibitor (ARNi). J Clin Pharmacol. 2010;50:401&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19934029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA. New Drug Application (NDA): 207620 (Entresto). 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMA. Assessment report: Entresto. 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CDE. Chemical catalogue set: Entresto. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua SK, Lai WT, Chen LC, et al. The antihypertensive effects and safety of LCZ696 in patients with hypertension: a systemic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Clin Med. 2021;10:2824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34206864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8268164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin LM, Wu Y, Wu MF, et al. Focus on the novel cardiovascular drug LZC696: from evidence to clinical consideration. Cardiovasc Drugs Ther. 2016;30:623&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27858191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kario K, Sun N, Chiang FT, et al. Efficacy and safety of LCZ696, a first-in-class angiotensin receptor neprilysin inhibitor, in Asian patients with hypertension: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Hypertension (Dallas, Tex: 1979). 2014;63:698&#x2013;705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huo Y, Li W, Webb R, et al. Efficacy and safety of sacubitril/valsartan compared with olmesartan in Asian patients with essential hypertension: a randomized, double-blind, 8-week study. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich). 2019;21:67&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo C, Li X, Fan L, et al. Effectiveness and safety of sacubitril/valsartan for patients with hypertension and heart failure in the real-world setting: a retrospective study in China. J Clin Pharm Therap. 2022. https://doi.org/10.1111/jcpt.13699 .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpt.13699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PMDA. New Drugs Approved in FY 2021. Pharmaceuticals and Medical Devices Agency, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin DS, Wang TD, Buranakitjaroen P, et al. Angiotensin receptor neprilysin inhibitor as a novel antihypertensive drug: evidence from Asia and around the globe. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich). 2021;23:556&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Si L, Xu L, Chen M, et al. Using strategic price negotiations to contain costs and expand access to medicines in China. BMJ Glob Health. 2020;5: e002256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32133184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7042576</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan L, Chen CH, Hwang JJ, et al. Cost-effectiveness of amlodipine compared with valsartan in preventing stroke and myocardial infarction among hypertensive patients in Taiwan. Int J General Med. 2016;9:175&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueshima H, Sekikawa A, Miura K, et al. Cardiovascular disease and risk factors in Asia: a selected review. Circulation. 2008;118:2702&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19106393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3096564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastwood SV, Tillin T, Chaturvedi N, et al. Ethnic differences in associations between blood pressure and stroke in South Asian and European Men. Hypertension (Dallas, Tex: 1979). 2015;66:481&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4632186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao Z, Ahmed S, Graham C, et al. Exploring subjective constructions of health in China: a Q-methodological investigation. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2020;18:165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32493342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7268713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peasgood T, Mukuria C, Brazier J, et al. Developing a new generic health and wellbeing measure: psychometric survey results for the EQ-HWB. Value Health. 2022;25:525&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35365299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Zhou Q, Xuan J, et al. A cost-effectiveness analysis between amlodipine and angiotensin II receptor blockers in stroke and myocardial infarction prevention among hypertension patients in China. Value Health Regional Issues. 2013;2:75&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lung T, Jan S, de Silva HA, et al. Fixed-combination, low-dose, triple-pill antihypertensive medication versus usual care in patients with mild-to-moderate hypertension in Sri Lanka: a within-trial and modelled economic evaluation of the TRIUMPH trial. Lancet Glob Health. 2019;7:e1359&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31477545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du X, Patel A, Anderson CS, et al. Epidemiology of cardiovascular disease in China and opportunities for improvement: JACC international. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019;73:3135&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian J, Yan J, Zhang Q, et al. Analysis of re-hospitalizations for patients with heart failure caused by coronary heart disease: data of first event and recurrent event. Ther Clin Risk Manag. 2019;15:1333&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31814728</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6861516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>IQVIA. Intercontinental Marketing Services (IMSHealth). 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang QF, Li Y, Wang JG. Overview of clinical use and side effect profile of valsartan in Chinese hypertensive patients. Drug Des Dev Ther. 2013;8:79&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams B, Mancia G, Spiering W, et al. 2018 ESC/ESH Guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension: the Task Force for the management of arterial hypertension of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European Society of Hypertension (ESH). Eur Heart J. 2018;39:3021&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelton PK, Carey RM, Aronow WS, et al. ACC/AHA/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/AGS/APhA/ASH/ASPC/NMA/PCNA guideline for the prevention, detection, evaluation, and management of high blood pressure in adults: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Hypertension (Dallas, Tex: 1979). 2018;71:1269&#x2013;324.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JG, Yukisada K, Sibulo A Jr, et al. Efficacy and safety of sacubitril/valsartan (LCZ696) add-on to amlodipine in Asian patients with systolic hypertension uncontrolled with amlodipine monotherapy. J Hypertens. 2017;35:877&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28030431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Supasyndh O, Sun N, Kario K, et al. Long-term (52-week) safety and efficacy of Sacubitril/valsartan in Asian patients with hypertension. Hypertension Res. 2017;40:472&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang Z, Zhang T, Lin T, et al. Health-related quality of life among rural men and women with hypertension: assessment by the EQ-5D-5L in Jiangsu, China. Quality Life Res. 2019;28:2069&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang M, Hou X, Hu W, et al. Serum lipid and lipoprotein levels of middle-aged and elderly Chinese men and women in Shandong Province. Lipids Health Dis. 2019;18:58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30832658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6399962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng Y, Li M, Li X, et al. The differences of left ventricular configuration between Chinese and international standard by echocardiography in Chinese adults with hypertension. Chin J Ultrasonogr. 2018;27:461&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Zhang M, Yang L, et al. Prevalence and patterns of tobacco smoking among Chinese adult men and women: findings of the 2010 national smoking survey. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2017;71:154&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27660401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing X, Yang X, Liu F, et al. Predicting 10-year and lifetime stroke risk in Chinese population. Stroke. 2019;50:2371&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31390964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X, Li J, Hu D, et al. Predicting the 10-year risks of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in Chinese population: the China-PAR project (prediction for ASCVD risk in China). Circulation. 2016;134:1430&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27682885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ettehad D, Emdin CA, Kiran A, et al. Blood pressure lowering for prevention of cardiovascular disease and death: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet (London, England). 2016;387:957&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai CL, Chien KL, Hsu HC, et al. Left ventricular mass and risk of cardiovascular events and all-cause death among ethnic Chinese&#x2013;the Chin-Shan Community Cardiovascular Cohort study. Int J Cardiol. 2011;149:347&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20202708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmieder RE, Wagner F, Mayr M, et al. The effect of sacubitril/valsartan compared to olmesartan on cardiovascular remodelling in subjects with essential hypertension: the results of a randomized, double-blind, active-controlled study. Eur Heart J. 2017;38:3308&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29029087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han Y, Chen J, Qiu M, et al. Predicting long-term ischemic events using routine clinical parameters in patients with coronary artery disease: the OPT-CAD risk score. Cardiovasc Ther. 2018;36: e12441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29869835</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokomichi H, Noda H, Nagai A, et al. Cholesterol levels of Japanese dyslipidaemic patients with various comorbidities: BioBank Japan. J Epidemiol. 2017;27:S77-s83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196738</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5350591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Ning X, Zhu C, et al. Prognostic significance of prior ischemic stroke in patients with coronary artery disease undergoing percutaneous coronary intervention. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2019;93:787&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng XF, Hai JJ, Ma Y, et al. Sudden cardiac death in mainland China: a systematic analysis. Circ Arrhythm Electrophysiol. 2018;11: e006684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30571181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desta L, Jernberg T, Spaak J, et al. Risk and predictors of readmission for heart failure following a myocardial infarction between 2004 and 2013: a Swedish nationwide observational study. Int J Cardiol. 2017;248:221&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28579167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura K, Barzi F, Lam TH, et al. Cigarette smoking, systolic blood pressure, and cardiovascular diseases in the Asia-Pacific region. Stroke. 2008;39:1694&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18323508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. The life tables for women and men. Geneva: WHO; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou M, Wang H, Zhu J, et al. Cause-specific mortality for 240 causes in China during 1990&#x2013;2013: a systematic subnational analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2013. Lancet (London, England). 2016;387:251&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson S, Rosengren A, Young K, et al. Mortality and morbidity trends after the first year in survivors of acute myocardial infarction: a systematic review. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2017;17:53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28173750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5297173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xf8;nnum-Hansen H, Davidsen M, Thorvaldsen P. Long-term survival and causes of death after stroke. Stroke. 2001;32:2131&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11546907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moran A, Gu D, Zhao D, et al. Future cardiovascular disease in china: markov model and risk factor scenario projections from the coronary heart disease policy model-china. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2010;3:243&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20442213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2937540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma LY, Chen WW, Gao RL, et al. China cardiovascular diseases report 2018: an updated summary. J Geriatric Cardiol JGC. 2020;17:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Zhang J, Butler J, et al. Contemporary epidemiology, management, and outcomes of patients hospitalized for heart failure in China: results from the China Heart Failure (China-HF) Registry. J Cardiac Fail. 2017;23:868&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed SN, Jhaj R, Sadasivam B, et al. Regression of the left ventricular hypertrophy in patients with essential hypertension on standard drug therapy. Discoveries (Craiova, Romania). 2020;8: e115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7575414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verdecchia P, Carini G, Circo A, et al. Left ventricular mass and cardiovascular morbidity in essential hypertension: the MAVI study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2001;38:1829&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu GG. China guidelines for pharmacoeconomic evaluations. Beijing: China Market Press; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Bureau of statistics. Annual data of consumer price index (CPI) in healthcare. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Bureau of Statistics of China. Statistical bulletin of national economic and social development of the people's Republic of China in 2021. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Yang Y, Luo M, et al. The impacts of national centralized drug procurement policy on drug utilization and drug expenditures: the case of Shenzhen, China. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;17:9415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7765443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long H, Yang Y, Geng X, et al. Changing characteristics of pharmaceutical prices in China under centralized procurement policy: a multi-intervention interrupted time series. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13: 944540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35910351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9335887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chengdu Healthcare Security Administration, Chengdu Municipal Health Commission. Price list of medical service price structure adjustment projects of municipal public medical institutions in Chengdu. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanghai Municipal Development and Reform Commission. Medical service price inquiry. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaoning Provincial Development and Reform Commission, Health Commission of Liaoning Province, Liaoning Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security, Liaoning Province Finance Department. Notice on printing and distributing price of medical service projects of public medical institutions in Liaoning Province. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>People&#x2019;s Government of Guangdong Province. Medical service projects and prices of public medical institutions in Guangzhou. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beijing Municipal Medical Insurance Bureau. Medical service price inquiry. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>KantarHealth. Kantar database extraction date 2020 for Quality of Life. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok CH, Kwok HHY, Ng CS, et al. Health state utility values for type 2 diabetes and related complications in east and Southeast Asia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Value Health. 2021;24:1059&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34243830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NBS. China Statistical Year Book 2021. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muramatsu T, Matsushita K, Yamashita K, et al. Comparison Between Valsartan and Amlodipine Regarding Cardiovascular Morbidity and Mortality in Hypertensive Patients With Glucose Intolerance. 2012;59:580&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y, Lin RS, Sung FC, et al. Chin-Shan Community Cardiovascular Cohort in Taiwan-baseline data and five-year follow-up morbidity and mortality. J Clin Epidemiol. 2000;53:838&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10942867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang KC, Lee HC, Tseng MC, et al. Three-year survival after first-ever ischemic stroke is predicted by initial stroke severity: A hospital-based study. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2010;112:296&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20106589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CH, Cheng CL, Yang YH, et al. Trends in the incidence and management of acute myocardial infarction from 1999 to 2008: get with the guidelines performance measures in Taiwan. J Am Heart Assoc. 2014; 3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honda T, Yoshida D, Hata J, et al. Development and validation of modified risk prediction models for cardiovascular disease and its subtypes: the Hisayama Study. Atherosclerosis. 2018;279:38&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30408715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devereux RB, Wachtell K, Gerdts E, et al. Prognostic significance of left ventricular mass change during treatment of hypertension. JAMA. 2004;292:2350&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15547162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Yu D, Cornelius V, et al. Potential health impact and cost-effectiveness of drug therapy for prehypertension. Int J Cardiol. 2017;240:403&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28501349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Yao C, Yang X, et al. Body mass index and the risk of cardiovascular and all-cause mortality among patients with hypertension: a population-based prospective cohort study among adults in Beijing, China. J Epidemiol. 2016;26:654&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27431649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5121434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Leong DP, Hu B, et al. The association of grip strength with cardiovascular diseases and all-cause mortality in people with hypertension: findings from the Prospective Urban Rural Epidemiology China Study. J Sport Health Sci. 2021;10:629&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33091627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs A, Sculpher M, Claxton K. Decision modelling for health economic evaluation. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren M, Xuan D, Lu Y, et al. Economic evaluation of olmesartan/amlodipine fixed-dose combination for hypertension treatment in China. J Med Econ. 2020;23:394&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31782677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito I, Kobayashi M, Matsushita Y, et al. Cost-utility analysis of antihypertensive combination therapy in Japan by a Monte Carlo simulation model. Hypertension Res. 2008;31:1373&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu Q, Yang N, Feng S, et al. Cost-effectiveness analysis of combining traditional Chinese medicine in the treatment of hypertension: compound Apocynum tablets combined with Nifedipine sustained-release tablets vs Nifedipine sustained-release tablets alone. BMC Complement Med Therap. 2020;20:330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsumali A, Djatche LM, Briggs A, et al. Cost effectiveness of vericiguat for the treatment of chronic heart failure with reduced ejection fraction following a worsening heart failure event from a US Medicare perspective. Pharmacoeconomics. 2021;39:1343&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34623625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">8516766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stafylas P, Kourlaba G, Hatzikou M, et al. Economic evaluation of a single-pill triple antihypertensive therapy with valsartan, amlodipine, and hydrochlorothiazide against its dual components. Cost Effective Resour Allocation C/E. 2015;13:10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borisenko O, Beige J, Lovett EG, et al. Cost-effectiveness of Barostim therapy for the treatment of resistant hypertension in European settings. J Hypertens. 2014;32:681&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24378998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maniadakis N, Ekman M, Fragoulakis V, et al. Economic evaluation of irbesartan in combination with hydrochlorothiazide in the treatment of hypertension in Greece. Eur J Health Econ. 2011;12:253&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20411401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazra NC, Rudisill C, Jackson SH, et al. Cost-effectiveness of antihypertensive therapy in patients older than 80 years: cohort Study and Markov Model. Value Health. 2019;22:1362&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31806192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes R, Judge PK, Staplin N, et al. Effects of Sacubitril/Valsartan versus Irbesartan in patients with chronic kidney disease. Circulation. 2018;138:1505&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30002098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eloisa Trina Cesante G, Enrique LD, Jacqueline Mariano C, et al. Renal outcomes of sacubitril-valsartan vs. ACE inhibitors and angiotensin receptor blockers in heart failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. 2020.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>