<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38747417</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5598</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hypertension</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hypertens</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hypertension and left ventricular hypertrophy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1505</StartPage><EndPage>1515</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1505-1515</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HJH.0000000000003774</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the initial stage, left ventricular hypertrophy (LVH) is adaptive, but in time, it transforms to maladaptive LVH which is specific for the development of various phenotypes that cause heart failure, initially with preserved, but later with reduced left ventricular ejection fraction. Pathophysiological mechanisms, which are characteristic for remodeling procedure, are numerous and extremely complex, and should be subjected to further research with the aim of making a comprehensive overview of hypertensive heart disease (HHD) and discovering new options for preventing and treating HHD. The contemporary methods, such as cardiac magnetic resonance (CMR) and computed tomography (CT) provide very accurate morphological and functional information on HHD. The objective of this review article is to summarize the available scientific information in terms of prevalence, pathophysiology, diagnostics, prevention, contemporary therapeutic options, as well as to present potential therapeutic solutions based on the research of pathological mechanisms which are at the core of HHD.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x110;or&#x111;evi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Dragan B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Nis.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Treatment and Rehabilitation Niska Banja.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kora&#x10d;evi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Goran P</ForeName><Initials>GP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Nis.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department for Cardiovascular Diseases, Clinical Center Nis, Nis, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>&#x110;or&#x111;evi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Aleksandar D</ForeName><Initials>AD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiology Department, University of Medicine Rostock, Rostock.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lovi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Dragan B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic for Internal Diseases Intermedica, Singidunum University Nis, Jovana Ristica, Nis, Serbia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Veterans Affair Medical Centre, Washington DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>J Hypertens</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8306882</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0263-6352</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017379" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertrophy, Left Ventricular</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38747417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HJH.0000000000003774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00004872-202409000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kannel WB, Dannenberg AL, Levy D. Population implications of electrocardiographic left ventricular hypertrophy. Am J Cardiol 1987; 60:85I&#x2013;93I.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancia G, Kreutz R, Brunstr&#xf6;m M, Burnier M, Grassi G, Januszewicz A, et al. 2023 ESH Guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension. The Task Force for the management of arterial hypertension of the European Society of Hypertension: endorsed by the International Society of Hypertension (ISH) and the European Renal Association (ERA). J Hypertens 2023; 41:1874&#x2013;2071.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kavey RE. Left ventricular hypertrophy in hypertensive children and adolescents: predictors and prevalence. Curr Hypertens Rep 2013; 15:453&#x2013;457.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frey N, Richardson JA, Olson EN. Calsarcins, a novel family of sarcomeric calcineurin-binding proteins. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2000; 97:14632&#x2013;14637.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hunter JJ, Chien KR. Signaling pathways for cardiac hypertrophy and failure. N Engl J Med 1999; 341:1276&#x2013;1283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samak M, Fatullayev J, Sabashnikov A, Zeriouh M, Schmack B, Farag M, et al. Cardiac hypertrophy: an introduction to molecular and cellular basis. Med Sci Monit Basic Res 2016; 22:75&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehtonen AO, Puukka P, Varis J, Porthan K, Tikkanen JT, Nieminen MS, et al. Prevalence and prognosis of ECG abnormalities in normotensive and hypertensive individuals. J Hypertens 2016; 34:959&#x2013;966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sparapani R, Dabbouseh NM, Gutterman D, Zhang J, Chen H, Bluemke DA, et al. Detection of left ventricular hypertrophy using Bayesian additive regression trees: the MESA. J Am Heart Assoc 2019; 8:e009959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apitz A, Socrates T, Burkard T, Mayr M, Vischer AS. Prevalence and characterisation of severe left ventricular hypertrophy diagnosed by echocardiography in hypertensive patients. J Clin Med 2022; 12:228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy D, Anderson KM, Savage DD, Kannel WB, Christiansen JC, Castelli WP. Echocardiographically detected left ventricular hypertrophy: prevalence and risk factors. The Framingham Heart Study. Ann Intern Med 1988; 108:7&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuspidi C, Sala C, Negri F, Mancia G, Morganti A. Italian Society of Hypertension. Prevalence of left-ventricular hypertrophy in hypertension: an updated review of echocardiographic studies. J Hum Hypertens 2012; 26:343&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zdravkovic M, Klasnja S, Popovic M, Djuran P, Mrda D, Ivankovic T, et al. Cardiac magnetic resonance in hypertensive heart disease: time for a new chapter. Diagnostics (Basel) 2023; 13:137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burchell AE, Rodrigues JC, Charalambos M, Ratcliffe LE, Hart EC, Paton JF, et al. Comprehensive first-line magnetic resonance imaging in hypertension: experience from a single-center tertiary referral clinic. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2017; 19:13&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oldfield CJ, Duhamel TA, Dhalla NS. Mechanisms for the transition from physiological to pathological cardiac hypertrophy. Can J Physiol Pharmacol 2020; 98:74&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caturano A, Vetrano E, Galiero R, Salvatore T, Docimo G, Epifani R. Cardiac hypertrophy: from pathophysiological mechanisms to heart failure development. Rev Cardiovasc Med 2022; 23:165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nwabuo CC, Vasan RS. Pathophysiology of hypertensive heart disease: beyond left ventricular hypertrophy. Curr Hypertens Rep 2020; 22:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levy BI, Ambrosio G, Pries AR, Struijker-Boudier HA. Microcirculation in hypertension: a new target for treatment? Circulation 2001; 104:735&#x2013;740.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano M, Minamino T, Toko H, Miyauchi H, Orimo M, Qin Y, et al. p53-induced inhibition of Hif-1 causes cardiac dysfunction during pressure overload. Nature 2007; 446:444&#x2013;448.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katus HA, Bassel-Duby R, Maier LS, Olson EN. The delta isoform of CaM kinase II is required for pathological cardiac hypertrophy and remodeling after pressure overload. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2009; 106:2342&#x2013;2347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnee JM, Hsueh WA. Angiotensin II, adhesion, and cardiac fibrosis. Cardiovasc Res 2000; 46:264&#x2013;268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Travers JG, Kamal FA, Robbins J, Yutzey KE, Blaxall BC. Cardiac fibrosis: the fibroblast awakens. Circ Res 2016; 118:1021&#x2013;1040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sato PY, Chuprun JK, Schwartz M, Koch WJ. The evolving impact of g protein-coupled receptor kinases in cardiac health and disease. Physiol Rev 2015; 95:377&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M, Sadoshima J. Mechanisms of physiological and pathological cardiac hypertrophy. Nat Rev Cardiol 2018; 15:387&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grassi G, Drager LF. Sympathetic overactivity, hypertension and cardiovascular disease: state of the art. Curr Med Res Opin 2024; 40 (sup1):5&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciarretta S, Forte M, Frati G, Sadoshima J. New insights into the role of mTOR signaling in the cardiovascular system. Circ Res 2018; 122:489&#x2013;505.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samuelsson AM, Bollano E, Mobini R, Larsson BM, Omerovic E, Fu M, et al. Hyperinsulinemia: effect on cardiac mass/function, angiotensin II receptor expression, and insulin signaling pathways. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 2006; 291:H787&#x2013;H796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djordjevic DB, Koracevic G, Djordjevic AD, Lovic DB. Diabetic cardiomyopathy: clinical and metabolic approach. Curr Vasc Pharmacol 2021; 19:487&#x2013;498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mewton N, Liu CY, Croisille P, Bluemke D, Lima JA. Assessment of myocardial fibrosis with cardiovascular magnetic resonance. J Am Coll Cardiol 2011; 57:891&#x2013;903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leask A. Getting to the heart of the matter: new insights into cardiac fibrosis. Circ Res 2015; 116:1269&#x2013;1276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kakkar R, Lee RT. Intramyocardial fibroblast myocyte communication. Circ Res 2010; 106:47&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenkranz S, Flesch M, Amann K, Haeuseler C, Kilter H, Seeland U, et al. Alterations of beta-adrenergic signaling and cardiac hypertrophy in transgenic mice overexpressing TGF-beta(1). Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol 2002; 283:H1253&#x2013;H1262.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koitabashi N, Danner T, Zaiman AL, Pinto YM, Rowell J, Mankowski J, et al. Pivotal role of cardiomyocyte TGF-&#x3b2; signaling in the murine pathological response to sustained pressure overload. J Clin Invest 2011; 121:2301&#x2013;2312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luitel H, Sydykov A, Schymura Y, Mamazhakypov A, Janssen W, Pradhan K, et al. Pressure overload leads to an increased accumulation and activity of mast cells in the right ventricle. Physiol Rep 2017; 5:e13146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Honold L, Nahrendorf M. Resident and monocyte-derived macrophages in cardiovascular disease. Circ Res 2018; 122:113&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong P, Christia P, Frangogiannis NG. The pathogenesis of cardiac fibrosis. Cell Mol Life Sci 2014; 71:549&#x2013;574.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eder P, Molkentin JD. TRPC channels as effectors of cardiac hypertrophy. Circ Res 2011; 108:265&#x2013;272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troupes CD, Wallner M, Borghetti G, Zhang C, Mohsin S, von Lewinski D, et al. Role of STIM1 (Stromal Interaction Molecule 1) in hypertrophy-related contractile dysfunction. Circ Res 2017; 121:125&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takimoto E, Kass DA. Role of oxidative stress in cardiac hypertrophy and remodeling. Hypertension 2007; 49:241&#x2013;248.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozomara A, Griffiths-Jones S. miRBase: integrating microRNA annotation and deep-sequencing data. Nucleic Acids Res 2011; 39 (Database issue):D152&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rooij E, Sutherland LB, Qi X, Richardson JA, Hill J, Olson EN. Control of stress-dependent cardiac growth and gene expression by a microRNA. Science 2007; 316:575&#x2013;579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creemers EE, Tijsen AJ, Pinto YM. Circulating microRNAs: novel biomarkers and extracellular communicators in cardiovascular disease? Circ Res 2012; 110:483&#x2013;495.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doenst T, Nguyen TD, Abel ED. Cardiac metabolism in heart failure: implications beyond ATP production. Circ Res 2013; 113:709&#x2013;724.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisner DA, Caldwell JL, Kistam&#xe1;s K, Trafford AW. Calcium and excitation-contraction coupling in the heart. Circ Res 2017; 121:181&#x2013;195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito M, Khan F, Stoklosa T, Iannaccone A, Negishi K, Marwick TH. Prognostic implications of LV strain risk score in asymptomatic patients with hypertensive heart disease. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging 2016; 9:911&#x2013;921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovic D, Erdine S, Catako&#x11f;lu AB. How to estimate left ventricular hypertrophy in hypertensive patients. Anadolu Kardiyol Derg 2014; 14:389&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ganau A, Devereux RB, Roman MJ, de Simone G, Pickering TG, Saba PS, et al. Patterns of left ventricular hypertrophy and geometric remodeling in essential hypertension. J Am Coll Cardiol 1992; 19:1550&#x2013;1558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavie CJ, Patel DA, Milani RV, Ventura HO, Shah S, Gilliland Y. Impact of echocardiographic left ventricular geometry on clinical prognosis. Prog Cardiovasc Dis 2014; 57:3&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbieri A, Albini A, Maisano A, De Mitri G, Camaioni G, Bonini N, et al. Clinical value of complex echocardiographic left ventricular hypertrophy classification based on concentricity, mass, and volume quantification. Front Cardiovasc Med 2021; 27:667984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabkin SW. Assessing myocardial strain and myocardial work as a marker for hypertensive heart disease: a meta-analysis. Rev Cardiovasc Med 2023; 24:217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen OS, Smiseth OA, Dokainish H, Abudiab MM, Schutt RC, Kumar A, et al. Estimating left ventricular filling pressure by echocardiography. J Am Coll Cardiol 2017; 69:1937&#x2013;1948.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadic M, Cuspidi C, Pencic-Popovic B, Celic V, Mancia G. The relationship between nighttime hypertension and left atrial function. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2017; 19:1096&#x2013;1104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrone-Filardi P, Coca A, Galderisi M, Paolillo S, Alpendurada F, de Simone G, et al. Noninvasive cardiovascular imaging for evaluating subclinical target organ damage in hypertensive patients: a consensus article from the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging, the European Society of Cardiology Council on Hypertension and the European Society of Hypertension. J Hypertens 2017; 35:1727&#x2013;1741.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ismail TF, Frey S, Kaufmann BA, Winkel DJ, Boll DT, Zellweger MJ, et al. Hypertensive heart disease - the imaging perspective. J Clin Med 2023; 12:3122.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greupner J, Zimmermann E, Grohmann A, D&#xfc;bel HP, Althoff TF, Borges AC, et al. Head-to-head comparison of left ventricular function assessment with 64-row computed tomography, biplane left cineventriculography, and both 2- and 3-dimensional transthoracic echocardiography: comparison with magnetic resonance imaging as the reference standard. J Am Coll Cardiol 2012; 59:1897&#x2013;1907.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pezel T, Venkatesh BA, De Vasconcellos HD, Kato Y, Shabani M, Xie E, et al. Left atrioventricular coupling index as a prognostic marker of cardiovascular events: the MESA Study. Hypertension 2021; 78:661&#x2013;671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pichler G, Redon J, Mart&#xed;nez F, Solaz E, Calaforra O, Andr&#xe9;s MS, et al. Cardiac magnetic resonance-derived fibrosis, strain and molecular biomarkers of fibrosis in hypertensive heart disease. J Hypertens 2020; 38:2036&#x2013;2042.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haaf P, Garg P, Messroghli DR, Broadbent DA, Greenwood JP, Plein S. Cardiac T1 Mapping and Extracellular Volume (ECV) in clinical practice: a comprehensive review. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson 2016; 18:89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadic M, Cuspidi C, Plein S, Milivojevic IG, Wang DW, Grassi G, et al. Comprehensive assessment of hypertensive heart disease: cardiac magnetic resonance in focus. Heart Fail Rev 2021; 26:1383&#x2013;1390.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tore D, Faletti R, Gaetani C, Bozzo E, Biondo A, Carisio A, et al. Cardiac magnetic resonance of hypertrophic heart phenotype: a review. Heliyon 2023; 9:e17336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maceira AM, Mohiaddin RH. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance in systemic hypertension. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson 2012; 14:28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giusca S, Steen H, Montenbruck M, Patel AR, Pieske B, Erley J, et al. Multiparametric assessment of left ventricular hypertrophy using late gadolinium enhancement, T1 mapping and strain-encoded cardiovascular magnetic resonance. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson 2021; 23:92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aquaro GD, Corsi E, Todiere G, Grigoratos C, Barison A, Barra V, et al. Magnetic resonance for differential diagnosis of left ventricular hypertrophy: diagnostic and prognostic implications. J Clin Med 2022; 11:651.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovic D, Narayan P, Pittaras A, Faselis C, Doumas M, Kokkinos P. Left ventricular hypertrophy in athletes and hypertensive patients. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2017; 19:413&#x2013;417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sabarudin A, Sun Z. Coronary CT angiography: dose reduction strategies. World J Cardiol 2013; 5:465&#x2013;472.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein R, Ametepe ES, Yam Y, Dwivedi G, Chow BJ. Cardiac CT assessment of left ventricular mass in mid-diastasis and its prognostic value. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging 2017; 18:95&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mao SS, Li D, Rosenthal DG, Cerilles M, Zeb I, Wu H, et al. Dual-standard reference values of left ventricular volumetric parameters by multidetector CT angiography. J Cardiovasc Comput Tomogr 2013; 7:234&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Windecker S, Kolh P, Alfonso F, Collet JP, Cremer J, Falk V, et al. 2014&#x200a;ESC/EACTS Guidelines on myocardial revascularization: the task force on Myocardial Revascularization of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and the European Association for Cardio-Thoracic Surgery (EACTS) developed with the special contribution of the European Association of Percutaneous Cardiovascular Interventions (EAPCI). Eur Heart J 2014; 35:2541&#x2013;2619.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkema M, Spitzer E, Soliman OI, Loewe C. Multimodality imaging for left ventricular hypertrophy severity grading: a methodological review. J Cardiovasc Ultrasound 2016; 24:257&#x2013;267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanna M, Ruberg FL, Maurer MS, Dispenzieri A, Dorbala S, Falk RH, et al. Cardiac scintigraphy with technetium-99m-labeled bone-seeking tracers for suspected amyloidosis: JACC review topic of the week. J Am Coll Cardiol 2020; 75:2851&#x2013;2862.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caobelli F, Braun M, Haaf P, Wild D, Zellweger MJ. Quantitative (99m)Tc-DPD SPECT/CT in patients with suspected ATTR cardiac amyloidosis: feasibility and correlation with visual scores. J Nucl Cardiol 2020; 27:1456&#x2013;1463.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hotta M, Minamimoto R, Awaya T, Hiroe M, Okazaki O, Hiroi Y. Radionuclide imaging of cardiac amyloidosis and sarcoidosis: roles and characteristics of various tracers. Radiographics 2020; 40:2029&#x2013;2041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadic M, Cuspidi C, Marwick TH. Phenotyping the hypertensive heart. Eur Heart J 2022; 43:3794&#x2013;3810.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yal&#xe7;in F, Topaloglu C, Ku&#xe7;ukler N, Ofgeli M, Abraham TP. Could early septal involvement in the remodeling process be related to the advance hypertensive heart disease? Int J Cardiol Heart Vasc 2015; 7:141&#x2013;145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusconi C, Sabatini T, Faggiano P, Ghizzoni G, Oneglia C, Simoncelli U, et al. Prevalence of isolated left ventricular diastolic dysfunction in hypertension as assessed by combined transmitral and pulmonary vein flow Doppler study. Am J Cardiol 2001; 87:357&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao Y, Cooper RS, Durazo-Arvizu R, Mensah GA, Ghali JK. Prediction of mortality risk by different methods of indexation for left ventricular mass. J Am Coll Cardiol 1997; 29:641&#x2013;647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chirinos JA, Segers P, De Buyzere ML, Kronmal RA, Raja MW, De Bacquer D, et al. Left ventricular mass: allometric scaling, normative values, effect of obesity, and prognostic performance. Hypertension 2010; 56:91&#x2013;98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuznetsova T, Cauwenberghs N, Knez J, Yang WY, Herbots L, D&#x2019;hooge J, et al. Additive prognostic value of left ventricular systolic dysfunction in a population-based cohort. Circ Cardiovasc Imaging 2016; 9:e004661.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagueh SF, Smiseth OA, Appleton CP, Byrd BF, Dokainish H, Edvardsen T, et al. Recommendations for the evaluation of left ventricular diastolic function by echocardiography: an update from the American Society of Echocardiography and the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging. J Am Soc Echocardiogr 2016; 29:277&#x2013;314.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sud K, Bhatia KS, Vogel B, Bohra C, Argulian E. Prognostic significance of exercise-induced diastolic dysfunction: a systematic review. Echocardiography 2020; 37:1594&#x2013;1602.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuspidi C, Sala C, Tadic M, Gherbesi E, Grassi G, Mancia G. Prehypertension and subclinical cardiac damage: a meta-analysis of echocardiographic studies. Int J Cardiol 2018; 270:302&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameli M, Pastore MC, Henein MY, Mondillo S. The left atrium and the right ventricle: two supporting chambers to the failing left ventricle. Heart Fail Rev 2019; 24:661&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Popa-Fotea NM, Micheu MM, Oprescu N, Alexandrescu A, Greavu M, Onciul S, et al. The role of left-atrial mechanics assessed by two-dimensional speckle-tracking echocardiography to differentiate hypertrophic cardiomyopathy from hypertensive left-ventricular hypertrophy. Diagnostics (Basel) 2021; 11:814.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemtsova V, Burkard T, Vischer AS. Hypertensive heart disease: a narrative review series - part 2: macrostructural and functional abnormalities. J Clin Med 2023; 12:5723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tadic M, Cuspidi C. Right ventricle in arterial hypertension: did we forget something? J Clin Med 2022; 11:6257.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Liao Y, Zhu Z, Wang S, Li Y, Liang D, et al. Association between cumulative blood pressure in early adulthood and right ventricular structure and function in middle age: the CARDIA study. Clin Cardiol 2022; 45:83&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borgdorff MA, Dickinson MG, Berger RM, Bartelds B. Right ventricular failure due to chronic pressure load: what have we learned in animal models since the NIH working group statement? Heart Fail Rev 2015; 20:475&#x2013;491.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg P, Assadi H, Jones R, Chan WB, Metherall P, Thomas R, et al. Left ventricular fibrosis and hypertrophy are associated with mortality in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction. Sci Rep 2021; 11:617.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham KS, Spears DA, Care M. Evaluation of cardiac hypertrophy in the setting of sudden cardiac death. Forensic Sci Res 2019; 4:223&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee S, Bavishi C, Sardar P, Agarwal V, Krishnamoorthy P, Grodzicki T, Messerli FH. Meta-analysis of left ventricular hypertrophy and sustained arrhythmias. Am J Cardiol 2014; 114:1049&#x2013;1052.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachtell K, Lehto M, Gerdts E, Olsen MH, Hornestam B, Dahl&#xf6;f B, et al. Angiotensin II receptor blockade reduces new-onset atrial fibrillation and subsequent stroke compared to atenolol: the Losartan Intervention For End Point Reduction in Hypertension (LIFE) study. J Am Coll Cardiol 2005; 45:712&#x2013;719.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang SA, Kim HK, Kim DH, Kim YJ, Sohn DW, Oh BH, et al. Left ventricular systolic and diastolic dyssynchrony in asymptomatic hypertensive patients. J Am Soc Echocardiogr 2009; 22:337&#x2013;342.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emiroglu MY, Bulut M, Sahin M, Acar G, Akcakoyun M, Kargin R, et al. Assessment of atrial conduction time in patients with essential hypertension. J Electrocardiol 2011; 44:251&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tribulova N, Okruhlicova L, Novakova S, Pancza D, Bernatova I, Pechanova O, et al. Hypertension-related intermyocyte junction remodelling is associated with a higher incidence of low-K(+)- induced lethal arrhythmias in isolated rat heart. Exp Physiol 2002; 87:195&#x2013;205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fialova M, Dlugosova K, Okruhlicova L, Kristek F, Manoach M, Tribulova N. Adaptation of the heart to hypertension is associated with maladaptive gap junction connexin-43 remodeling. Physiol Res 2008; 57:7&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavrogeni S, Katsi V, Vartela V, Noutsias M, Markousis-Mavrogenis G, Kolovou G, Manolis A. The emerging role of Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance in the evaluation of hypertensive heart disease. BMC Cardiovasc Disord 2017; 17:132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nemtsova V, Vischer AS, Burkard T. Hypertensive heart disease: a narrative review series - part 1: pathophysiology and microstructural changes. J Clin Med 2023; 12:2606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen JS, Pei Y, Li CE, Li YN, Wang QY, Yu J. Comparative efficacy of different types of antihypertensive drugs in reversing left ventricular hypertrophy as determined with echocardiography in hypertensive patients: a network meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2020; 22:2175&#x2013;2183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayin BY, Oto A. Left ventricular hypertrophy: etiology-based therapeutic options. Cardiol Ther 2022; 11:203&#x2013;230.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devereux RB, Wachtell K, Gerdts E, Boman K, Nieminen MS, Papademetriou V, et al. Prognostic significance of left ventricular mass change during treatment of hypertension. JAMA 2004; 292:2350&#x2013;2356.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klingbeil AU, Schneider M, Martus P, Messerli FH, Schmieder RE. A meta-analysis of the effects of treatment on left ventricular mass in essential hypertension. Am J Med 2003; 115:41&#x2013;46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Zhou R, Lu C, Chen Q, Xu T, Li D. Effects of the angiotensin-receptor neprilysin inhibitor on cardiac reverse remodeling: meta-analysis. J Am Heart Assoc 2019; 8:e012272.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonagh TA, Metra M, Adamo M, Gardner RS, Baumbach A, B&#xf6;hm M, et al. ESC Scientific Document Group. 2023 Focused Update of the 2021 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure: developed by the task force for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) With the special contribution of the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur Heart J 2023; 44:3627&#x2013;3639.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tian J, Zhang M, Suo M, Liu D, Wang X, Liu M, et al. Dapagliflozin alleviates cardiac fibrosis through suppressing EndMT and fibroblast activation via AMPK&#x3b1;/TGF&#x3b2;/Smad signalling in type 2 diabetic rats. J Cell Mol Med 2021; 25:7642&#x2013;7659.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morfino P, Aimo A, Castiglione V, G&#xe1;lvez-Mont&#xf3;n C, Emdin M, Bayes-Genis A. Treatment of cardiac fibrosis: from neuro-hormonal inhibitors to CAR-T cell therapy. Heart Fail Rev 2023; 28:555&#x2013;569.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton E, Windebank E, Skiba M, Reid C, Schneider H, Rosenfeldt F, et al. Why did high-dose rosuvastatin not improve cardiac remodeling in chronic heart failure? Mechanistic insights from the UNIVERSE study. Int J Cardiol 2011; 146:404&#x2013;407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zile MR, O&#x2019;Meara E, Claggett B, Prescott MF, Solomon SD, Swedberg K, et al. Effects of sacubitril/valsartan on biomarkers of extracellular matrix regulation in patients with HFrEF. J Am Coll Cardiol 2019; 73:795&#x2013;806.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Floris E, Cozzolino C, Marconi S, Tonicello F, Picchio V, Pagano F, et al. A Review of therapeutic strategies against cardiac fibrosis: from classical pharmacology to novel molecular, epigenetic, and biotechnological approaches. Rev Cardiovasc Med 2023; 24:226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu MP, Zhang YS, Xu X, Zhou Q, Li JD, Yan C. Vinpocetine attenuates pathological cardiac remodeling by inhibiting cardiac hypertrophy and fibrosis. Cardiovasc Drugs Ther 2017; 31:157&#x2013;166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeon KI, Xu X, Aizawa T, Lim JH, Jono H, Kwon DS, et al. Vinpocetine inhibits NF-kappaB-dependent inflammation via an IKK-dependent but PDE-independent mechanism. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 2010; 107:9795&#x2013;9800.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller CL, Cai Y, Oikawa M, Thomas T, Dostmann WR, Zaccolo M, et al. Cyclic nucleotide phosphodiesterase 1A: a key regulator of cardiac fibroblast activation and extracellular matrix remodeling in the heart. Basic Res Cardiol 2011; 106:1023&#x2013;1039.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Zhang Y, Lighthouse JK, Mickelsen DM, Wu J, Yao P, et al. Novel role of cyclic nucleotide phosphodiesterase 10A in pathological cardiac remodeling and dysfunction. Circulation 2020; 141:217&#x2013;233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Xing W, Zhang M, Geng F, Yang H, Zhang H, et al. Antifibrotic cardioprotection of berberine via downregulating myocardial IGF-1 receptor-regulated MMP-2/MMP-9 expression in diabetic rats. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physio 2018; 315:H802&#x2013;H813.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu J, Qiu M, Lu Y, Ji Y, Qian Z, Sun W. Piperlongumine attenuates angiotensin-II-induced cardiac hypertrophy and fibrosis by inhibiting Akt-FoxO1 signalling. Phytomedicine 2021; 82:153461.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsu CP, Zhai P, Yamamoto T, Maejima Y, Matsushima S, Hariharan N, et al. Silent information regulator 1 protects the heart from ischemia/reperfusion. Circulation 2010; 122:2170&#x2013;2182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sciarretta S, Yee D, Nagarajan N, Bianchi F, Saito T, Valenti V, et al. Trehalose-induced activation of autophagy improves cardiac remodeling after myocardial infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol 2018; 71:1999&#x2013;2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuo C, Li X, Huang J, Chen D, Ji K, Yang Y, et al. Osteoglycin attenuates cardiac fibrosis by suppressing cardiac myofibroblast proliferation and migration through antagonizing lysophosphatidic acid 3/matrix metalloproteinase 2/epidermal growth factor receptor signalling. Cardiovas Res 2018; 114:703&#x2013;712.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medzikovic L, Heese H, van Loenen PB, van Roomen CPAA, Hooijkaas IB, Christoffels VM, et al. Nuclear receptor Nur77 controls cardiac fibrosis through distinct actions on fibroblasts and cardiomyocytes. Int J Mol Sci 2021; 22:1600.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Zhuang Y, Yang W, Xie Y, Shang W, Su S, et al. Silencing of METTL3 attenuates cardiac fibrosis induced by myocardial infarction via inhibiting the activation of cardiac fibroblasts. FASEB J 2021; 35:e21162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez P, Sassi Y, Troncone L, Benard L, Ishikawa K, Gordon RE, et al. Deletion of delta-like 1 homologue accelerates fibroblast-myofibroblast differentiation and induces myocardial fibrosis. Eur Heart J 2019; 40:967&#x2013;978.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su SA, Yang D, Wu Y, Xie Y, Zhu W, Cai Z, et al. EphrinB2 regulates cardiac fibrosis through modulating the interaction of Stat3 and TGF-&#x3b2;/Smad3 signaling. Circ Res 2017; 121:617&#x2013;627.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ni C, Chen Y, Xu Y, Zhao J, Li Q, Xiao C, et al. Flavin containing monooxygenase 2 prevents cardiac fibrosis via CYP2J3-SMURF2 axis. Circ Res 2022; 131:189&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markouli M, Strepkos D, Chlamydas S, Piperi C. Histone lysine methyltransferase SETDB1 as a novel target for central nervous system diseases. Prog Neurobiol 2021; 200:101968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kee HJ, Sohn IS, Nam KI, Park JE, Qian YR, Yin Z, et al. Inhibition of histone deacetylation blocks cardiac hypertrophy induced by angiotensin II infusion and aortic banding. Circulation 2006; 113:51&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tseliou E, Fouad J, Reich H, Slipczuk L, de Couto G, Aminzadeh M, et al. Fibroblasts rendered antifibrotic, antiapoptotic, and angiogenic by priming with cardiosphere-derived extracellular membrane vesicles. J Am Coll Cardiol 2015; 66:599&#x2013;611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferreira MPA, Talman V, Torrieri G, Liu DF, Marques G, Moslova K, et al. Dual-drug delivery using dextran-functionalized nanoparticles targeting cardiac fibroblasts for cellular reprogramming. Adv Funct Mater 2018; 28:1705134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rurik JG, Tomb&#xe1;cz I, Yadegari A, M&#xe9;ndez Fern&#xe1;ndez PO, Shewale SV, Li L, et al. CAR T cells produced in vivo to treat cardiac injury. Science 2022; 375:91&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>