<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40172683</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-689X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical systems</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Syst</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hyper-DREAM, a Multimodal Digital Transformation Hypertension Management Platform Integrating Large Language Model and Digital Phenotyping: Multicenter Development and Initial Validation Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>42</StartPage><MedlinePgn>42</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10916-025-02176-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Within the mHealth framework, systematic research that collects and analyzes patient data to establish comprehensive digital health archives for hypertensive patients, and leverages large language models (LLMs) to assist clinicians in health management and Blood Pressure (BP) control remains limited. In this study, our aims to describe the design, development and usability evaluation process of a management platform (Hyper-DREAM) for hypertension. Our multidisciplinary team employed an iterative design approach over the course of a year to develop the Hyper-DREAM platform. This platform's primary functionalities encompass multimodal data collection (personal hypertensive digital phenotype archive), multimodal interventions (BP measurement, medication assistance, behavior modification, and hypertension education) and multimodal interactions (clinician-patient engagement and BP Coach component). In August 2024, the mHealth App Usability Questionnaire (MAUQ) was conducted involving 51 hypertensive patients recruited from three distinct centers. In parallel, six clinicians engaged in management activities and contributed feedback via the Doctor's Software Satisfaction Questionnaire (DSSQ). Concurrently, a real-world comparative experiment was conducted to evaluate the usability of the BP Coach, ChatGPT-4o Mini, ChatGPT-4o and clinicians. The comparative experiment demonstrated that the BP Coach achieved significantly higher scores in utility (mean scores 4.05, SD 0.87) and completeness (mean scores 4.12, SD 0.78) when compared to ChatGPT-4o Mini, ChatGPT-4o, and clinicians. In terms of clarity, the BP Coach was slightly lower than clinicians (mean scores 4.03, SD 0.88). In addition, the BP Coach exhibited lower performance in conciseness (mean scores 3.00, SD 0.96). Clinicians reported a marked improvement in work efficiency (2.67 vs. 4.17, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001) and experienced faster and more effective patient interactions (3.0 vs. 4.17, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.004). Furthermore, the Hyper-DREAM platform significantly decreased work intensity (2.5 vs. 3.5, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.01) and minimized disruptions to daily routines (2.33 vs. 3.55, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.004). The Hyper-DREAM platform demonstrated significantly greater overall satisfaction compared to the WeChat-based standard management (3.33 vs. 4.17, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.01). Additionally, clinicians exhibited a markedly higher willingness to integrate the Hyper-DREAM platform into clinical practice (2.67 vs. 4.17, P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;.001). Furthermore, patient management time decreased from 11.5&#xa0;min (SD 1.87) with Wechat-based standard management to 7.5&#xa0;min (SD 1.84, P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.01) with Hyper-DREAM. Hypertensive patients reported high satisfaction with the Hyper-DREAM platform, including ease of use (mean scores 1.60, SD 0.69), system information arrangement (mean scores 1.69, SD 0.71), and usefulness (mean scores 1.57, SD 0.58). In conclusion, our study presents Hyper-DREAM, a novel artificial intelligence-driven platform for hypertension management, designed to alleviate clinician workload and exhibiting significant promise for clinical application. The Hyper-DREAM platform is distinguished by its user-friendliness, high satisfaction rates, utility, and effective organization of information. Furthermore, the BP Coach component underscores the potential of LLMs in advancing mHealth approaches to hypertension management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yijun</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical Universtiy, 287 Changhuai Road, Longzihu District, Bengbu City, Anhui Province, 430060, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Tongjian</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Institute of Cardiovascular Diseases, Xiangyang Central Hospital, Affliated Hospital of Hubei University of Arts and Science, Xiangyang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Tong</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical Universtiy, 287 Changhuai Road, Longzihu District, Bengbu City, Anhui Province, 430060, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medicine and Department of Cardiology, Renmin Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, 442000, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Wuping</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sun Yat-Sen Memorial Hospital, Sun Yat-Sen University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Kezhong</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Institute of Cardiovascular Diseases, Xiangyang Central Hospital, Affliated Hospital of Hubei University of Arts and Science, Xiangyang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yao</LastName><ForeName>Zhuoya</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical Universtiy, 287 Changhuai Road, Longzihu District, Bengbu City, Anhui Province, 430060, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical Universtiy, 287 Changhuai Road, Longzihu District, Bengbu City, Anhui Province, 430060, P.R. China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Siyang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Institute of Cardiovascular Diseases, Xiangyang Central Hospital, Affliated Hospital of Hubei University of Arts and Science, Xiangyang, Hubei, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qin</LastName><ForeName>Fanglin</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mental Health Center and Psychiatric Laboratory, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, 610041, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xu</LastName><ForeName>Yannan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical Universtiy, Bengbu, Anhui, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tan</LastName><ForeName>Liguo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Clinical Medicine and Department of Cardiology, Renmin Hospital, Hubei University of Medicine, Shiyan, 442000, Hubei, China. tanliguo2001@126.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Jinjun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical Universtiy, 287 Changhuai Road, Longzihu District, Bengbu City, Anhui Province, 430060, P.R. China. byyfyliujinjun@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Bengbu Medical Universtiy, 287 Changhuai Road, Longzihu District, Bengbu City, Anhui Province, 430060, P.R. China. junwang0607@163.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>202427b10020086, 202427b10020089, 202427b10020097</GrantID><Agency>Clinical research transformation project of Anhui Province</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024bydjk001, 2024bydjk002, 2024bydjk005</GrantID><Agency>Research Funds of Joint Research Center for Regional Diseases of IHM</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2023AH051901</GrantID><Agency>Key Research Projects in Higher Education Institutions of Anhui Province</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D023361">Validation Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Syst</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7806056</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0148-5598</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063731" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mobile Applications</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000098342" MajorTopicYN="N">Large Language Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ChatGPT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital phenotyping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital transformation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Large language models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mobile health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multimodal intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Precision medicine</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40172683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10916-025-02176-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10916-025-02176-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Burden of disease scenarios for 204 countries and territories, 2022&#x2013;2050: a forecasting analysis for the global burden of disease study 2021. Lancet 2024&#x2013;05&#x2013;18;403(10440):2204&#x2013;2256. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(24)00685-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang JG, Zhang W, Li Y, Liu L. Hypertension in china: epidemiology and treatment initiatives. Nat Rev Cardiol 2023&#x2013;08&#x2013;01;20(8):531&#x2013;545. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41569-022-00829-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The W. Report on cardiovascular health and diseases in china 2022: an updated summary. Biomed Environ Sci 2023&#x2013;08&#x2013;20;36(8):669&#x2013;701. https://doi.org/10.3967/bes2023.106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Chen Z, Zhang L, Wang X, Hao G, Zhang Z, et al. Status of hypertension in china: results from the china hypertension survey, 2012&#x2013;2015. Circulation 2018&#x2013;05&#x2013;29;137(22):2344&#x2013;2356. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.117.032380</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parmar MP, Kaur M, Bhavanam S, Mulaka G, Ishfaq L, Vempati R, et al. A systematic review of the effects of smoking on the cardiovascular system and general health. Cureus 2023&#x2013;04&#x2013;01;15(4):e38073. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.38073</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmaleh-Sachs A, Schwartz JL, Bramante CT, Nicklas JM, Gudzune KA, Jay M. Obesity management in adults: a review. Jama 2023&#x2013;11&#x2013;28;330(20):2000&#x2013;2015. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2023.19897</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta DK, Lewis CE, Varady KA, Su YR, Madhur MS, Lackland DT, et al. Effect of dietary sodium on blood pressure: a crossover trial. Jama 2023&#x2013;12&#x2013;19;330(23):2258&#x2013;2266. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2023.23651</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aljuraiban GS, Gibson R, Chan DS, Van Horn L, Chan Q. The role of diet in the prevention of hypertension and management of blood pressure: an umbrella review of meta-analyses of interventional and observational studies. Adv Nutr 2024&#x2013;01&#x2013;01;15(1):100123. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.advnut.2023.09.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim MM, Damasceno A. Hypertension in developing countries. Lancet 2012&#x2013;08&#x2013;11;380(9841):611&#x2013;619. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(12)60861-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spatz ES, Ginsburg GS, Rumsfeld JS, Turakhia MP. Wearable digital health technologies for monitoring in cardiovascular medicine. N Engl J Med 2024&#x2013;01&#x2013;25;390(4):346&#x2013;356. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMra2301903</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soto JT, Hershman SG, Ashley EA. Combining digital data and artificial intelligence for cardiovascular health. Cardiovasc Res 2021&#x2013;07&#x2013;27;117(9):e116-e117. https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvab211 ]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu H, Long H. The effect of smartphone app-based interventions for patients with hypertension: systematic review and meta-analysis. Jmir Mhealth Uhealth 2020&#x2013;10&#x2013;19;8(10):e21759. https://doi.org/10.2196/21759</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arshed M, Mahmud A, Minhat HS, Lim PY, Zakar R. Effectiveness of a multifaceted mobile health intervention (multi-aid-package) in medication adherence and treatment outcomes among patients with hypertension in a low- to middle-income country: randomized controlled trial. Jmir Mhealth Uhealth 2024&#x2013;06&#x2013;19;12:e50248. https://doi.org/10.2196/50248</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Guo F, Wang J, Li Z, Tan W, Xie M, et al. Efficacy of a wechat-based multimodal digital transformation management model in new-onset mild to moderate hypertension: randomized clinical trial. J Med Internet Res 2023&#x2013;12&#x2013;04;25:e52464. https://doi.org/10.2196/52464</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khera R, Oikonomou EK, Nadkarni GN, Morley JR, Wiens J, Butte AJ, et al. Transforming cardiovascular care with artificial intelligence: from discovery to practice: jacc state-of-the-art review. J Am Coll Cardiol 2024&#x2013;07&#x2013;02;84(1):97&#x2013;114. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2024.05.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu JR, Power JR, Zannad F, Lam C. Artificial intelligence and digital tools for design and execution of cardiovascular clinical trials. Eur Heart J 2024&#x2013;11&#x2013;29. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehae794</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leitner J, Chiang PH, Agnihotri P, Dey S. The effect of an ai-based, autonomous, digital health intervention using precise lifestyle guidance on blood pressure in adults with hypertension: single-arm nonrandomized trial. Jmir Cardio 2024&#x2013;05&#x2013;28;8:e51916. https://doi.org/10.2196/51916</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yano Y, Nishiyama A, Suzuki Y, Morimoto S, Morikawa T, Gohda T, et al. Relevance of chatgpt's responses to common hypertension-related patient inquiries. Hypertension 2024&#x2013;01&#x2013;01;81(1):e1-e4. https://doi.org/10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.123.22084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niko MM, Karbasi Z, Kazemi M, Zahmatkeshan M. Comparing chatgpt and bing, in response to the home blood pressure monitoring (hbpm) knowledge checklist. Hypertens Res 2024&#x2013;05&#x2013;01;47(5):1401&#x2013;1409. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41440-024-01624-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peng C, Yang X, Chen A, Smith KE, PourNejatian N, Costa AB, et al. A study of generative large language model for medical research and healthcare. Npj Digit Med 2023&#x2013;11&#x2013;16;6(1):210. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41746-023-00958-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrusic I, Ha WS, Labastida-Ramirez A, Messina R, Onan D, Tana C, et al. Influence of next-generation artificial intelligence on headache research, diagnosis and treatment: the junior editorial board members' vision - part 1. J Headache Pain 2024&#x2013;09&#x2013;13;25(1):151. https://doi.org/10.1186/s10194-024-01847-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raghunathan R, Jacobs AR, Sant VR, King LJ, Rothberger G, Prescott J, et al. Can large language models address unmet patient information needs and reduce provider burnout in the management of thyroid disease? Surgery 2024&#x2013;10&#x2013;17. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surg.2024.06.075</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choudhury A, Shamszare H. The impact of performance expectancy, workload, risk, and satisfaction on trust in chatgpt: cross-sectional survey analysis. Jmir Hum Factors 2024&#x2013;05&#x2013;27;11:e55399. https://doi.org/10.2196/55399</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez JA, Alsentzer E, Bates DW. Leveraging large language models to foster equity in healthcare. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2024&#x2013;09&#x2013;01;31(9):2147&#x2013;2150. https://doi.org/10.1093/jamia/ocae055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Napoleone J, Linke S, Noble M, Turken M, Rakotz M, et al. Long-term results of a digital hypertension self-management program: retrospective cohort study. Jmir Cardio 2023&#x2013;08&#x2013;24;7:e43489. https://doi.org/10.2196/43489</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen B, Dou Y, Yu X, Ma D. Influence of internet-based health management on control of clinical parameters in patients with hypertension: four-year longitudinal study. J Med Internet Res 2023&#x2013;03&#x2013;20;25:e42896. https://doi.org/10.2196/42896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zangger G, Bricca A, Liaghat B, Juhl CB, Mortensen SR, Andersen RM, et al. Benefits and harms of digital health interventions promoting physical activity in people with chronic conditions: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Internet Res 2023&#x2013;07&#x2013;06;25:e46439. https://doi.org/10.2196/46439</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eyles H, Grey J, Jiang Y, Umali E, McLean R, Te ML, et al. Effectiveness of a sodium-reduction smartphone app and reduced-sodium salt to lower sodium intake in adults with hypertension: findings from the salt alternatives randomized controlled trial. Jmir Mhealth Uhealth 2023&#x2013;03&#x2013;09;11:e43675. https://doi.org/10.2196/43675</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya S, Neupane G, Seals A, Kc M, Giustini D, Sharma S, et al. Self-measured blood pressure-guided pharmacotherapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis of united states-based telemedicine trials. Hypertension 2024&#x2013;03&#x2013;01;81(3):648&#x2013;657. https://doi.org/10.1161/HYPERTENSIONAHA.123.22109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaidyam A, Halamka J, Torous J. Enabling research and clinical use of patient-generated health data (the mindlamp platform): digital phenotyping study. Jmir Mhealth Uhealth 2022&#x2013;01&#x2013;07;10(1):e30557. https://doi.org/10.2196/30557</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Gong Z, Wang G, Jia J, Xu Y, Zhao J, et al. Chatgpt performs on the chinese national medical licensing examination. J Med Syst 2023;47:86. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10916-023-01961-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran H, Yang Z, Yao Z, Yu H. Bioinstruct: instruction tuning of large language models for biomedical natural language processing. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2024&#x2013;09&#x2013;01;31(9):1821&#x2013;1832. https://doi.org/10.1093/jamia/ocae122</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kee X, Sng G, Lim D, Tung J, Abdullah HR, Chowdury AR. Use of a large language model with instruction-tuning for reliable clinical frailty scoring. J Am Geriatr Soc 2024&#x2013;12&#x2013;01;72(12):3849&#x2013;3854. https://doi.org/10.1111/jgs.19114</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nahass GR, Chin SW, Scharf IM, Kazmouz S, Kaplan N, Chiu R, et al. Prompt engineering to increase gpt3.5's performance on the plastic surgery in-service exams. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg 2024&#x2013;11&#x2013;01;98:158&#x2013;160. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bjps.2024.09.001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu S, Wright AP, Mccoy AB, Huang SS, Genkins JZ, Peterson JF, et al. Using large language model to guide patients to create efficient and comprehensive clinical care message. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2024&#x2013;08&#x2013;01;31(8):1665&#x2013;1670. https://doi.org/10.1093/jamia/ocae142</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Bao J, Setiawan I, Saptono A, Parmanto B. The mhealth app usability questionnaire (mauq): development and validation study. Jmir Mhealth Uhealth 2019&#x2013;04&#x2013;11;7(4):e11500. https://doi.org/10.2196/11500</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boima V, Doku A, Agyekum F, Tuglo LS, Agyemang C. Effectiveness of digital health interventions on blood pressure control, lifestyle behaviours and adherence to medication in patients with hypertension in low-income and middle-income countries: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Eclinicalmedicine 2024&#x2013;03&#x2013;01;69:102432. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.eclinm.2024.102432</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Z, Xu Y, Tang L, Wu M, Wu B, Zhu T, et al. Predicting long-term prognosis after percutaneous coronary intervention in patients with new onset st-elevation myocardial infarction: development and external validation of a nomogram model. Cardiovasc Diabetol 2023&#x2013;04&#x2013;13;22(1):87. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12933-023-01820-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou T, Wang Y, Xu Y, Xu L, Tang L, Yang Y, et al. Multimodal data integration for enhanced longitudinal prediction for cardiac and cerebrovascular events following initial diagnosis of obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. J Glob Health 2024&#x2013;05&#x2013;17;14:4103. https://doi.org/10.7189/jgh.14.04103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang L, Wu M, Xu Y, Zhu T, Fang C, Ma K, et al. Multimodal data-driven prognostic model for predicting new-onset st-elevation myocardial infarction following emergency percutaneous coronary intervention. Inflamm Res 2023&#x2013;09&#x2013;01;72(9):1799&#x2013;1809. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00011-023-01781-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Wu X, Sun J, Xu T, Zhu T, Yu F, et al. Prediction of major adverse cardiovascular events in patients with acute coronary syndrome: development and validation of a non-invasive nomogram model based on autonomic nervous system assessment. Front Cardiovasc Med 2022&#x2013;01&#x2013;20;9:1053470. https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2022.1053470</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Xu Y, Zhu J, Wu B, Wang Y, Tan L, et al. Multimodal data-driven, vertical visualization prediction model for early prediction of atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in patients with new-onset hypertension. J Hypertens 2024&#x2013;10&#x2013;01;42(10):1757&#x2013;1768. https://doi.org/10.1097/HJH.0000000000003798</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Wang Y, Duan S, Xu L, Xu Y, Yin W, et al. Multimodal data-driven prognostic model for predicting long-term prognosis in patients with ischemic cardiomyopathy and heart failure with preserved ejection fraction after coronary artery bypass grafting: a multicenter cohort study. J Am Heart Assoc 2024&#x2013;12&#x2013;03;13(23):e36970. https://doi.org/10.1161/JAHA.124.036970</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun T, Xu X, Ding Z, Xie H, Ma L, Zhang J, et al. Development of a health behavioral digital intervention for patients with hypertension based on an intelligent health promotion system and wechat: randomized controlled trial. Jmir Mhealth Uhealth 2024&#x2013;04&#x2013;05;12:e53006. https://doi.org/10.2196/53006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu F, Song T, Yu P, Deng N, Guan Y, Yang Y, et al. Efficacy of an mhealth app to support patients' self-management of hypertension: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res 2023&#x2013;12&#x2013;19;25:e43809. https://doi.org/10.2196/43809</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalakoti M, Wong S, Lee W, Lee J, Yang H, Loong S, et al. Incorporating ai into cardiovascular diseases prevention-insights from singapore. Lancet Reg Health West Pac 2024&#x2013;07&#x2013;01;48:101102. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lanwpc.2024.101102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kario K, Nomura A, Harada N, Okura A, Nakagawa K, Tanigawa T, et al. Efficacy of a digital therapeutics system in the management of essential hypertension: the herb-dh1 pivotal trial. Eur Heart J 2021&#x2013;10&#x2013;21;42(40):4111&#x2013;4122. https://doi.org/10.1093/eurheartj/ehab559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedi S, Liu Y, Orr-Ewing L, Dash D, Koyejo S, Callahan A, et al. Testing and evaluation of health care applications of large language models: a systematic review. Jama 2024&#x2013;10&#x2013;15. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2024.21700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nolin-Lapalme A, Theriault-Lauzier P, Corbin D, Tastet O, Sharma A, Hussin JG, et al. Maximising large language model utility in cardiovascular care: a practical guide. Can J Cardiol 2024&#x2013;10&#x2013;01;40(10):1774&#x2013;1787. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjca.2024.05.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascella M, Montomoli J, Bellini V, Bignami E. Evaluating the feasibility of chatgpt in healthcare: an analysis of multiple clinical and research scenarios. J Med Syst 2023;47:33. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10916-023-01925-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cascella M, Semeraro F, Montomoli J, Bellini V, Piazza O, Bignami E. The breakthrough of large language models release for medical applications: 1-year timeline and perspectives. J Med Syst 2024;48:22. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10916-024-02045-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue X, Zhang D, Sun C, Shi Y, Wang R, Tan T, et al. Xiaoqing: a q&amp;a model for glaucoma based on llms. Comput Biol Med 2024&#x2013;05&#x2013;01;174:108399. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compbiomed.2024.108399</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sezgin E. Redefining virtual assistants in health care: the future with large language models. J Med Internet Res 2024&#x2013;01&#x2013;19;26:e53225. https://doi.org/10.2196/53225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tripathi S, Sukumaran R, Cook TS. Efficient healthcare with large language models: optimizing clinical workflow and enhancing patient care. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2024&#x2013;05&#x2013;20;31(6):1436&#x2013;1440. https://doi.org/10.1093/jamia/ocad258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feretzakis G, Papaspyridis K, Gkoulalas-Divanis A, Verykios VS. Privacy-preserving techniques in generative ai and large language models: a narrative review. Information 2024&#x2013;01&#x2013;01;15(11). https://doi.org/10.3390/info15110697</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feretzakis G, Verykios VS. Trustworthy ai: securing sensitive data in large language models. Ai 2024&#x2013;01&#x2013;01;5(4):2773&#x2013;2800. https://doi.org/10.3390/ai5040134</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denecke K, May R, Rivera-Romero O. Transformer models in healthcare: a survey and thematic analysis of potentials, shortcomings and risks. J Med Syst. 2024;48:23. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10916-024-02043-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao SJ, Isath A, Krishnan P, Tangsrivimol JA, Virk H, Wang Z, et al. Chatgpt: a conceptual review of applications and utility in the field of medicine. J Med Syst 2024;48:59. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10916-024-02043-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalodanis K, Rizomiliotis P, Anagnostopoulos D. European artificial intelligence act: an ai security approach. Information &amp; Computer Security 2024&#x2013;01&#x2013;01;32(3):265&#x2013;281. https://doi.org/10.1108/ICS-10-2022-0165</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willms A, Rhodes RE, Liu S. The development of a hypertension prevention and financial-incentive mhealth program using a "no-code" mobile app builder: development and usability study. Jmir Form Res 2023&#x2013;04&#x2013;05;7:e43823. https://doi.org/10.2196/43823</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessa T, S HM, Alsulamy N, de Witte L. Using a commercially available app for the self-management of hypertension: acceptance and usability study in saudi arabia. Jmir Mhealth Uhealth 2021&#x2013;02&#x2013;09;9(2):e24177. https://doi.org/10.2196/24177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X, Wang Y, Wang Y, Wang J, Peng C, Cheng S, et al. The effectiveness of digital animation-based multistage education for patients with atrial fibrillation catheter ablation: randomized clinical trial. J Med Internet Res 2025;27:e65685. https://doi.org/10.2196/65685</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>