<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39250181</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2291-5222</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>09</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR mHealth and uHealth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Mhealth Uhealth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy of the mHealth-Based Exercise Intervention re.flex for Patients With Knee Osteoarthritis: Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e54356</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e54356</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e54356</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/54356</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Exercise therapy is recommended by international guidelines as a core treatment for patients with knee osteoarthritis. However, there is a significant gap between recommendations and practice in health care. Digital exercise apps are promising to help solve this undersupply.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aims to evaluate the efficacy of a 12-week fully automated app-based exercise intervention with and without a supporting knee brace on health-related outcomes, performance measures, and adherence in patients with knee osteoarthritis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This closed user group trial included participants with moderate to severe unicondylar painful knee osteoarthritis. Randomization was 1:1:2 into an intervention group (IG) with 2 subgroups (app-based training [IG A] and app-based training and a supportive knee brace [IG AB]) and a control group (CG). The intervention included a 12-week home exercise program with 3 sessions per week. Instructions for the exercises were given via the app and monitored using 2 accelerometers placed below and above the affected knee joint. Participants in the CG did not receive any study intervention but were allowed to make use of usual care. Osteoarthritis-specific pain (Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score) was defined as the primary outcome, and secondary outcomes included all other Knee Injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score subscales, general health-related quality of life (Veterans RAND 12-item Health Survey), psychological measures (eg, exercise self-efficacy), performance measures (strength and postural control), and the monitoring of adherence and safety. Outcomes were assessed at baseline and after 12 weeks. Intervention effects were calculated using baseline-adjusted analysis of covariance for the joint comparison of IG A and IG AB versus the CG using a per-protocol approach. Subgroup analyses were conducted for each IG separately.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 61 participants were included (IG: n=30, 49%; CG: n=31, 51%; male: n=31, 51%; female: n=30, 49%; mean age 62.9, SD 8.5 years; mean BMI 27.7, SD 4.5 kg/m<sup>2</sup>). Analysis revealed statistically significant effects in favor of the IG for pain reduction (P&lt;.001; effect size [ES]=0.76), improvements in physical function (P&lt;.001; ES=0.64), improvements in symptoms (P=.01; ES=0.53), improvements in sport and recreation activities (P=.02; ES=0.47), improvements in knee-related quality of life (P&lt;.001; ES=0.76), and improvements in the physical component of general health-related quality of life (P&lt;.001; ES=0.74). Mean differences ranged from 6.0 to 13.2 points (scale range 0-100). ESs indicated small to medium effects. No effects were found for psychological and performance measures. Participants adhered to 92.5% (899/972) of all scheduled exercise sessions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Individuals with knee osteoarthritis undergoing a 12-week sensor-assisted app-based exercise intervention with or without an additional knee brace experienced clinically meaningful treatment effects regarding pain relief and improvements in physical function as well as other osteoarthritis-specific concerns compared to controls.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">German Clinical Trials Register (DRKS) DRKS00023269; https://drks.de/search/de/trial/DRKS00023269.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Valerie Dieter, Pia Janssen, Inga Krauss. Originally published in JMIR mHealth and uHealth (https://mhealth.jmir.org), 09.09.2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dieter</LastName><ForeName>Valerie</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1874-115X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Medical Clinic, University Hospital T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interfaculty Research Institute for Sports and Physical Activity, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janssen</LastName><ForeName>Pia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-9965-7566</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Medical Clinic, University Hospital T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interfaculty Research Institute for Sports and Physical Activity, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krauss</LastName><ForeName>Inga</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6818-6276</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Medical Clinic, University Hospital T&#xfc;bingen, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Interfaculty Research Institute for Sports and Physical Activity, T&#xfc;bingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Mhealth Uhealth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101624439</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2291-5222</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteoarthritis, Knee</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="Y">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063731" MajorTopicYN="N">Mobile Applications</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital app</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee brace</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee osteoarthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile health</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: This study was an investigator-initiated trial in cooperation with an industrial partner, the financial supporter of the study. The authors declare no further potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39250181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11420596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/54356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v12i1e54356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cross M, Smith E, Hoy D, Nolte S, Ackerman I, Fransen M, Bridgett L, Williams S, Guillemin F, Hill CL, Laslett LL, Jones G, Cicuttini F, Osborne R, Vos T, Buchbinder R, Woolf A, March L. The global burden of hip and knee osteoarthritis: estimates from the Global Burden of Disease 2010 study. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014 Jul 19;73(7):1323&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1136/annrheumdis-2013-204763.annrheumdis-2013-204763</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2013-204763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24553908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vos T, Flaxman AD, Naghavi M, Lozano R, Michaud C, Ezzati M, Shibuya K, Salomon JA, S S, Aboyans V, Abraham J, Ackerman I, Aggarwal R, Ahn SY, Ali MK, Alvarado M, Anderson HR, Anderson LM, Andrews KG, Atkinson C, Baddour LM, Bahalim AN, Barker-Collo S, Barrero LH, Bartels DH, Bas&#xe1;&#xf1;ez MG, Baxter A, Bell ML, Benjamin EJ, Bennett D, Bernab&#xe9; E, Bhalla K, Bhandari B, Bikbov B, Bin Abdulhak A, Birbeck G, Black JA, Blencowe H, Blore JD, Blyth F, Bolliger I, Bonaventure A, Boufous S, Bourne R, Boussinesq M, Braithwaite T, Brayne C, Bridgett L, Brooker S, Brooks P, Brugha TS, Bryan-Hancock C, Bucello C, Buchbinder R, Buckle G, Budke CM, Burch M, Burney P, Burstein R, Calabria B, Canter CE, Carabin H, Carapetis J, Carmona L, Cella C, Charlson F, Chen H, Cheng AT, Chou D, Chugh SS, Coffeng LE, Colan SD, Colquhoun S, Colson KE, Condon J, Connor MD, Cooper LT, Corriere M, Cortinovis M, de Vaccaro KC, Couser W, Cowie BC, Criqui MH, Cross M, Dabhadkar KC, Dahiya M, Dahodwala N, Damsere-Derry J, Danaei G, Davis A, De Leo D, Degenhardt L, Dellavalle R, Delossantos A, Denenberg J, Derrett S, Des Jarlais DC, Dharmaratne SD, Dherani M, Diaz-Torne C, Dolk H, Dorsey ER, Driscoll T, Duber H, Ebel B, Edmond K, Elbaz A, Ali SE, Erskine H, Erwin PJ, Espindola P, Ewoigbokhan SE, Farzadfar F, Feigin V, Felson DT, Ferrari A, Ferri CP, F&#xe8;vre EM, Finucane MM, Flaxman S, Flood L, Foreman K, Forouzanfar MH, Fowkes FG, Franklin R, Fransen M, Freeman MK, Gabbe BJ, Gabriel SE, Gakidou E, Ganatra HA, Garcia B, Gaspari F, Gillum RF, Gmel G, Gosselin R, Grainger R, Groeger J, Guillemin F, Gunnell D, Gupta R, Haagsma J, Halasa YA, Hall W, Haring D, Haro JM, Harrison JE, Havmoeller R, Hay RJ, Higashi H, Hill C, Hoen B, Hoffman H, Hotez PJ, Hoy D, Huang JJ, Ibeanusi SE, Jacobsen KH, James SL, Jarvis D, Jasrasaria R, Jayaraman S, Johns N, Jonas JB, Karthikeyan G, Kassebaum N, Kawakami N, Keren A, Khoo JP, King CH, Knowlton LM, Kobusingye O, Koranteng A, Krishnamurthi R, Lalloo R, Laslett LL, Lathlean T, Leasher JL, Lee YY, Leigh J, Lim SS, Limb E, Lin JK, Lipnick M, Lipshultz SE, Liu W, Loane M, Ohno SL, Lyons R, Ma J, Mabweijano J, MacIntyre MF, Malekzadeh R, Mallinger L, Manivannan S, Marcenes W, March L, Margolis DJ, Marks GB, Marks R, Matsumori A, Matzopoulos R, Mayosi BM, McAnulty JH, McDermott MM, McGill N, McGrath J, Medina-Mora ME, Meltzer M, Mensah GA, Merriman TR, Meyer AC, Miglioli V, Miller M, Miller TR, Mitchell PB, Mocumbi AO, Moffitt TE, Mokdad AA, Monasta L, Montico M, Moradi-Lakeh M, Moran A, Morawska L, Mori R, Murdoch ME, Mwaniki MK, Naidoo K, Nair MN, Naldi L, Narayan KM, Nelson PK, Nelson RG, Nevitt MC, Newton CR, Nolte S, Norman P, Norman R, O'Donnell M, O'Hanlon S, Olives C, Omer SB, Ortblad K, Osborne R, Ozgediz D, Page A, Pahari B, Pandian JD, Rivero AP, Patten SB, Pearce N, Padilla RP, Perez-Ruiz F, Perico N, Pesudovs K, Phillips D, Phillips MR, Pierce K, Pion S, Polanczyk GV, Polinder S, Pope CA, Popova S, Porrini E, Pourmalek F, Prince M, Pullan RL, Ramaiah KD, Ranganathan D, Razavi H, Regan M, Rehm JT, Rein DB, Remuzzi G, Richardson K, Rivara FP, Roberts T, Robinson C, De Le&#xf2;n FR, Ronfani L, Room R, Rosenfeld LC, Rushton L, Sacco RL, Saha S, Sampson U, Sanchez-Riera L, Sanman E, Schwebel DC, Scott JG, Segui-Gomez M, Shahraz S, Shepard DS, Shin H, Shivakoti R, Singh D, Singh GM, Singh JA, Singleton J, Sleet DA, Sliwa K, Smith E, Smith JL, Stapelberg NJ, Steer A, Steiner T, Stolk WA, Stovner LJ, Sudfeld C, Syed S, Tamburlini G, Tavakkoli M, Taylor HR, Taylor JA, Taylor WJ, Thomas B, Thomson WM, Thurston GD, Tleyjeh IM, Tonelli M, Towbin JA, Truelsen T, Tsilimbaris MK, Ubeda C, Undurraga EA, van der Werf MJ, van Os J, Vavilala MS, Venketasubramanian N, Wang M, Wang W, Watt K, Weatherall DJ, Weinstock MA, Weintraub R, Weisskopf MG, Weissman MM, White RA, Whiteford H, Wiersma ST, Wilkinson JD, Williams HC, Williams SR, Witt E, Wolfe F, Woolf AD, Wulf S, Yeh PH, Zaidi AK, Zheng ZJ, Zonies D, Lopez AD, Murray CJ, AlMazroa MA, Memish ZA. Years lived with disability (YLDs) for 1160 sequelae of 289 diseases and injuries 1990-2010: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. Lancet. 2012 Dec 15;380(9859):2163&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(12)61729-2. 
 
S0140-6736(12)61729-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(12)61729-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6350784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs J, Rabenberg M, Scheidt-Nave C. Pr&#xe4;valenz ausgew&#xe4;hlter muskuloskelettaler Erkrankungen. Bundesgesundheitsblatt Gesundheitsforschung Gesundheitsschutz. 2013 May 25;56(5-6):678&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1007/s00103-013-1687-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00103-013-1687-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23703486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Doherty M, Peat G, Bierma-Zeinstra MA, Arden NK, Bresnihan B, Herrero-Beaumont G, Kirschner S, Leeb BF, Lohmander LS, Mazi&#xe8;res B, Pavelka K, Punzi L, So AK, Tuncer T, Watt I, Bijlsma JW. EULAR evidence-based recommendations for the diagnosis of knee osteoarthritis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2010 Mar 17;69(3):483&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1136/ard.2009.113100.ard.2009.113100</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2009.113100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19762361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandes L, Hagen KB, Bijlsma JW, Andreassen O, Christensen P, Conaghan PG, Doherty M, Geenen R, Hammond A, Kjeken I, Lohmander LS, Lund H, Mallen CD, Nava T, Oliver S, Pavelka K, Pitsillidou I, da Silva JA, de la Torre J, Zanoli G, Vliet Vlieland TP, European League Against Rheumatism (EULAR)  EULAR recommendations for the non-pharmacological core management of hip and knee osteoarthritis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2013 Jul;72(7):1125&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1136/annrheumdis-2012-202745. 
 
annrheumdis-2012-202745</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2012-202745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23595142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAlindon TE, Bannuru RR, Sullivan MC, Arden NK, Berenbaum F, Bierma-Zeinstra S, Hawker G, Henrotin Y, Hunter D, Kawaguchi H, Kwoh K, Lohmander S, Rannou F, Roos E, Underwood M. OARSI guidelines for the non-surgical management of knee osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2014 Mar;22(3):363&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2014.01.003. 
 
S1063-4584(14)00016-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2014.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24462672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xf6;ve J. S2k-Leitlinie gonarthrose. The Association of Scientific Medical Societies in Germany. 2018.  [2024-04-29].  
 https://register.awmf.org/de/leitlinien/detail/187-050
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bannuru RR, Osani MC, Vaysbrot EE, Arden NK, Bennell K, Bierma-Zeinstra S, Kraus V, Lohmander L, Abbott J, Bhandari M, Blanco F, Espinosa R, Haugen I, Lin J, Mandl L, Moilanen E, Nakamura N, Snyder-Mackler L, Trojian T, Underwood M, McAlindon T. OARSI guidelines for the non-surgical management of knee, hip, and polyarticular osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2019 Nov;27(11):1578&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2019.06.011. 
 
S1063-4584(19)31116-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2019.06.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31278997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fransen M, McConnell S, Harmer AR, Van der Esch M, Simic M, Bennell KL. Exercise for osteoarthritis of the knee: a Cochrane systematic review. Br J Sports Med. 2015 Dec 24;49(24):1554&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2015-095424.bjsports-2015-095424</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bjsports-2015-095424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26405113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kolasinski SL, Neogi T, Hochberg MC, Oatis C, Guyatt G, Block J, Callahan L, Copenhaver C, Dodge C, Felson D, Gellar K, Harvey WF, Hawker G, Herzig E, Kwoh CK, Nelson AE, Samuels J, Scanzello C, White D, Wise B, Altman RD, DiRenzo D, Fontanarosa J, Giradi G, Ishimori M, Misra D, Shah AA, Shmagel AK, Thoma LM, Turgunbaev M, Turner AS, Reston J. 2019 American College of Rheumatology/Arthritis Foundation guideline for the Management of Osteoarthritis of the Hand, Hip, and Knee. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2020 Feb 06;72(2):220&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1002/art.41142. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.41142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10518852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31908163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs H, Callhoff J, Albrecht K, Postler A, Saam J, Lange T, Goronzy J, G&#xfc;nther KP, Hoffmann F. Use of physical therapy in patients with osteoarthritis in Germany: an analysis of a linkage of claims and survey data. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2021 Jul 28;73(7):1013&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1002/acr.24365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.24365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32609432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagen KB, Smedslund G, &#xd8;ster&#xe5;s N, Jamtvedt G. Quality of community-based osteoarthritis care: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2016 Oct 16;68(10):1443&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1002/acr.22891. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.22891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26991934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell KL, Dobson F, Hinman RS. Exercise in osteoarthritis: moving from prescription to adherence. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2014 Feb;28(1):93&#x2013;117. doi: 10.1016/j.berh.2014.01.009.S1521-6942(14)00010-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.berh.2014.01.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24792947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biebl JT, Huber S, Rykala M, Kraft E, Lorenz A. Attitudes and expectations of health care professionals toward app-based therapy in patients with osteoarthritis of the Hip or Knee: questionnaire study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020 Oct 28;8(10):e21704. doi: 10.2196/21704. 
 
v8i10e21704</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/21704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33112255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durst J, Roesel I, Sudeck G, Sassenberg K, Krauss I. Comparison of human versus digital instructions for exercise in patients with hip osteoarthritis: results of a non-inferiority randomized cross-over trial. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2020 Apr;28:S463. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2020.02.725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2020.02.725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7551118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32985991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossen D, Veenhof C, Dekker J, de Bakker D. The usability and preliminary effectiveness of a web-based physical activity intervention in patients with knee and/or hip osteoarthritis. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2013 May 28;13(1):61. doi: 10.1186/1472-6947-13-61. 
 
1472-6947-13-61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6947-13-61</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3671204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23714120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barak A, Klein B, Proudfoot JG. Defining internet-supported therapeutic interventions. Ann Behav Med. 2009 Aug 29;38(1):4&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1007/s12160-009-9130-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12160-009-9130-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19787305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennison L, Morrison L, Conway G, Yardley L. Opportunities and challenges for smartphone applications in supporting health behavior change: qualitative study. J Med Internet Res. 2013 Apr 18;15(4):e86. doi: 10.2196/jmir.2583. 
 
v15i4e86</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.2583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3636318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23598614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen T, Or CK, Chen J. Effects of technology-supported exercise programs on the knee pain, physical function, and quality of life of individuals with knee osteoarthritis&#xa0;and/or chronic knee pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2021 Feb 15;28(2):414&#x2013;23. doi: 10.1093/jamia/ocaa282. 
 
6000401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocaa282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7883981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33236109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf6;nsson T, Dell'Isola A, Lohmander LS, Wagner P, Cronstr&#xf6;m A. Comparison of face-to-face vs digital delivery of an osteoarthritis treatment program for hip or knee osteoarthritis. JAMA Netw Open. 2022 Nov 01;5(11):e2240126. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.40126. 
 
2798148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.40126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9634502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36326763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber F, M&#xfc;ller C, Bahns C, Kopkow C, F&#xe4;rber F, Gellert P, Otte I, Vollmar HC, Brannath W, Diederich F, Kloep S, Rothgang H, Dieter V, Krau&#xdf; I, Kloek C, Veenhof C, Collisi S, Repschl&#xe4;ger U, B&#xf6;binger H, Gr&#xfc;neberg C, Thiel C, Peschke D. Smartphone-assisted training with education for patients with hip and/or knee osteoarthritis (SmArt-E): study protocol for a multicentre pragmatic randomized controlled trial. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2023 Mar 23;24(1):221. doi: 10.1186/s12891-023-06255-7. 
 
10.1186/s12891-023-06255-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12891-023-06255-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10034894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36959595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelle T, Bevers K, van der Palen J, van den Hoogen FH, van den Ende CH. Effect of the dr. Bart application on healthcare use and clinical outcomes in people with osteoarthritis of the knee and/or hip in the Netherlands; a randomized controlled trial. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2020 Apr;28(4):418&#x2013;27. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2020.02.831. 
 
S1063-4584(20)30900-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2020.02.831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32119972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mecklenburg G, Smittenaar P, Erhart-Hledik JC, Perez DA, Hunter S. Effects of a 12-week digital care program for chronic knee pain on pain, mobility, and surgery risk: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2018 Apr 25;20(4):e156. doi: 10.2196/jmir.9667. 
 
v20i4e156</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.9667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5943627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29695370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skrepnik N, Spitzer A, Altman R, Hoekstra J, Stewart J, Toselli R. Assessing the impact of a novel smartphone application compared with standard follow-up on mobility of patients with knee osteoarthritis following treatment with Hylan G-F 20: a randomized controlled trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2017 May 09;5(5):e64. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.7179. 
 
v5i5e64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.7179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5442351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28487266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaudreuil J, Bendaya S, Faucher M, Coudeyre E, Ribinik P, Revel M, Rannou F. Clinical practice guidelines for rest orthosis, knee sleeves, and unloading knee braces in knee osteoarthritis. Joint Bone Spine. 2009 Dec;76(6):629&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.jbspin.2009.02.002.S1297-319X(09)00054-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2009.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19467901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raja K, Dewan N. Efficacy of knee braces and foot orthoses in conservative management of knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2011 Mar;90(3):247&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0b013e318206386b.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0b013e318206386b</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21273902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G, CONSORT-EHEALTH Group  CONSORT-EHEALTH: improving and standardizing evaluation reports of web-based and mobile health interventions. J Med Internet Res. 2011 Dec 31;13(4):e126. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1923. 
 
v13i4e126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22209829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slade SC, Dionne CE, Underwood M, Buchbinder R, Beck B, Bennell K, Brosseau L, Costa l, Cramp F, Cup E, Feehan L, Ferreira M, Forbes S, Glasziou P, Habets B, Harris S, Hay-Smith J, Hillier S, Hinman R, Holland A, Hondras M, Kelly G, Kent P, Lauret GJ, Long A, Maher C, Morso L, Osteras N, Peterson T, Quinlivan R, Rees K, Regnaux JP, Rietberg M, Saunders D, Skoetz N, Sogaard K, Takken T, van Tulder M, Voet N, Ward L, White C. Consensus on exercise reporting template (CERT): modified delphi study. Phys Ther. 2016 Oct;96(10):1514&#x2013;24. doi: 10.2522/ptj.20150668.ptj.20150668</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20150668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27149962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuchs J, Kuhnert R, Scheidt-Nave C. 12-monats-pr&#xe4;valenz von arthrose in deutschland &#x2212; fact sheet &#x2212; JoHM 3/2017. Robert Koch-Institut. 2017.  [2024-04-29].  
 https://www.rki.de/DE/Content/Gesundheitsmonitoring/Gesundheitsberichterstattung/GBEDownloadsJ/FactSheets/JoHM_03_2017_Praevalenz_Arthrose.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Physical activity readiness questionnaire - PAR-Q. Canadian Society for Exercise Physiology (CSEP) 2012.  [2023-01-10].  
 http://westpointgrey.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/PAR-QXXForm.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>PAR-Q fragebogen (Deutsche Fassung) Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Sportmedizin und Pr&#xe4;vention (DGSP) 2012.  [2023-01-10].  
 https://daten2.verwaltungsportal.de/dateien/seitengenerator/leitlinie_vorsorgeuntersuchung_4.10.2007-anlage-1.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber CE, Blissmer B, Deschenes MR, Franklin BA, Lamonte MJ, Lee IM. American College of Sports Medicine position stand. Quantity and quality of exercise for developing and maintaining cardiorespiratory, musculoskeletal, and neuromotor fitness in apparently healthy adults: guidance for prescribing exercise. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011;43(7):1334&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1249/mss.0b013e318213fefb.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/mss.0b013e318213fefb</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21694556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haupt G, Jan&#xdf;en P, Krau&#xdf; I, Steinhilber B. Das T&#xfc;binger H&#xfc;ftkonzept. Essen, Germany: Verlag Hellblau; 2014. pp. 1&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krauss I, Mueller G, Haupt G, Steinhilber B, Janssen P, Jentner N, Martus P. Effectiveness and efficiency of an 11-week exercise intervention for patients with hip or knee osteoarthritis: a protocol for a controlled study in the context of health services research. BMC Public Health. 2016 Apr 30;16(1):367. doi: 10.1186/s12889-016-3030-0. 
 
10.1186/s12889-016-3030-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-016-3030-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4851810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27129849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krauss I, Steinhilber B, Haupt G, Miller R, Grau S, Janssen P. Efficacy of conservative treatment regimes for hip osteoarthritis--evaluation of the therapeutic exercise regime "Hip School": a protocol for a randomised, controlled trial. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2011 Nov 24;12(1):270. doi: 10.1186/1471-2474-12-270. 
 
1471-2474-12-270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2474-12-270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3252289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22114973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krau&#xdf; I, Steinhilber B, Haupt G, Miller R, Martus P, Jan&#xdf;en P. Exercise therapy in hip osteoarthritis--a randomized controlled trial. Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2014 Sep 01;111(35-36):592&#x2013;9. doi: 10.3238/arztebl.2014.0592. 
 
arztebl.2014.0592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3238/arztebl.2014.0592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4174683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25249361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merk J, Horstmann T, Krauss I, Danzinger B, Ziegler C, Belzl H. Sporttherapie f&#xfc;r Patienten mit Kniearthrose oder Knieendoprothese - Konzept, Inhalte und Evaluation der T&#xfc;binger Kniesportgruppe. Z Physiother. 2005;57:262&#x2013;73. 
 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinhilber B, Haupt G, Miller R, Boeer J, Grau S, Janssen P, Krauss I. Feasibility and efficacy of an 8-week progressive home-based strengthening exercise program in patients with osteoarthritis of the hip and/or total hip joint replacement: a preliminary trial. Clin Rheumatol. 2012 Mar 17;31(3):511&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s10067-011-1893-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10067-011-1893-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22086491</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen J. Iterative user-interface design. Computer. 1993 Nov;26(11):32&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1109/2.241424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/2.241424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roos EM, Lohmander LS. The Knee injury and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score (KOOS): from joint injury to osteoarthritis. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2003 Nov 03;1:64. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-1-64. 
 
1477-7525-1-64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-1-64</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC280702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14613558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler S, Lang S, Puhl W, St&#xf6;ve J. Der knee injury and osteoarthritis outcome score: ein funktionsfragebogen zur outcome-messung in der knieendoprothetik. Z Orthop Ihre Grenzgeb. 2003 Jun 24;141(3):277&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1055/s-2003-40083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2003-40083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12822074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal S, Rogers W, Selim A. The Veterans RAND 12 item health survey (VR-12): what it is and how it is used. Boston University. 2007.  [2024-03-18].  
 https://www.bu.edu/sph/files/2015/01/veterans_rand_12_item_health_survey_vr-12_2007.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bucholz I, Kohlmann T. Vergleichende Untersuchung der psychometrischen Eigenschaften des SF-36/SF-12 vs. VR-36/VR-12. Institut f&#xfc;r Community Medicine der Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Greifswald. 2017.  [2024-04-29].  
 https://reha-vffr.de/images/vffrpdf/projekte/2017/VR-Abschlussbericht_vffr205.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusu AC, Kreddig N, Hallner D, H&#xfc;lsebusch J, Hasenbring MI. Fear of movement/(Re)injury in low back pain: confirmatory validation of a German version of the Tampa Scale for Kinesiophobia. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2014 Aug 19;15(1):280. doi: 10.1186/1471-2474-15-280. 
 
1471-2474-15-280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2474-15-280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4246485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25138111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finger JD, Tafforeau J, Gisle L, Oja L, Ziese T, Thelen J, Mensink GB, Lange C. Development of the European Health Interview Survey - physical activity questionnaire (EHIS-PAQ) to monitor physical activity in the European Union. Arch Public Health. 2015 Dec 2;73(1):59. doi: 10.1186/s13690-015-0110-z. 
 
110</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13690-015-0110-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4667448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26634120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodgers WM, Wilson PM, Hall CR, Fraser SN, Murray TC. Evidence for a multidimensional self-efficacy for exercise scale. Res Quart Exerc Sport. 2008 Jun 01;79(2):222&#x2013;34. doi: 10.5641/193250308x13086753543590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5641/193250308x13086753543590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18664046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sudeck G, Pfeifer K. Physical activity-related health competence as an integrative objective in exercise therapy and health sports &#x2013; conception and validation of a short questionnaire. Sportwiss. 2016;46:74&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1007/s12662-016-0405-4. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12662-016-0405-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assessment 30-second chair stand. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2017.  [2023-01-10].  
 https://www.cdc.gov/steadi/pdf/STEADI-Assessment-30Sec-508.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faces pain scale. International Association for the Study of Pain. 2001.  [2023-01-10].  
 https://www.iasp-pain.org/Education/Content.aspx?ItemNumber=1519&amp;navItemNumber=577
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters SJ, Jacques RM, Dos Anjos Henriques-Cadby IB, Candlish J, Totton N, Xian MT. Sample size estimation for randomised controlled trials with repeated assessment of patient-reported outcomes: what correlation between baseline and follow-up outcomes should we assume? Trials. 2019 Sep 13;20(1):566. doi: 10.1186/s13063-019-3671-2. 
 
10.1186/s13063-019-3671-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-019-3671-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6743178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31519202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olejnik S, Algina J. Measures of effect size for comparative studies: applications, interpretations, and limitations. Contemp Educ Psychol. 2000 Jul;25(3):241&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1006/ceps.2000.1040.S0361476X00910403</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/ceps.2000.1040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10873373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bossen D, Veenhof C, Van Beek KE, Spreeuwenberg PM, Dekker J, De Bakker DH. Effectiveness of a web-based physical activity intervention in patients with knee and/or hip osteoarthritis: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2013 Nov 22;15(11):e257. doi: 10.2196/jmir.2662. 
 
v15i11e257</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.2662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3841352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24269911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uesugi Y, Koyanagi J, Takagi K, Yamaguchi R, Hayashi S, Nishii T. Exercise therapy interventions in patients with hip osteoarthritis: comparison of the effects of DVD and website-based interventions. JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol. 2018 May 07;5(1):e10. doi: 10.2196/rehab.8251. 
 
v5i1e10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/rehab.8251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5962826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29735473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angst F, Benz T, Lehmann S, Aeschlimann A, Angst J. Multidimensional minimal clinically important differences in knee osteoarthritis after comprehensive rehabilitation: a prospective evaluation from the Bad Zurzach Osteoarthritis Study. RMD Open. 2018 Oct 08;4(2):e000685. doi: 10.1136/rmdopen-2018-000685. 
 
rmdopen-2018-000685</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/rmdopen-2018-000685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6203096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30402264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messier SP, Callahan LF, Golightly YM, Keefe F. OARSI clinical trials recommendations: design and conduct of clinical trials of lifestyle diet and exercise interventions for osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2015 May;23(5):787&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2015.03.008. 
 
S1063-4584(15)00846-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2015.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11728937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25952349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anwer S, Alghadir A, Brism&#xe9;e JM. Effect of home exercise program in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2016;39(1):38&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1519/JPT.0000000000000045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25695471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verhagen A, Ferreira M, Reijneveld-van de Vendel E, Teirlinck C, Runhaar J, van Middelkoop M, Hermsen L, de Groot I, Bierma-Zeinstra S. Do we need another trial on exercise in patients with knee osteoarthritis?: no new trials on exercise in knee OA. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2019 Sep;27(9):1266&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2019.04.020. 
 
S1063-4584(19)31087-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2019.04.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31220609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden M, Hattle M, Runhaar J, Riley R, Healey E, Quicke J, van der Windt DA, Dziedzic K, van Middelkoop M, Burke D, Corp N, Legha A, Bierma-Zeinstra S, Foster NE, STEER OA Patient Advisory Group. OA Trial Bank Exercise Collaborative  Moderators of the effect of therapeutic exercise for knee and hip osteoarthritis: a systematic review and individual participant data meta-analysis. Lancet Rheumatol. 2023 Jul;5(7):e386&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1016/S2665-9913(23)00122-4. 
 
S2665-9913(23)00122-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(23)00122-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38251550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanaka R, Ozawa J, Kito N, Moriyama H. Does exercise therapy improve the health-related quality of life of people with knee osteoarthritis? A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Phys Ther Sci. 2015 Oct;27(10):3309&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1589/jpts.27.3309. 
 
jpts-2015-348</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1589/jpts.27.3309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4668190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26644699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selim AJ, Rogers W, Fleishman JA, Qian SX, Fincke BG, Rothendler JA, Kazis LE. Updated U.S. population standard for the Veterans RAND 12-item Health Survey (VR-12) Qual Life Res. 2009 Feb 3;18(1):43&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1007/s11136-008-9418-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-008-9418-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19051059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gohir SA, Eek F, Kelly A, Abhishek A, Valdes AM. Effectiveness of internet-based exercises aimed at treating knee osteoarthritis: the iBEAT-OA randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open. 2021 Feb 01;4(2):e210012. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.0012. 
 
2776721</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.0012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33620447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Runhaar J, Holden MA, Hattle M, Quicke J, Healey EL, van der Windt D, Dziedzic KS, Middelkoop MV, Bierma-Zeinstra S, Foster NE, STEER OA Patient Advisory Group. OA Trial Bank Exercise Collaborative  Mechanisms of action of therapeutic exercise for knee and hip OA remain a black box phenomenon: an individual patient data mediation study with the OA trial bank. RMD Open. 2023 Aug 28;9(3):e003220. doi: 10.1136/rmdopen-2023-003220. 
 
rmdopen-2023-003220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/rmdopen-2023-003220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10462947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37640513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharias A, Green R, Semciw A, Kingsley M, Pizzari T. Efficacy of rehabilitation programs for improving muscle strength in people with hip or knee osteoarthritis: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2014 Nov;22(11):1752&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2014.07.005. 
 
S1063-4584(14)01178-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2014.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25065642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobson F, Hinman RS, Roos EM, Abbott JH, Stratford P, Davis AM, Buchbinder R, Snyder-Mackler L, Henrotin Y, Thumboo J, Hansen P, Bennell K. OARSI recommended performance-based tests to assess physical function in people diagnosed with hip or knee osteoarthritis. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2013 Aug;21(8):1042&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1016/j.joca.2013.05.002. 
 
S1063-4584(13)00790-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joca.2013.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23680877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell KL, Hinman RS. A review of the clinical evidence for exercise in osteoarthritis of the hip and knee. J Sci Med Sport. 2011 Jan;14(1):4&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.jsams.2010.08.002.S1440-2440(10)00164-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsams.2010.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20851051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks R. Knee osteoarthritis and exercise adherence: a review. Curr Aging Sci. 2012 Feb 01;5(1):72&#x2013;83. doi: 10.2174/1874612811205010072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1874612811205010072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21762086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto Y, Murata Y, Tanaka N, Shigemura T, Maruyama J, Nakane R, Wada Y. Mobile application for home exercise adherence in patients with knee osteoarthritis: a pilot study. Medicine (Baltimore) 2022 Oct 21;101(42):e31181. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000031181. 
 
00005792-202210210-00043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000031181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9592287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36281120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela T, Okubo Y, Woodbury A, Lord SR, Delbaere K. Adherence to technology-based exercise programs in older adults: a systematic review. J Geriatr Phys Ther. 2018;41(1):49&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1519/JPT.0000000000000095.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1519/JPT.0000000000000095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27362526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ay S, Evcik D, Kutsal YG, Toraman F, Okumu' M, Eyig&#xf6;r S, &#x15e;ahin N. Compliance to home-based exercise therapy in elderly patients with knee osteoarthritis. Turk J Phys Med Rehab. 2016 Dec 19;62(4):323&#x2013;8. doi: 10.5606/tftrd.2016.54189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5606/tftrd.2016.54189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisters MF, Veenhof C, de Bakker DH, Schellevis FG, Dekker J. Behavioural graded activity results in better exercise adherence and more physical activity than usual care in people with osteoarthritis: a cluster-randomised trial. J Physiother. 2010;56(1):41&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/s1836-9553(10)70053-9. 
 
S1836-9553(10)70053-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1836-9553(10)70053-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20500136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakobsen JC, Gluud C, Wetterslev J, Winkel P. When and how should multiple imputation be used for handling missing data in randomised clinical trials - a practical guide with flowcharts. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2017 Dec 06;17(1):162. doi: 10.1186/s12874-017-0442-1. 
 
10.1186/s12874-017-0442-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-017-0442-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29207961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>