<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39239633</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2471-2531</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Twelve-month results for a randomized sham-controlled effectiveness trial of an in-home skills-based virtual reality program for chronic low back pain.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1182</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e1182</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e1182</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001182</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Low-risk, accessible, and long-term effective nonpharmacologic behavioral interventions for chronic low back pain (cLBP) are needed. Pain education and cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) are recommended first-line treatments, but access is poor, treatment effectiveness is variable, and long-term effectiveness is inconsistent. In-home virtual reality (VR)-delivered therapies might address these shortcomings because therapeutic content can be delivered in a consistent and quality-controlled manner.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To determine whether a 56-session, self-administered in-home, Skills-Based VR program for cLBP (RelieVRx) yields long-term reductions in pain intensity and pain interference 12 months posttreatment in a large demographically diverse and clinically severe real-world sample.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Participants were 1,093 demographically diverse individuals with self-reported nonmalignant cLBP &gt;3 months duration and average pain intensity and interference scores &gt;4/10. Participants were randomized to Skills-Based VR or active Sham, and data were collected from January 31, 2022 to October 31, 2023. Pretreatment to 12-month posttreatment analyses were conducted.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">From baseline to 12 months posttreatment, Skills-Based VR reductions for average pain intensity (1.7 &#xb1; 2.1) and pain interference (1.9 &#xb1; 2.3) were robust and significantly greater than those found for Sham. More than half of Skills-Based VR participants reported at least a 2-point reduction in pain intensity, pain interference, or both at 12 months posttreatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A standardized, in-home Skills-Based VR therapy is effective for reducing pain intensity and pain interference, and these effects are maintained to 12 months posttreatment.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. on behalf of The International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maddox</LastName><ForeName>Todd</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1265-4960</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AppliedVR, Inc., Van Nuys, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oldstone</LastName><ForeName>Liesl</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AppliedVR, Inc., Van Nuys, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sackman</LastName><ForeName>Josh</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AppliedVR, Inc., Van Nuys, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maddox</LastName><ForeName>Roselani</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AppliedVR, Inc., Van Nuys, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adair</LastName><ForeName>Takisha</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AppliedVR, Inc., Van Nuys, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ffrench</LastName><ForeName>Kelsey</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AppliedVR, Inc., Van Nuys, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sparks</LastName><ForeName>Charisse</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inspire Medical Systems, Inc, Golden Valley, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Darnall</LastName><ForeName>Beth D</ForeName><Initials>BD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Perioperative and Pain Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Palo Alto, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101683899</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2471-2531</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual Reality</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Dr. Maddox, Dr. Oldstone, Roselani Maddox, Kelsey Ffrench, and Takisha Adair are employees of AppliedVR, Inc. Joshua Sackman is president of AppliedVR, Inc. Dr. Sparks is a former employee of AppliedVR, Inc who was employed during execution of the study. Dr. Darnall is chief science advisor for AppliedVR, Inc. Dr. Darnall has authored or coauthored 5 pain treatment books for patients and clinicians and receives royalties for 4. Dr. Darnall is the principal investigator for pain research grants and awards from the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Patient-Centered Research Outcomes Research Institute (none specific to the current work). Dr. Darnall is a co-investigator on 2 NIH research grants investigating virtual reality analgesia; neither of these grants is specific to the current work. Dr. Darnall serves on the Board of Directors for the American Academy of Pain Medicine and is on the Board of Directors for the Institute for Brain Potential. Dr. Darnall is a scientific member of the NIH Interagency Pain Research Coordinating Committee, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Opioid Workgroup (2020&#x2013;2021), and the Pain Advisory Group of the American Psychological Association.Sponsorships or competing interests that may be relevant to content are disclosed at the end of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39239633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11377093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PR9.0000000000001182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PAINREPORTS-D-23-0204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bao S, Quao M, Lu Y, Jiant Y. Neuroimaging mechanism of cognitive behavioral therapy in pain management. Pain Res Manag 2022;2022:6266619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8828323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35154551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birckhead B, Khalil C, Liu X, Conovitz S, Rizzo A, Danovitch I, Bullock K, Spiegel B. Recommendations for methodology of virtual reality clinical trials in health care by an international working group: iterative study. JMIR Ment Health 2019;6:e11973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6374734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30702436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Yount S, Rothrock N, Gershon R, Cook K, Reeve B, Ader D, Fries JF, Bruce B, Rose M, PROMIS Cooperative Group. The Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS): progress of an NIH roadmap cooperative group during its first two years. Med Care 2007;45:S3&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2829758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17443116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherkin DC, Sherman KJ, Balderson BH, Cook AJ, Anderson ML, Hawkes RJ, Hansen KE, Turner JA. Effect of mindfulness-based stress reduction vs cognitive behavioral therapy or usual care on back pain and functional limitations in adults with chronic low back pain: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2016;315:1240&#x2013;1249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4914381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27002445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cleeland CS, Ryan KM. Pain assessment: global use of the Brief pain inventory. Ann Acad Med Singap 1994;23:129&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8080219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnall BD, Burns JW, Hong J, Roy A, Slater K, Poupore-King H, Ziadni MS, You DS, Jung C, Cook KF, Lorig K, Tian L, Mackey SC. Empowered Relief, cognitive behavioral therapy, and health education for people with chronic pain: a comparison of outcomes at 6-month Follow-up for a randomized controlled trial. Pain Rep 2024;9:e1116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10824382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38288134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnall BD, Krishnamurthy P, Tsuei J, Minor JD. Self-administered skills-based virtual reality intervention for chronic pain: randomized controlled pilot study. JMIR Form Res 2020;4:e17293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnall BD, Roy A, Chen AL, Ziadni MS, Keane RT, You DS, Slater K, Poupore-King H, MacKey I, Kao MC, Cook KF, Lorig K, Zhang D, Hong J, Tian L, MacKey SC. Comparison of a single-session pain management skills intervention with a single-session health education intervention and 8 sessions of cognitive behavioral therapy in adults with chronic low back pain: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Netw Open 2021;4:e2113401.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8369357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34398206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnall BD, Scheman J, Davin S, Burns JW, Murphy JL, Wilson AC, Kerns RD, Mackey SC. Pain psychology: a global needs assessment and national call to action. Pain Med (United States) 2016;17:250&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4758272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26803844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day MA, Ehde DM, Bindicsova I, Jensen MP. Understanding the role of therapist quality in accounting for heterogeneity of patient outcomes in psychosocial chronic pain treatments. J Pain 2024;25:843&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37832902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng X, Jian C, Yang Q, Jiang N, Huang Z, Zhao S. The analgesic effect of different interactive modes of virtual reality: a prospective functional near-infrared spectroscopy (fNIRS) study. Front Neurosci 2022;16:1033155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9707398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36458040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dowell D, Ragan KR, Jones CM, Baldwin GT, Chou R. CDC clinical practice guideline for prescribing opioids for pain - United States, 2022. MMWR Recomm Rep 2022;71:1&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9639433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36327391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Everitt HA, Landau S, O'Reilly G, Sibelli A, Hughes S, Windgassen S, Holland R, Little P, McCrone P, Bishop FL, Goldsmith K, Coleman N, Logan R, Chalder T, Moss-Morris R. Cognitive behavioural therapy for irritable bowel syndrome: 24-month follow-up of participants in the ACTIB randomised trial. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 2019;4:863&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7026694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31492643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fairbank JCT, Pynsent PB. The Oswestry disability index. Spine 2000;25:2940&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11074683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrar JT, Young JP, LaMoreaux L, Werth JL, Poole RM. Clinical importance of changes in chronic pain intensity measured on an 11-point numerical pain rating scale. PAIN 2001;94:149&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11690728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster NE, Anema JR, Cherkin D, Chou R, Cohen SP, Gross DP, Ferreira PH, Fritz JM, Koes BW, Peul W, Turner JA, Maher CG, Buchbinder R, Hartvigsen J, Cherkin D, Foster NE, Maher CG, Underwood M, van Tulder M, Anema JR, Chou R, Cohen SP, Menezes Costa L, Croft P, Ferreira M, Ferreira PH, Fritz JM, Genevay S, Gross DP, Hancock MJ, Hoy D, Karppinen J, Koes BW, Kongsted A, Louw Q, &#xd6;berg B, Peul WC, Pransky G, Schoene M, Sieper J, Smeets RJ, Turner JA, Woolf A. Prevention and treatment of low back pain: evidence, challenges, and promising directions. Lancet (London, England) 2018;391:2368&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29573872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fu H, Garrett B, Tao G, Cordingley E, Ofoghi Z, Taverner T, Sun C, Cheung T. Virtual reality&#x2013;guided meditation for chronic pain in patients with cancer: exploratory analysis of electroencephalograph activity. JMIR Biomed Eng 2021;6:e26332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11135186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38907380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Furlan AD, Sandoval JA, Mailis-Gagnon A, Tunks E. Opioids for chronic noncancer pain: a meta-analysis of effectiveness and side effects. CMAJ 2006;174:1589&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1459894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia L, Birckhead B, Krishnamurthy P, Mackey I, Sackman J, Salmasi V, Louis R, Castro C, Maddox R, Maddox T, Darnall BD. Durability of the treatment effects of an 8-week self-administered home-based virtual reality program for chronic low back pain: 6-month follow-up study of a randomized clinical trial. J Med Int Res 2022;24:e37480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9177046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35612905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia L, Darnall B, Krishnamurthy P, Mackey I, Sackman J, Louis R, Maddox T, Birckhead B. Self-administered behavioral skills&#x2013;Based at-home virtual reality therapy for chronic low back pain: protocol for a randomized controlled trial. JMIR Res Protoc 2021;10:e25291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7854039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33464215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia LM, Birckhead BJ, Krishnamurthy P, Sackman J, Mackey IG, Louis RG, Salmasi V, Maddox T, Darnall BD. An 8-week self-administered at-home behavioral skills-based virtual reality program for chronic low back pain: double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial conducted during COVID-19. J Med Internet Res 2021;23:e26292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7939946</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33484240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho EKY, Chen L, Simic M, Ashton-James CE, Comachio J, Wang DXM, Hayden JA, Ferreira ML, Ferreira PH. Psychological interventions for chronic, non-specific low back pain: systematic review with network meta-analysis. BMJ 2022;376:e067718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8965745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman HG, Patterson DR, Carrougher GJ. Use of virtual reality for adjunctive treatment of adult burn pain during physical therapy: a controlled study. Clin J Pain 2000;16:244&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11014398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman HG, Richards TL, Coda B, Bills AR, Blough D, Richards AL, Sharar SR. Modulation of thermal pain-related brain activity with virtual reality: evidence from fMRI. Neuroreport 2004;15:1245&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15167542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffman HG, Richards TL, Van Oostrom T, Coda BA, Jensen MP, Blough DK, Sharar SR. The analgesic effects of opioids and immersive virtual reality distraction: evidence from subjective and functional brain imaging assessments. Anesth Analg 2007;105:1776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18042882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khadra C, Ballard A, D&#xe9;ry J, Paquin D, Fortin JS, Perreault I, Labbe DR, Hoffman HG, Bouchard S, LeMay S. Projector-based virtual reality dome environment for procedural pain and anxiety in young children with burn injuries: a pilot study. J Pain Res 2018;11:343&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5817417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29491717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kovacs FM, Abraira V, Royuela A, Corcoll J, Alegre L, Cano A, Muriel A, Zamora J, Gil Del Real MT, Gestoso M, Mufraggi N. Minimal clinically important change for pain intensity and disability in patients with nonspecific low back pain. Spine (Phila Pa 1976) 2007;32:2915&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18246018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SY, Cha JY, Yoo JW, Nazareno M, Cho YS, Joo SY, Seo CH. Effect of the application of virtual reality on pain reduction and cerebral blood flow in robot-assisted gait training in burn patients. J Clin Med 2022;11:3762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9267903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35807047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddox T, Fitzpatrick T. The promise of virtual reality in health-care education and training: it's all in the neuroscience. Digital Med 2019;5:133&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddox T, Garcia H, Ffrench K, Maddox R, Garcia L, Krishnamurthy P, Okhotin D, Sparks C, Oldstone L, Birckhead B, Sackman J, MacKey I, Louis R, Salmasi V, Oyao A, Darnall B. In-home virtual reality program for chronic low back pain: durability of a randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trial to 18 months post-treatment. Reg Anesth Pain Med 2024;49:373&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11103290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36427904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddox T, Oldstone L, Sparks CY, Sackman J, Oyao A, Garcia L, Maddox RU, Ffrench K, Garcia H, Adair T, Irvin A, Maislin D, Keenan B, Bonakdar R, Darnall BD. In-home virtual reality program for chronic lower back pain: a randomized sham-controlled effectiveness trial in a clinically severe and diverse sample. Mayo Clinic Proc Digital Health 2023;1:563&#x2013;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddox T, Sparks C, Oldstone L, Chibarro M, Sackman J, Judge E, Bonakdar R, Maddox R, Darnall B. Perspective: the promise of virtual reality as an immersive therapeutic. J Med Extended Reality 2024;1:13&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddox T, Sparks C, Oldstone L, Maddox R, Ffrench K, Garcia H, Krishnamurthy P, Okhotin D, Garcia LM, Birckhead BJ, Sackman J, Mackey I, Louis R, Salmasi V, Oyao A, Darnall BD. Durable chronic low back pain reductions up to 24 months after treatment for an accessible, 8-week, in-home behavioral skills&#x2013;based virtual reality program: a randomized controlled trial. Pain Med 2023;24:1200&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10546478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37220894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallari B, Spaeth EK, Goh H, Boyd BS. Virtual reality as an analgesic for acute and chronic pain in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Pain Res 2019;12:2053&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31308733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martucci KT, MacKey SC. Neuroimaging of pain: human evidence and clinical relevance of central nervous System processes and modulation. Anesthesiology 2018;128:1241&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5953782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29494401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthie NS, Giordano NA, Jenerette CM, Magwood GS, Leslie SL, Northey EE, Webster CI, Sil S. Use and efficacy of virtual, augmented, or mixed reality technology for chronic pain: a systematic review. Pain Manag 2022;12:859&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9517958</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36098065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monticone M, Cedraschi C, Ambrosini E, Rocca B, Fiorentini R, Restelli M, Gianola S, Ferrante S, Zanoli G, Moja L. Cognitive-behavioural treatment for subacute and chronic neck pain. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2015. .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8922276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26006174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohaj A, Bulaj G. Digital therapeutics (DTx) expand multimodal treatment options for chronic low back pain: the nexus of precision medicine, patient education, and public health. Healthcare (Switzerland) 2023;11:1469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10218553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37239755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seminowicz DA, Shpaner M, Keaser ML, Krauthamer GM, Mantegna J, Dumas JA, Newhouse PA, Filippi CG, Keefe FJ, Naylor MR. Cognitive-behavioral therapy increases prefrontal cortex gray matter in patients with chronic pain. J Pain 2013;14:1573&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3874446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24135432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shpaner M, Kelly C, Lieberman G, Perelman H, Davis M, Keefe FJ, Naylor MR. Unlearning chronic pain: a randomized controlled trial to investigate changes in intrinsic brain connectivity following Cognitive Behavioral Therapy. Neuroimage Clin 2014;5:365&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4749849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26958466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh VM, Adkinson SM, Brandow A. Pain management best practices inter-agency task force report: Updates, gaps, inconsistencies, and recommendations. Vol. 11. US Department of Health and Human Services, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith V, Warty RR, Sursas JA, Payne O, Nair A, Krishnan S, da Silva Costa F, Wallace EM, Vollenhoven B. The effectiveness of virtual reality in managing acute pain and anxiety for medical inpatients: systematic review. J Med Internet Res 2020;22:e17980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7669439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33136055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel B, Fuller G, Lopez M, Dupuy T, Noah B, Howard A, Albert M, Tashjian V, Lam R, Ahn J, Dailey F, Rosen BT, Vrahas M, Little M, Garlich J, Dzubur E, IsHak W, Danovitch I. Virtual reality for management of pain in hospitalized patients: a randomized comparative effectiveness trial. PLoS One 2019;14:e0219115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6693733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31412029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel Brennan MR. VRx: How virtual therapeutics will revolutionize medicine. 1st ed. Basic Books; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran Y, Austin P, Lo C, Craig A, Middleton JW, Wrigley PJ, Siddall P. An exploratory EEG analysis on the effects of virtual reality in people with neuropathic pain following spinal cord injury. Sensors 2022;22:2629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9002545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35408245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traylor C. Medicaid strategies for non-opioid pharmacologic and non-pharmacologic chronic pain management. CMCS Informational Bulletin. Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevlaki E. The effectiveness of cognitive behavioral therapy in chronic low back pain. Biomed J Scientific Tech Res. 2023;48. doi: 10.26717/BJSTR.2023.48.007643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26717/BJSTR.2023.48.007643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AcdeC, Fisher E, Hearn L, Eccleston C. Psychological therapies for the management of chronic pain (excluding headache) in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020;2021. .</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32794606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang J, Lo WLA, Zheng F, Cheng X, Yu Q, Wang C. Evaluation of cognitive behavioral therapy on improving pain, fear avoidance, and self-efficacy in patients with chronic low back pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain Res Manag 2022;2022:4276175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8957446</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35345623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshino A, Okamoto Y, Okada G, Takamura M, Ichikawa N, Shibasaki C, Yokoyama S, Doi M, Jinnin R, Yamashita H, Horikoshi M, Yamawaki S. Changes in resting-state brain networks after cognitive-behavioral therapy for chronic pain. Psychol Med 2018;48:1148&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28893330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L, Buysse DJ, Germain A, Moul DE, Stover A, Dodds NE, Johnston KL, Pilkonis PA. Development of short forms from the PROMIS<sup>TM</sup> sleep disturbance and sleep-related impairment item banks. Behav Sleep Med
2011;10:6&#x2013;24.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3261577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22250775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>