<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36514730</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2641-7650</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>27</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Kidney360</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Kidney360</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial of Integrated Palliative Care and Nephrology Care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1720</StartPage><EndPage>1729</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1720-1729</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.34067/KID.0000352022</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">There has been a call by both patients and health professionals for the integration of palliative care with nephrology care, yet there is little evidence describing the effect of this approach. The objective of this paper is to report the feasibility and acceptability of a pilot randomized controlled trial testing the efficacy of integrated palliative and nephrology care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">English speaking patients with CKD stage 5 were randomized to monthly palliative care visits for 3 months in addition to their usual care, as compared with usual nephrology care. Feasibility of recruitment, retention, completion of intervention processes, and feedback on participation was measured. Other outcomes included differences in symptom burden change, measured by the Integrated Palliative Outcome Scale-Renal, and change in quality of life, measured by the Kidney Disease Quality of Life questionnaire and completion of advance care planning documents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of the 67 patients approached, 45 (67%) provided informed consent. Of these, 27 patients completed the study (60%), and 14 (74%) of those in the intervention group completed all visits. We found small improvements in overall symptom burden (-2.92 versus 1.57) and physical symptom burden scores (-1.92 versus 1.79) in the intervention group. We did not see improvements in the quality-of-life scores, with the exception of the physical component score. The intervention group completed more advance care planning documents than controls (five health care proxy forms completed versus one, nine Medical Orders for Life Sustaining Treatment forms versus none).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">We found that pilot testing through a randomized controlled trial of an ambulatory integrated palliative and nephrology care clinical program was feasible and acceptable to participants. This intervention has the potential to improve the disease experience for those with nondialysis CKD and should be tested in other CKD populations with longer follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIALS REGISTRY NAME AND REGISTRATION NUMBER">Pilot Randomized-controlled Trial of Integrated Palliative and Nephrology Care Versus Usual Nephrology Care, NCT04520984.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the American Society of Nephrology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scherer</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4679-5673</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatric Medicine and Palliative Care, Department of Internal Medicine, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rau</LastName><ForeName>Megan E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatric Medicine and Palliative Care, Department of Internal Medicine, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krieger</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xia</LastName><ForeName>Yuhe</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics, Department of Population Health, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhong</LastName><ForeName>Hua</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2163-8447</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics, Department of Population Health, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brody</LastName><ForeName>Abraham</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3405-7043</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatric Medicine and Palliative Care, Department of Internal Medicine, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hartford Institute for Geriatric Nursing, NYU Rory Meyers College of Nursing, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Charytan</LastName><ForeName>David M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7695-3583</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chodosh</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7784-4306</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatric Medicine and Palliative Care, Department of Internal Medicine, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04520984</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 DK125840</GrantID><Acronym>DK</Acronym><Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P30 AG066512</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Kidney360</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101766381</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2641-7650</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010166" MajorTopicYN="N">Palliative Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009398" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nephrology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007676" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Failure, Chronic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">geriatric and palliative nephrology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">palliative care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pilot projects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">randomized controlled trials</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>A. Brody reports having ownership interest in Accomplish Health, and having consultancy agreements with David Horowitz (PC), Ryan Ryan Deluca, and Victoria Crown Law (PC). D.M. Charytan reports having consultancy agreements with Allena Pharmaceuticals (data and safety monitoring board), Amgen, AstraZeneca, CSL Behring, Eli Lilly/Boehringer Ingelheim, GlaxoSmithKline, Janssen (steering committee), Fresenius, Gilead, Medtronic, Merck, Novo Nordisk, PLC medical (clinical events committee), Renalytix, and Zogenix; receiving grants and personal fees from Amgen, Gilead, Medtronic, and Novo Nordisk; receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer/Eli Lily, CSL Behring, Fresenius, GlaxoSmithKline, Merck, and Zoll; serving in an advisory or leadership role for CJASN; receiving personal fees and other from Janssen; and receiving expert witness fees related to proton pump inhibitors. J. Chodosh reports serving in an advisory or leadership role for the Journal of American Geriatrics Society. M.E. Rau reports having ownership interest in Doximity. J.S. Scherer reports serving in an advisory or leadership role for Cara Pharmaceuticals and Monogram Health (clinical advisory board), and receiving honoraria from Vifor Pharmaceuticals. All remaining authors have nothing to disclose. H. Zhong receives funding from National Institute of Aging grants 1R011AG065330-01, 5R01AG 054467-04, and 3R01AG54467-04S1All remaining authors have nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36514730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9717658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34067/KID.0000352022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">02200512-202210000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Weisbord SD, Carmody SS, Bruns FJ, Rotondi AJ, Cohen LM, Zeidel ML, Arnold RM: Symptom burden, quality of life, advance care planning and the potential value of palliative care in severely ill haemodialysis patients. Nephrol Dial Transplant 18: 1345&#x2013;1352, 2003. 10.1093/ndt/gfg105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ndt/gfg105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12808172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davison SN, Jhangri GS: Impact of pain and symptom burden on the health-related quality of life of hemodialysis patients. J Pain Symptom Manage 39: 477&#x2013;485, 2010. 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2009.08.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2009.08.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20303025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>United States Renal Data System : 2021 USRDS Annual Data Report: Epidemiology of kidney disease in the United States. Chapter 6: Mortality. Bethesda, MD, National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, 2021. Available at: https://adr.usrds.org/2021/end-stage-renal-disease/6-mortality. Accessed August 29, 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurella Tamura M, Liu S, Montez-Rath ME, O&#x2019;Hare AM, Hall YN, Lorenz KA: Persistent gaps in use of advance directives among nursing home residents receiving maintenance dialysis. JAMA Intern Med 177: 1204&#x2013;1205, 2017. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2017.1618</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2017.1618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5796530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28520863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wachterman MW, Lipsitz SR, Lorenz KA, Marcantonio ER, Li Z, Keating NL: End-of-life experience of older adults dying of end-stage renal disease: A comparison with cancer. J Pain Symptom Manage 54: 789&#x2013;797, 2017. 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2017.08.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2017.08.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5786651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28843455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center to Advance Palliative Care : About palliative care. Available at: https://www.capc.org/about/palliative-care/. Accessed February 1, 2018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam DY, Scherer JS, Brown M, Grubbs V, Schell JO: A conceptual framework of palliative care across the continuum of advanced kidney disease. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 14: 635&#x2013;641, 2019. 10.2215/CJN.09330818</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.09330818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30728167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renal Physician&#x2019;s Association : Shared Decision-Making in the Appropriate Initiation of and Withdrawal From Dialysis, 2nd Ed., Rockville, MD, Renal Physicians Association, 2010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AW, Dwyer AC, Eddy AA, Fink JC, Jaber BL, Linas SL, Michael B, O&#x2019;Hare AM, Schaefer HM, Shaffer RN, Trachtman H, Weiner DE, Falk AR; American Society of Nephrology Quality, and Patient Safety Task Force : Critical and honest conversations: The evidence behind the &#x201c;Choosing Wisely&#x201d; campaign recommendations by the American Society of Nephrology. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 7: 1664&#x2013;1672, 2012. 10.2215/CJN.04970512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.04970512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22977214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urquhart-Secord R, Craig JC, Hemmelgarn B, Tam-Tham H, Manns B, Howell M, Polkinghorne KR, Kerr PG, Harris DC, Thompson S, Schick-Makaroff K, Wheeler DC, van Biesen W, Winkelmayer WC, Johnson DW, Howard K, Evangelidis N, Tong A: Patient and caregiver priorities for outcomes in hemodialysis: An international nominal group technique study. Am J Kidney Dis 68: 444&#x2013;454, 2016. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2016.02.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2016.02.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26968042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Carter SM, Hall B, Harris DC, Walker RG, Hawley CM, Chadban S, Craig JC: Patients&#x2019; priorities for health research: Focus group study of patients with chronic kidney disease. Nephrol Dial Transplant 23: 3206&#x2013;3214, 2008. 10.1093/ndt/gfn207</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ndt/gfn207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18445638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evangelidis N, Tong A, Manns B, Hemmelgarn B, Wheeler DC, Tugwell P, Crowe S, Harris T, Van Biesen W, Winkelmayer WC, Sautenet B, O&#x2019;Donoghue D, Tam-Tham H, Youssouf S, Mandayam S, Ju A, Hawley C, Pollock C, Harris DC, Johnson DW, Rifkin DE, Tentori F, Agar J, Polkinghorne KR, Gallagher M, Kerr PG, McDonald SP, Howard K, Howell M, Craig JC; Standardized Outcomes in Nephrology&#x2013;Hemodialysis (SONG-HD) Initiative : Developing a set of core outcomes for trials in hemodialysis: An international Delphi survey. Am J Kidney Dis 70: 464&#x2013;475, 2017. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2016.11.029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2016.11.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28238554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combs SA, Culp S, Matlock DD, Kutner JS, Holley JL, Moss AH: Update on end-of-life care training during nephrology fellowship: A cross-sectional national survey of fellows. Am J Kidney Dis 65: 233&#x2013;239, 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4305463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25245300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal AH, Bull JH, Swetz KM, Wolf SP, Shanafelt TD, Myers ER: Future of the palliative care workforce: Preview to an impending crisis. Am J Med 130: 113&#x2013;114, 2017. 10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.08.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.08.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27687068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eneanya ND, Labbe AK, Stallings TL, Percy S, Temel JS, Klaiman TA, Park ER: Caring for older patients with advanced chronic kidney disease and considering their needs: A qualitative study. BMC Nephrol 21: 213, 2020. 10.1186/s12882-020-01870-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12882-020-01870-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7271389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32493235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ladin K, Pandya R, Kannam A, Loke R, Oskoui T, Perrone RD, Meyer KB, Weiner DE, Wong JB: Discussing conservative management with older patients with CKD: An interview study of nephrologists. Am J Kidney Dis 71: 627&#x2013;635, 2018. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2017.11.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2017.11.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5916578</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29396240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong SPY, Boyapati S, Engelberg RA, Thorsteinsdottir B, Taylor JS, O&#x2019;Hare AM: Experiences of US nephrologists in the delivery of conservative care to patients with advanced kidney disease: A national qualitative study. Am J Kidney Dis 75: 167&#x2013;176, 2020. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2019.07.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2019.07.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7012760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31570175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamar FB, Tam-Tham H, Thomas C: A description of advanced chronic kidney disease patients in a major urban center receiving conservative care. Can J Kidney Health Dis 4: 2054358117718538, 2017. 10.1177/2054358117718538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2054358117718538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5528906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28835848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Josland E, Brennan F, Anastasiou A, Brown MA: Developing and sustaining a renal supportive care service for people with end-stage kidney disease. Renal Soc Australas 8: 12&#x2013;18, 2012</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chao CT, Tsai HB, Shih CY, Hsu SH, Hung YC, Lai CF, Ueng RH, Chan DC, Hwang JJ, Huang SJ: Establishment of a renal supportive care program: Experience from a rural community hospital in Taiwan. J Formos Med Assoc 115: 490&#x2013;500, 2016. 10.1016/j.jfma.2015.12.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfma.2015.12.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26825873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hui D, Bruera E: Models of palliative care delivery for patients with cancer. J Clin Oncol 38: 852&#x2013;865, 2020. 10.1200/JCO.18.02123</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.18.02123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32023157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherer JS, Harwood K, Frydman JL, Moriyama D, Brody AA, Modersitzki F, Blaum CS, Chodosh J: A descriptive analysis of an ambulatory kidney palliative care program. J Palliat Med 38: 259&#x2013;263, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6987731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31295050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bristol AA, Chaudhry S, Assis D, Wright R, Moriyama D, Harwood K, Brody AA, Charytan DM, Chodosh J, Scherer JS: An exploratory qualitative study of patient and caregiver perspectives of ambulatory kidney palliative care. Am J Hosp Palliat Care 38: 1242&#x2013;1249, 2021. 10.1177/1049909120986121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049909120986121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8275690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33438435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palliative Care Research Cooperative Group : Training videos. Available at: https://palliativecareresearch.org/resources/training-videos. Accessed February 28, 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scherer JS, Wright R, Blaum CS, Wall SP: Building an outpatient kidney palliative care clinical program. J Pain Symptom Manage 55: 108&#x2013;116.e2, 2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28803081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoong J, Park ER, Greer JA, Jackson VA, Gallagher ER, Pirl WF, Back AL, Temel JS: Early palliative care in advanced lung cancer: A qualitative study. JAMA Intern Med 173: 283&#x2013;290, 2013. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2013.1874</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2013.1874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23358690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raj R, Ahuja K, Frandsen M, Murtagh FEM, Jose M: Validation of the IPOS-Renal Symptom Survey in advanced kidney disease: A cross-sectional study. J Pain Symptom Manage 56: 281&#x2013;287, 2018. 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2018.04.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2018.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29729346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murtagh FE, Ramsenthaler C, Firth A, Groeneveld EI, Lovell N, Simon ST, Denzel J, Guo P, Bernhardt F, Schildmann E, van Oorschot B, Hodiamont F, Streitwieser S, Higginson IJ, Bausewein C: A brief, patient- and proxy-reported outcome measure in advanced illness: Validity, reliability and responsiveness of the Integrated Palliative care Outcome Scale (IPOS). Palliat Med 33: 1045&#x2013;1057, 2019. 10.1177/0269216319854264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269216319854264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6691591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31185804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rand Health Care : Kidney Disease Quality of Life Instrument. Available at: https://www.rand.org/health-care/surveys_tools/kdqol.html. Accessed October 10, 2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peipert JD, Bentler PM, Klicko K, Hays RD: Psychometric properties of the Kidney Disease Quality of Life 36-Item Short-Form Survey (KDQOL-36) in the United States. Am J Kidney Dis 71: 461&#x2013;468, 2018. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2017.07.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2017.07.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29128411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ricardo AC, Hacker E, Lora CM, Ackerson L, DeSalvo KB, Go A, Kusek JW, Nessel L, Ojo A, Townsend RR, Xie D, Ferrans CE, Lash JP; CRIC Investigators : Validation of the Kidney Disease Quality of Life Short Form 36 (KDQOL-36) US Spanish and English versions in a cohort of Hispanics with chronic kidney disease. Ethn Dis 23: 202&#x2013;209, 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3651651</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23530302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones TA, Olds TS, Currow DC, Williams MT: Feasibility and pilot studies in palliative care research: A systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manage 54: 139&#x2013;151.e4, 2017. 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2017.02.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2017.02.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28450220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagen NA, Biondo PD, Brasher PM, Stiles CR: Formal feasibility studies in palliative care: Why they are important and how to conduct them. J Pain Symptom Manage 42: 278&#x2013;289, 2011. 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2010.11.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2010.11.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21444184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldridge SM, Lancaster GA, Campbell MJ, Thabane L, Hopewell S, Coleman CL, Bond CM: Defining feasibility and pilot studies in preparation for randomised controlled trials: Development of a conceptual framework. PLoS One 11: e0150205, 2016. 10.1371/journal.pone.0150205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0150205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4792418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26978655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flythe JE, Hilliard T, Castillo G, Ikeler K, Orazi J, Abdel-Rahman E, Pai AB, Rivara MB, St Peter WL, Weisbord SD, Wilkie C, Mehrotra R: Symptom prioritization among adults receiving in-center hemodialysis: A mixed methods study. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 13: 735&#x2013;745, 2018. 10.2215/CJN.10850917</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.10850917</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5969481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29559445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown SA, Tyrer FC, Clarke AL, Lloyd-Davies LH, Stein AG, Tarrant C, Burton JO, Smith AC: Symptom burden in patients with chronic kidney disease not requiring renal replacement therapy. Clin Kidney J 10: 788&#x2013;796, 2017. 10.1093/ckj/sfx057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ckj/sfx057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5716066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29225808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>