<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37748556</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-6787</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>90</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Acad Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Best practices in the treatment of melasma with a focus on patients with skin of color.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>269</StartPage><EndPage>279</EndPage><MedlinePgn>269-279</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jaad.2023.07.1045</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0190-9622(23)02850-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Melasma is a chronic hypermelanosis of the skin that affects approximately 1% of the global population, predominantly affects women, and is more prevalent in skin of color. Melasma is a common driver for patients with skin of color to seek out a dermatologist for treatment, and ensuring the right approach for these patients is important because some treatments may be associated with adverse side effects. Because of the chronicity of the disease and established psychosocial and emotional impacts, there is a large need to ensure care follows the best available evidence on the treatment of patients with melasma.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Here, we summarized current available topical treatments for melasma with considerations dermatologists should have for their patients with skin of color.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Steering committee consensus on clinical best practices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">We describe a flexible and focused treatment algorithm that reflects both treatment and maintenance periods that is a consensus of our extensive clinical experience.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS">Use of real-world evidence and potential for individual practice bias.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Melasma can be challenging to treat, particularly in patients with skin of color, and our recommendations for best practices for patients in the United States are an important step toward standardizing care.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Published by Elsevier Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Seemal R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas; Innovative Dermatology, Plano, Texas. Electronic address: seemald@yahoo.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexis</LastName><ForeName>Andrew F</ForeName><Initials>AF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Weill Cornell Medicine, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elbuluk</LastName><ForeName>Nada</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Keck School of Medicine Dermatology, University of South California, Los Angeles, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grimes</LastName><ForeName>Pearl E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Vitiligo &amp; Pigmentation Institute of Southern California, David Geffen School of Medicine, University of California, Los Angeles, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiss</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, Georgia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hamzavi</LastName><ForeName>Iltefat H</ForeName><Initials>IH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Henry Ford Hospital; Hamzavi Dermatology/Dermatology Specialists, Detroit, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Susan C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Acad Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7907132</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0190-9622</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0CD5FD6S2M</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005446">Fluocinolone Acetonide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006873">Hydroquinones</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>5688UTC01R</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014212">Tretinoin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005446" MajorTopicYN="N">Fluocinolone Acetonide</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006873" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydroquinones</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008548" MajorTopicYN="Y">Melanosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012880" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin Pigmentation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014212" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tretinoin</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000091762" MajorTopicYN="N">Ethnic and Racial Minorities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cosmeceutical</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fluocinolone acetonide</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">general dermatology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hydroquinone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">maintenance treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanical procedures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">melasma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical modalities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">skin of color</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tranexamic acid</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment algorithm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tretinoin</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest Dr Desai has served as a consultant and/or investigator for Galderma, Pfizer, Dermavant, Scientis, AbbVie, and several other organizations. He also serves in multiple leadership roles with dermatologic organizations. Dr Alexis has received grants from LEO Pharma, Novartis, Almirall, Bristol Myers Squibb, Amgen, Vyne, Galderma, Valeant (now Bausch Health), Cara, Arcutis, Dermavant, AbbVie, and Castle and consulting fees or honoraria from Leo, Galderma, Pfizer, Sanofi-Regeneron, Dermavant, Beiersdorf, Ortho, L&#x2019;Oreal, Bristol Myers Squibb, Bausch Health, UCB, Vyne, Arcutis, Janssen, Allergan, Almirall, AbbVie, Sol-Gel, Amgen, VisualDx, Eli Lilly, Swiss American, Cutera, Cara, EPI, and Incyte. He has also received speaker fees from Regeneron, Sanofi-Genzyme, Pfizer, and Bristol Myers Squibb. Dr Elbuluk has received fees, research funding, or stock options for consulting, speaking, or participating in advisory boards from Allergan, Avita Medical, Beiersdorf, Est&#xe9;e Lauder, Galderma Laboratories, Incyte, Janssen, La Roche-Posay, L&#x2019;Oreal, Scientis, Unilever, and VisualDx. Dr Grimes has served as a consultant and/or investigator for Procter &amp; Gamble, Clinuvel, L&#x2019;Oreal, Galderma Laboratories, LaserOptek, Versicolor Technologies, Incyte, Pfizer, AbbVie/Allergan, and SkinBetterScience. Dr Weiss served on the advisory board for Galderma Laboratories and Valeant Pharmaceuticals International (now Bausch Health), receiving honoraria. He also served as consultant for Abbott Laboratories, Celgene Corporation, LEO Pharma, and Sebacia, receiving honoraria. Dr Hamzavi is a consultant to AbbVie, Pfizer, Incyte, UCB, Boerhinger Ingelheim, Sonoma, Union therapeutics, Novartis, Janssen, Avita, and for Galderma Laboratories. Dr Hamzavi is an investigator for LENICURA, Pfizer, Incyte, Avita, and L&#x2019;Oreal/La Roche-Posay. He is a board member and past president of the HS Foundation and Global Vitiligo Foundation. Dr Taylor reports service as an investigator for Concert Pharmaceuticals, Croma-Pharma, Eli Lilly, and&#xa0;Pfizer. Dr Taylor has received salaries, fees, honoraria, and stock options as a consultant, advisor, board member, and speaker for Mercer Strategies, AbbVie, Arcutis Biotherapeutics, Armis Scientific, Beiersdorf, Biorez, Cara Therapeutics, EPI Pharma, Evolus, Galderma Laboratories, Glo Getter, Hugel America, Janssen, Johnson &amp; JohnsonJohnson &amp; Johnson, L&#x2019;Oreal, Medscape/WebMD, MJH Life Sciences, Piction Health, Regeneron, Scientis US, UCB, and Vichy Laboratoires.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37748556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2023.07.1045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0190-9622(23)02850-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>