<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38779376</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1941-2789</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of clinical and aesthetic dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Putting the Formulation Back in Foam: Optimizing Seborrheic Dermatitis Treatment Across Diverse Hair Types.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>30</StartPage><EndPage>33</EndPage><MedlinePgn>30-33</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Seborrheic dermatitis (SD) is a chronic inflammatory skin condition that commonly involves the scalp, and thus, affects a diverse demographic with varying hair care needs. Current SD treatments are limited based on optimized formulation, efficacy, adverse events, and lack of placebo-controlled trials. A novel roflumilast foam formulation has emerged as a promising therapeutic option optimally designed for use on the scalp and other hair-bearing areas. We conducted a comprehensive assessment of beauty industry standards, confirming the foam formulation's alignment with industry guidelines and exclusion of potentially harmful ingredients. In addition, consultation with an expert dermatologist panel yielded a strong endorsement, underscoring a high level of confidence in prescribing the foam across diverse hair and skin types.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024. Matrix Medical Communications. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Chovatiya</LastName><ForeName>Raj</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Chovatiya is a Clinical Associate Professor at the Rosalind Franklin University of Chicago Medical School and is the Founder and Director of the Center for Medical Dermatology and Immunology Research in Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Polaskey</LastName><ForeName>Meredith Tyree</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ms. Polaskey is with the Department of Dermatology at Northwestern University Feinberg School of Medicine in Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lain</LastName><ForeName>Edward</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Lain is with Sanova Dermatology and the Austin Institute for Clinical Research in Austin, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlesinger</LastName><ForeName>Todd</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Schlesinger is with the Dermatology and Laser Center of Charleston and Clinical Research Center of the Carolinas in Charleston, South Carolina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Woolery-Llloyd</LastName><ForeName>Heather</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dr. Woolery-Llloyd is with Dr. Phillip Frost's Department of Dermatology and Cutaneous Surgery at University of Miami's Miller School of Medicine in Miami, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burnett</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drs. Hanna and Burnett are with Arcutis Biotherapeutics, Inc. in Westlake Village, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanna</LastName><ForeName>Diane</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drs. Hanna and Burnett are with Arcutis Biotherapeutics, Inc. in Westlake Village, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Clin Aesthet Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518173</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-2789</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Seborrheic dermatitis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>DISCLOSURES.: Drs. Hanna and Burnett are employees of Arcutis Biotherapeutics, Inc. EL has served as an investigator, advisor, consultant, and/or speaker for AbbVie, Eli Lilly and Company, Bristol Myers Squibb, Ortho Dermatologics, Pfizer Inc, Sanofi, Regeneron, Galderma, Dermavant, Incyte, UCB, and Journey. Dr. Schlesinger has served as a consultant, speaker and/or investigator for AbbVie, Arcutis, Boehringer-Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cara Therapeutics, Eli Lilly and Company, Galderma, Janssen, Novartis, Pfizer Inc., UCB. Dr. Woolery-Llloyd has served as a consultant, speaker, and/or investigator for Ortho Dermatologics, L&#x2019;Or&#xe9;al, Eli Lillly and Company, Incyte, Pfizer Inc., Galderma, Allergan, Arcutis, Vyne, Eirion, and Regeneron Dr. Chovatiya has served as an advisory board member, consultant, and/or investigator for AbbVie, Apogee Therapeutics, Arcutis, Argenx, ASLAN Pharmaceuticals, Beiersdorf, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cara Therapeutics, Dermavant, Eli Lilly and Company, FIDE, Galderma, Genentech, Incyte, Janssen, LEO Pharma, L&#x2019;Or&#xe9;al, Nektar Therapeutics, Novan, Inc., Opsidio, Pfizer Inc., Regeneron, RAPT, Sanofi, and UCB. Dr. Polaskey has no conflicts of interest relevant to this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>50</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38779376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11107903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rucker Wright D, Gathers R, Kapke A et al. Hair care practices and their association with scalp and hair disorders in African American girls. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2011;64(2):253&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20728245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danby FW, Maddin WS, Margesson LJ et al. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of ketoconazole 2% shampoo versus selenium sulfide 2.5% shampoo in the treatment of moderate to severe dandruff. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1993;29(6):1008&#x2013;1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8245236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebwohl M, Plott T. Safety and efficacy of ciclopirox 1% shampoo for the treatment of seborrheic dermatitis of the scalp in the US population: Results of a double-blind, vehicle-controlled trial. Int J Dermatol. 2004;43(Supp. 1):17&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15271196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollins LC, Butt M, Hong J et al. Research in Brief: Survey of hair care practices in various ethnic and racial pediatric populations. Pediatr Dermatol. 2022;39(3):494&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35243692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam M, Zhu JW, Tadrous M et al. Association between Topical Calcineurin Inhibitor Use and Risk of Cancer, including Lymphoma, Keratinocyte Carcinoma, and Melanoma: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. JAMA Dermatology. 2021;157(5):549&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8014232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33787818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zirwas MJ, Draelos ZD, Dubois J et al. Efficacy of Roflumilast Foam, 0.3%, in Patients with Seborrheic Dermatitis: A Double-blind, Vehicle-Controlled Phase 2a Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Dermatology. 2023;159(6):613&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10157502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37133856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langley A, Beecker J. Management of common side effects of apremilast. J Cutan Med Surg. 2018;22(4):415&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29290125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong C, Virtucio C, Zemska O et al. Treatment of skin inflammation with benzoxaborole phosphodiesterase inhibitors: Selectivity, cellular activity, and effect on cytokines associated with skin inflammation and skin architecture changes. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2016;358(3):413&#x2013;422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27353073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborne DW, Berk D. Treatment of Skin Conditions Using High Krafft Temperature Anionic Surfactants. 2021. pp. 1&#x2013;31. Published online.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborne DW. Method and Formulation for Improving Roflumilast Skin Penetration Lag Time. 2019:. pp. 1&#x2013;10. Published online.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obukowho P, Gallagher K, Pereira AG Emulsifying System. 2007:. pp. 1&#x2013;7. Published online.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell MC., Jr. 17 Dangerous Ingredients to Avoid in Hair Care Products. https://www.consumernotice.org/products/dangerous-hair-care-ingredients/ Accessed November 10, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prajapati RR, Bhagwat SS. Effect of foam boosters on Krafft temperature. J Chem Eng Data. 2012;57(3):869&#x2013;874.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborne DW, Musakhanian J. Skin Penetration and Permeation Properties of Transcutol&#xae;&#x2014;Neat or Diluted Mixtures. AAPS PharmSciTech. 2018;19(8):3512&#x2013;3533.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6848246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30421383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukkanna KS, Stone NM, Ingram JR. Para-phenylenediamine allergy: Current perspectives on diagnosis and management. J Asthma Allergy. 2017;10:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5261844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28176912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt JD, Johansen JD, Nielsen MM et al. Immune responses to hair dyes containing toluene-2,5-diamine. Br J Dermatol. 2014;170(2):352&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24124869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Groot AC. Side-effects of henna and semi-permanent &#x201c;black henna&#x201d; tattoos: A full review. Contact Dermatitis. 2013;69(1):1&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23782354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee HS, Lin YW. Permeation of hair dye ingredients, p-phenylenediamine and aminophenol isomers, through protective gloves. Ann Occup Hyg. 2009;53(3):289&#x2013;296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19279162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone CA, Liu Y, Relling M V. et al. Immediate Hypersensitivity to Polyethylene Glycols and Polysorbates: More Common Than We Have Recognized. J Allergy Clin Immunol Pract. 2019;7(5):1533&#x2013;1540.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6706272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30557713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deza G, Gim&#xe9;nez-Arnau AM. Allergic contact dermatitis in preservatives: Current standing and future options. Curr Opin Allergy Clin Immunol. 2017;17(4):263&#x2013;268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28548971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneller-Pavelescu L, Ochando-Ibern&#xf3;n G, Silvestre-Salvador JF. An Update on Fragrance Contact Dermatitis. Curr Treat Options Allergy. 2019;6(1):92&#x2013;102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkic A, Stappen I. Essential oils and their single compounds in cosmetics-a critical review. Cosmetics. 2018;5(1):1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller E. Aromatherapy Handbook for Beauty, Hair, and Skin Care. 1999. Healing Arts Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessandrini A, Piraccini BM. Essential of hair care cosmetics. Cosmetics. 2016;3(34):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorg O, Kuenzli S, Saurat JH. Side Effects and Pitfalls in Retinoid Therapy. In: Vahlquist A, Duvic M, eds. Basic and Clinical Dermatology. 2007. pp. 225&#x2013;248. Informa Healthcare USA, Inc.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>