<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38884849</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1942</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>47</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Drug safety</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Drug Saf</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proceedings of the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network's 2023 National Meeting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>829</StartPage><EndPage>839</EndPage><MedlinePgn>829-839</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40264-024-01444-2</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pierson</LastName><ForeName>Tiphaine</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Outcomes Research and Evaluation, Research Institute of the McGill University Health Centre, Montreal, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arcand</LastName><ForeName>Verna</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kipohtakaw Education Centre, Alexander First Nations, Sturgeon County, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farrell</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruy&#x117;re Research Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Waterloo School of Pharmacy, Waterloo, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gagnon</LastName><ForeName>Camille L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network, Centre de Recherche, Institut Universitaire de G&#xe9;riatrie de Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Leung</LastName><ForeName>Larry</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McCarthy</LastName><ForeName>Lisa M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bruy&#x117;re Research Institute, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Waterloo School of Pharmacy, Waterloo, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Leslie Dan Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Better Health and Family Department, Trillium Health Partners, Mississauga, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family and Community Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murphy</LastName><ForeName>Andrea L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Pharmacy, Dalhousie University, Halifax, NS, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Persaud</LastName><ForeName>Nav</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family and Community Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Li Ka Shing Knowledge Institute, St. Michael's Hospital, Unity Health Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family and Community Medicine, St Michael's Hospital, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Health Policy, Management, and Evaluation, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raman-Wilms</LastName><ForeName>Lalitha</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Pharmacy, Rady Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, MB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre on Aging, University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, MB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silvius</LastName><ForeName>James L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network, Centre de Recherche, Institut Universitaire de G&#xe9;riatrie de Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Provincial Seniors Health and Continuing Care, Alberta Health Services, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Geriatric Medicine, Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steinman</LastName><ForeName>Michael A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of California San Francisco and San Francisco Veterans Affairs Medical Center, San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tannenbaum</LastName><ForeName>Cara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Universit&#xe9; de Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thompson</LastName><ForeName>Wade</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, Pharmacology, and Therapeutics, Faculty of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trimble</LastName><ForeName>Johanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patient Voices Network, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Sadowski</LastName><ForeName>Cheryl A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Alberta, Edmonton, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>McDonald</LastName><ForeName>Emily G</ForeName><Initials>EG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network, Centre de Recherche, Institut Universitaire de G&#xe9;riatrie de Montr&#xe9;al, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada. emily.mcdonald@mcgill.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Experimental Medicine, Department of Medicine, McGill University Health Centre, Office 3E.03, 5252 De Maisonneuve Blvd, Montreal, QC, H4A3S9, Canada. emily.mcdonald@mcgill.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of General Internal Medicine, Department of Medicine, McGill University Health Centre, Montr&#xe9;al, QC, Canada. emily.mcdonald@mcgill.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>MOP - 130529</GrantID><Agency>Operating Grant: Canadian Institutes of Health Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Drug Saf</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002928</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0114-5916</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002170" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Canada</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069340" MajorTopicYN="Y">Deprescriptions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057970" MajorTopicYN="N">Inappropriate Prescribing</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Tiphaine Pierson has received research support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network, a health organization that receives funding from Health Canada, Accelerating Clinical Trials Canada, and the Canadian Institute of Health Research. Verna Arcand received travel support and speaker honoraria from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting. Barbara Farrell receives annual honoraria from the US Deprescribing Research Network for her participation as a member of their Scientific Advisory Board, as well as travel expenses from the latter and from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend annual meetings. Camille L. Gagnon is assistant director of the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network, a health organization that receives funding from Health Canada, the Canadian Institutes of Health Research, and Accelerated Clinical Trials Canada. Larry Leung received travel support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting. He serves as a volunteer member of the board of directors for Indigicare Medicines Ltd. Lisa M. McCarthy received travel support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting, and receives funding from Health Canada, Canadian Institutes of Health Research, Ontario Centres for Learning, Research &amp; Innovation in Long-Term Care, and the University of Toronto. Andrea L. Murphy is a co-lead for Sleepwell and has received funding from the Drug Evaluation Alliance of Nova Scotia, and with the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network received funding from the Canadian Drug Agency Transition Office. Nav Persaud received travel support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting, and receives research funding from the Canadian Institutes of Health Research, Ontario SPOR Support Unit, and St Michael&#x2019;s Hospital Foundation. Lalitha Raman-Wilms received travel support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting. James L. Silvius is the executive director of the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network, a health organization that receives funding from Health Canada, the Canadian Institutes of Health Research, and Accelerated Clinical Trials Canada. James L. Silvius is also the Provincial Medical Director for Seniors Health and Senior Medical Director at Alberta Health Services, and both the chair of the Canadian Drug Expert Committee and a member of the Formulary Management Expert Committee at Canada&#x2019;s Drug and Health Technology Agency. Michael A. Steinman received travel support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting, and receives royalties from UpToDate, as well as honoraria from the American Geriatrics Society. Cara Tannenbaum receives financial compensation through a university interchange in her role as departmental science advisor to Health Canada since 2020. Cara Tannenbaum co-founded CaDeN and was its co-director from 2015&#x2013;2019. Wade Thompson received travel support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting, received research funding from Health Canada, the Canadian Institutes of Health Research, Michael Smith Health Research BC, and National Institute on Aging (USA), and received an honorarium from Pharmacy Practice Plus magazine for an article on deprescribing. Johanna Trimble received travel support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting. Cheryl A. Sadowski received travel support from the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network to attend the National Meeting, and received research funding from the Indigenous Wellness Core, the Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council, and the Indigenous Primary Health Care &amp; Policy Research Network. Emily G. McDonald is the scientific director of the Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network, a health organization that receives funding from Health Canada, the Canadian Institute of Health Research, and Accelerating Clinical Trials Canada. Emily G. McDonald has received funding from the Canadian Institute of Health Research and the Centre for Aging and Brain Health Innovation for her ongoing research evaluating the impact of MedSafer on prescribing practices.&#xa0;Emily G. McDonald is the CEO of MedSafer, the copyright for which is jointly held with McGill University and one other.&#xa0;</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38884849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11324714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40264-024-01444-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40264-024-01444-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pazan F, Wehling M. Polypharmacy in older adults: a narrative review of definitions, epidemiology and consequences. Eur Geriatr Med. 2021;12(3):443&#x2013;52.&#xa0;10.1007/s41999-021-00479-3. 10.1007/s41999-021-00479-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s41999-021-00479-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8149355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33694123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leelakanok N, Holcombe AL, Lund BC, et al. Association between polypharmacy and death: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Pharm Assoc. 2003;57(6):729&#x2013;38.&#xa0;10.1016/j.japh.2017.06.002. 10.1016/j.japh.2017.06.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.japh.2017.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28784299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leipzig RM, Cumming RG, Tinetti ME. Drugs and falls in older people: a systematic review and meta-analysis: II. Cardiac and analgesic drugs. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1999;47(1):40&#x2013;50. 10.1111/j.1532-5415.1999.tb01899.x. 10.1111/j.1532-5415.1999.tb01899.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.1999.tb01899.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9920228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carmona-Torres JM, Cobo-Cuenca AI, Recio-Andrade B, et al. Prevalence and factors associated with polypharmacy in the older people: 2006&#x2013;2014. J Clin Nurs. 2018;27(15&#x2013;16):2942&#x2013;52.&#xa0;10.1111/jocn.14371. 10.1111/jocn.14371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.14371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29603814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang N, Sundquist J, Sundquist K, et al. An increasing trend in the prevalence of polypharmacy in Sweden: a nationwide register-based study. Front Pharmacol. 2020;11:326. 10.3389/fphar.2020.00326. 10.3389/fphar.2020.00326</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2020.00326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7103636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32265705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlesworth CJ, Smit E, Lee DSH, et al. Polypharmacy among adults aged 65 years and older in the United States: 1988&#x2013;2010. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2015;70(8):989&#x2013;95.&#xa0;10.1093/gerona/glv013. 10.1093/gerona/glv013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/gerona/glv013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4573668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25733718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oktora MP, Denig P, Bos JHJ, et al. Trends in polypharmacy and dispensed drugs among adults in the Netherlands as compared to the United States. PLoS ONE. 2019;14(3):e0214240. 10.1371/journal.pone.0214240. 10.1371/journal.pone.0214240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0214240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6430511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30901377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Institute of Health Information. Drug use among seniors in Canada. 2021. https://www.cihi.ca/en/drug-use-among-seniors-in-canada. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assari S, Bazargan M. Race/ethnicity, socioeconomic status, and polypharmacy among older Americans. Pharmacy (Basel). 2019;7(2):41. 10.3390/pharmacy7020041. 10.3390/pharmacy7020041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/pharmacy7020041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6631748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31027176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuh JL, Hewuse AJ. The cost of unused medications. Fed Pract. 2015;32(4):14&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6363319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30766054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cussans A, Harvey G, Kemple T, et al. Interventions to reduce the environmental impact of medicines: a UK perspective. J Clim Change Health. 2021;4:100079. 10.1016/j.joclim.2021.100079. 10.1016/j.joclim.2021.100079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joclim.2021.100079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiem U, Wilm S, Greiner W, et al. Reduction of potentially inappropriate medication in the elderly: design of a cluster-randomised controlled trial in German primary care practices (RIME). Ther Adv Drug Saf. 2020;11:2042098620918459. 10.1177/2042098620918459. 10.1177/2042098620918459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2042098620918459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7225783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32435445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeve E, Gnjidic D, Long J, et al. A systematic review of the emerging definition of &#x201c;deprescribing&#x201d; with network analysis: implications for future research and clinical practice. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2015;80(6):1254&#x2013;68. 10.1111/bcp.12732. 10.1111/bcp.12732</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.12732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4693477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27006985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tannenbaum C, Farrell B, Shaw J, et al. An ecological approach to reducing potentially inappropriate medication use: Canadian Deprescribing Network. Can J Aging. 2017;36(1):97&#x2013;107. 10.1017/S0714980816000702. 10.1017/S0714980816000702</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0714980816000702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28091333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network. 2018 Summit on Medication Safety. Reports. 2018. https://www.deprescribingnetwork.ca/2018-summit-on-medication-safety. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner JP, Currie J, Trimble J, et al. Strategies to promote public engagement around deprescribing. Ther Adv Drug Saf. 2018;9(11):653&#x2013;65. 10.1177/2042098618794165. 10.1177/2042098618794165</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2042098618794165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6243424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30479740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell B, Raman-Wilms L, Sadowski CA, et al. A proposed curricular framework for an interprofessional approach to deprescribing. Med Sci Educ. 2023;33(2):551&#x2013;67. 10.1007/s40670-022-01704-9. 10.1007/s40670-022-01704-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40670-022-01704-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10226933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37261023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network. A national strategy for Canada. Policy. 2022. https://www.deprescribingnetwork.ca/policy. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SaferMedsNL. https://safermedsnl.ca/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Canada. Canadian Drug Agency Transition Office. Activities and responsibilities. Last modified 2023. https://www.canada.ca/en/health-canada/corporate/about-health-canada/activities-responsibilities/canadian-drug-agency-transition-office.html. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Centre for Truth and Reconciliation, University of Manitoba. https://nctr.ca/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reeve E, To J, Hendrix I, et al. Patient barriers to and enablers of deprescribing: a systematic review. Drugs Aging. 2013;30(10):793&#x2013;807. 10.1007/s40266-013-0106-8. 10.1007/s40266-013-0106-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40266-013-0106-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23912674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linsky A, Zimmerman KM. Provider and system-level barriers to deprescribing: interconnected problems and solutions. Public Policy Aging Rep. 2018;28(4):129&#x2013;33. 10.1093/ppar/pry030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ppar/pry030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleepwell. https://mysleepwell.ca/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy AL, Turner JP, Rajda M, et al. A protocol for a randomized controlled trial comparing Sleepwell, EMPOWER, and treatment-as-usual for benzodiazepine receptor agonist discontinuation in older adults: the your answers when needing sleep in New Brunswick (YAWNS NB) study. Explor Res Clin Soc Pharm. 2022;7:100164. 10.1016/j.rcsop.2022.100164. 10.1016/j.rcsop.2022.100164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rcsop.2022.100164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9420952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36045710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kania J, Kramer M. Collective impact. Stanford Soc Innov Rev. 2011;9(1):36&#x2013;41. 10.48558/5900-KN19. 10.48558/5900-KN19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.48558/5900-KN19</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cragg A, Small SS, Lau E, et al. Sharing adverse drug event reports between hospitals and community pharmacists to inform re-dispensing: an analysis of reports and process outcomes. Drug Saf. 2023;46(11):1161&#x2013;72. 10.1007/s40264-023-01348-7. 10.1007/s40264-023-01348-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40264-023-01348-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10632212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37783974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDonald EG, Wu PE, Rashidi B, et al. The MedSafer study: electronic decision support for deprescribing in hospitalized older adults: a cluster randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2022;182(3):265&#x2013;73. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2021.7429. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2021.7429</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2021.7429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35040926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrell B, Famiyeh IM, Preteroti M, et al. Ten years of deprescribing guideline work: where are we now? Can Fam Physician. 2023;69(10):666&#x2013;9. 10.46747/cfp.6910666. 10.46747/cfp.6910666</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.46747/cfp.6910666</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10575655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37833083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutics Initiative, The University of British Columbia. Prescribing portraits. 2022. https://www.ti.ubc.ca/portrait/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michael HU, Enechukwu O, Brouillette MJ, et al. The prognostic utility of anticholinergic burden scales: an integrative review and gap analysis. Drugs Aging. 2023;40(9):763&#x2013;83. 10.1007/s40266-023-01050-4. 10.1007/s40266-023-01050-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40266-023-01050-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37462902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bortolussi-Courval E, Podymow T, Trinh E, et al. Electronic decision support for deprescribing in patients on hemodialysis: clinical research protocol for a prospective, controlled, quality improvement study. Can J Kidney Health Dis. 2023;10:20543581231165712. 10.1177/20543581231165712. 10.1177/20543581231165712</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20543581231165712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10331104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37435299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics Canada. Primary health care access among First Nations people living off reserve, M&#xe9;tis and Inuit, 2017 to 2020. Indigenous peoples thematic series. 2023. https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/pub/41-20-0002/412000022023005-eng.htm. Accessed 7 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham S, Muir NM, Formsma JW, et al. First Nations, Inuit and Metis peoples living in urban areas of Canada and their access to healthcare: a systematic review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(11):5956.&#xa0;10.3390/ijerph20115956. 10.3390/ijerph20115956</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20115956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10252616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37297560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen NH, Subhan FB, Williams K, et al. Barriers and mitigating strategies to healthcare access in indigenous communities of Canada: a narrative review. Healthcare (Basel). 2020;8(2):112. 10.3390/healthcare8020112. 10.3390/healthcare8020112</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare8020112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7349010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32357396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fazelipour M, Leung L, Min J, et al. Building practice-informed indigenous health curricula: a systematic review of pharmacy services for indigenous peoples. Curr Pharm Teach Learn. 2022;14(11):1448&#x2013;60. 10.1016/j.cptl.2022.09.019. 10.1016/j.cptl.2022.09.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cptl.2022.09.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36180334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min J, Albon S, Leung L, et al. Creating a pharmacy elective course in indigenous health. Curr Pharm Teach Learn. 2020;12(8):1004&#x2013;13. 10.1016/j.cptl.2020.04.010. 10.1016/j.cptl.2020.04.010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cptl.2020.04.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32564987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbet R. An UPROOT approach to decolonizing pharmacy education. Stories. The University of British Columbia. 2023. https://tlef.ubc.ca/stories/uproot-approach-decolonization-pharmacy-education/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cortes K, Smith L. Pharmaceutical access and use during the pandemic in insights on Canadian society. Statistics Canada. 2022. https://www150.statcan.gc.ca/n1/en/pub/75-006-x/2022001/article/00011-eng.pdf?st=jN_qX5db. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persaud N, Bedard M, Boozary AS, et al. Effect on treatment adherence of distributing essential medicines at no charge: the CLEAN Meds randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2020;18(1):27&#x2013;34. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2019.4472. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2019.4472</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2019.4472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6784757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31589276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persaud N, Bedard M, Boozary AS, et al. Adherence at 2 years with distribution of essential medicines at no charge: the CLEAN Meds randomized clinical trial. PLoS Med. 2021;18(5):e100359. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003590. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003590</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34019540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persaud N, Bedard M, Boozary AS, et al. Effect of free medicine distribution on health care costs in Canada over 3 years: a secondary analysis of the CLEAN Meds randomized clinical trial. JAMA Health Forum. 2023;4(5):e231127. 10.1001/jamahealthforum.2023.1127. 10.1001/jamahealthforum.2023.1127</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamahealthforum.2023.1127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10220517</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37234014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Canada. A prescription for Canada: achieving pharmacare for all. 2019. https://www.canada.ca/en/health-canada/corporate/about-health-canada/public-engagement/external-advisory-bodies/implementation-national-pharmacare/final-report.html. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The US Deprescribing Research Network. https://deprescribingresearch.org/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson K, Stowasser D, Freeman C, et al. Prescriber barriers and enablers to minimising potentially inappropriate medications in adults: a systematic review and thematic synthesis. BMJ Open. 2014;4(12):e006544. 10.1136/bmjopen-2014-006544. 10.1136/bmjopen-2014-006544</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2014-006544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4265124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25488097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doherty AJ, Boland P, Reed J, et al. Barriers and facilitators to deprescribing in primary care: a systematic review. BJGP Open. 2020;4(3):bjgpopen20X101096. 10.3399/bjgpopen20X101096. 10.3399/bjgpopen20X101096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3399/bjgpopen20X101096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7465575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32723784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Canada. Module 1: overview of Vanessa&#x2019;s Law and reporting requirements. Education modules to meet requirements for mandatory hospital reporting. 2019. https://www.canada.ca/en/health-canada/services/drugs-health-products/medeffect-canada/adverse-reaction-reporting/mandatory-hospital-reporting/education/module-1.html. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckelman MJ, Sherman JD, MacNeill AJ. Life cycle environmental emissions and health damages from the Canadian healthcare system: an economic-environmental-epidemiological analysis. PLoS Med. 2018;15(7):e1002623. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1002623. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1002623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1002623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6067712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30063712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevalier J, Buckles D. Participatory action research: theory and methods for engaged inquiry. 2nd ed. Routledge; 2019. 10.4324/9781351033268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Institute for Health Information. Drug use among seniors in Canada, 2016. 2016. https://secure.cihi.ca/free_products/drug-use-among-seniors-2016-en-web.pdf. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sleepwell. L&#x2019;histoire de Georges. 2020. https://mieux-dormir.ca/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galley E, Farrell B, Conklin J, et al. Using community engagement to initiate conversations about medication management and deprescribing in primary care. J Commun Engage Scholar. 2022;15(1). 10.54656/jces.v15i1.447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Medication Appropriateness and Deprescribing Network. https://www.deprescribingnetwork.ca/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11324714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38884849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deprescribing.org. https://deprescribing.org/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Therapeutics Initiative, The University of British Columbia. https://www.ti.ubc.ca/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MedSafer. Working towards safer prescribing. https://www.medsafer.org/. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hau JP, Brasher PMA, Cragg A, et al. Using ActionADE to create information continuity to reduce re-exposures to harmful medications: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2021;22(1):119. 10.1186/s13063-021-05061-7. 10.1186/s13063-021-05061-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-021-05061-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7866708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33546752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Medications without harm: initiatives. 2024. https://www.who.int/initiatives/medication-without-harm. Accessed 27 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>