<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40171832</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1651-2057</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>105</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta dermato-venereologica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Derm Venereol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chronic Hand Eczema, Real World, and Patient Centricity: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>adv42596</StartPage><MedlinePgn>adv42596</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">42596</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2340/actadv.v105.42596</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic hand eczema is a multifactorial, fluctuating, inflammatory skin disease of the hands and wrists, defined as hand eczema that persists for at least 3&#xa0;months or recurs at least twice within 1 year. Chronic hand eczema is heterogeneous in nature with different clinical manifestations. This chronic condition can significantly impact daily activities and health-related quality of life for patients, including notable physical, psychosocial, occupational, and socioeconomic burdens. However, awareness of the disease and the patient experience remains poor. This review aims to improve understanding of chronic hand eczema in the context of its underlying pathogenesis, clinical subtypes and presentation, and risk factors. Additionally, an overview of the patient experience of the disease, including health-related quality of life and socioeconomic implications, is provided. Improved understanding of chronic hand eczema will support optimal patient care by empowering healthcare providers to more quickly and correctly diagnose this disease with high unmet treatment needs and subsequently offer appropriate holistic care.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molin</LastName><ForeName>Sonja</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Queen's University, Kingston, Canada; Department of Dermatology, Venerology and Allergy, Charit&#xe9;-Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany. sonja-christine.molin@charite.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guttman-Yassky</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thyssen</LastName><ForeName>Jacob P</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>LEO Pharma A/S, Ballerup, Denmark and Department of Dermatology, Bispebjerg Hospital, University of Copenhagen, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bewley</LastName><ForeName>Anthony</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barts Health NHS Trust &amp; QMUL, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Sweden</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Derm Venereol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370310</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0001-5555</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006229" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hand Dermatoses</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004485" MajorTopicYN="Y">Eczema</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017281" MajorTopicYN="N">Cost of Illness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012959" MajorTopicYN="N">Socioeconomic Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>SM has received honoraria as consultant/adviser or speaker and/or grants from AbbVie, Almirall, Aralez, Arcutis, Basilea, Bausch Health and Lomb, Bristol Myer Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, Evidera, Galderma, GSK, Incyte, Jamp Biopharma, LEO Pharma A/S, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Pfizer, Sanofi, Sun Pharma, and UCB. She is currently an investigator for Novartis and LEO Pharma A/S. EG-Y is an employee of Mount Sinai and has received research grants (paid to the institution) from Abbvie, Amgen, AnaptysBio, Arcutis, Aslan, Bristol Myers Squibb, Concert, Eli Lilly, GSK, Incyte, Inmagene Bio, Janssen, LEO Pharma A/S, Pfizer, Q32 Bio, Regeneron, and Sanofi. She is a consultant for Abbvie, Almirall, Amgen, AnaptysBio, Apogee Therapeutics, Apollo Therapeutics, Artax Biopharma, Astria, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, Calliditas, Cara Therapeutics, Celldex, Centrexion Therapeutics, Connect Bio-pharm, Coty, DBV Technologies, Eli Lilly, Enveda Biosciences, Escient Pharmaceuticals, Fairmount Funds Management, FL2022-001, Inc., Galderma, Gate Bio, Google Ventures, GSK Immunology, Incyte, Inmagene, Janssen Biotech, Jasper Therapeutics, Kymera Therapeutics, Kyowa Kirin, LEO Pharma A/S, Matchpoint Therapeutics, Merck, Nektar Therapeutics, Novartis Pharmaceuticals, NUMAB Therapeutics AG, Nuvig, OrbiMed Advisors, OTSUKA, Pfizer, Pharmaxis, Pioneering Medicines, Proteologix US, Inc., RAPT, RayThera, Inc., Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, Ribon Therapeutics, Sanofi, SATO, Schr&#xf6;dinger, Sitryx, Sun Pharma Advanced Research Company (SPARC), Takeda, Teva Branded Pharmaceutical Products R&amp;D, Inc., UCB, and Ventyx Biosciences. JPT is an employee and stockholder of LEO Pharma A/S and has been a speaker/investigator/adviser for AbbVie, Almirall, Arena Pharmaceuticals, Aslan Pharmaceuticals, Eli Lilly, LEO Pharma A/S, OM Pharma, Pfizer, Regeneron, Sanofi-Genzyme, and Union Therapeutics. AB has had ad hoc consultancy/travel bursaries/lecturing fees from AbbVie, Almirall, Bristol Myers Squibb, Galderma, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, LEO Pharma A/S, Lilly, MSD, Novartis Pfizer, Sanofi, and UCB.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40171832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11977413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/actadv.v105.42596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thyssen JP, Schuttelaar MLA, Alfonso JH, Andersen KE, Angelova-Fischer I, Arents BWM, et al. Guidelines for diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of hand eczema. Contact Dermatitis 2022; 86: 357&#x2013;378. 10.1111/cod.14035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cod.14035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34971008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaade AS, Alinaghi F, Dietz JB, Erichsen CY, Johansen JD. Chronic hand eczema: a prevalent disease in the general population associated with reduced quality of life and poor overall health measures. Contact Dermatitis 2023; 89: 453&#x2013;463. 10.1111/cod.14407</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cod.14407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37634937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidinger S, Novak N. Hand eczema. Lancet 2024; 404: 2476&#x2013;2486. 10.1016/S0140-6736(24)01810-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(24)01810-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39615508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thyssen JP, Silverberg JI, Guttman-Yassky E. Chronic hand eczema understanding has ramifications on clinical management. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2020; 34: e429&#x2013;e430. 10.1111/jdv.16375</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.16375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32180277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apfelbacher CJ, Ofenloch RF, Weisshaar E, Molin S, Bauer A, Mahler V, et al. Chronic hand eczema in Germany: 5-year follow-up data from the CARPE registry. Contact Dermatitis 2019; 80: 45&#x2013;53. 10.1111/cod.13113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cod.13113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30246346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaade AS, Simonsen AB, Halling AS, Thyssen JP, Johansen JD. Prevalence, incidence, and severity of hand eczema in the general population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Contact Dermatitis 2021; 84: 361&#x2013;374. 10.1111/cod.13804</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cod.13804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33548072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubin C, Del Duca E, Guttman-Yassky E. Drugs for the treatment of chronic hand eczema: successes and key challenges. Ther Clin Risk Manag 2020; 16: 1319&#x2013;1332. 10.2147/TCRM.S292504</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/TCRM.S292504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7780849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33408476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant L, Seiding Larsen L, Burrows K, Belsito DV, Weisshaar E, Diepgen T, et al. Development of a conceptual model of chronic hand eczema (CHE) based on qualitative interviews with patients and expert dermatologists. Adv Ther 2020; 37: 692&#x2013;706. 10.1007/s12325-019-01164-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-019-01164-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7004418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31956966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee GR, Maarouf M, Hendricks AK, Lee DE, Shi VY. Current and emerging therapies for hand eczema. Dermatol Ther 2019; 32: e12840. 10.1111/dth.12840</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dth.12840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30693618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaade AS, Wang X, S&#xf8;lberg JBK, McCauley BD, Thyssen JP, Becker C, et al. Inflammatory plasma signature of chronic hand eczema: associations with aetiological and clinical subtypes. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2024; 38: 1101&#x2013;1111. 10.1111/jdv.19742</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.19742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38151335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quaade AS, Wang X, S&#xf8;lberg JBK, Ulrich NH, McCauley BD, Thyssen JP, et al. Circulating biomarkers are associated with disease severity of chronic hand eczema and atopic dermatitis. Br J Dermatol 2023; 189: 114&#x2013;124. 10.1093/bjd/ljad110</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjd/ljad110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37052074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tancredi V, Buononato D, Caccavale S, Di Brizzi EV, Di Caprio R, Argenziano G, et al. New perspectives in the management of chronic hand eczema: lessons from pathogenesis. Int J Mol Sci 2023; 25: 362. 10.3390/ijms25010362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms25010362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10778876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38203533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen MB, Skov L, Menn&#xe9; T, Johansen JD, Olsen J. Gene expression time course in the human skin during elicitation of allergic contact dermatitis. J Invest Dermatol 2007; 127: 2585&#x2013;2595. 10.1038/sj.jid.5700902</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.jid.5700902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17597826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg FM, Wardenaar R, Voorberg AN, Spierings DCJ, Schuttelaar MA. Transcriptional differences between vesicular hand eczema and atopic dermatitis. Contact Dermatitis 2024; 90: 23&#x2013;31. 10.1111/cod.14442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cod.14442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37857578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg JI, Guttman-Yassky E, Agner T, Bissonnette R, Cohen DE, Simpson E, et al. Chronic hand eczema guidelines from an expert panel of the International Eczema Council. Dermatitis 2021; 32: 319&#x2013;326. 10.1097/DER.0000000000000659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/DER.0000000000000659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8437046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32991335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agner T, Aalto-Korte K, Andersen KE, Foti C, Gimen&#xe9;z-Arnau A, Goncalo M, et al. Classification of hand eczema. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2015; 29: 2417&#x2013;2422. 10.1111/jdv.13308</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.13308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26371368</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gimenez-Arnau AM, Pesque D, Maibach HI. Contact urticaria syndrome: a comprehensive review. Curr Dermatol Rep 2022; 11: 194&#x2013;201. 10.1007/s13671-022-00379-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13671-022-00379-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9672538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36415744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agner T, Aalto-Korte K, Andersen KE, Foti C, Gimen&#xe9;z-Arnau A, Goncalo M, et al. Factors associated with combined hand and foot eczema. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2017; 31: 828&#x2013;832. 10.1111/jdv.14016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.14016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27768241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petersen AH, Johansen JD, Hald M. Hand eczema &#x2013; prognosis and consequences: a 7-year follow-up study. Br J Dermatol 2014; 171: 1428&#x2013;1433. 10.1111/bjd.13371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.13371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25156938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertoli MJ, Schwartz RA, Janniger CK. Autoeczematization: a strange id reaction of the skin. Cutis 2021; 108: 163&#x2013;166. 10.12788/cutis.0342</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12788/cutis.0342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34826280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heede NG, Thyssen JP, Thuesen BH, Linneberg A, Johansen JD. Predictive factors of self-reported hand eczema in adult Danes: a population-based cohort study with 5-year follow-up. Br J Dermatol 2016; 175: 287&#x2013;295. 10.1111/bjd.14476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.14476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26872425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xf6;nhagen C, Lid&#xe9;n C, Wahlgren CF, Ballardini N, Bergstr&#xf6;m A, Kull I, et al. Hand eczema and atopic dermatitis in adolescents: a prospective cohort study from the BAMSE project. Br J Dermatol 2015; 173: 1175&#x2013;1182. 10.1111/bjd.14019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.14019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26152456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruff SMD, Engebretsen KA, Zachariae C, Johansen JD, Silverberg JI, Egeberg A, et al. The association between atopic dermatitis and hand eczema: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Dermatol 2018; 178: 879&#x2013;888. 10.1111/bjd.16147</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.16147</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29172235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apfelbacher C, Bewley A, Molin S, Fargnoli MC, Gimenez-Arnau AM, Brignoli L, et al. Prevalence of chronic hand eczema in adults: a cross-sectional survey of over 60,000 respondents in the general population in Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Spain, and the United Kingdom. Br J Dermatol 2025. Jan 11 [Online ahead of print]. 10.1093/bjd/ljaf020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjd/ljaf020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39797908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lund T, Petersen SB, Flachs EM, Ebbeh&#xf8;j NE, Bonde JP, Agner T. Risk of work-related hand eczema in relation to wet work exposure. Scand J Work Environ Health 2020; 46: 437&#x2013;445. 10.5271/sjweh.3876</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5271/sjweh.3876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8506312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31956920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lerbaek A, Kyvik KO, Mortensen J, Bryld LE, Menn&#xe9; T, Agner T. Heritability of hand eczema is not explained by comorbidity with atopic dermatitis. J Invest Dermatol 2007; 127: 1632&#x2013;1640. 10.1038/sj.jid.5700750</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.jid.5700750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17301829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heede NG, Thyssen JP, Thuesen BH, Linneberg A, Johansen JD. Anatomical patterns of dermatitis in adult filaggrin mutation carriers. J Am Acad Dermatol 2015; 72: 440&#x2013;448. 10.1016/j.jaad.2015.01.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2015.01.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25659224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalgard FJ, Gieler U, Tomas-Aragones L, Lien L, Poot F, Jemec GBE, et al. The psychological burden of skin diseases: a cross-sectional multicenter study among dermatological out-patients in 13 European countries. J Invest Dermatol 2015; 135: 984&#x2013;991. 10.1038/jid.2014.530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jid.2014.530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4378256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25521458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed A, Shah R, Papadopoulos L, Bewley A. An ethnographic study into the psychological impact and adaptive mechanisms of living with hand eczema. Clin Exp Dermatol 2015; 40: 495&#x2013;501. 10.1111/ced.12619</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ced.12619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25754269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong A, Hahn-Pedersen J, Bartlett C, Glanville J, Thyssen JP. Economic burden of chronic hand eczema: a review. Am J Clin Dermatol 2022; 23: 287&#x2013;300. 10.1007/s40257-021-00669-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-021-00669-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9142418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosterhaven JAF, Flach PA, B&#xfc;ltmann U, Schuttelaar MLA. Presenteeism in a Dutch hand eczema population: a cross-sectional survey. Contact Dermatitis 2018; 79: 10&#x2013;19. 10.1111/cod.12993</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cod.12993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6001425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29607512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fowler JF, Ghosh A, Sung J, Emani S, Chang J, Den E, et al. Impact of chronic hand dermatitis on quality of life, work productivity, activity impairment, and medical costs. J Am Acad Dermatol 2006; 54: 448&#x2013;457. 10.1016/j.jaad.2005.11.1053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2005.11.1053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16488296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Egeberg A, Schlapbach C, Haugaard JH, Nymand L, Thein D, Thomsen SF, et al. Adverse events from topical corticosteroid use in chronic hand eczema: findings from the Danish Skin Cohort. JAAD Int 2024; 14: 77&#x2013;83. 10.1016/j.jdin.2023.11.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdin.2023.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10808964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38274394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scalone L, Cortesi PA, Mantovani LG, Belisari A, Ayala F, Fortina AB, et al. Clinical epidemiology of hand eczema in patients accessing dermatological reference centres: results from Italy. Br J Dermatol 2015; 172: 187&#x2013;195. 10.1111/bjd.13220</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.13220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24974982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christoffers WA, Politiek K, Coenraads PJ, van der Schaft J, de Bruin-Weller MS, Schuttelaar ML. Drug survival of cyclosporine in the treatment of hand eczema: a multicentre, daily use study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2016; 30: 63&#x2013;66. 10.1111/jdv.13057</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.13057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25731072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oosterhaven JAF, Politiek K, Schuttelaar M-LA. Azathioprine treatment and drug survival in patients with chronic hand eczema: results from daily practice. Contact Dermatitis 2017; 76: 304&#x2013;307. 10.1111/cod.12691</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cod.12691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28386975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Politiek K, Christoffers WA, Coenraads PJ, Schuttelaar MA. Alitretinoin and acitretin in severe chronic hand eczema: results from a retrospective daily practice study. Dermatol Ther 2016; 29: 364&#x2013;371. 10.1111/dth.12362</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dth.12362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27146260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Politiek K, van der Schaft J, Christoffers WA, Coenraads PJ, van den Reek JM, de Jong EM, et al. Drug survival of methotrexate treatment in hand eczema patients: results from a retrospective daily practice study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol 2016; 30: 1405&#x2013;1407. 10.1111/jdv.13253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.13253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26369396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho JSS, Molin S. A review of existing and new treatments for the management of hand eczema. J Cutan Med Surg 2023; 27: 493&#x2013;503. 10.1177/12034754231188325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/12034754231188325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10617006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37496489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency . Anzupgo: EPAR &#x2013; Product information
[accessed 24 March 2024]. Available from: https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/anzupgo.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>