<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36156810</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-2787</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Season>Jul-Aug</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Mass spectrometry reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mass Spectrom Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Inferring kinase activity from phosphoproteomic data: Tool comparison and recent applications.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>725</StartPage><EndPage>751</EndPage><MedlinePgn>725-751</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mas.21808</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Aberrant cellular signaling pathways are a hallmark of cancer and other diseases. One of the most important signaling mechanisms involves protein phosphorylation/dephosphorylation. Protein phosphorylation is catalyzed by protein kinases, and over 530 protein kinases have been identified in the human genome. Aberrant kinase activity is one of the drivers of tumorigenesis and cancer progression and results in altered phosphorylation abundance of downstream substrates. Upstream kinase activity can be inferred from the global collection of phosphorylated substrates. Mass spectrometry-based phosphoproteomic experiments nowadays routinely allow identification and quantitation of &gt;10k phosphosites per biological sample. This substrate phosphorylation footprint can be used to infer upstream kinase activities using tools like Kinase Substrate Enrichment Analysis (KSEA), Posttranslational Modification Substrate Enrichment Analysis (PTM-SEA), and Integrative Inferred Kinase Activity Analysis (INKA). Since the topic of kinase activity inference is very active with many new approaches reported in the past 3 years, we would like to give an overview of the field. In this review, an inventory of kinase activity inference tools, their underlying algorithms, statistical frameworks, kinase-substrate databases, and user-friendliness is presented. The most widely-used tools are compared in-depth. Subsequently, recent applications of the tools are described focusing on clinical tissues and hematological samples. Two main application areas for kinase activity inference tools can be discerned. (1) Maximal biological insights can be obtained from large data sets with group comparisons using multiple complementary tools (e.g.,&#xa0;PTM-SEA and KSEA or INKA).&#xa0;(2)&#xa0;In the oncology context where personalized treatment requires analysis of single samples, INKA for example, has emerged as tool that can prioritize actionable kinases for targeted inhibition.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 The Authors. Mass Spectrometry Reviews published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piersma</LastName><ForeName>Sander R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>OncoProteomics Laboratory Amsterdam UMC, Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valles-Marti</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>OncoProteomics Laboratory Amsterdam UMC, Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rolfs</LastName><ForeName>Frank</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>OncoProteomics Laboratory Amsterdam UMC, Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pham</LastName><ForeName>Thang V</ForeName><Initials>TV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>OncoProteomics Laboratory Amsterdam UMC, Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henneman</LastName><ForeName>Alex A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>OncoProteomics Laboratory Amsterdam UMC, Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jim&#xe9;nez</LastName><ForeName>Connie R</ForeName><Initials>CR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>OncoProteomics Laboratory Amsterdam UMC, Vrije Universiteit, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>KWF10212</GrantID><Agency>"The Dutch Cancer Society is acknowledged for support of AVM (KWF10212)"</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Mass Spectrom Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8219702</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0277-7037</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010750">Phosphoproteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.-</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011494">Protein Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040901" MajorTopicYN="Y">Proteomics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010750" MajorTopicYN="Y">Phosphoproteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010766" MajorTopicYN="N">Phosphorylation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011494" MajorTopicYN="Y">Protein Kinases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013058" MajorTopicYN="N">Mass Spectrometry</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000465" MajorTopicYN="N">Algorithms</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011499" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein Processing, Post-Translational</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D030562" MajorTopicYN="N">Databases, Protein</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012984" MajorTopicYN="N">Software</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013379" MajorTopicYN="N">Substrate Specificity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36156810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mas.21808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Aasebo, E., F. S. Berven, S. Bartaula&#x2010;Brevik, T. Stokowy, R. Hovland, M. Vaudel, S. O. Doskeland, E. McCormack, T. S. Batth, J. V. Olsen, O. Bruserud, F. Selheim, and M. Hernandez&#x2010;Valladares. 2020. &#x2018;Proteome and phosphoproteome changes associated with prognosis in acute myeloid leukemia&#x2019;, Cancers (Basel), 12; 709.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aasebo, E., F. S. Berven, R. Hovland, S. O. Doskeland, O. Bruserud, F. Selheim, and M. Hernandez&#x2010;Valladares. 2020. &#x2018;The progression of acute myeloid leukemia from first diagnosis to chemoresistant relapse: a comparison of proteomic and phosphoproteomic profiles&#x2019;, Cancers (Basel), 12; 1466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe, Y., H. Hirano, H. Shoji, A. Tada, J. Isoyama, A. Kakudo, D. Gunji, K. Honda, N. Boku, J. Adachi, and T. Tomonaga. 2020. &#x2018;Comprehensive characterization of the phospho&#x2010;proteome of gastric cancer from endoscopic biopsy specimens&#x2019;, Theranostics, 10: 2115&#x2010;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Alphen, C., J. Cloos, R. Beekhof, D. G. J. Cucchi, S. R. Piersma, J. C. Knol, A. A. Henneman, T. V. Pham, J. van Meerloo, G. J. Ossenkoppele, H. M. W. Verheul, J. J. W. M. Janssen, and C. R. Jimenez. 2020. &#x2018;Phosphotyrosine&#x2010;based phosphoproteomics for target identification and drug response prediction in AML cell lines&#x2019;, Mol Cell Proteomics, 19: 884&#x2010;99.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Alphen, C., D. G. J. Cucchi, J. Cloos, T. Schelfhorst, A. A. Henneman, S. R. Piersma, T. V. Pham, J. C. Knol, C. R. Jimenez, and J. J. W. M. Janssen. 2021. &#x2018;The influence of delay in mononuclear cell isolation on acute myeloid leukemia phosphorylation profiles&#x2019;, J Proteomics, 238: 104134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson, L., and J. Porath. 1986. &#x2018;Isolation of phosphoproteins by immobilized metal (Fe3+) affinity chromatography&#x2019;, Anal Biochem, 154: 250&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bai, B., X. Wang, Y. Li, P. C. Chen, K. Yu, K. K. Dey, J. M. Yarbro, X. Han, B. M. Lutz, S. Rao, Y. Jiao, J. M. Sifford, J. Han, M. Wang, H. Tan, T. I. Shaw, J. H. Cho, S. Zhou, H. Wang, M. Niu, A. Mancieri, K. A. Messler, X. Sun, Z. Wu, V. Pagala, A. A. High, W. Bi, H. Zhang, H. Chi, V. Haroutunian, B. Zhang, T. G. Beach, G. Yu, and J. Peng. 2020. &#x2018;Deep multilayer brain proteomics identifies molecular networks in Alzheimer's disease progression&#x2019;, Neuron, 105: 975&#x2010;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbie, D. A., P. Tamayo, J. S. Boehm, S. Y. Kim, S. E. Moody, I. F. Dunn, A. C. Schinzel, P. Sandy, E. Meylan, C. Scholl, S. Frohling, E. M. Chan, M. L. Sos, K. Michel, C. Mermel, S. J. Silver, B. A. Weir, J. H. Reiling, Q. Sheng, P. B. Gupta, R. C. Wadlow, H. Le, S. Hoersch, B. S. Wittner, S. Ramaswamy, D. M. Livingston, D. M. Sabatini, M. Meyerson, R. K. Thomas, E. S. Lander, J. P. Mesirov, D. E. Root, D. G. Gilliland, T. Jacks, and W. C. Hahn. 2009. &#x2018;Systematic RNA interference reveals that oncogenic KRAS&#x2010;driven cancers require TBK1&#x2019;, Nature, 462: 108&#x2010;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball, L. E., B. Agana, S. Comte&#x2010;Walters, D. C. Rockey, H. Masur, S. Kottilil, and E. G. Meissner. 2021. &#x2018;Hepatitis C virus treatment with direct&#x2010;acting antivirals induces rapid changes in the hepatic proteome&#x2019;, J Viral Hepat, 28(11): 1614&#x2010;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beausoleil, S. A., J. Villen, S. A. Gerber, J. Rush, and S. P. Gygi. 2006. &#x2018;A probability&#x2010;based approach for high&#x2010;throughput protein phosphorylation analysis and site localization&#x2019;, Nat&#xa0;Biotechnol, 24: 1285&#x2010;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beekhof, R., C. van Alphen, A. A. Henneman, J. C. Knol, T. V. Pham, F. Rolfs, M. Labots, E. Henneberry, T. Y. Le Large, R. R. de Haas, S. R. Piersma, V. Vurchio, A. Bertotti, L. Trusolino, H. M. Verheul, and C. R. Jimenez. 2019. &#x2018;INKA, an integrative data analysis pipeline for phosphoproteomic inference of active kinases&#x2019;, Mol Syst Biol, 15: e8981.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Beijnum, J. R., A. Weiss, R. H. Berndsen, T. J. Wong, L. C. Reckman, S. R. Piersma, M. Zoetemelk, R. de Haas, O. Dormond, A. Bex, A. A. Henneman, C. R. Jimenez, A. W. Griffioen, and P. Nowak&#x2010;Sliwinska. 2020. &#x2018;Integrating phenotypic search and phosphoproteomic profiling of active kinases for optimization of drug mixtures for RCC treatment&#x2019;, Cancers (Basel), 12; 2697.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekker&#x2010;Jensen, D. B., O. M. Bernhardt, A. Hogrebe, A. Martinez&#x2010;Val, L. Verbeke, T. Gandhi, C. D. Kelstrup, L. Reiter, and J. V. Olsen. 2020. &#x2018;Rapid and site&#x2010;specific deep phosphoproteome profiling by data&#x2010;independent acquisition without the need for spectral libraries&#x2019;, Nat Commun, 11; 787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beli, P., N. Lukashchuk, S. A. Wagner, B. T. Weinert, J. V. Olsen, L. Baskcomb, M. Mann, S. P. Jackson, and C. Choudhary. 2012. &#x2018;Proteomic investigations reveal a role for RNA processing factor THRAP3 in the DNA damage response&#x2019;, Mol Cell, 46: 212&#x2212;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennetzen, M. V., D. H. Larsen, J. Bunkenborg, J. Bartek, J. Lukas, and J. S. Andersen. 2010. &#x2018;Site&#x2010;specific phosphorylation dynamics of the nuclear proteome during the DNA damage response&#x2019;, Mol&#xa0;Cell&#xa0;Proteomics, 9: 1314&#x2010;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bensimon, A., A. Schmidt, Y. Ziv, R. Elkon, S. Y. Wang, D. J. Chen, R. Aebersold, and Y. Shiloh. 2010. &#x2018;ATM&#x2010;dependent and &#x2010;independent dynamics of the nuclear phosphoproteome after DNA damage&#x2019;, Sci Signal, 3: rs3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casado, P., M. Hijazi, H. Gerdes, and P. R. Cutillas. 2022. &#x2018;Implementation of clinical phosphoproteomics and proteomics for personalized medicine&#x2019;, Methods Mol Biol, 2420: 87&#x2010;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casado, P., J. C. Rodriguez&#x2010;Prados, S. C. Cosulich, S. Guichard, B. Vanhaesebroeck, S. Joel, and P. R. Cutillas. 2013. &#x2018;Kinase&#x2010;substrate enrichment analysis provides insights into the heterogeneity of signaling pathway activation in leukemia cells&#x2019;, Sci Signal, 6: rs6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen, Y. J., T. I. Roumeliotis, Y. H. Chang, C. T. Chen, C. L. Han, M. H. Lin, H. W. Chen, G. C. Chang, Y. L. Chang, C. T. Wu, M. W. Lin, M. S. Hsieh, Y. T. Wang, Y. R. Chen, I. Jonassen, F. Z. Ghavidel, Z. S. Lin, K. T. Lin, C. W. Chen, P. Y. Sheu, C. T. Hung, K. C. Huang, H. C. Yang, P. Y. Lin, T. C. Yen, Y. W. Lin, J. H. Wang, L. Raghav, C. Y. Lin, Y. S. Chen, P. S. Wu, C. T. Lai, S. H. Weng, K. Y. Su, W. H. Chang, P. Y. Tsai, A. I. Robles, H. Rodriguez, Y. J. Hsiao, W. H. Chang, T. Y. Sung, J. S. Chen, S. L. Yu, J. S. Choudhary, H. Y. Chen, P. C. Yang, and Y. J. Chen. 2020. &#x2018;Proteogenomics of non&#x2010;smoking lung cancer in east Asia delineates molecular signatures of pathogenesis and progression&#x2019;, Cell, 182: 226&#x2010;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cordo, V., M. T. Meijer, R. Hagelaar, R. Goeij&#x2010;de Haas, V. M. Poort, A. A. Henneman, S. R. Piersma, T. V. Pham, K. Oshima, A. A. Ferrando, G. J. R. Zaman, C. R. Jimenez, and J. P. P. Meijerink. 2022. &#x2018;Phosphoproteomic profiling of T cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia reveals targetable kinases and combination treatment strategies&#x2019;, Nat Commun, 13; 1048.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox, J., and M. Mann. 2008. &#x2018;MaxQuant enables high peptide identification rates, individualized p.p.b.&#x2010;range mass accuracies and proteome&#x2010;wide protein quantification&#x2019;, Nat Biotechnol, 26: 1367&#x2010;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox, J., N. Neuhauser, A. Michalski, R. A. Scheltema, J. V. Olsen, and M. Mann. 2011. &#x2018;Andromeda: a peptide search engine integrated into the MaxQuant environment&#x2019;, J&#xa0;Proteome Res, 10: 1794&#x2010;805.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cucchi, D. G. J., C. Van Alphen, S. Zweegman, B. Van Kuijk, Z. J. Kwidama, A. Al Hinai, A. A. Henneman, J. C. Knol, S. R. Piersma, T. V. Pham, C. R. Jimenez, J. Cloos, J.Janssen. 2021. &#x2018;Phosphoproteomic characterization of primary AML samples and relevance for response toward FLT3&#x2010;inhibitors&#x2019;, Hemasphere, 5: e606.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deb, B., P. Sengupta, J. Sambath, and P. Kumar. 2020. &#x2018;Bioinformatics analysis of global proteomic and phosphoproteomic data sets revealed activation of NEK2 and AURKA in cancers&#x2019;, Biomolecules, 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deznabi, I., B. Arabaci, M. Koyuturk, and O. Tastan. 2020. &#x2018;DeepKinZero: zero&#x2010;shot learning for predicting kinase&#x2010;phosphosite associations involving understudied kinases&#x2019;, Bioinformatics, 36: 3652&#x2010;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diella, F., S. Cameron, C. Gemund, R. Linding, A. Via, B. Kuster, T. Sicheritz&#x2010;Ponten, N. Blom, and T. J. Gibson. 2004. &#x2018;Phospho.ELM: a database of experimentally verified phosphorylation sites in eukaryotic proteins&#x2019;, BMC Bioinformatics, 5: 79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dou, Y., E. A. Kawaler, D. Cui Zhou, M. A. Gritsenko, C. Huang, L. Blumenberg, A. Karpova, V. A. Petyuk, S. R. Savage, S. Satpathy, W. Liu, Y. Wu, C. F. Tsai, B. Wen, Z. Li, S. Cao, J. Moon, Z. Shi, M. Cornwell, M. A. Wyczalkowski, R. K. Chu, S. Vasaikar, H. Zhou, Q. Gao, R. J. Moore, K. Li, S. Sethuraman, M. E. Monroe, R. Zhao, D. Heiman, K. Krug, K. Clauser, R. Kothadia, Y. Maruvka, A. R. Pico, A. E. Oliphant, E. L. Hoskins, S. L. Pugh, S. J. I. Beecroft, D. W. Adams, J. C. Jarman, A. Kong, H. Y. Chang, B. Reva, Y. Liao, D. Rykunov, A. Colaprico, X. S. Chen, A. Czekanski, M. Jedryka, R. Matkowski, M. Wiznerowicz, T. Hiltke, E. Boja, C. R. Kinsinger, M. Mesri, A. I. Robles, H. Rodriguez, D. Mutch, K. Fuh, M. J. Ellis, D. DeLair, M. Thiagarajan, D. R. Mani, G. Getz, M. Noble, A. I. Nesvizhskii, P. Wang, M. L. Anderson, D. A. Levine, R. D. Smith, S. H. Payne, K. V. Ruggles, K. D. Rodland, L. Ding, B. Zhang, T. Liu, D. Fenyo, and Consortium Clinical Proteomic Tumor Analysis. 2020. &#x2018;Proteogenomic characterization of endometrial carcinoma&#x2019;, Cell, 180: 729&#x2010;48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake, J. M., N. A. Graham, T. Stoyanova, A. Sedghi, A. S. Goldstein, H. Cai, D. A. Smith, H. Zhang, E. Komisopoulou, J. Huang, T. G. Graeber, and O. N. Witte. 2012. &#x2018;Oncogene&#x2010;specific activation of tyrosine kinase networks during prostate cancer progression&#x2019;, Proc Natl Acad Sci USA, 109: 1643&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake, J. M., E. O. Paull, N. A. Graham, J. K. Lee, B. A. Smith, B. Titz, T. Stoyanova, C. M. Faltermeier, V. Uzunangelov, D. E. Carlin, D. T. Fleming, C. K. Wong, Y. Newton, S. Sudha, A. A. Vashisht, J. Huang, J. A. Wohlschlegel, T. G. Graeber, O. N. Witte, and J. M. Stuart. 2016. &#x2018;Phosphoproteome integration reveals patient&#x2010;specific networks in prostate cancer&#x2019;, Cell, 166: 1041&#x2010;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frese, C. K., H. J. Zhou, T. Taus, A. F. M. Altelaar, K. Mechter, A. J. R. Heck, S. Mohammed. 2013. &#x2018;Unambiguous phosphosite localization using electron&#x2010;transfer/higher&#x2010;energy collision dissociation (EThcD)&#x2019;, J Proteome Res, 12: 1520&#x2010;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrich, C., S. Schallenberg, M. Kirchner, M. Ziehm, S. Niquet, M. Haji, C. Beier, J. Neudecker, F. Klauschen, and P. Mertins. 2021. &#x2018;Comprehensive micro&#x2010;scaled proteome and phosphoproteome characterization of archived retrospective cancer repositories&#x2019;, Nat Commun, 12: 3576.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillette, M. A., S. Satpathy, S. Cao, S. M. Dhanasekaran, S. V. Vasaikar, K. Krug, F. Petralia, Y. Li, W. W. Liang, B. Reva, A. Krek, J. Ji, X. Song, W. Liu, R. Hong, L. Yao, L. Blumenberg, S. R. Savage, M. C. Wendl, B. Wen, K. Li, L. C. Tang, M. A. MacMullan, S. C. Avanessian, M. H. Kane, C. J. Newton, M. Cornwell, R. B. Kothadia, W. Ma, S. Yoo, R. Mannan, P. Vats, C. Kumar&#x2010;Sinha, E. A. Kawaler, T. Omelchenko, A. Colaprico, Y. Geffen, Y. E. Maruvka, F. da Veiga Leprevost, M. Wiznerowicz, Z. H. Gumus, R. R. Veluswamy, G. Hostetter, D. I. Heiman, M. A. Wyczalkowski, T. Hiltke, M. Mesri, C. R. Kinsinger, E. S. Boja, G. S. Omenn, A. M. Chinnaiyan, H. Rodriguez, Q. K. Li, S. D. Jewell, M. Thiagarajan, G. Getz, B. Zhang, D. Fenyo, K. V. Ruggles, M. P. Cieslik, A. I. Robles, K. R. Clauser, R. Govindan, P. Wang, A. I. Nesvizhskii, L. Ding, D. R. Mani, S. A. Carr, and Consortium Clinical Proteomic Tumor Analysis. 2020. &#x2018;Proteogenomic characterization reveals therapeutic vulnerabilities in lung adenocarcinoma&#x2019;, Cell, 182: 200&#x2010;25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gjerga, E., A. Dugourd, L. Tobalina, A. Sousa, and J. Saez&#x2010;Rodriguez. 2021. &#x2018;PHONEMeS: efficient modeling of signaling networks derived from large&#x2010;scale mass spectrometry data&#x2019;, J Proteome Res, 20: 2138&#x2010;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallal, M., S. Braga&#x2010;Lagache, J. Jankovic, C. Simillion, R. Bruggmann, A. C. Uldry, R. Allam, M. Heller, and N. Bonadies. 2021. &#x2018;Inference of kinase&#x2010;signaling networks in human myeloid cell line models by Phosphoproteomics using kinase activity enrichment analysis (KAEA)&#x2019;, BMC Cancer, 21: 789.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanahan, D., and R. A. Weinberg. 2011. &#x2018;Hallmarks of cancer: the next generation&#x2019;, Cell, 144: 646&#x2010;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez&#x2010;Armenta, C., D. Ochoa, E. Goncalves, J. Saez&#x2010;Rodriguez, and P. Beltrao. 2017. &#x2018;Benchmarking substrate&#x2010;based kinase activity inference using phosphoproteomic data&#x2019;, Bioinformatics, 33: 1845&#x2010;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez&#x2010;Valladares, M., E. Aasebo, F. Berven, F. Selheim, and O. Bruserud. 2020. &#x2018;Biological characteristics of aging in human acute myeloid leukemia cells: the possible importance of aldehyde dehydrogenase, the cytoskeleton and altered transcriptional regulation&#x2019;, Aging&#x2010;Us, 12: 24734&#x2010;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez&#x2010;Valladares, M., R. Wangen, E. Aasebo, H. Reikvam, F. S. Berven, F. Selheim, and O. Bruserud. 2021. &#x2018;Proteomic studies of primary acute myeloid leukemia cells derived from patients before and during disease&#x2010;stabilizing treatment based on all&#x2010;trans retinoic acid and valproic acid&#x2019;, Cancers, 13; 2143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hijazi, M., R. Smith, V. Rajeeve, C. Bessant, and P. R. Cutillas. 2020. &#x2018;Reconstructing kinase network topologies from phosphoproteomics data reveals cancer&#x2010;associated rewiring&#x2019;, Nat Biotechnol, 38: 493&#x2010;502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn, H., E. M. Schoof, J. Kim, X. Robin, M. L. Miller, F. Diella, A. Palma, G. Cesareni, L. J. Jensen, and R. Linding. 2014. &#x2018;KinomeXplorer: an integrated platform for kinome biology studies&#x2019;, Nat Methods, 11: 603&#x2010;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hornbeck, P. V., B. Zhang, B. Murray, J. M. Kornhauser, V. Latham, and E. Skrzypek. 2015. &#x2018;PhosphoSitePlus, 2014: mutations, PTMs and recalibrations&#x2019;, Nucleic Acids Res, 43: D512&#x2010;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang, P. H., A. Mukasa, R. Bonavia, R. A. Flynn, Z. E. Brewer, W. K. Cavenee, F. B. Furnari, and F. M. White. 2007. &#x2018;Quantitative analysis of EGFRvIII cellular signaling networks reveals a combinatorial therapeutic strategy for glioblastoma&#x2019;, Proc Natl Acad Sci USA, 104: 12867&#x2010;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphrey, S. J., O. Karayel, D. E. James, and M. Mann. 2018. &#x2018;High&#x2010;throughput and high&#x2010;sensitivity phosphoproteomics with the EasyPhos platform&#x2019;, Nat Protoc, 13: 1897&#x2010;916.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imamura, H., N. Sugiyama, M. Wakabayashi, and Y. Ishihama. 2014. &#x2018;Large&#x2010;scale identification of phosphorylation sites for profiling protein kinase selectivity&#x2019;, J&#xa0;Proteome Res, 13: 3410&#x2010;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keenan, A. B., S. L. Jenkins, K. M. Jagodnik, S. Koplev, E. He, D. Torre, Z. Wang, A. B. Dohlman, M. C. Silverstein, A. Lachmann, M. V. Kuleshov, A. Ma'ayan, V. Stathias, R. Terryn, D. Cooper, M. Forlin, A. Koleti, D. Vidovic, C. Chung, S. C. Schurer, J. Vasiliauskas, M. Pilarczyk, B. Shamsaei, M. Fazel, Y. Ren, W. Niu, N. A. Clark, S. White, N. Mahi, L. Zhang, M. Kouril, J. F. Reichard, S. Sivaganesan, M. Medvedovic, J. Meller, R. J. Koch, M. R. Birtwistle, R. Iyengar, E. A. Sobie, E. U. Azeloglu, J. Kaye, J. Osterloh, K. Haston, J. Kalra, S. Finkbiener, J. Li, P. Milani, M. Adam, R. Escalante&#x2010;Chong, K. Sachs, A. Lenail, D. Ramamoorthy, E. Fraenkel, G. Daigle, U. Hussain, A. Coye, J. Rothstein, D. Sareen, L. Ornelas, M. Banuelos, B. Mandefro, R. Ho, C. N. Svendsen, R. G. Lim, J. Stocksdale, M. S. Casale, T. G. Thompson, J. Wu, L. M. Thompson, V. Dardov, V. Venkatraman, A. Matlock, J. E. Van Eyk, J. D. Jaffe, M. Papanastasiou, A. Subramanian, T. R. Golub, S. D. Erickson, M. Fallahi&#x2010;Sichani, M. Hafner, N. S. Gray, J. R. Lin, C. E. Mills, J. L. Muhlich, M. Niepel, C. E. Shamu, E. H. Williams, D. Wrobel, P. K. Sorger, L. M. Heiser, J. W. Gray, J. E. Korkola, G. B. Mills, M. LaBarge, H. S. Feiler, M. A. Dane, E. Bucher, M. Nederlof, D. Sudar, S. Gross, D. F. Kilburn, R. Smith, K. Devlin, R. Margolis, L. Derr, A. Lee, and A. Pillai. 2018. &#x2018;The Library of Integrated Network&#x2010;Based Cellular Signatures NIH Program: System&#x2010;level cataloging of human cells response to perturbations&#x2019;, Cell Syst, 6: 13&#x2010;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keshava Prasad, T. S., R. Goel, K. Kandasamy, S. Keerthikumar, S. Kumar, S. Mathivanan, D. Telikicherla, R. Raju, B. Shafreen, A. Venugopal, L. Balakrishnan, A. Marimuthu, S. Banerjee, D. S. Somanathan, A. Sebastian, S. Rani, S. Ray, C. J. Harrys Kishore, S. Kanth, M. Ahmed, M. K. Kashyap, R. Mohmood, Y. L. Ramachandra, V. Krishna, B. A. Rahiman, S. Mohan, P. Ranganathan, S. Ramabadran, R. Chaerkady, and A. Pandey. 2009. &#x2018;Human Protein Reference Database&#x2014;2009 update&#x2019;, Nucleic Acids Res, 37: D767&#x2010;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krug, K., P. Mertins, B. Zhang, P. Hornbeck, R. Raju, R. Ahmad, M. Szucs, F. Mundt, D. Forestier, J. Jane&#x2010;Valbuena, H. Keshishian, M. A. Gillette, P. Tamayo, J. P. Mesirov, J. D. Jaffe, S. Carr, and D. R. Mani. 2019. &#x2018;A curated resource for phosphosite&#x2010;specific signature analysis&#x2019;, Mol&#xa0;Cell Proteomics, 18: 576&#x2010;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuleshov, M. V., Z. Xie, A. B. K. London, J. Yang, J. E. Evangelista, A. Lachmann, I. Shu, D. Torre, and A. Ma'ayan. 2021. &#x2018;KEA3: improved kinase enrichment analysis via data integration&#x2019;, Nucleic Acids Res, 49: W304&#x2010;W16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labots, M., T. V. Pham, R. J. Honeywell, J. C. Knol, R. Beekhof, R. de Goeij&#x2010;de Haas, H. Dekker, M. Neerincx, S. R. Piersma, J. C. van der Mijn, D. L. van der Peet, M. R. Meijerink, G. J. Peters, N. C. T. van Grieken, C. R. Jimenez, H. M. W. Verheul. 2020. &#x2018;Kinase inhibitor treatment of patients with advanced cancer results in high tumor drug concentrations and in specific alterations of the tumor phosphoproteome&#x2019;, Cancers, 12(2): 330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labots, M., J. C. van der Mijn, R. Beekhof, S. R. Piersma, R. R. de Goeij&#x2010;de Haas, T. V. Pham, J. C. Knol, H. Dekker, N. C. T. van Grieken, H. M. W. Verheul, C. R. Jimenez. 2017. &#x2018;Phosphotyrosine&#x2010;based&#x2010;phosphoproteomics scaled&#x2010;down to biopsy level for analysis of individual tumor biology and treatment selection&#x2019;, J Proteomics, 162: 99&#x2010;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lachmann, A., and A. Ma'ayan. 2009. &#x2018;KEA: kinase enrichment analysis&#x2019;, Bioinformatics, 25: 684&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Large, T. Y. S., M. F. Bijlsma, B. El Hassouni, G. Mantini, T. Lagerweij, A. A. Henneman, N. Funel, B. Kok, T. V. Pham, R. de Haas, L. Morelli, J. C. Knol, S. R. Piersma, G. Kazemier, H. W. M. van Laarhoven, E. Giovannetti, and C. R. Jimenez. 2021. &#x2018;Focal adhesion kinase inhibition synergizes with nab&#x2010;paclitaxel to target pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma&#x2019;, J Exp Clin Cancer Res, 40: 91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, B., X. Kong, H. Post, L. Raaijmakers, D. S. Peeper, and M. Altelaar. 2021. &#x2018;Proteomics and phosphoproteomics profiling of drug&#x2010;addicted BRAFi&#x2010;resistant melanoma cells&#x2019;, J Proteome Res, 20: 4381&#x2010;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li, C., Y. D. Sun, G. Y. Yu, J. R. Cui, Z. Lou, H. Zhang, Y. Huang, C. G. Bai, L. L. Deng, P. Liu, K. Zheng, Y. H. Wang, Q. Q. Wang, Q. R. Li, Q. Q. Wu, Q. Liu, Y. Shyr, Y. X. Li, L. N. Chen, J. R. Wu, W. Zhang, and R. Zeng. 2020. &#x2018;Integrated omics of metastatic colorectal cancer&#x2019;, Cancer Cell, 38: 734&#x2010;47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Licata, L., P. Lo Surdo, M. Iannuccelli, A. Palma, E. Micarelli, L. Perfetto, D. Peluso, A. Calderone, L. Castagnoli, and G. Cesareni. 2020. &#x2018;SIGNOR 2.0, the SIGnaling Network Open Resource 2.0: 2019 update&#x2019;, Nucleic Acids Res, 48: D504&#x2010;D10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lim Kam Sian, T. C. C., A. C. Chueh, and R. J. Daly. 2021. &#x2018;Proteomics&#x2010;based interrogation of the kinome and its implications for precision oncology&#x2019;, Proteomics, 21: e2000161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linding, R., L. J. Jensen, G. J. Ostheimer, M. A. van Vugt, C. Jorgensen, I. M. Miron, F. Diella, K. Colwill, L. Taylor, K. Elder, P. Metalnikov, V. Nguyen, A. Pasculescu, J. Jin, J. G. Park, L. D. Samson, J. R. Woodgett, R. B. Russell, P. Bork, M. B. Yaffe, and T. Pawson. 2007. &#x2018;Systematic discovery of in vivo phosphorylation networks&#x2019;, Cell, 129: 1415&#x2010;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu, Y., M. J. Jurczak, T. B. Lear, B. Lin, M. B. Larsen, J. R. Kennerdell, Y. W. Chen, B. R. Huckestein, M. K. Nguyen, F. Tuncer, Y. Jiang, S. P. Monga, C. P. O'Donnell, T. Finkel, B. B. Chen, and R. K. Mallampalli. 2021. &#x2018;A Fbxo48 inhibitor prevents pAMPK alpha degradation and ameliorates insulin resistance&#x2019;, Nat Chem Biol, 17: 298&#x2010;306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Low, T. Y., M. A. Mohtar, P. Y. Lee, N. Omar, H. Zhou, and M. Ye. 2021. &#x2018;Widening the bottleneck of phosphoproteomics: evolving strategies for phosphopeptide enrichment&#x2019;, Mass Spectrom Rev, 40: 309&#x2212;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manning, G., D. B. Whyte, R. Martinez, T. Hunter, and S. Sudarsanam. 2002. &#x2018;The protein kinase complement of the human genome&#x2019;, Science, 298: 1912.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mantini, G., T. V. Pham, S. R. Piersma, and C. R. Jimenez. 2021. &#x2018;Computational analysis of phosphoproteomics data in multi&#x2010;omics cancer studies&#x2019;, Proteomics, 21: e1900312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mari, M., M&#xf6;sbauer, K., Wyler, E., Landthaler, M., Drosten, C., Selbach, M. 2022. &#x2018;In vitro Kinase&#x2010;to&#x2010;Phosphosite database (iKiP&#x2010;DB) predicts kinase activity in phosphoproteomic datasets&#x2019;. Journal of Proteome Research, 21: 1575&#x2212;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuoka, S., B. A. Ballif, A. Smogorzewska, E. R. McDonald 3rd, K. E. Hurov, J. Luo, C. E. Bakalarski, Z. Zhao, N. Solimini, Y. Lerenthal, Y. Shiloh, S. P. Gygi, and S. J. Elledge. 2007. &#x2018;ATM and ATR substrate analysis reveals extensive protein networks responsive to DNA damage&#x2019;, Science, 316: 1160&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDermott, J. E., O. A. Arshad, V. A. Petyuk, Y. Fu, M. A. Gritsenko, T. R. Clauss, R. J. Moore, A. A. Schepmoes, R. Zhao, M. E. Monroe, M. Schnaubelt, C. F. Tsai, S. H. Payne, C. Huang, L. B. Wang, S. Foltz, M. Wyczalkowski, Y. Wu, E. Song, M. A. Brewer, M. Thiagarajan, C. R. Kinsinger, A. I. Robles, E. S. Boja, H. Rodriguez, D. W. Chan, B. Zhang, Z. Zhang, L. Ding, R. D. Smith, T. Liu, K. D. Rodland, and Consortium Clinical Tumor Analysis. 2020. &#x2018;Proteogenomic characterization of ovarian HGSC implicates mitotic kinases, replication stress in observed chromosomal instability&#x2019;, Cell Rep Med, 1; 100004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertins, P., D. R. Mani, K. V. Ruggles, M. A. Gillette, K. R. Clauser, P. Wang, X. L. Wang, J. W. Qiao, S. Cao, F. Petralia, E. Kawaler, F. Mundt, K. Krug, Z. D. Tu, J. T. Lei, M. L. Gatza, M. Wilkerson, C. M. Perou, V. Yellapantula, K. L. Huang, C. W. Lin, M. D. McLellan, P. Yan, S. R. Davies, R. R. Townsend, S. J. Skates, J. Wang, B. Zhang, C. R. Kinsinger, M. Mesri, H. Rodriguez, L. Ding, A. G. Paulovich, D. Fenyo, M. J. Ellis, S. A. Carr, and Nci Cptac. 2016. &#x2018;Proteogenomics connects somatic mutations to signalling in breast cancer&#x2019;, Nature, 534: 55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mischnik, M., F. Sacco, J. Cox, H. C. Schneider, M. Schafer, M. Hendlich, D. Crowther, M. Mann, and T. Klabunde. 2016. &#x2018;IKAP: a heuristic framework for inference of kinase activities from phosphoproteomics data&#x2019;, Bioinformatics, 32: 424&#x2010;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Needham, E. J., B. L. Parker, T. Burykin, D. E. James, and S. J. Humphrey. 2019. &#x2018;Illuminating the dark phosphoproteome&#x2019;, Sci Signal, 12; eaau8645.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ochoa, D., A. F. Jarnuczak, C. Vieitez, M. Gehre, M. Soucheray, A. Mateus, A. A. Kleefeldt, A. Hill, L. Garcia&#x2010;Alonso, F. Stein, N. J. Krogan, M. M. Savitski, D. L. Swaney, J. A. Vizcaino, K. M. Noh, and P. Beltrao. 2020. &#x2018;The functional landscape of the human phosphoproteome&#x2019;, Nat Biotechnol, 38: 365&#x2010;73.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan, L., X. Wang, L. Yang, L. Zhao, L. Zhai, J. Xu, Y. Yang, Y. Mao, S. Cheng, T. Xiao, and M. Tan. 2020. &#x2018;Proteomic and phosphoproteomic maps of lung squamous cell carcinoma from Chinese patients&#x2019;, Front Oncol, 10: 963.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perfetto, L., L. Briganti, A. Calderone, A. Cerquone Perpetuini, M. Iannuccelli, F. Langone, L. Licata, M. Marinkovic, A. Mattioni, T. Pavlidou, D. Peluso, L. L. Petrilli, S. Pirro, D. Posca, E. Santonico, A. Silvestri, F. Spada, L. Castagnoli, and G. Cesareni. 2016. &#x2018;SIGNOR: a database of causal relationships between biological entities&#x2019;, Nucleic Acids Res, 44: D548&#x2010;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peri, S., J. D. Navarro, R. Amanchy, T. Z. Kristiansen, C. K. Jonnalagadda, V. Surendranath, V. Niranjan, B. Muthusamy, T. K. Gandhi, M. Gronborg, N. Ibarrola, N. Deshpande, K. Shanker, H. N. Shivashankar, B. P. Rashmi, M. A. Ramya, Z. Zhao, K. N. Chandrika, N. Padma, H. C. Harsha, A. J. Yatish, M. P. Kavitha, M. Menezes, D. R. Choudhury, S. Suresh, N. Ghosh, R. Saravana, S. Chandran, S. Krishna, M. Joy, S. K. Anand, V. Madavan, A. Joseph, G. W. Wong, W. P. Schiemann, S. N. Constantinescu, L. Huang, R. Khosravi&#x2010;Far, H. Steen, M. Tewari, S. Ghaffari, G. C. Blobe, C. V. Dang, J. G. Garcia, J. Pevsner, O. N. Jensen, P. Roepstorff, K. S. Deshpande, A. M. Chinnaiyan, A. Hamosh, A. Chakravarti, and A. Pandey. 2003. &#x2018;Development of human protein reference database as an initial platform for approaching systems biology in humans&#x2019;, Genome Res, 13: 2363&#x2010;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkins, D. N., D. J. C. Pappin, D. M. Creasy, and J. S. Cottrell. 1999. &#x2018;Probability&#x2010;based protein identification by searching sequence databases using mass spectrometry data&#x2019;, Electrophoresis, 20: 3551&#x2010;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinkse, M. W., P. M. Uitto, M. J. Hilhorst, B. Ooms, and A. J. Heck. 2004. &#x2018;Selective isolation at the femtomole level of phosphopeptides from proteolytic digests using 2D&#x2010;NanoLC&#x2010;ESI&#x2010;MS/MS and titanium oxide precolumns&#x2019;, Anal Chem, 76: 3935&#x2010;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potel, C. M., S. Lemeer, and A. J. R. Heck. 2019. &#x2018;Phosphopeptide fragmentation and site localization by mass spectrometry: an update&#x2019;, Anal Chem, 91: 126&#x2010;41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich, M., T. Liefeld, J. Gould, J. Lerner, P. Tamayo, and J. P. Mesirov. 2006. &#x2018;GenePattern 2.0&#x2019;, Nat Genet, 38: 500&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren, R. 2005. &#x2018;Mechanisms of BCR&#x2010;ABL in the pathogenesis of chronic myelogenous leukaemia&#x2019;, Nat Rev Cancer, 5: 172&#x2010;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rikova, K., A. Guo, Q. Zeng, A. Possemato, J. Yu, H. Haack, J. Nardone, K. Lee, C. Reeves, Y. Li, Y. Hu, Z. Tan, M. Stokes, L. Sullivan, J. Mitchell, R. Wetzel, J. Macneill, J. M. Ren, J. Yuan, C. E. Bakalarski, J. Villen, J. M. Kornhauser, B. Smith, D. Li, X. Zhou, S. P. Gygi, T. L. Gu, R. D. Polakiewicz, J. Rush, and M. J. Comb. 2007. &#x2018;Global survey of phosphotyrosine signaling identifies oncogenic kinases in lung cancer&#x2019;, Cell, 131: 1190&#x2010;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rolfs, F., S. R. Piersma, M. P. Dias, J. Jonkers, and C. R. Jimenez. 2021. &#x2018;Feasibility of phosphoproteomics on leftover samples after RNA extraction with guanidinium thiocyanate&#x2019;, Mol Cell Proteomics, 20: 100078.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush, J., A. Moritz, K. A. Lee, A. Guo, V. L. Goss, E. J. Spek, H. Zhang, X. M. Zha, R. D. Polakiewicz, and M. J. Comb. 2005. &#x2018;Immunoaffinity profiling of tyrosine phosphorylation in cancer cells&#x2019;, Nat Biotechnol, 23: 94&#x2010;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sano, A., and H. Nakamura. 2004. &#x2018;Chemo&#x2010;affinity of titania for the column&#x2010;switching HPLC analysis of phosphopeptides&#x2019;, Anal Sci, 20: 565&#x2010;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satpathy, S., E. J. Jaehnig, K. Krug, B. J. Kim, A. B. Saltzman, D. W. Chan, K. R. Holloway, M. Anurag, C. Huang, P. Singh, A. Gao, N. Namai, Y. Dou, B. Wen, S. V. Vasaikar, D. Mutch, M. A. Watson, C. Ma, F. O. Ademuyiwa, M. F. Rimawi, R. Schiff, J. Hoog, S. Jacobs, A. Malovannaya, T. Hyslop, K. R. Clauser, D. R. Mani, C. M. Perou, G. Miles, B. Zhang, M. A. Gillette, S. A. Carr, and M. J. Ellis. 2020. &#x2018;Microscaled proteogenomic methods for precision oncology&#x2019;, Nat Commun, 11: 532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satpathy, S., K. Krug, P. M. Jean Beltran, S. R. Savage, F. Petralia, C. Kumar&#x2010;Sinha, Y. Dou, B. Reva, M. H. Kane, S. C. Avanessian, S. V. Vasaikar, A. Krek, J. T. Lei, E. J. Jaehnig, T. Omelchenko, Y. Geffen, E. J. Bergstrom, V. Stathias, K. E. Christianson, D. I. Heiman, M. P. Cieslik, S. Cao, X. Song, J. Ji, W. Liu, K. Li, B. Wen, Y. Li, Z. H. Gumus, M. E. Selvan, R. Soundararajan, T. H. Visal, M. G. Raso, E. R. Parra, O. Babur, P. Vats, S. Anand, T. Schraink, M. Cornwell, F. M. Rodrigues, H. Zhu, C. K. Mo, Y. Zhang, F. da Veiga Leprevost, C. Huang, A. M. Chinnaiyan, M. A. Wyczalkowski, G. S. Omenn, C. J. Newton, S. Schurer, K. V. Ruggles, D. Fenyo, S. D. Jewell, M. Thiagarajan, M. Mesri, H. Rodriguez, S. A. Mani, N. D. Udeshi, G. Getz, J. Suh, Q. K. Li, G. Hostetter, P. K. Paik, S. M. Dhanasekaran, R. Govindan, L. Ding, A. I. Robles, K. R. Clauser, A. I. Nesvizhskii, P. Wang, S. A. Carr, B. Zhang, D. R. Mani, M. A. Gillette, and Consortium Clinical Proteomic Tumor Analysis. 2021. &#x2018;A proteogenomic portrait of lung squamous cell carcinoma&#x2019;, Cell, 184: 4348&#x2010;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savage, S. R., and B. Zhang. 2020. &#x2018;Using phosphoproteomics data to understand cellular signaling: a comprehensive guide to bioinformatics resources&#x2019;, Clin&#xa0;Proteomics, 17; 27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savitski, M. M., S. Lemeer, M. Boesche, M. Lang, T. Mathieson, M. Bantscheff, and B. Kuster. 2011. &#x2018;Confident Phosphorylation Site Localization Using the Mascot Delta Score&#x2019;, Mol Cell Proteomics, 10; M110.003830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shteynberg, D. D., E. W. Deutsch, D. S. Campbell, M. R. Hoopmann, U. Kusebauch, D. Lee, L. Mendoza, M. K. Midha, Z. Sun, A. D. Whetton, and R. L. Moritz. 2019. &#x2018;PTMProphet: fast and accurate mass modification localization for the trans&#x2010;proteomic pipeline&#x2019;, J Proteome Res, 18: 4262&#x2010;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simillion, C., R. Liechti, H. E. Lischer, V. Ioannidis, and R. Bruggmann. 2017. &#x2018;Avoiding the pitfalls of gene set enrichment analysis with SetRank&#x2019;, BMC Bioinformatics, 18: 151.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storey, A. J., K. S. Naceanceno, R. S. Lan, C. L. Washam, L. M. Orr, S. G. Mackintosh, A. J. Tackett, R. D. Edmondson, Z. Wang, H. Y. Li, B. Frett, S. Kendrick, and S. D. Byrum. 2020. &#x2018;ProteoViz: a tool for the analysis and interactive visualization of phosphoproteomics data&#x2019;, Mol Omics, 16: 316&#x2010;26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama, N., H. Imamura, and Y. Ishihama. 2019. &#x2018;Large&#x2010;scale discovery of substrates of the human kinome&#x2019;, Sci Rep, 9: 10503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taus, T., T. Kocher, P. Pichler, C. Paschke, A. Schmidt, C. Henrich, and K. Mechtler. 2011. &#x2018;Universal and confident phosphorylation site localization using phosphoRS&#x2019;, J Proteome Res, 10: 5354&#x2010;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terfve, C. D., E. H. Wilkes, P. Casado, P. R. Cutillas, and J. Saez&#x2010;Rodriguez. 2015. &#x2018;Large&#x2010;scale models of signal propagation in human cells derived from discovery phosphoproteomic data&#x2019;, Nat Commun, 6: 8033.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong, M., C. Yu, J. Shi, W. Huang, S. Ge, M. Liu, L. Song, D. Zhan, X. Xia, W. Liu, J. Feng, W. Shi, J. Ji, J. Gao, T. Shi, W. Zhu, C. Ding, Y. Wang, F. He, L. Shen, T. Li, and J. Qin. 2019. &#x2018;Phosphoproteomics enables molecular subtyping and nomination of kinase candidates for individual patients of diffuse&#x2010;type gastric cancer&#x2019;, iScience, 22: 44&#x2010;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Villen, J., and S. P. Gygi. 2008. &#x2018;The SCX/IMAC enrichment approach for global phosphorylation analysis by mass spectrometry&#x2019;, Nat Protoc, 3: 1630&#x2010;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogelstein, B., N. Papadopoulos, V. E. Velculescu, S. Zhou, L. A. Diaz Jr, and K. W. Kinzler. 2013. &#x2018;Cancer genome landscapes&#x2019;, Science, 339: 1546&#x2010;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weidner, C., C. Fischer, and S. Sauer. 2014. &#x2018;PHOXTRACK&#x2014;a tool for interpreting comprehensive datasets of post&#x2010;translational modifications of proteins&#x2019;, Bioinformatics, 30: 3410&#x2010;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkes, E. H., P. Casado, V. Rajeeve, and P. R. Cutillas. 2017. &#x2018;Kinase activity ranking using phosphoproteomics data (KARP) quantifies the contribution of protein kinases to the regulation of cell viability&#x2019;, Mol Cell Proteomics, 16: 1694&#x2010;704.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkes, E. H., C. Terfve, J. G. Gribben, J. Saez&#x2010;Rodriguez, and P. R. Cutillas. 2015. &#x2018;Empirical inference of circuitry and plasticity in a kinase signaling network&#x2019;, Proc Natl Acad Sci USA, 112: 7719&#x2010;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiredja, D. D., M. Koyuturk, and M. R. Chance. 2017. &#x2018;The KSEA App: a web&#x2010;based tool for kinase activity inference from quantitative phosphoproteomics&#x2019;, Bioinformatics, 33: 3489&#x2010;91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu, J. Y., C. Zhang, X. Wang, L. Zhai, Y. Ma, Y. Mao, K. Qian, C. Sun, Z. Liu, S. Jiang, M. Wang, L. Feng, L. Zhao, P. Liu, B. Wang, X. Zhao, H. Xie, X. Yang, L. Zhao, Y. Chang, J. Jia, X. Wang, Y. Zhang, Y. Wang, Y. Yang, Z. Wu, L. Yang, B. Liu, T. Zhao, S. Ren, A. Sun, Y. Zhao, W. Ying, F. Wang, G. Wang, Y. Zhang, S. Cheng, J. Qin, X. Qian, Y. Wang, J. Li, F. He, T. Xiao, and M. Tan. 2020. &#x2018;Integrative proteomic characterization of human lung adenocarcinoma&#x2019;, Cell, 182: 245&#x2010;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, P., E. Patrick, S. J. Humphrey, S. Ghazanfar, D. E. James, R. Jothi, and J. Y. Yang. 2016. &#x2018;KinasePA: phosphoproteomics data annotation using hypothesis driven kinase perturbation analysis&#x2019;, Proteomics, 16: 1868&#x2010;71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, P., E. Patrick, S. X. Tan, D. J. Fazakerley, J. Burchfield, C. Gribben, M. J. Prior, D. E. James, and Y. Hwa Yang. 2014. &#x2018;Direction pathway analysis of large&#x2010;scale proteomics data reveals novel features of the insulin action pathway&#x2019;, Bioinformatics, 30: 808&#x2010;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang, P., X. Zheng, V. Jayaswal, G. Hu, J. Y. Yang, and R. Jothi. 2015. &#x2018;Knowledge&#x2010;based analysis for detecting key signaling events from time&#x2010;series phosphoproteomics data&#x2019;, PLoS Comput Biol, 11: e1004403.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz, S., M. Ayati, D. Schlatzer, A. E. Cicek, M. R. Chance, and M. Koyuturk. 2021. &#x2018;Robust inference of kinase activity using functional networks&#x2019;, Nat Commun, 12; 1177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang, H., T. Liu, Z. Zhang, S. H. Payne, B. Zhang, J. E. McDermott, J. Y. Zhou, V. A. Petyuk, L. Chen, D. Ray, S. S. Sun, F. Yang, L. J. Chen, J. Wang, P. Shah, S. W. Cha, P. Aiyetan, S. Woo, Y. Tian, M. A. Gritsenko, T. R. Clauss, C. Choi, M. E. Monroe, S. Thomas, S. Nie, C. C. Wu, R. J. Moore, K. H. Yu, D. L. Tabb, D. Fenyo, V. Bafna, Y. Wang, H. Rodriguez, E. S. Boja, T. Hiltke, R. C. Rivers, L. Sokoll, H. Zhu, I. M. Shih, L. Cope, A. Pandey, B. Zhang, M. P. Snyder, D. A. Levine, R. D. Smith, D. W. Chan, K. D. Rodland, and CPTAC Investigators. 2016. &#x2018;Integrated proteogenomic characterization of human high&#x2010;grade serous ovarian cancer&#x2019;, Cell, 166: 755&#x2010;65.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, H. J., M. L. Ye, J. Dong, G. H. Han, X. N. Jiang, R. N. Wu, and H. F. Zou. 2008. &#x2018;Specific phosphopeptide enrichment with immobilized titanium ion affinity chromatography adsorbent for phosphoproteome analysis&#x2019;, J Proteome Res, 7: 3957&#x2010;67.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>