<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40802763</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2375-2548</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>33</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science advances</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Adv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Stable isotope evidence for the participation of commoners in Inka khipu production.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>eadv1950</StartPage><MedlinePgn>eadv1950</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">eadv1950</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1126/sciadv.adv1950</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study presents previously unknown evidence about the social status of Inka-era khipu experts. A lack of physical evidence hinders our understanding of the specialists who made Inka khipus (knotted cords that served as writing). On the basis of primarily Spanish-language colonial chronicles, it is thought that khipus were created exclusively by male bureaucratic elites. We analyzed Inka khipu, KH0631, whose primary cord is composed of human hair. Historically, human hair on a khipu served as a "signature" to indicate the khipu's creator. Recent advances in elemental analysis-isotope ratio mass spectrometry allowed us to undertake simultaneous carbon, nitrogen, and sulfur measurements from a single KH0631 hair sample, revealing that this individual consumed a diet characteristic of low-ranking commoners. This finding suggests that commoners participated in Inka khipu production.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hyland</LastName><ForeName>Sabine</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9728-5289</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>St Mary's College, University of St Andrews, St Andrews KY16 9AJ, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Kit</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2215-2318</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anthropology, East China Normal University, Shanghai 200062, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koon</LastName><ForeName>Hannah</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6849-2676</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Light Stable Isotope Lab, School of Archaeological and Forensic Sciences, University of Bradford, Bradford BD7 1DP, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laukkanen</LastName><ForeName>Sanna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Measurlabs, Helsinki 00510, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spindler</LastName><ForeName>Luke</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Light Stable Isotope Lab, School of Archaeological and Forensic Sciences, University of Bradford, Bradford BD7 1DP, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016456">Historical Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Adv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101653440</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2375-2548</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D009587">Nitrogen Isotopes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002247">Carbon Isotopes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007554">Isotopes</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006197" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hair</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009587" MajorTopicYN="N">Nitrogen Isotopes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013058" MajorTopicYN="N">Mass Spectrometry</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002247" MajorTopicYN="N">Carbon Isotopes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007554" MajorTopicYN="Y">Isotopes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40802763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12346260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.adv1950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>M. Meedrano, G.Brokaw, <i>Quipu</i> (Oxford Bibliographies in Latin American Studies, 2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brezine C., Clindaniel J., Ghezzi I., Hyland S., Medrano M., A new naming convention for Andean khipus. Latin Am. Antiq. 35, 1039&#x2013;1044 (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Ascher, R. Ascher, <i>The Mathematics of the Incas: Code of the Quipu</i> (University of Michigan Press, 1997).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G. Urton, <i>Inka History in Knots</i> (University of Texas Press, 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Mackey, &#x201c;The continuing khipu tradition: Principle and practice,&#x201d; in <i>Narrative Threads: Accounting and Recounting in Andean Khipu</i>, J. Quilter, G. Urton, Eds. (University of Texas Press, 2002), pp. 320&#x2013;348.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland S., Ply, markedness, and redundancy. Am. Anthropol. 116, 1&#x2013;6 (2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeakel J., Accountant-historians of the Incas. Account. Historians J. 10, 39&#x2013;51 (1983).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V. Muscovich, <i>El khipu y la yupana</i> (Arequipa, 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos Vargas M., Quipus y quipucamayos en el registro arque&#xf3;logico. Cuadernos del Qhapac Nan 4, 36&#x2013;65 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen C., When utensils revolt: Mind, matter, and modes of being in the pre-Columbian Andes. Res. Anthropol. Aesthet. 33, 19&#x2013;27 (1998).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Salomon, J. Urioste, <i>The Huarochiri Manuscript</i> (University of Texas Press, 1991).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Quilter, &#x201c;Yncap Cimin Quipococ&#x2019;s knots,&#x201d; in <i>Narrative Threads</i>, J. Quilter, G. Urton, Eds. (University of Texas, 2002), pp. 197&#x2013;222.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barraza Lescano S., Areche Espinola R., Marcone Flores G., By stones and knots: The counting and recording of chili peppers stored during the Inca occupation of the Guarco Administrative Center of Huacones-Vilcahuasi, Lower Ca&#xf1;ete Valley, Peru. Andean Past 13, 221&#x2013;264 (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Clindaniel, &#x201c;Toward a grammar of the Inka sign,&#x201d; thesis, Harvard University (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Curatola, J. Puente Luna, &#x201c;Contar concertando,&#x201d; in <i>El Quipu Colonial</i>, M. Curatola, J. Puente Luna, Eds. (PUCP, 2013), pp. 193&#x2013;244.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puente Luna J. C., That which belongs to all. Americas 72, 9&#x2013;54 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. Medrano, <i>Quipus</i> (Plaeneta, 2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>F. Guaman Poma, <i>The First New Cronicle and Good Government</i> (University of Texas, 2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Costin, &#x201c;Housewives, chosen women, skilled men,&#x201d; in <i>Craft and Social Identity</i>, C. Costin, R. Wright, Eds. (AAA, 1998), pp. 123&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gose P., The state as a chosen woman: Brideservice and the feeding of tributaries in the Inka Empire. Am. Anthropol. 102, 84&#x2013;97 (2000).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urton G., A calendrical and demographic tomb text from northern Peru. Latin Am. Antiq. 12, 127&#x2013;147 (2001).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Mackey, &#x201c;Knot records in ancient and modern Peru,&#x201d; thesis, University of California, Berkeley (1970).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Menzel, <i>Pottery Style and Society in Ancient Peru</i> (University of California, 1976).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>L. D&#xed;az Arriola, P. Landa Cragg, &#x201c;S&#xed;mbolos incaicos de identidad en Armatambo,&#x201d; in <i>Sistemas de Notaci&#xf3;n Inca</i>, C. Arellano Hoffman, Ed, 147&#x2013;175 (Ministerio de Cultura, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A. Herring, <i>Art and Vision in the Inca Empire</i> (Press Cambridge Univ, 2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson A., Hair and sacrifice in the Andean world. Internet Archaeol. 42, 10.11141/ia.42.6.2 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J. Betanzos, <i>Narrative of the Incas</i> (University of Texas, 1996).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson A., Brown E., Villa C., Lynnerup N., Healey A., Ceruti M. C., Reinhard J., Previgliano C. H., Arias Araoz F., Gonzalez Diez J., Taylor T., Archaeological, radiological, and biological evidence offer insight into Inca child sacrifice. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 100, 13322&#x2013;13327 (2013).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3746857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23898165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereyra H., Descripci&#xf3;n de un quipu en cuerdas entorchadas. Scientia 1, 127&#x2013;152 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Radicati, <i>Estudios Sobre Los Quipus</i> (Universidad Nacional de San Marcos, 2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland S., Writing with twisted cords: The inscriptive capacity of Andean khipus. Curr. Anthropol. 58, 412&#x2013;419 (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D. Arnold, J. Dios Yapita, <i>The Metamorphosis of Heads</i> (University of Pittsburgh Press, 2006).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hyland S., How khipus indicated labour contributions in an Andean village: An explanation of colour banding, seriation and ethnocategories. J. .Mater.Cult 21, 490&#x2013;509 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson A. S., Taylor T., Ceruti M. C., Chavez J. A., Reinhard J., Grimes V., Meier-Augenstein W., Cartmell L., Stern B., Richards M. P., Worobey M., Barnes I., Gilbert M. T. P., Stable isotope and DNA evidence for ritual sequences in Inca child sacrifice. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 104, 16456&#x2013;16461 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2034262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17923675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray T., Inka pottery as culinary equipment. Latin Am. Antiq. 14, 3&#x2013;28 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. H. Ambrose, L. Norr, &#x201c;Experimental evidence for the relationship of the carbon isotope ratios of whole diet and dietary protein to those of bone collagen and carbonate,&#x201d; in <i>Prehistoric Human Bone</i>, J. Lambert, Ed. (Springer-Verlag, 1993), pp. 1&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schoeninger M. J., Deniro M. J., Tauber H., Stable nitrogen isotope ratios of bone collagen reflect marine and terrestrial components of prehistoric human diet. Science 220, 1381&#x2013;1383 (1983).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6344217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedges R., Reynard L. M., Nitrogen isotopes and the trophic level of humans in archaeology. J. Archaeol. Sci. 34, 1240&#x2013;1251 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee-Thorp J. A., Sealy J. C., van der Merwe N. J., Stable carbon isotope ratio differences between bone collagen and bone apatite, and their relationship to diet. J. Archaeol. Sci. 16, 585&#x2013;599 (1989).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards M., Hedges R., Stable isotope evidence for similarities in the types of marine foods used by Late Mesolithic humans at sites along the Atlantic Coast of Europe. J. Archaeol. Sci. 26, 717&#x2013;722 (1999).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards M. P., Fuller B. T., Sponheimer M., Robinson T., Ayliffe L., Sulphur isotopes in paleodietary studies: A review and results from a controlled feeding experiment. Int. J. Osteoarcheol. 13, 37&#x2013;45 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tafuri M., Craig O., Canci A., Stable isotope evidence for the consumption of millet and other plants in Bronze Age Italy. Am. J. Biol. Anthropol. 139, 146&#x2013;153 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19051259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makarewicz C. A., Sealy J., Dietary reconstruction, mobility, and the analysis of ancient skeletal tissues. J. Archaeol. Sci. 56, 146&#x2013;158 (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M. A. Katzenburg, A. Waters-Rist, &#x201c;Stable isotope analysis,&#x201d; in <i>Biological Anthropology of the Human Skeleton</i>, M. A. Katzenberg, S. R. Saunders, Eds. (2018), pp. 467&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tykot R., Stable isotopes and diet. Phys. Methods Archaeom. 154, 433&#x2013;444 (2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp Z. D., Atudorei V., Panarello H. O., Fern&#xe1;ndez J., Douthitt C., Hydrogen isotope systematics of hair. J. Archaeol. Sci. 30, 1709&#x2013;1716 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Bray, &#x201c;To dine splendidly: Imperial pottery, commensal politics, and the Inca state,&#x201d; in <i>The Archaeology and Politics of Food and Feasting in Early States and Empires</i>, T Bray, Ed. (Kluwer Academic/Plenum, 2003), pp. 93&#x2013;142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>T. Cummins, <i>Toasts with the Inca: Andean Abstractions and Colonial Images on Quero Vessels</i> (University of Michigan Press, 2002).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastorf C., Johannessen S., Pre-Hispanic political change and the role of maize in the central Andes. Am. Anthropol. 95, 115&#x2013;138 (1993).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C. Morris, &#x201c;Maize beer in the economics, politics, and religion of the Inca Empire,&#x201d; in <i>Fermented Food Beverages in Nutrition</i>, C. F. Gastineau, W. J. Darby, T. B. Turner, Eds. (Academic Press, 1979), pp. 21&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S. Houston, <i>The First Writing: Script Invention as History and Process</i> (Cambridge Univ. Press, 2004).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Udea M., Bell L. S., The application of a CART model for forensic human geolocation using stable hydrogen and oxygen isotopes. Sci. Rep. 12, 21169 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9729567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36477390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macko S. A., Engel M. H., Andrusevich V., Lubec G., O&#x2019;Connell T. C., Hedges R. E., Documenting the diet in ancient human populations through stable isotope analysis of hair. Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond. B Biol. Sci. 354, 65&#x2013;76 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1692445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10091248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xed;az-Zorita Bonilla M., Drucker D., Richardin P., Silva-Pinto V., Sep&#xfa;lveda M., Bocherens H., Marine food consumption in coastal northern Chile populations during the Formative Period. Implications of isotopic evidence (C, N, S) for the Neolithic process in south central Andes. J. Archaeol. Sci. 6, 768&#x2013;776 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharp Z. D., Atudorei V., Panarello H. O., Fern&#xe1;ndez J., Douthitt C., Hydrogen isotope systematics of hair: Archeological and forensic applications. J. Archaeol. Sci. 30, 1709&#x2013;1716 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connell T. C., Hedges R. E., Investigations into the effect of diet on modern human hair isotopic values. Am. J. Phys. Anthropol. 108, 409&#x2013;425 (1999).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10229386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Britton K. E., McManus-Fry E., Nehlich O., Richards M., Ledger P. M., Knecht R., Stable carbon, nitrogen and sulphur isotope analysis of permafrost preserved human hair from rescue excavations (2009, 2010) at the precontact site of Nunalleq, Alaska. J. Archaeol. Sci. Rep. 17, 950&#x2013;963 (2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panzer S., Peschel O., Haas-Gebhard B., Bachmeier B. E., Pusch C. M., Nerlich A. G., Reconstructing the life of an unknown mummy (ca. 500 years-old South American Inca) mummy&#x2014;Multidisciplinary study of a Peruvian Inca mummy suggests severe Chagas disease and ritual homicide. PLOS ONE 9, e89528 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3935882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24586848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X., Wang X., A comparative study on the felting propensity of animal fibers. Textile Res. J. 77, 957&#x2013;963 (2007).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unal P. G., Atav R., Determination of the relationship between fiber characteristics and felting tendency of luxury fibers from various origins. Textile Res. J. 88, 1&#x2013;8 (2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehleringer J. R., Bowen G. L., Chesson L. A., West A. G., Podlesak D. W., Cerling T. E., Hydrogen and oxygen isotope ratios in human hair are related to geography. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 105, 2788&#x2013;2793 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2268538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18299562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sayle K. L., Brodie C. R., Cook G. T., Hamilton W. D., 
Sequential measurement of &#x3b4;<sup>15</sup> N, &#x3b4;<sup>13</sup> C and &#x3b4;<sup>34</sup> S values in archaeological bone collagen at the Scottish Universities Environmental Research Centre (SUERC): A new analytical frontier. Rapid Commun. Mass Spectrom.
33, 
1258&#x2013;1266 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30993809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hogg A. G., Heaton T. J., Hua Q., Palmer J. G., Turner C., Southon J., Bayliss A., Blackwell P. G., Boswijk G., Bronk Ramsey C., Pearson C., Petchey F., Reimer P., Reimer R., Wacker L., SHCal20 Southern Hemisphere calibration, 0&#x2013;55,000 years cal BP. Radiocarbon 62, 759&#x2013;778 (2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraser I., Meier-Augenstein W., Stable 2H isotope analysis of modern-day human hair and nails can aid forensic human identification. Rapid Commun. Mass Spectrom. 21, 3279&#x2013;3285 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17879389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen G. J., Isoscapes: Spatial pattern in isotopic biogeochemistry. Annu. Rev. Earth Planet. Sci. 38, 161&#x2013;187 (2010).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen G. J., Revenaugh J., Interpolating the isotopic composition of modern meteoric precipitation. Water Resour. Res. 39, 1299 (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knudson K. J., Oxygen isotope analysis in a land of environmental extremes: The complexities of isotopic work in the Andes. Int. J. Osteoarchaeol. 19, 171&#x2013;191 (2009).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>