<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40691408</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8245</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Ophthalmology and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ophthalmol Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Continuous versus Intermittent Use of Tear Substitutes in Patients Treated with Anti-VEGF for Neovascular Age-Related Macular Degeneration: The TREDIA Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2231</StartPage><EndPage>2241</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2231-2241</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40123-025-01201-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The aim of this prospective randomized bicenter study was to compare the effects of continuous versus intermittent use of tear substitutes on the ocular surface and dry eye symptoms in patients receiving repeated and frequent intravitreal injections (IVIs) for neovascular age-related macular degeneration (nAMD).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients with nAMD treated with anti-vascular endothelial growth factor (anti-VEGF) for more than 1 year at 4-8-week intervals were included. The intermittent treatment group received standard 1.5% povidone artificial tears for three days after each IVI, while the continuous treatment group received an ophthalmic lubricant emulsion with 0.18% sodium hyaluronate four times a day throughout the study. The primary endpoint was the mean change in Ocular Surface Disease Index (OSDI) score between baseline and the day of the fourth IVI. Secondary endpoints included the Schirmer test score, tear break-up time (TBUT), and Oxford staining score.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Sixty-five patients with mean age of 83.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;6.0&#xa0;years who had previously received a mean number of 28.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;20.3 IVIs were included. The mean OSDI score change from baseline was -6.6&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;13.5 points in the continuous treatment group versus&#x2009;+0.6&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;13.7 points in the intermittent treatment group (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.04). No significant differences in Schirmer test score, TBUT, and Oxford score were found between the groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Continuous use of tear substitutes in patients with nAMD receiving repeated and frequent IVIs could be beneficial in improving dry eye symptoms, as shown by a significant improvement in OSDI scores in our study, despite no substantial changes in other ocular surface metrics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">NCT06174181.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres-Villaros</LastName><ForeName>H&#xe9;lo&#xef;se</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5090-7845</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Avicenne Hospital, Sorbonne Paris Nord University, Service d'ophtalmologie, 125 Rue de Stalingrad, 93000, Bobigny, France. heloise.torres-villaros@aphp.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giocanti-Aur&#xe9;gan</LastName><ForeName>Audrey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Avicenne Hospital, Sorbonne Paris Nord University, Service d'ophtalmologie, 125 Rue de Stalingrad, 93000, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doan</LastName><ForeName>Serge</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Foundation Adolphe de Rothschild Hospital and Bichat Hospital, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agard</LastName><ForeName>Emilie</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Edouard Herriot University Hospital, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Billant</LastName><ForeName>J&#xe9;r&#xe9;my</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Edouard Herriot University Hospital, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arbousoff</LastName><ForeName>Nathalie</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Edouard Herriot University Hospital, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matagrin</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Edouard Herriot University Hospital, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fenniri</LastName><ForeName>In&#xe8;s</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Edouard Herriot University Hospital, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dot</LastName><ForeName>Corinne</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ophthalmology Department, Edouard Herriot University Hospital, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>French Military Heath Academy of Val de Gr&#xe2;ce, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06174181</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Ophthalmol Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101634502</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dry eye syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intravitreal injection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neovascular age-related macular degeneration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tear substitutes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: H&#xe9;lo&#xef;se Torres-Villaros, Emilie Agard, J&#xe9;r&#xe9;my Billant, Benjamin Matagrin, Nathalie Arbousoff, and In&#xe8;s Fenniri declare that they have no competing interests; Serge Doan reports receiving personal fees from Bausch&amp;Lomb, Horus Pharma, Quantel Medical, Santen, and Th&#xe9;a; Audrey Giocanti-Aur&#xe9;gan reports receiving personal fees from Abbvie, Apellis, Bayer, Horus Pharma, Roche, Novartis, and Th&#xe9;a; Corinne Dot reports receiving personal fees from Abbvie, Bayer, Horus Pharma, Novartis, and Roche. Ethical Approval: All patients received information on the study and signed a consent form to participate in the study. This study was conducted in accordance with the tenets of the Declaration of Helsinki. It obtained a favorable opinion from our institutional review board (ID-RCB no. 2023-A00620-45; Comit&#xe9; de Protection des Personnes Ouest II, France) according to the principles of Jarde law no. 2012&#x2013;300, including the decrees of 23 December 2023, on Research Involving the Human Person (called RIPH in French). Data were collected and processed in accordance with the MR-003 reference methodology. The IRB approval covered both study sites. Medical Writing/Editorial Assistance: The manuscript was linguistically reviewed by Mrs. Sophie Pegorier, a native English-speaking professional specializing in medical translation (Pegorier Traductions, Paris, France). This assistance was funded by the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40691408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12370589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40123-025-01201-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40123-025-01201-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Li E, Donati S, Lindsley KB, Krzystolik MG, Virgili G. Treatment regimens for administration of anti-vascular endothelial growth factor agents for neovascular age-related macular degeneration. Cochrane Eyes and Vision Group, editor. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7202375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32374423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talks J, Daien V, Finger RP, Eldem B, Sakamoto T, Cardillo JA, et al. The use of real-world evidence for evaluating anti&#x2013;vascular endothelial growth factor treatment of neovascular age-related macular degeneration. Surv Ophthalmol. 2019;64(5):707&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30797883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polat OA, &#xc7;etinkaya Z, Evereklio&#x11f;lu C, Karaca &#xc7;, Erkili&#xe7; K. Effect of repeated topical povidone-iodine and antibiotic applications on Meibomian glands and ocular surface parameters in patients with repeated intravitreal injections. Eye Contact Lens. 2021;47(12):651&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34570021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saedon H, Nosek J, Phillips J, Narendran N, Yang YC. Ocular surface effects of repeated application of povidone iodine in patients receiving frequent intravitreal injections. Cutan Ocul Toxicol. 2017;36(4):343&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28166657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbulut E, Kirik F, Ekinci Aslanoglu C, Hekimoglu ER, Haciosmanoglu Aldogan E, Ozdemir MH. The inflammatory and cytological effect of repeated povidone-iodine application in patients receiving intravitreal injections. Eye Contact Lens. 2024;50(2):73&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37791838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Ahn Y, Lee Y, Kim H. Toxicity of povidone-iodine to the ocular surface of rabbits. BMC Ophthalmol. 2020;20(1):359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7466785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32873276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mac Rae SM, Brown B, Edelhauser HF. The corneal toxicity of presurgical skin antiseptics. Am J Ophthalmol. 1984;97(2):221&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6696033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridder WH, Oquindo C, Dhamdhere K, Burke J. Effect of povidone iodine 5% on the cornea, vision, and subjective comfort. Optom Vis Sci. 2017;94(7):732&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28609415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verrecchia S, Chiambaretta F, Kodjikian L, Nakouri Y, El Chehab H, Mathis T, et al. A prospective multicentre study of intravitreal injections and ocular surface in 219 patients: IVIS study. Acta Ophthalmol. 2021;99(8):877&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33733603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyle J, Vukicevic M, Koklanis K, Itsiopoulos C, Rees G. Experiences of patients undergoing repeated intravitreal anti-vascular endothelial growth factor injections for neovascular age-related macular degeneration. Psychol Health Med. 2018;23(2):127&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28064517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriksen K, Adhami S. Patient experience of intravitreal injections in AMD. Int J Ophthalmic Pract. 2010;1(2):68&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thetford C, Hodge S, Harding S, Taylor S, Knox PC. Living with age-related macular degeneration treatment: patient experiences of being treated with ranibizumab (Lucentis)<sup>(R)</sup> intravitreal injections. Br J Visual Impairment. 2013;31(2):89&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senra H, Ali Z, Balaskas K, Aslam T. Psychological impact of anti-VEGF treatments for wet macular degeneration&#x2014;a review. Graefes Arch Clin Exp Ophthalmol. 2016;254(10):1873&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5045477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27262729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiffman RM. Reliability and validity of the ocular surface disease index. Arch Ophthalmol. 2000;118(5):615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10815152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Methodologies to Diagnose and Monitor Dry Eye Disease. Report of the diagnostic methodology subcommittee of the international dry eye workshop (2007). Ocul Surf. 2007;5(2):108&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17508118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bron AJ, Evans VE, Smith JA. Grading of corneal and conjunctival staining in the context of other dry eye tests. Cornea. 2003;22(7):640&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14508260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grzybowski A, Told R, Sacu S, Bandello F, Moisseiev E, Loewenstein A, et al. 2018 Update on intravitreal injections: euretina expert consensus recommendations. Ophthalmologica. 2018;239(4):181&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29393226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller KL. Minimal clinically important difference for the ocular surface disease index. Arch Ophthalmol. 2010;128(1):94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20065224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malet F, Le Goff M, Colin J, Schweitzer C, Delyfer M, Korobelnik J, et al. Dry eye disease in French elderly subjects: the Alienor Study. Acta Ophthalmol. 2014. 10.1111/aos.12174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aos.12174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23742664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolffsohn JS, Arita R, Chalmers R, Djalilian A, Dogru M, Dumbleton K, et al. TFOS DEWS II diagnostic methodology report. Ocul Surf. 2017;15(3):539&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28736342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao M, Xia F, Wang P, Feng Z, Wang X. Influence of serial intravitreal injections on measures of dry eye: a systemic review and meta-analysis. Cont Lens Anterior Eye. 2024;47(2): 102127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38350814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang J, Wu M, Shen T. The toxic effect of different concentrations of povidone iodine on the rabbit&#x2019;s cornea. Cutaneous Ocular Toxicol. 2009;28(3):119&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19694608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pels E, Vrensen GFJM. Microbial decontamination of human donor eyes with povidone-iodine: penetration, toxicity, and effectiveness. Br J Ophthalmol. 1999;83(9):1019&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1723175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10460768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peden MC, Hammer ME, Su&#xf1;er IJ. Dilute povidone-iodine prophylaxis maintains safety while improving patient comfort after intravitreal injections. Retina. 2019;39(11):2219&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30142109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali FS, Jenkins TL, Boparai RS, Obeid A, Ryan ME, Wibblesman TD, et al. Aqueous chlorhexidine compared with povidone-iodine as ocular antisepsis before intravitreal injection: a randomized clinical trial. Ophthalmol Retina. 2021;5(8):788&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33221515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stephenson KA, Merkur A, Kirker A, Albiani D, Pakzad-Vaezi K. Rates of endophthalmitis before and after transition from povidone-iodine to aqueous chlorhexidine asepsis for intravitreal injection. Can J Ophthalmol. 2024;59(6):424&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38387861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss SE, Klein R, Klein BEK. Long-term incidence of dry eye in an older population. Optom Vis Sci. 2008;85(8):668&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18677233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galor A, Feuer W, Lee DJ, Florez H, Carter D, Pouyeh B, et al. Prevalence and risk factors of dry eye syndrome in a United States veterans affairs population. Am J Ophthalmol. 2011;152(3):377&#x2013;84 (<b>e2</b>).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4113967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21684522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones L, Downie LE, Korb D, Benitez-del-Castillo JM, Dana R, Deng SX, et al. TFOS DEWS II management and therapy report. Ocular Surf. 2017;15(3):575&#x2013;628.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28736343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semp DA, Beeson D, Sheppard AL, Dutta D, Wolffsohn JS. Artificial tears: a systematic review. OPTO janv. 2023;15:9&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36647552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Definition and Classification of Dry Eye Disease. Report of the definition and classification subcommittee of the international dry eye workshop (2007). Ocular Surf. 2007;5(2):75&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17508116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hua R, Yao K, Hu Y, Chen L. Discrepancy between subjectively reported symptoms and objectively measured clinical findings in dry eye: a population based analysis. BMJ Open. 2014;4(8): e005296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4156796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25168038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidl D, Witkowska KJ, Kaya S, Baar C, Faatz H, Nepp J, et al. The association between subjective and objective parameters for the assessment of dry-eye syndrome. Investig Ophthalmol Visual Sci. 2015;56(3):1467&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25650419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols KK, Nichols JJ, Mph M, Mitchell GL. The lack of association between signs and symptoms in patients with dry eye disease. Cornea. 2004;23(8):762&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15502475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan BD, Crews LA, Messmer EM, Foulks GN, Nichols KK, Baenninger P, et al. Correlations between commonly used objective signs and symptoms for the diagnosis of dry eye disease: clinical implications. Acta Ophthalmologica mars. 2014;92(2):161&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23279964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastor-Pascual F, Pastor-Pascual R, G&#xe1;lvez-Perez P, Dolz-Marco R, Gallego-Pinazo R. Use of artificial tears in patients undergoing treatment with anti-VEGF intravitreal injections. OPTH. 2022;16:3959&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9719699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36474999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin HD, Surbeck JW, Marsh HR, Ding K, Kingsley RM, Riaz KM, et al. The effect of punctal plugs in reducing ocular surface irritation after povidone-iodine preparation of intravitreal injection&#x2014;a randomized trial. Eye. 2022;36(3):568&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8873466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33746207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labetoulle M, the CBL-101 Study Group, Mortemousque B, Allali J, Blanc P, Bonne M, et al. Performance and safety of a sodium hyaluronate tear substitute with polyethylene glycol in dry eye disease: a multicenter, investigator-masked, randomized, noninferiority trial. J Ocular Pharmacol Ther. 2022;38(9):607&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9700343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36269661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>