<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32782777</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2042-0188</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Therapeutic advances in endocrinology and metabolism</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ther Adv Endocrinol Metab</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>SGLT inhibitors in type 1 diabetes: weighing efficacy and side effects.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2042018820938545</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2042018820938545</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2042018820938545</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/2042018820938545</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Even before sodium-glucose cotransporter inhibitors (SGLTi) became popular agents for the treatment of people with type&#x2009;2 diabetes (T2DM), clinicians had explored their potential as adjunct therapies in type&#x2009;1 diabetes (T1DM). Several trials have demonstrated improved glycemic control (compared with placebo) and a decrease in glucose variability with a clinically relevant increase of time in range. In addition, weight loss and decreased systolic blood pressure are observed. The magnitude of the effects observed depends on the type of SGLTi, the dose administrated, and the duration of observation in the studies. As seen in T2DM, there was an increase in the risk of urogenital mycotic infections, but no increase in the risk of severe hypoglycemia. However, concerns arose regarding an increase in incidence of diabetic ketoacidosis. Mitigation strategies, including careful patient selection, extensive education of patients and (para)medical personnel, adequate insulin dose titration, and the adoption of a ketone-centered approach, are suggested. In different areas of the world, SGLTi are approved for use in T1DM with restrictions concerning patient selection and SGLTi dose. Real-world data on the effect of introduction of SGLTi in people with T1DM will yield insight on the robustness of glycemic effects over time, and allow us to determine whether the positive risk-benefit profile observed in clinical trials can be translated to the real world.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s), 2020.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janssens</LastName><ForeName>Birgit</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrinology BE, KU Leuven University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Vlaams Brabant, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caerels</LastName><ForeName>Simon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2555-9196</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrinology BE, KU Leuven University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Vlaams Brabant, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathieu</LastName><ForeName>Chantal</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrinology BE, KU Leuven University Hospitals Leuven, Leuven, Vlaams Brabant, 3000 Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Ther Adv Endocrinol Metab</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101532143</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2042-0188</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SGLT inhibition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diabetic ketoacidosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">time in range</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 1 diabetes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unmet medical need</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest statement: BJ and SC declare no conflicts of interest. CM serves, or has served, on the advisory panel for Novo Nordisk, Sanofi, Merck Sharp and Dohme Ltd., Eli Lilly and Company, Novartis, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Hanmi Pharmaceuticals, Roche, Medtronic, ActoBio Therapeutics, Pfizer, Dianax, and UCB. Financial compensation for these activities has been received by KU Leuven; KU Leuven has received research support for CM from Medtronic, Novo Nordisk, Sanofi, Merck Sharp and Dohme Ltd., Eli Lilly and Company, Roche, Abbott, ActoBio Therapeutics, and Novartis; CM serves, or has served, on the speakers bureau for Novo Nordisk, Sanofi, Merck Sharp and Dohme, Eli Lilly and Company, Boehringer Ingelheim, Astra Zeneca, and Novartis. Financial compensation for these activities has been received by KU Leuven. CM was an investigator in the EASE, inTandem and DEPICT trials. She is an author on DEPICT manuscripts.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7383636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2042018820938545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_2042018820938545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Foster NC, Beck RW, Miller KM, et al. State of type 1 diabetes management and outcomes from the T1D exchange in 2016&#x2013;2018. Diabetes Technol Ther 2019; 21: 66&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7061293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30657336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubitosi-Klug RA, Braffett BH, White NH, et al. Risk of severe hypoglycemia in type 1 diabetes over 30 years of follow-up in the DCCT/EDIC study. Diabetes Care 2017; 40: 1010&#x2013;1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5521975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28550194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevenion. National diabetes statistics report, 2020. Atlanta, GA: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, US Department of Health and Human Services, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayona Cebada A, Nattero-Chavez L, Alonso Diaz S, et al. Efficacy and safety of SGLT2 inhibitors in type 1 diabetes after the introduction of an off-label use protocol for clinical practice. Diabetes Technol Ther 2020; 22: 208&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31644310</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuypers J, Mathieu C, Benhalima K. SGLT2-inhibitors: a novel class for the treatment of type 2 diabetes introduction of SGLT2-inhibitors in clinical practice. Acta Clin Belg 2013; 68: 287&#x2013;293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24455799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorsey-Trevino EG, Gonzalez-Gonzalez JG, Alvarez-Villalobos N, et al. Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT-2) inhibitors and microvascular outcomes in patients with type 2 diabetes: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Endocrinol Invest 2020; 43: 289&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31489568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giugliano D, Longo M, Ida Maiorino M, et al. Efficacy of SGLT-2 inhibitors in older adults with diabetes: systematic review with meta-analysis of cardiovascular outcome trials. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2020; 162: 108114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32165164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkovic V, Jardine MJ, Neal B, et al. Canagliflozin and renal outcomes in type 2 diabetes and nephropathy. N Engl J Med 2019; 380: 2295&#x2013;2306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30990260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buse JB, Wexler DJ, Tsapas A, et al. 2019 Update to: management of hyperglycaemia in type 2 diabetes, 2018. A consensus report by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) and the European Association for the Study of Diabetes (EASD). Diabetologia 2020; 63: 221&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31853556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Sotagliflozin with insulin for treating type 1 diabetes [Internet]. Technology appraisal guidance (TA622). NICE, www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ta622 (2020, accessed May 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. Dapagliflozin with insulin for treating type 1 diabetes [Internet]. Technology appraisal guidance (TA597). NICE, www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ta597 (2019, accessed May 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dashora U, Dipesh CP, Gregory R, et al. Association of British Clinical Diabetologist (ABCD) position statement on the use of sodium-glucose cotransporter-2 inhibitors in type 1 diabetes (updated 2019). Br J Diabetes 2019; 19: 66&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buse JB, Garg SK, Rosenstock J, et al. Sotagliflozin in combination with optimized insulin therapy in adults with type 1 diabetes: the North American inTandem1 study. Diabetes Care 2018; 41: 1970&#x2013;1980.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6105319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Danne T, Cariou B, Banks P, et al. 
HbA<sub>1c</sub> and hypoglycemia reductions at 24 and 52 weeks with sotagliflozin in combination with insulin in adults with type 1 diabetes: the European inTandem2 study. Diabetes Care
2018; 41: 1981&#x2013;1990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg SK, Henry RR, Banks P, et al. Effects of sotagliflozin added to insulin in patients with type 1 diabetes. N Engl J Med 2017; 377: 2337&#x2013;2348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28899222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danne T, Cariou B, Buse JB, et al. Improved time in range and glycemic variability with sotagliflozin in combination with insulin in adults with type 1 diabetes: a pooled analysis of 24-week continuous glucose monitoring data from the inTandem program. Diabetes Care 2019; 42: 919&#x2013;930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6905498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30833371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dandona P, Mathieu C, Phillip M, et al. Efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in patients with inadequately controlled type 1 diabetes (DEPICT-1): 24 week results from a multicentre, double-blind, phase 3, randomised controlled trial. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2017; 5: 864&#x2013;876.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dandona P, Mathieu C, Phillip M, et al. Efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in patients with inadequately controlled type 1 diabetes: the DEPICT-1 52-week study. Diabetes Care 2018; 41: 2552&#x2013;2559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30352894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu C, Dandona P, Gillard P, et al. Efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in patients with inadequately controlled type 1 diabetes (the DEPICT-2 study): 24-week results from a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Care 2018; 41: 1938&#x2013;1946.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30026335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu C, Dandona P, Philip M, et al. Glucose variables in type 1 diabetes studies with dapagliflozin: pooled analysis of continuous glucose monitoring data from DEPICT-1 and -2. Diabetes Care 2019; 42: 1081&#x2013;1087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30967434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathieu C, Rudofsky G, Phillip M, et al. Long-term efficacy and safety of dapagliflozin in patients with inadequately controlled type 1 diabetes (the DEPICT-2 study): 52-week results from a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metab. Epub ahead of print 20 April 2020. DOI: 10.1111/dom.14060.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dom.14060.</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7496089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32311204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenstock J, Marquard J, Laffel LM, et al. Empagliflozin as adjunctive to insulin therapy in type 1 diabetes: the EASE trials. Diabetes Care 2018; 41: 2560&#x2013;2569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30287422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry RR, Payal T, Cindy T, et al. Efficacy and safety of canagliflozin, a sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor, as add-on to insulin in patients with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care 2015; 38: 2258&#x2013;2265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26486192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieber TR, Famulla S, Eilbracht J, et al. Empagliflozin as adjunct to insulin in patients with type 1 diabetes: a 4-week, randomized, placebo-controlled trial (EASE-1). Diabetes Obes Metab 2015; 17: 928&#x2013;935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4745028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26080652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hampp C, Swain RS, Horgan C, et al. Use of sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors in patients with type 1 diabetes and rates of diabetic ketoacidosis. Diabetes Care 2020; 43: 90&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31601640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danne T, Pettus J, Giaccari A, et al. Sotagliflozin added to optimized insulin therapy leads to lower rates of clinically relevant hypoglycemic events at any HbA1c at 52 weeks in adults with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Technol Ther 2019; 21: 471&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6708262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31335194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musso G, Gambino R, Cassader M, et al. Efficacy and safety of dual SGLT 1/2 inhibitor sotagliflozin in type 1 diabetes: meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. BMJ 2019; 365: I1328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6454301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30967375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada T, Shojima N, Noma H. Sodium-glucose co-transporter-2 inhibitors as add-on therapy to insulin for type 1 diabetes mellitus: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetes Obes Metab 2018; 20: 1755&#x2013;1761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29451721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu J, Tang L, Meng H, et al. Effects of sodium-glucose cotransporter (SGLT) inhibitors in addition to insulin therapy on glucose control and safety outcomes in adults with type 1 diabetes: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Diabetes Metab Res Rev 2019; 35: e3169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30974510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danne T, Garg S, Peters AL, et al. International consensus on risk management of diabetic ketoacidosis in patients with type 1 diabetes treated with sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter (SGLT) inhibitors. Diabetes Care 2019; 42: 1147&#x2013;1154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6973545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30728224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldenberg RM, Gilbert JD, Hramiak IM, et al. Sodium-glucose co-transporter inhibitors, their role in type 1 diabetes treatment and a risk mitigation strategy for preventing diabetic ketoacidosis: the STOP DKA protocol. Diabetes Obes Metab 2019; 21: 2192&#x2013;2202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31183975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg SK, Peters AL, Buse JB, et al. Strategy for mitigating DKA risk in patients with type 1 diabetes on adjunctive treatment with SGLT inhibitors: a STICH protocol. Diabetes Technol Ther 2018; 20: 571&#x2013;575.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30129772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Macfarlane J, Dhatariya K. Incidence of euglycemic diabetic ketoacidosis in adults with type 1 diabetes in the United Kingdom before the widespread use of sodium glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitors. Mayo Clin Proc 2019; 94: 1909&#x2013;1910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31486388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters AL, Robert RH, Thakkar P, et al. Diabetic ketoacidosis with canagliflozin, a sodium&#x2013;glucose cotransporter 2 inhibitor, in patients with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care 2016; 39: 532&#x2013;538.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26989182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benoit SR, Zhang Y, Geiss LS, et al. Trends in diabetic ketoacidosis hospitalizations and in-hospital mortality&#x2014;United States, 2000&#x2013;2014. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2018; 67: 362&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5877353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29596400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor SI, Blau JE, Rother KI, et al. SGLT2 inhibitors as adjunctive therapy for type 1 diabetes: balancing benefits and risks. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 2019; 7: 949&#x2013;958.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6872914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31585721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>