<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">37128974</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-4965</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>111</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of biomedical materials research. Part A</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Biomed Mater Res A</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Engineering of poly(caprolactone) and poly(glycerol sebacate) small-diameter vascular prosthesis with quercetin.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1500</StartPage><EndPage>1512</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1500-1512</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jbm.a.37535</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The fabrication of biodegradable, bioabsorbable, and biocompatible vascular scaffolds with enhanced mechanical and biological properties that are able to modulate local inflammation and induce endothelialization after surgical implant is still a challenge. In this work, a fibrous scaffold, made of poly(&#x3b5;-caprolactone) and poly(glycerol sebacate), was fabricated to be potentially used as a small-diameter graft in vascular surgery. The novelty of this research is represented by the direct incorporation of quercetin, a well-known antioxidant compound with several biological&#xa0;properties, into a polymeric scaffold obtaining a vascular construct able to modulate two key factors involved in postsurgical inflammation, matrix metalloproteinase-9 and endothelial nitric oxide synthase. For its production, an electrospinning apparatus, a solution made of the two polymers (both 20% (w/v), mixed at the ratio 1:1 (v/v)), and free quercetin (0.05% (w/v))&#xa0;were used. Scanning electron and atomic force microscopies were employed to investigate the morphological properties of the fabricated electrospun scaffolds. Furthermore, physicochemical properties, including&#xa0;Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy, mass loss, fluid uptake, quercetin release, mechanical properties, and biological activity of the scaffolds were studied. The expression of matrix metalloproteinase-9, tissue inhibitor of metalloproteinase-1, and of endothelial nitric oxide synthase was evaluated when the quercetin-functionalized scaffold was exposed to&#xa0; human endothelial cells treated with tumor necrosis factor-&#x3b1;. The results of this study confirmed the feasibility of incorporating free quercetin during the electrospinning process to impart biological properties to small-diameter vascular prostheses.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferrari</LastName><ForeName>Pier Francesco</ForeName><Initials>PF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7054-3559</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil, Chemical and Environmental Engineering, University of Genoa, via Opera Pia, 15, 16145, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Biologically Inspired Engineering in Vascular Medicine and Longevity, University of Genoa, via Montallegro, 1, 16145, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aliakbarian</LastName><ForeName>Bahar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9425-5949</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biosystems and Agricultural Engineering, Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Axia Institute, Michigan State University, Midland, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barisione</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8831-1054</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Biologically Inspired Engineering in Vascular Medicine and Longevity, University of Genoa, via Montallegro, 1, 16145, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical and Integrated Diagnostic Sciences, University of Genoa, viale Benedetto XV, 6, 16132, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kahn</LastName><ForeName>Cyril J F</ForeName><Initials>CJF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5282-6558</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Lorraine, LIBio, F-54000, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arab-Tehrany</LastName><ForeName>Elmira</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2182-8531</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Lorraine, LIBio, F-54000, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palombo</LastName><ForeName>Domenico</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9686-1782</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Biologically Inspired Engineering in Vascular Medicine and Longevity, University of Genoa, via Montallegro, 1, 16145, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical and Integrated Diagnostic Sciences, University of Genoa, viale Benedetto XV, 6, 16132, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vascular and Endovascular Surgery Unit, IRCCS Ospedale Policlinico San Martino, largo Rosanna Benzi, 10, 16132, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perego</LastName><ForeName>Patrizia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5904-2940</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Civil, Chemical and Environmental Engineering, University of Genoa, via Opera Pia, 15, 16145, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Center for Biologically Inspired Engineering in Vascular Medicine and Longevity, University of Genoa, via Montallegro, 1, 16145, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Biomed Mater Res A</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101234237</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1549-3296</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001672">Biocompatible Materials</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>9IKM0I5T1E</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011794">Quercetin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>24980-41-4</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C016240">polycaprolactone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011091">Polyesters</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C469892">poly(glycerol-sebacate)</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003651">Decanoates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>PDC6A3C0OX</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D005990">Glycerol</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011108">Polymers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001807" MajorTopicYN="Y">Blood Vessel Prosthesis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002460" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Line</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002470" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Survival</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001672" MajorTopicYN="N">Biocompatible Materials</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011794" MajorTopicYN="N">Quercetin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011091" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Polyesters</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003651" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Decanoates</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005990" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Glycerol</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000031" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">analogs &amp; derivatives</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011108" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Polymers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antioxidants</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bioactive scaffolds</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">electrospinning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polymeric biomaterials</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vascular tissue engineering</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37128974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jbm.a.37535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abdulhannan P, Russell DA, Homer-Vanniasinkam S. Peripheral arterial disease: A literature review. Br Med Bull. 2012;104(1):21-39. doi:10.1093/bmb/lds027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray CJ, Barber RM, Foreman KJ, et al. Global, regional, and national disability-adjusted life years (DALYs) for 306 diseases and injuries and healthy life expectancy (HALE) for 188 countries, 1990-2013: Quantifying the epidemiological transition. Lancet. 2015;386(10009):2145-2191. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(15)61340-X7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Criqui MH, Matsushita K, Aboyans V, et al. Lower extremity peripheral artery disease: Contemporary epidemiology, management gaps, and future directions: A scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2021;144(9):e171-e191. doi:10.1161/CIR.0000000000001005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J-J, Chao W-C, Lee P-Y, Huang C-H. Construction and characterization of an electrospun tubular scaffold for small-diameter tissue-engineered vascular grafts: A scaffold membrane approach. J Mech Behav Biomed Mater. 2012;13:140-155. doi:10.1016/j.jmbbm.2012.04.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerem RM, Seliktar D. Vascular tissue engineering. Annu Rev Biomed Eng. 2001;3(1):225-243. doi:10.1146/annurev.bioeng.3.1.225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konig G, McAllister TN, Dusserre N, et al. Mechanical properties of completely autologous human tissue engineered blood vessels compared to human saphenous vein and mammary artery. Biomaterials. 2009;30(8):1542-1550. doi:10.1016/j.biomaterials.2008.11.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tara S, Kurobe H, Maxfield MW, et al. Evaluation of remodeling process in small-diameter cell-free tissue-engineered arterial graft. J Vasc Surg. 2015;62(3):734-743. doi:10.1016/j.jvs.2014.03.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H-F, Dai W-W, Qian D-H, et al. A simply prepared small-diameter artificial blood vessel that promotes in situ endothelialization. Acta Biomater. 2017;54:107-116. doi:10.1016/j.actbio.2017.02.038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatterton M, Wilshaw S-P, Ingham E, Homer-Vanniasinkam S. The use of antithrombotic therapies in reducing synthetic small-diameter vascular graft thrombosis. Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2012;46(3):212-222. doi:10.1177/1538574411433299</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan Y, Wang X, Yin D, Zhang R. A new polyurethane/heparin vascular graft for small-caliber vein repair. J Bioact Compat Polym. 2007;22(3):323-341. doi:10.1177/0883911507078386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta RI, Mukherjee AK, Patterson TD, Fishbein MC. Pathology of explanted polytetrafluoroethylene vascular grafts. Cardiovasc Pathol. 2011;20(4):213-221. doi:10.1016/j.carpath.2010.06.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teebken OE, Haverich A. Tissue engineering of small diameter vascular grafts. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2002;23(6):475-485. doi:10.1053/ejvs.2002.1654</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee Y, Kwon J, Khang G, Lee D. Reduction of inflammatory responses and enhancement of extracellular matrix formation by vanillin-incorporated poly(lactic-co-glycolic acid) scaffolds. Tissue Eng Part A. 2012;18(19-20):1967-1978. doi:10.1089/ten.tea.2012.0001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi J, Zhang X, Jiang L, et al. Regulation of the inflammatory response by vascular grafts modified with Aspirin-Triggered Resolvin D1 promotes blood vessel regeneration. Acta Biomater. 2019;97:360-373. doi: 10.1016/j.actbio.2019.07.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tuan-Mu H-Y, Lu P-C, Lee P-Y, et al. Rapid fabrication of a cell-seeded collagen gel-based tubular construct that withstands arterial pressure. Ann Biomed Eng. 2016;44(11):3384-3397. doi:10.1007/s10439-016-1645-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melchiorri AJ, Hibino N, Best CA, et al. 3D-printed biodegradable polymeric vascular grafts. Adv Healthc Mater. 2016;5(3):319-325. doi:10.1002/adhm.201500725</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Del Gaudio C, Ercolani E, Galloni P, et al. Aspirin-loaded electrospun poly(&#x3b5;-caprolactone) tubular scaffolds: Potential small-diameter vascular grafts for thrombosis prevention. J Mater Sci Mater Med. 2013;24:523-532. doi:10.1007/s10856-012-4803-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melchiorri AJ, Hibino N, Brandes ZR, Jonas RA, Fisher JP. Development and assessment of a biodegradable solvent cast polyester fabric small-diameter vascular graft. J Biomed Mater Res A. 2014;102(6):1972-1981. doi:10.1002/jbm.a.34872.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teebken OE, Bader A, Steinhoff G, Haverich A. Tissue engineering of vascular grafts: Human cell seeding of decellularised porcine matrix. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2000;19(4):381-386. doi:10.1053/ejvs.1999.1004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gui L, Muto A, Chan SA, Breuer CK, Niklason LE. Development of decellularized human umbilical arteries as small-diameter vascular grafts. Tissue Eng Part A. 2009;15(9):2665-2676. doi:10.1089/ten.tea.2008.0526</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari PF, Aliakbarian B, Lagazzo A, Tamayol A, Palombo D, Perego P. Tailored electrospun small-diameter graft for vascular prosthesis. Int J Polym Mater Polym Biomater. 2017;66(12):635-643. doi:10.1080/00914037.2016.1252361</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleemann R, Verschuren L, Morrison M, et al. Anti-inflammatory, anti-proliferative and anti-atherosclerotic effects of quercetin in human in vitro and in vivo models. Atherosclerosis. 2011;218(1):44-52. doi:10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2011.04.023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobuchi H, Roy S, Sen CK, Nguyen HG, Packer L. Quercetin inhibits inducible ICAM-1 expression in human endothelial cells through the JNK pathway. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 1999;277(3):C403-C411. doi:10.1152/ajpcell.1999.277.3.C403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baghel SS, Shrivastava N, Baghel RS, Agrawal P, Rajput S. A review of quercetin: Antioxidant and anticancer properties. World J Pharm Pharm Sci. 2012;1(1):146-160.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boots AW, Haenen GRMM, Bast A. Health effects of quercetin: From Antioxidant to nutraceutical. Eur J Pharmacol. 2008;585(2-3):325-337. doi:10.1016/j.ejphar.2008.03.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wattel A, Kamel S, Prouillet C, et al. Flavonoid quercetin decreases osteoclastic differentiation induced by RANKL via a mechanism involving NF&#x3ba;B and AP-1. J Cell Biochem. 2004;92(2):285-295. doi:10.1002/jcb.20071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila MA, Velasco JA, Cansado J, Notario V. Quercetin mediates the down-regulation of mutant p53 in the human breast cancer cell line MDA-MB468. Cancer Res. 1994;54(9):2424-2428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russo M, Spagnuolo C, Tedesco I, Bilotto S, Russo GL. The flavonoid quercetin in disease prevention and therapy: Facts and fancies. Biochem Pharmacol. 2012;83(1):6-15. doi:10.1016/j.bcp.2011.08.010</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crespo I, Garc&#xed;a-Mediavilla MV, Guti&#xe9;rrez B, S&#xe1;nchez-Campos S, Tu&#xf1;&#xf3;n MJ, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Gallego J. A comparison of the effects of kaempferol and quercetin on cytokine-induced pro-inflammatory status of cultured human endothelial cells. Br J Nutr. 2008;100(5):968-976. doi:10.1017/S0007114508966083</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari PF, Aliakbarian B, Palombo D, Perego P. Small diameter vascular grafts coated with gelatin. Chem Eng Trans. 2017;57. doi:10.3303/CET1757241</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Ameer GA, Sheppard BJ, Langer R. A tough biodegradable elastomer. Nat Biotechnol. 2002;20(6):602-606. doi:10.1038/nbt0602-602</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence BJ, Madihally SV. Cell colonization in degradable 3D porous matrices. Cell Adhes Migr. 2008;2(1):9-16. doi:10.4161/cam.2.1.5884</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim SE, Heo DN, Lee JB, et al. Electrospun gelatin/polyurethane blended nanofibers for wound healing. Biomed Mater. 2009;4(4):1-11. doi:10.1088/1748-6041/4/4/044106</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi S, Fathi M, Javanmard SH, et al. Generation of PGS/PCL blend nanofibrous scaffolds mimicking corneal stroma structure. Macromol Mater Eng. 2014;299(4):455-469. doi:10.1002/mame.201300187</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Florence JM, Krupa A, Booshehri LM, Allen TC, Kurdowska AK. Metalloproteinase-9 contributes to endothelial dysfunction in atherosclerosis via protease activated receptor-1. PLoS One. 2017;12(2):1-24. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0171427</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szmitko PE, Wang CH, Weisel RD, Jeffries GA, Anderson TJ, Verma S. Biomarkers of vascular disease linking inflammation to endothelial activation: Part II. Circulation. 2003;108(17):2041-2048. doi:10.1161/01.CIR.0000089093.75585.98</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakraborty S, Stalin S, Das N, Choudhury ST, Ghosh S, Swarnakar S. The use of nano-quercetin to arrest mitochondrial damage and MMP-9 upregulation during prevention of gastric inflammation induced by ethanol in rat. Biomaterials. 2012;33(10):2991-3001. doi:10.1016/j.biomaterials.2011.12.037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scoditti E, Calabriso N, Massaro M, et al. Mediterranean diet polyphenols reduce inflammatory angiogenesis through MMP-9 and COX-2 inhibition in human vascular endothelial cells: A potentially protective mechanism in atherosclerotic vascular disease and cancer. Arch Biochem Biophys. 2012;527(2):81-89. doi:10.1016/j.abb.2012.05.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan H-C, Jiang Q, Yu Y, Mei J-P, Cui Y-K, Zhao W-J. Quercetin promotes cell apoptosis and inhibits the expression of MMP-9 and fibronectin via the AKT and ERK signalling pathways in human glioma cells. Neurochem Int. 2015;80:60-71. doi:10.1016/j.neuint.2014.12.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nee LE, McMorrow T, Campbell E, Slattery C, Ryan MP. TNF-&#x3b1; and IL-1&#x3b2;-mediated regulation of MMP-9 and TIMP-1 in renal proximal tubular cells. Kidney Int. 2004;66(4):1376-1386. doi:10.1111/j.1523-1755.2004.00900.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ries C. Cytokine functions of TIMP-1. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2014;71:659-672. doi:10.1007/s00018-013-1457-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari PF, Palmieri D, Casazza AA, Aliakbarian B, Perego P, Palombo D. TNF&#x3b1;-induced endothelial activation is counteracted by polyphenol extract from UV-stressed cyanobacterium Arthrospira platensis. Med Chem Res. 2015;24:275-282. doi:10.1007/s00044-014-1126-6</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>