<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36662568</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1929-0748</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR research protocols</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Res Protoc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Prescription Digital Therapeutic to Support Unsupervised Buprenorphine Initiation for Patients With Opioid Use Disorder: Protocol for a Proof-of-Concept Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e43122</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e43122</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e43122</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/43122</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Home-based (unsupervised) buprenorphine initiation is considered safe and effective, yet many patients report barriers to successful treatment initiation. Prescription digital therapeutics (PDTs) are software-based disease treatments regulated by the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA). The reSET-O PDT was authorized by the FDA in 2018 and delivers behavioral treatment for individuals receiving buprenorphine for opioid use disorder (OUD). A prototype PDT (PEAR-002b) designed for use with reSET-O was developed to assist in unsupervised buprenorphine initiation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The primary objective of this pilot study is to evaluate the acceptability of PEAR-002b in individuals with OUD who use it to support buprenorphine initiation, their unsupervised buprenorphine initiation success rate, and their medication adherence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ten adults with OUD will be recruited for acceptability and feasibility testing. Outcomes will be assessed using week-1 visit attendance, participant interviews and satisfaction surveys, and urine drug screening (UDS). Three tools will be used in the study: PEAR-002b, reSET-O, and EmbracePlus. PEAR-002b includes a new set of features designed for use with reSET-O. The mechanism of action for the combined PEAR-002b and reSET-O treatment is a program of medication dosing support during week 1 of the initiation phase, cognitive behavioral therapy, and contingency management. During the medication initiation phase, participants are guided through a process to support proper medication use. PEAR-002b advises them when to take their buprenorphine based on provider inputs (eg, starting dose), self-reported substance use, and self-reported withdrawal symptoms. This study also administers the EmbracePlus device, a medical-grade smartwatch, to pilot methods for collecting physiologic data (eg, heart rate and skin conductance) and evaluate the device's potential for use along with PDTs that are designed to improve OUD treatment initiation. Home buprenorphine initiation success will be summarized as the proportion of participants attending the post-buprenorphine initiation visit (week 1) and the proportion of participants who experience buprenorphine initiation-related adverse events (eg, precipitated withdrawal). Acceptability of PEAR-002b will be evaluated based on individual participants' ratings of ease of use, satisfaction, perceived helpfulness, and likelihood of recommending PEAR-002b. Medication adherence will be evaluated by participant self-report data and confirmed by UDS. UDS data will be summarized as the mean of individual participants' proportion of total urine samples testing positive for buprenorphine or norbuprenorphine over the 4-week study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This project was funded in September 2019. As of September 2022, participant enrollment is ongoing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This is the first study to our knowledge to develop a PDT that assists with unsupervised buprenorphine initiation with the intent to better support patients and prescribers during this early phase of treatment. This pilot study will assess the acceptability and utility of a digital therapeutic to assist individuals with OUD with unsupervised buprenorphine initiation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov NCT05412966; https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05412966.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERNATIONAL REGISTERED REPORT IDENTIFIER (IRRID)" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">PRR1-10.2196/43122.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Hilary Luderer, Nicole Enman, Robert Gerwien, Stephen Braun, Samantha McStocker, Xiaorui Xiong, Carrington Koebele, Christopher Cannon, Joseph Glass, Yuri Maricich. Originally published in JMIR Research Protocols (https://www.researchprotocols.org), 20.01.2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luderer</LastName><ForeName>Hilary</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3737-946X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Enman</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3925-1603</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerwien</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8368-5188</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braun</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9891-3825</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McStocker</LastName><ForeName>Samantha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8662-2983</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Xiong</LastName><ForeName>Xiaorui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7838-4524</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koebele</LastName><ForeName>Carrington</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6795-295X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Whitman-Walker Institute, Washington, DC, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cannon</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1937-4283</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Whitman-Walker Institute, Washington, DC, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glass</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2923-3698</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maricich</LastName><ForeName>Yuri</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8667-5233</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc, Boston, MA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05412966</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R44 DA042652</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R44 DA049493</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Res Protoc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101599504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1929-0748</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OUD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PDT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">buprenorphine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medication adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opioid use disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescription digital therapeutic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reSET-O</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unsupervised buprenorphine initiation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: HL, RG, SM, XX, YM, and SB are consultants or employees of Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc. NE was an employee of Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc at the time this manuscript was written. Pear Therapeutics Inc provided digital therapeutic prescriptions at no cost to Kaiser Permanente Washington during a quality improvement pilot study that was led by JG. JG is a coinvestigator on a grant proposal awarded to Pear Therapeutics Inc by the National Institute on Drug Abuse, which evaluates potential improvements to reSET-O (R44DA042652). Pear Therapeutics does not provide funding to JG.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36662568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9898828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/43122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v12i1e43122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Increse in fatal drug overdoses across the United States driven by synthetic opioids before and during the COVID-19 pandemic. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.  [2022-12-14].  
 https://emergency.cdc.gov/han/2020/han00438.asp
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Key substance use and mental health indicators in the United States: Results from the 2020 National Survey on Drug Use and Health. Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.  [2022-12-15].  
 https://www.samhsa.gov/data/sites/default/files/reports/rpt35319/2020NSDUHFFR1PDFW102121.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer M, Warner M, Bastian B, Trinidad James P, Hedegaard Holly. Drug overdose deaths involving fentanyl, 2011-2016. Natl Vital Stat Rep. 2019 Mar;68(3):1&#x2013;19. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31112123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vital statistics rapid release: provisional drug overdose death counts. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.  [2022-12-15].  
 https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/nvss/vsrr/drug-overdose-data.htm
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanham HJ, Papac J, Olmos DI, Heydemann EL, Simonetti N, Schmidt S, Potter JS. Survey of barriers and facilitators to prescribing buprenorphine and clinician perceptions on the Drug Addiction Treatment Act of 2000 waiver. JAMA Netw Open. 2022 May 02;5(5):e2212419. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.12419. 
 
2792215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2022.12419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9099423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35552721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haffajee RL, Andraka-Christou B, Attermann J, Cupito A, Buche J, Beck AJ. A mixed-method comparison of physician-reported beliefs about and barriers to treatment with medications for opioid use disorder. Subst Abuse Treat Prev Policy. 2020 Sep 14;15(1):69. doi: 10.1186/s13011-020-00312-3. 
 
10.1186/s13011-020-00312-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13011-020-00312-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7491096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32928272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFlavio J, Rolin S, Nordstrom B, Kazal Louis A. Analysis of barriers to adoption of buprenorphine maintenance therapy by family physicians. Rural Remote Health. 2015;15:3019. doi: 10.22605/rrh3019. 
 
3019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22605/rrh3019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25651434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackey K, Veazie S, Anderson J, Bourne D, Peterson K. Barriers and facilitators to the use of medications for opioid use disorder: a rapid review. J Gen Intern Med. 2020 Dec;35(Suppl 3):954&#x2013;963. doi: 10.1007/s11606-020-06257-4. 
 
10.1007/s11606-020-06257-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-020-06257-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7728943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33145687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai B, Croghan I, Ebbert JO. Buprenorphine waiver attitudes among primary care providers. J Prim Care Community Health. 2022;13:21501319221112272. doi: 10.1177/21501319221112272. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/21501319221112272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9284198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35822763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hser Y, Saxon AJ, Huang D, Hasson A, Thomas C, Hillhouse M, Jacobs P, Teruya C, McLaughlin P, Wiest K, Cohen A, Ling W. Treatment retention among patients randomized to buprenorphine/naloxone compared to methadone in a multi-site trial. Addiction. 2014 Jan;109(1):79&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1111/add.12333. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.12333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3947022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23961726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soeffing JM, Martin LD, Fingerhood MI, Jasinski DR, Rastegar DA. Buprenorphine maintenance treatment in a primary care setting: outcomes at 1 year. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2009 Dec;37(4):426&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2009.05.003.S0740-5472(09)00086-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2009.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19553061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings LK, Lane S, McCauley J, Moreland A, Hartwell K, Haynes L, Barth KS, Gainey SS, Brady KT. Retention in treatment after emergency department-initiated buprenorphine. J Emerg Med. 2021 Sep;61(3):211&#x2013;221. doi: 10.1016/j.jemermed.2021.04.007. 
 
S0736-4679(21)00381-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jemermed.2021.04.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8628549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34176686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein MD, Cioe P, Friedmann PD. Buprenorphine retention in primary care. J Gen Intern Med. 2005 Nov;20(11):1038&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1111/j.1525-1497.2005.0228.x. 
 
JGI228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1525-1497.2005.0228.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1490248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16307630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakubowski A, Lu T, DiRenno F, Jadow B, Giovanniello A, Nahvi S, Cunningham C, Fox A. Same-day vs. delayed buprenorphine prescribing and patient retention in an office-based buprenorphine treatment program. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2020 Dec;119:108140. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2020.108140. 
 
S0740-5472(20)30397-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2020.108140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7609975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33138925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruetsch C, Tkacz J, Nadipelli VR, Brady BL, Ronquest N, Un H, Volpicelli J. Heterogeneity of nonadherent buprenorphine patients: subgroup characteristics and outcomes. Am J Manag Care. 2017 Jun 01;23(6):e172&#x2013;e179. 
 
87126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28817294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronquest N, Willson T, Montejano L, Nadipelli V, Wollschlaeger B. Relationship between buprenorphine adherence and relapse, health care utilization and costs in privately and publicly insured patients with opioid use disorder. Subst Abuse Rehabil. 2018;9:59&#x2013;78. doi: 10.2147/SAR.S150253. 
 
sar-9-059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/SAR.S150253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30310349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams AR, Samples H, Crystal S, Olfson M. Acute care, prescription opioid use, and overdose following discontinuation of long-term buprenorphine treatment for opioid use disorder. Am J Psychiatry. 2020 Feb 01;177(2):117&#x2013;124. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2019.19060612. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2019.19060612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7002204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31786933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teruya C, Schwartz RP, Mitchell SG, Hasson AL, Thomas C, Buoncristiani SH, Hser Y, Wiest K, Cohen AJ, Glick N, Jacobs P, McLaughlin P, Ling W. Patient perspectives on buprenorphine/naloxone: a qualitative study of retention during the starting treatment with agonist replacement therapies (START) study. J Psychoactive Drugs. 2014;46(5):412&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1080/02791072.2014.921743. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02791072.2014.921743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4220245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25364994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham C, Edlund Mj, Fishman M, Gordon Aj, Jones He, Langleben D, Femino J. The ASAM National Practice Guideline for the Treatment of Opioid Use Disorder: 2020 focused update. J Addict Med. 2020;14(2S Suppl 1):1&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000633.01271255-202004001-00001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0000000000000633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32511106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pergolizzi JV, Raffa RB, Rosenblatt MH. Opioid withdrawal symptoms, a consequence of chronic opioid use and opioid use disorder: Current understanding and approaches to management. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2020 Oct;45(5):892&#x2013;903. doi: 10.1111/jcpt.13114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpt.13114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel WK, Marsch LA, Buchhalter AR, Badger GJ. Computerized behavior therapy for opioid-dependent outpatients: a randomized controlled trial. Exp Clin Psychopharmacol. 2008 Apr;16(2):132&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1037/1064-1297.16.2.132. 
 
2008-03846-004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1064-1297.16.2.132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18489017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stitzer M, Petry N. Contingency management for treatment of substance abuse. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2006;2:411&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1146/annurev.clinpsy.2.022305.095219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.clinpsy.2.022305.095219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17716077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walter K, Petry N. Motivation and contingency management treatments for substance use disorders. Curr Top Behav Neurosci. 2016;27:569&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1007/7854_2015_374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/7854_2015_374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25762429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schottenfeld RS, Chawarski MC, Pakes JR, Pantalon MV, Carroll KM, Kosten TR. Methadone versus buprenorphine with contingency management or performance feedback for cocaine and opioid dependence. Am J Psychiatry. 2005 Feb;162(2):340&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.162.2.340.162/2/340</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.162.2.340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15677600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen S, Weimer M, Levander X, Peckham Alyssa M, Tetrault Jeanette M, Morford Kenneth L. Low dose initiation of buprenorphine: a narrative review and practical approach. J Addict Med. 2022;16(4):399&#x2013;406. doi: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000945.01271255-900000000-98961</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0000000000000945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34954746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>