<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40416910</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Sentiment and Thematic Analysis of User Reviews for FDA-Cleared Prescription Digital Therapeutics: A Mixed-Methods Real-World Evidence Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e84710</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e84710</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e84710</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.84710</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Background Prescription digital therapeutics (PDTs) are FDA-cleared, evidence-backed, smartphone-based interventions. While clinical trials establish efficacy under controlled conditions, the patient experience in real-world settings remains poorly characterized. App store reviews, though informal, offer a potential source of real-world evidence (RWE) reflecting user sentiment, barriers to engagement, and perceived benefit. Objective To characterize the real-world user experience of FDA-cleared PDTs through a mixed-methods analysis of publicly available app store reviews, combining quantitative sentiment classification with qualitative thematic analysis. Methods FDA-cleared PDTs via FDA's De Novo or 510(k) pathways were identified. Reviews were collected from the Apple App Store and Google Play Store using structured scraping tools. A rules-based sentiment classifier was applied based on user star ratings, and thematic content analysis was conducted using a hybrid natural language processing and manual coding approach. Reviews were grouped by app and platform, and dominant themes were extracted using unsupervised topic modeling. Results Of the 13 PDTs identified, seven had publicly accessible user reviews, yielding a dataset of 247 unique entries: AspyreRx, EndeavorRx, Regulora, Rejoyn, reSET, reSET-O, and Stanza. Sentiment classification revealed that 25.1% of reviews were positive, 12.6% neutral, and 62.3% negative. Thematic analysis identified six recurrent themes, including pediatric benefit and engagement, rewards and incentives, access and activation barriers, technical issues, emotional reactions and cost sensitivity, and boredom and frustration. While negative sentiment was more prevalent overall, several products, particularly Rejoyn and EndeavorRx, received meaningful reports of perceived benefit and therapeutic value. Company transitions were noted to have disrupted the continuity of historical review data of some PDTs. Conclusions App store reviews provide a rich, user-centered source of RWE and insights for PDTs. They highlight dimensions of access, usability, and trust not typically captured in clinical trials. Integrating such feedback into post-market evaluation may inform future design, regulation, and reimbursement of software-based therapeutics.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Lakhan et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lakhan</LastName><ForeName>Shaheen E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Office, Click Therapeutics, Inc., New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, A.T. Still University School of Osteopathic Medicine in Arizona, Mesa, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Morehouse School of Medicine, Atlanta, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioscience, Global Neuroscience Initiative Foundation, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">app store reviews</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fda-cleared software</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient experience</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pdt</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescription digital therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">real-world evidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sentiment analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thematic analysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: Shaheen E Lakhan declare(s) employment and stock/stock options from Click Therapeutics. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40416910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12102580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.84710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>When software becomes medicine: Ignoring it may soon be malpractice. Lakhan SE. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12015761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40271230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA. Establishment Registration &amp; Device Listing.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfrl/rl.cfm https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfrl/rl.cfm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apple App Store.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.apple.com/app-store/ https://www.apple.com/app-store/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Google Play Store for Apps.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2025. https://play.google.com/store/apps https://play.google.com/store/apps</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apify.  [
May;
2025 
]. 2025. https://apify.com/ https://apify.com/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>An effective short-text topic modelling with neighbourhood assistance-driven NMF in Twitter. Athukorala S, Mohotti W. Soc Netw Anal Min. 2022;12:89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9309003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35911485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scikit-learn: Machine learning in Python. Pedregosa F, Varoquaux G, Gramfort A, et al. J Mach Learn Res. 2011;12:2825&#x2013;2830.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conceptualizing trust in digital environments: Health-e Skepticism: Trust in the age of the internet. Harris A, Wyatt S, Kelly S. SSRN. 2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamification for health promotion: Systematic review of behaviour change techniques in smartphone apps. Edwards EA, Lumsden J, Rivas C, et al. BMJ Open. 2016;6:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5073629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27707829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical review of user engagement with mental health smartphone apps: Evidence, theory and improvements. Torous J, Nicholas J, Larsen ME, Firth J, Christensen H. Evid Based Ment Health. 2018;21:116&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10270395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29871870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The engagement problem: A review of engagement with digital mental health interventions and recommendations for a path forward. Lipschitz JM, Pike CK, Hogan TP, Murphy SA, Burdick KE. Curr Treat Options Psychiatry. 2023;10:119&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10883589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38390026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Human-centered design approaches in digital mental health interventions: Exploratory mapping review. Vial S, Boudhra&#xe2; S, Dumont M. JMIR Ment Health. 2022;9:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9214621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35671081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The digital therapeutics real-world evidence framework: An approach for guiding evidence-based digital therapeutics design, development, testing, and monitoring. Kim M, Patrick K, Nebeker C, et al. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10951831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38441954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The future landscape of large language models in medicine. Clusmann J, Kolbinger FR, Muti HS, et al. Commun Med (Lond) 2023;3:141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10564921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37816837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>