<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">21179402</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2011</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The social context of cannibalism in migratory bands of the Mormon cricket.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e15118</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e15118</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e15118</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0015118</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Cannibalism has been shown to be important to the collective motion of mass migratory bands of insects, such as locusts and Mormon crickets. These mobile groups consist of millions of individuals and are highly destructive to vegetation. Individuals move in response to attacks from approaching conspecifics and bite those ahead, resulting in further movement and encounters with others. Despite the importance of cannibalism, the way in which individuals make attack decisions and how the social context affects these cannibalistic interactions is unknown. This can be understood by examining the decisions made by individuals in response to others. We performed a field investigation which shows that adult Mormon crickets were more likely to approach and attack a stationary cricket that was side-on to the flow than either head- or abdomen-on, suggesting that individuals could reduce their risk of an attack by aligning with neighbours. We found strong social effects on cannibalistic behaviour: encounters lasted longer, were more likely to result in an attack, and attacks were more likely to be successful if other individuals were present around a stationary individual. This local aggregation appears to be driven by positive feedback whereby the presence of individuals attracts others, which can lead to further crowding. This work improves our understanding of the local social dynamics driving migratory band formation, maintenance and movement at the population level.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bazazi</LastName><ForeName>Sepideh</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Zoology, University of Oxford, Oxford, United Kingdom. sbazazi@gmail.com</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ioannou</LastName><ForeName>Christos C</ForeName><Initials>CC</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simpson</LastName><ForeName>Stephen J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sword</LastName><ForeName>Gregory A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torney</LastName><ForeName>Colin J</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lorch</LastName><ForeName>Patrick D</ForeName><Initials>PD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Couzin</LastName><ForeName>Iain D</ForeName><Initials>ID</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000819" MajorTopicYN="N">Animal Communication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D025041" MajorTopicYN="N">Animal Migration</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001522" MajorTopicYN="N">Behavior, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002190" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cannibalism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003299" MajorTopicYN="N">Cooperative Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020387" MajorTopicYN="N">Food Chain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006135" MajorTopicYN="N">Gryllidae</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011235" MajorTopicYN="N">Predatory Behavior</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012306" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012919" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012931" MajorTopicYN="N">Social Environment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2010</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2011</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2010</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21179402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3001859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0015118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bonabeau E, Theraulaz G, Deneubourg J-L, Aron S, Camazine S. Self-organization in social insects. Trends in Ecology and Evolution. 1997;12:188&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21238030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camazine S, Deneubourg J-L, Franks NR, Sneyd J, Theraulaz G, et al. Princeton, New Jersey: Princeton University Press; 2001. Self-Organization in Biological Systems.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazazi S, Romanczuk P, Thomas S, Schimansky-Geier L, Hale JJ, et al. Nutritional state and collective motion: from individuals to mass migration. Proceedings of the Royal Society London Series B: published online 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3013415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nathan R, Getz WM, Revilla E, Holyoak M, Kadmon R, et al. A movement ecology paradigm for unifying organismal movement research. Proceedings National Academy of Sciences USA. 2008;105:19052&#x2013;19059.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2614714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19060196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin ID. Collective cognition in animal groups. Trends in Cognitive Sciences. 2009;13:36&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19058992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin ID, Krause J, Franks NR, Levin SA. Effective leadership and decision making in animal groups on the move. Nature. 2005;433:513&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15690039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krause J, Ruxton GD. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2002. Living in groups.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ame JM, Rivault C, Deneubourg J-L. Cockroach aggregation based on strain odour recognition. Animal Behaviour. 2004;68:793&#x2013;801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couzin ID, Krause J. Self-organization and collective behaviour of vertebrates. Advances in the Study of Behaviour. 2003;32:1&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhl J, Sword GA, Clissold F, Simpson SJ. Group structure and the intrinsic dynamics of collective movement in locust hopper bands. Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology in press</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dingle H. New York: Oxford University Press; 1996. Migration: The Biology of Life on the Move.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorch PD, Sword GA, Gwynne DT, Anderson GL. Radiotelemetry reveals differences in individual movement patterns between outbreak and non-outbreak Mormon cricket populations. Ecological Entomology. 2005;30:548&#x2013;555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowan FT. Life history, habits, and control of the Mormon cricket. United States Department of Agriculture Technical Bulletin. 1929;161:1&#x2013;28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwynne DT. New York: Cornell University Press; 2001. Katydids and Bush-Crickets: Reproductive Behaviour and Evolution of the Tettigoniidae.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacVean CM. Ecology and management of Mormon cricket, Anabrus simplex, Haldeman. In: Capinera JL, editor. Integrated Pest Management on Rangeland: A Shortgrass Prairie Perspective. Boulder, Colorado: Westview Press; 1987. pp. 116&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakeland C. Mormon crickets in North America. United States Department of Agriculture Technical Bulletin. 1959;1202:1&#x2013;77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sword GA, Lorch PD, Gwynne DT. Migratory bands give crickets protection. Nature. 2005;433:703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15716941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson SJ, Sword GA, Lorch PD, Couzin ID. Cannibal crickets on a forced march for protein and salt. Proceedings National Academy of Sciences USA. 2006;103:4152&#x2013;4156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1449662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16537500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bazazi S, Buhl J, Hale JJ, Anstey ML, Sword GA, et al. Collective motion and cannibalism in locust migratory bands. Current Biology. 2008;18:735&#x2013;739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18472424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collett TS. Insect Vision: Controlling Actions through Optic Flow. Current Biology. 2002;12:R615&#x2013;R617.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12372265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danchin E, Giraldeau L-A, Valone TJ, Wagner RH. Public Information: From Nosy Neighbors to Cultural Evolution. Science. 2004;305:487&#x2013;491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15273386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnie KE, Earley RL. Expanding the scope for social information use. Animal Behaviour. 2007;74:171&#x2013;181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valone TJ, Templeton JJ. Public information for the assessment of quality: a widespread social phenomenon. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London: Series B. 2002;357:1549&#x2013;1557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1693063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12495512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown C, Laland KN. Social learning in fishes: a review. Fish and Fisheries. 2003;4:280&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galef BG, Giraldeau L-A. Social influences on foraging in vertebrates: Causal mechanisms and adaptive functions. Animal Behaviour. 2001;61:3&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11170692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galef BG, Heyes CM. 1996. Social Learning in Animals: the Roots of Culture San Diego: San Diego: Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giraldeau L-A, Valone TJ, Templeton JJ. Potential disadvantages of using socially-acquired information. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London: Series B. 2002;357:1559&#x2013;1566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1693065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12495513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chittka L, Leadbeater E. Social learning: public information in insects. Current Biology. 2005;15:R869&#x2013;R871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16271856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leadbeater E, Chittka L. Social Learning in Insects- From Miniature Brains to Consensus Building. Current Biology. 2007;17:R703&#x2013;R713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17714664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Webster SJ, Fiorito G. Socially guided behaviour in non-insect invertebrates. Animal Cognition. 2001;4:69&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laidre M. How rugged individualists enable one another to find food and shelter: field experiments with tropical hermit crabs. Proceedings of the Royal Society London Series B. 2009;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2871931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20031987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coolen I, Dangles O, Casas J. Social learning in noncolonial insects. Current Biology. 2005;15:1931&#x2013;1935.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16271870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mery F, Varela SAM, Danchin E, Blanchet S, Parejo D, et al. Public versus personal information for mate copying in an invertebrate. Current Biology. 2009;19:730&#x2013;734.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19361993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baude M, Dajoz I, Danchin E. Inadvertent social information in foraging bumblebees: effects of flower distribution and implications for pollination. Animal Behaviour. 2008;76:1863&#x2013;1873.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danchin E, Giraldeau L-A, Cezilly F. Behavioural Ecology; In: Danchin E, Giraldeau L-A, Cezilly F, editors. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buhl J, Sumpter DJT, Couzin ID, Hale JJ, Despland E, et al. From Disorder to Order in Marching Locusts. Science. 2006;312:1402&#x2013;1406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16741126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima SL, Dill LM. Behavioral decisions made under the risk of predation: a review and prospectus. Canadian Journal of Zoology. 1990;68:619&#x2013;640.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srygley RB, Lorch PD, Simpson SJ, Sword GA. Immediate protein dietary effects on movement and the generalized immunocompetence of migrating Mormon crickets Anabrus simplex (Orthoptera: Tettigoniidae). Ecological Entomology. 2009;34:633&#x2013;688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elgar MA, Crespi BJ. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 1992. Cannibalism: Ecology and evolution among different taxa.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins LM, Sumpter DJT. The feeding dynamics of broiler chickens. Journal of the Royal Society Interface. 2007;4:65&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2358962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17015286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Castro JM. Social facilitation of duration and size but not rate of the spontaneous meal intake of humans. Physiology and Behaviour. 1990;47:1129&#x2013;1135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2395917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurta A. Social Facilitation of Foraging Behavior by the Hermit Crab, Coenobita compressus, in Costa Rica. Biotropica. 1982;14:132&#x2013;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweeting MP, Houpt CE, Houpt KA. Social facilitation of feeding and time budgets in stabled ponies. Journal of Animal Sciences. 1985;60:369&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3988629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sword GA. Local population density and the activation of movements in migratory band-forming Mormon crickets. Animal Behaviour. 2005;69:437&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>