<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36820057</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2049-4637</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>British journal of pain</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Pain</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>How has the COVID-19 pandemic affected patients' experience of pain management therapy?</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>46</StartPage><EndPage>57</EndPage><MedlinePgn>46-57</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20494637221121703</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The current service evaluation aimed to explore the impact of COVID-19 on patients' experiences of pain management therapy. The study examined the barriers and benefits of the move from face-to-face to eHealth methods of delivery.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A service evaluation was conducted in an outpatient pain clinic in an NHS Trust in the East of England. A qualitative approach was taken using semi-structured interviews.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Participants were recruited through a health psychology service operating as part of a multidisciplinary pain management clinic. Six patients, aged 39-67, were interviewed one-to-one using the online platform Zoom<sup>TM</sup>. During COVID-19, participants had individual or group pain management therapy via telephone or video conferencing. All interviews were transcribed using Otter.ai<sup>TM</sup> and thematic analysis was performed. The study was approved by internal clinical governance for service evaluations and the authors adhered to the BPS Code of Human Research Ethics.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Three key themes emerged from the analysis; <i>Benefits Aside From Pain Relief, Limited Their Experience,</i> and <i>COVID-</i> <i>19: A D</i> <i>ouble-Edged</i> <i>Sword.</i></AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Findings suggested patients were able to benefit from pain management therapy despite the impact of COVID-19 on daily routines and pain experience. Adopting eHealth methods during the pandemic was an effective means of accessing pain management therapy. These methods allowed patients to continue to benefit from peer support and learn about skills and resources regarding self-management, whilst also improving accessibility for those with chronic pain. Yet, these methods are not without their limitations. Technical issues and difficulties creating therapeutic connections with psychologists limited patients' experience of pain management therapy.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>French</LastName><ForeName>Olivia</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4869-5035</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, University of Buckingham, Buckingham, UK.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">2060</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattacola</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology, University of Buckingham, Buckingham, UK.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">2060</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Pain</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101583844</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2049-4637</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient experience</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36820057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9703013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20494637221121703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20494637221121703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mills SEE, Nicolson KP, Smith BH. Chronic pain: a review of its epidemiology and associated factors in population-based studies. Br J Anaesth 2019; 123(2): e273&#x2013;e283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6676152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31079836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fayaz A, Croft P, Langford RM, et al. Prevalence of chronic pain in the UK: a systematic review and meta-analysis of population studies. BMJ Open 2016: 6(6): e010364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4932255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27324708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2017 Disease and Injury Incidence and Prevalence Collaborators . Global, regional, and national incidence, prevalence, and years lived with disability for 354 diseases and injuries for 195 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2017: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Lancet 2018; 392(10159): 1789&#x2013;1858.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6227754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30496104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johannes CB, Le TK, Zhou X, et al. The prevalence of chronic pain in United States adults: results of an Internet-based survey. J Pain 2010; 11(11): 1230&#x2013;1239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20797916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauw DJ, Essex MN, Pitman V, et al. Reframing chronic pain as a disease, not a symptom: rationale and implications for pain management. Postgrad Med 2019; 131(3): 185&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giusti E, Pietrabissa G, Manzoni GM, et al. The economic utility of clinical psychology in the multidisciplinary management of pain. Front Psychol 2017; 8: 1860.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5671758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29163260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niknejad B, Bolier R, Henderson CR, et al. Association between psychological interventions and chronic pain outcomes in older adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med 2018; 178(6): 830&#x2013;839.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6145761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29801109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters A, Siripong N, Wang L, et al. Enhanced recovery after surgery outcomes in minimally invasive nonhysterectomy gynecologic procedures. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2020; 223(2): 234.e8.e1&#x2013;234.e8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7395891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32087147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toelle TR, Utpadel-Fischler DA, Haas K-K, et al. App-based multidisciplinary back pain treatment versus combined physiotherapy plus online education: a randomized controlled trial. Npj Digit Med 2019; 2(1): 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6550294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31304380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The British Pain SocietyLocation . https://www.britishpainsociety.org/static/uploads/resources/files/pmp2013_main_FINAL_v6.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson IR. Management of chronic pain through pain management programmes. Br Med Bull 2017; 124(1): 55&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28927228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight LD, Guildford BJ, Daly-Eichenhardt A, et al. Assessment and patient selection process for a pain management programme: a case study in specialty care. Br J Pain 2019; 13(2): 74&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6463347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31019688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shanthanna H, Strand NH, Provenzano DA, et al. Caring for patients with pain during the COVID-19 pandemic: consensus recommendations from an international expert panel. Anaesthesia 2020; 75(7): 935&#x2013;944.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32259288</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burgess R. Moving from face-to-face to telephone assessments with patients during the COVID-19 pandemic. Nurs Stand 2021; 36: 45&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33682394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aafjes-van Doorn K, B&#xe9;k&#xe9;s V, Prout TA. Grappling with our therapeutic relationship and professional self-doubt during COVID-19: will we use video therapy again? Counselling Psychol Q 2020; 0(0): 1&#x2013;12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geller S. Cultivating online therapeutic presence: strengthening therapeutic relationships in teletherapy sessions. Counselling Psychol Q 2020; 34: 1&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javed S, Hung J, Huh BK. Impact COVID-19 on chronic pain patients: a pain physician&#x2019;s Perspective. Pain Manag 2020; 10(5):275&#x2013;277. DOI: 10.2217/pmt-2020-0035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/pmt-2020-0035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7422723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaremka LM, Andridge RR, Fagundes CP, et al. Pain, depression, and fatigue: loneliness as a longitudinal risk factor. Health Psychol 2014; 33(9): 948&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3992976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23957903</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clauw DJ, H&#xe4;user W, Cohen SP, et al. Considering the potential for an increase in chronic pain after the COVID-19 pandemic. Pain 2020; 161(8): 1694&#x2013;1697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7302093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32701829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coluzzi F, Marinangeli F, Pergolizzi J. Managing chronic pain patients at the time of COVID-19 pandemic. Minerva Anestesiol 2020; 86(8): 797&#x2013;799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32400999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puntillo F, Giglio M, Brienza N, et al. Impact of COVID-19 pandemic on chronic pain management: looking for the best way to deliver care. Best Pract Res Clin Anaesthesiol 2020; 34(3): 529&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7366114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33004164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccleston C, Blyth FM, Dear BF, et al. Managing patients with chronic pain during the COVID-19 outbreak: considerations for the rapid introduction of remotely supported (eHealth) pain management services. Pain 2020; 161(5): 889&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7172975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiani B, Siddiqi I, Lee SC, et al. Telerehabilitation: development, application, and need for increased usage in the COVID-19 era for patients with spinal pathology. Cureus 2020; 12(9): e10563.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33101809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien KM, Hodder RK, Wiggers J, et al. Effectiveness of telephone-based interventions for managing osteoarthritis and spinal pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PeerJ 2018; 6: e5846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6214231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30397549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walumbe J, Belton J, Denneny D. Pain management programmes via video conferencing: a rapid review. Scand J Pain 2021; 21(1): 32&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33027056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, Wherton J, Shaw S, et al. Video consultations for covid-19. BMJ 2020; 368: m998.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32165352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths F, Lindenmeyer A, Powell J, et al. Why are health care interventions delivered over the internet? A systematic review of the published literature. J Med Internet Res 2006; 8(2): e10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1550698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16867965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dear BF, Titov N, Perry KN, et al. The Pain Course: a randomised controlled trial of a clinician-guided Internet-delivered cognitive behaviour therapy program for managing chronic pain and emotional well-being. Pain 2013; 154(6): 942&#x2013;950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23688830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dear BF, Nicholson Perry K, Siddall P, et al. The pain course: exploring the feasibility of an internet-delivered pain management programme for adults with spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord 2018; 56(10): 931&#x2013;939.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29855612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner-Stokes L, Erkeller-Yuksel F, Miles A, et al. Outpatient cognitive behavioral pain management programs: a randomized comparison of a group-based multidisciplinary versus an individual therapy model. Arch Phys Med Rehabil 2003; 84(6): 781&#x2013;788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12808527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nevedal DC, Wang C, Oberleitner L, et al. Effects of an individually tailored web-based chronic pain management program on pain severity, psychological health, and functioning. J Med Internet Res 2013; 15(9): e2296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3785999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24067267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore F, Williams L, Dunbar M. Sociodemographic predictors of attendance at a Scottish pain management programme. Br J Pain 2020; 15: 2049463720970579.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8611294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34840787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruehlman LS, Karoly P, Enders C. A randomized controlled evaluation of an online chronic pain self management program. Pain 2012; 153(2): 319&#x2013;330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22133450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Successful qualitative research: a practical guide for beginners. 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeJonckheere M, Vaughn LM. Semistructured interviewing in primary care research: a balance of relationship and rigour. Fam Med Com Health 2019; 7(2): e000057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6910737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32148704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill P, Stewart K, Treasure E, et al. Methods of data collection in qualitative research: interviews and focus groups. Br Dent J 2008; 204(6): 291&#x2013;295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18356873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roulston K, Choi M. Qualitative interviews. in: the SAGE handbook of qualitative data collection [Internet]. 55 City Road: SAGE Publications Ltd; 2018: 233&#x2013;249. Available from: https://sk.sagepub.com/reference/the-sage-handbook-of-qualitative-data-collection/i1709.xml.[cited 2021 Aug 18]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol 2006; 3(2): 77&#x2013;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V, Weate P. Using thematic analysis in sport and exercise research. Available from: https://uwe-repository.worktribe.com/output/3123247/using-thematic-analysis-in-sport-and-exercise-research. 2016 Sep 1.[cited 2021 Aug 18].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King N. Using templates in the thematic analysis of text. In: Essential Guide to Qualitative Methods in Organizational Research [Internet]. London, UK: SAGE Publications Ltd, 2021, pp. 256&#x2013;270. Available from: https://sk.sagepub.com/books/essential-guide-to-qualitative-methods-in-organizational-research/n21.xml.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Thematic analysis. Available from: https://uwe-repository.worktribe.com/output/841297/thematic-analysis
2015 Jan 1.[cited 2021 Aug 18]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowell LS, Norris JM, White DE, et al. Thematic analysis: striving to meet the trustworthiness criteria. Int J Qual Methods 2017; 16(1): 1609406917733847.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnathan AS. Qualitative psychology: a practical guide to research methods [Internet]. 3rd edition.
Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE Publications Ltd. Available from: https://us.sagepub.com/en-us/nam/qualitative-psychology/book242733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The British Psychological Society . BPS Code of Human Research Ethics [Internet]. The British Psychological Society. https://www.bps.org.uk/sites/www.bps.org.uk/files/Policy/Policy%20-%20Files/BPS%20Code%20of%20Human%20Research%20Ethics.pdf (2021.Available from</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieto R, Pardo R, Sora B, et al. Impact of COVID-19 lockdown measures on spanish people with chronic pain: an online study survey. J Clin Med 2020; 9(11): 3558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7694344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33167322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du S, Liu W, Cai S, et al. The efficacy of e-health in the self-management of chronic low back pain: a meta analysis. Int J Nurs Stud 2020; 106: 103507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32320936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ledel Solem IK, Varsi C, Eide H, et al. Patients&#x2019; needs and requirements for ehealth pain management interventions: qualitative study. J Med Internet Res 2019; 21(4): e13205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6462891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30877780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ridling DA, Lewis-Newby M, Lindsey D. Chapter 9-family-centered care in the pediatric intensive care unit. In: Fuhrman BP, Zimmerman JJ. (eds). Pediatric Critical Care. 4th Edition.
Saint Louis, MO: Mosby, 2021, pp. 92&#x2013;101. Available from: https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/B9780323073073100096.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodgen-Magee D. Deviced! balancing life and technology in a digital world. Lanham, MD: Rowman &amp; Littlefield Publishers, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn R, Callahan JL, Swift JK, et al. Effects of pre-session centering for therapists on session presence and effectiveness. Psychother Res 2013; 23(1): 78&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23066649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Latulippe K, Hamel C, Giroux D. Social health inequalities and ehealth: a literature review with qualitative synthesis of theoretical and empirical studies. J Med Internet Res 2017; 19(4): e136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5427250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28450271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palyo SA, Schopmeyer KA, McQuaid JR. Tele-pain management: use of videoconferencing technology in the delivery of an integrated cognitive-behavioral and physical therapy group intervention. Psychol Serv 2012; 9(2): 200&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22662734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Tallawy SN, Nalamasu R, Pergolizzi JV, et al. Pain management during the COVID-19 pandemic. Pain Ther 2020; 9(2): 453&#x2013;466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32840756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widberg C, Wiklund B, Klarare A. Patients&#x2019; experiences of eHealth in palliative care: an integrative review. BMC Palliat Care 2020; 19: 158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7560207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33054746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>So H, Szeto C-C, Tam L-S. Patient acceptance of using telemedicine for follow-up of lupus nephritis in the COVID-19 outbreak. Ann Rheum Dis 2021; 80(6): e97&#x2013;e97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32581085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaghesh E, Hajizadeh A. The role of telehealth during COVID-19 outbreak: a systematic review based on current evidence. BMC Public Health 2020; 20(1): 1193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7395209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>