<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38606247</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Assessment of Generalized Joint Hypermobility and Its Association With Osteoarthritis, BMI, and Age: A Study in Southern Lahore.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e55990</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e55990</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e55990</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.55990</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Joint hypermobility is a physiological variation in the joint range of motion that allows individuals to move their joints beyond the normal limit. Generalized joint hypermobility (GJH) refers to an increased flexibility observed throughout various joints in the body. In younger individuals, joint hypermobility is often more pronounced, serving as a double-edged sword by providing enhanced flexibility for certain activities while simultaneously increasing the susceptibility to musculoskeletal issues. Weight gain and overactivity of joints (joint hypermobility) are associated with the onset of osteoarthritis (OA), and data for the local populace is lacking. This study aims to assess GJH and OA in young and middle-aged women in southern Lahore.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODOLOGY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A cross-sectional study recruited 116 diagnosed OA patients through a random convenient sampling method. These patients were assessed for GJH&#xa0;using the Beighton criterion. For the assessment of GJH, the Beighton criterion was used, and for OA, radiographs of knee joints were taken. The Beighton criterion consists of nine movements, and each maneuver is assigned a score of either 0 or 1, resulting in a range from 0 to 9. A chi-square test was used for the group comparison of study variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 116 adult females participated, with a mean age of 38.34 &#xb1; 9.761 and an age range of 20 to 55 years.&#xa0;GJH was assessed and correlated with age using the chi-square correlation and test. Results indicated that 78 (67.24%) exhibited hypermobility at various joint levels, with a likelihood ratio of 43.336 and a <i>P</i>-value of &lt;0.001. GJH and BMI were correlated by employing Pearson chi-square correlation, with Pearson chi-square of 2.51 and <i>P</i>-value of 0.112 suggestive of no significant association between BMI and GJH.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The dynamic nature of joint hypermobility emphasizes the need to consider age-related changes when assessing its impact on musculoskeletal health. Assessment and management of hypermobility in patients of OA, especially in females, should be made part of routine practices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024, Qamar et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Qamar</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Shaheer</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics, University College of Medicine and Dentistry, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tahir</LastName><ForeName>Malik Usman</ForeName><Initials>MU</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neurology, Central Park Teaching Hospital, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shehroz</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology, Hameed Latif Teaching Hospital, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zameer</LastName><ForeName>Anusha</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Aziz Bhatti Shaheed Teaching Hospital, Gujrat, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Islam</LastName><ForeName>Amil</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Aziz Bhatti Shaheed Teaching Hospital, Gujrat, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yousaf</LastName><ForeName>Marya</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Community Medicine, Central Park Medical College, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Naseer</LastName><ForeName>Nimra</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Central Park Teaching Hospital, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sikandar</LastName><ForeName>Mirza Zeeshan</ForeName><Initials>MZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Orthopedics and Traumatology, Central Park Medical College, Lahore, PAK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bmi</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">generalized joint hypermobility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">joint hypermobility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">osteoarthritis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38606247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11007284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.55990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Joint hypermobility is not positively associated with prevalent multiple joint osteoarthritis: a cross-sectional study of older adults. Gullo TR, Golightly YM, Flowers P, et al. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2019;20:165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6460832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30975124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Defining multiple joint osteoarthritis, its frequency and impact in a community-based cohort. Gullo TR, Golightly YM, Cleveland RJ, et al. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2019;48:950&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6456431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30390991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Associations of educational attainment, occupation and community poverty with knee osteoarthritis in the Johnston County (North Carolina) osteoarthritis project. Callahan LF, Cleveland RJ, Shreffler J, et al. Arthritis Res Ther. 2011;13:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3308104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22011570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelvic girdle pain, hypermobility spectrum disorder and hypermobility-type Ehlers-Danlos syndrome: a narrative literature review. Ali A, Andrzejowski P, Kanakaris NK, Giannoudis PV. J Clin Med. 2020;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7764306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33317183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of generalized joint laxity (hypermobility) in fourteen-year-old children from the UK: a population-based evaluation. Clinch J, Deere K, Sayers A, Palmer S, Riddoch C, Tobias JH, Clark EM. Arthritis Rheum. 2011;63:2819&#x2013;2827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3164233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21547894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Is the association between knee injury and knee osteoarthritis modified by the presence of general joint hypermobility. Shiue KY, Cleveland RJ, Schwartz TA, et al. Osteoarthr Cartil Open. 2020;2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9107321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35573167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correlation of muscle and bone parameters, daily function and participation in women with generalized joint hypermobility: a descriptive evaluation. Luder G, Aeberli D, Mueller Mebes C, et al. J Musculoskelet Neuronal Interact. 2022;22:15&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8919655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35234155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical management of benign joint hypermobility syndrome: a case series. Boudreau PA, Steiman I, Mior S. J Can Chiropr Assoc. 2020;64:43&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7250515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32476667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kellgren/Lawrence grading in cohort studies: methodological update and implications illustrated using data from a Dutch hip and knee cohort. Macri EM, Runhaar J, Damen J, Oei EH, Bierma-Zeinstra SM. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2022;74:1179&#x2013;1187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9541941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33450140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Beighton score as a measure of generalised joint hypermobility. Malek S, Reinhold EJ, Pearce GS. Rheumatol Int. 2021;41:1707&#x2013;1716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8390395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33738549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Epidemiology of general joint hypermobility and basis for the proposed criteria for benign joint hypermobility syndrome: review of the literature. Remvig L, Jensen DV, Ward RC. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17407233/ J Rheumatol. 2007;34:804&#x2013;809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17407233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A framework for the classification of joint hypermobility and related conditions. Castori M, Tinkle B, Levy H, Grahame R, Malfait F, Hakim A. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2017;175:148&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28145606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measurement properties of clinical assessment methods for classifying generalized joint hypermobility-a systematic review. Juul-Kristensen B, Schmedling K, Rombaut L, Lund H, Engelbert RH. Am J Med Genet C Semin Med Genet. 2017;175:116&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28306223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The revised (Brighton 1998) criteria for the diagnosis of benign joint hypermobility syndrome (BJHS) Grahame R, Bird HA, Child A. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10914867/ J Rheumatol. 2000;27:1777&#x2013;1779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10914867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proprioception and muscle torque deficits in children with hypermobility syndrome. Fatoye F, Palmer S, Macmillan F, Rowe P, van der Linden M. Rheumatology (Oxford) 2009;48:152&#x2013;157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19088133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Examination and treatment of a patient with hypermobility syndrome. Russek LN. Phys Ther. 2000;80:386&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10758523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A simple questionnaire to detect hypermobility: an adjunct to the assessment of patients with diffuse musculoskeletal pain. Hakim AJ, Grahame R. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/12723715/ Int J Clin Pract. 2003;57:163&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12723715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>