<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32130185</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1929-0748</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR research protocols</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Res Protoc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Beating Cancer-Related Fatigue With the Untire Mobile App: Protocol for a Waiting List Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e15969</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e15969</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e15969</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/15969</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Many cancer patients and survivors worldwide experience disabling fatigue as the main side effect of their illness and the treatments involved. Face-to-face therapy is effective in treating cancer-related fatigue (CRF), but it is also resource-intensive. Offering a self-management program via a mobile phone app (ie, the Untire app), based on elements of effective face-to-face treatments, might increase the number of patients receiving adequate support for fatigue and decrease care costs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this protocol is to describe a randomized controlled trial (RCT) to assess the effectiveness of the Untire app in reducing fatigue in cancer patients and survivors after 12 weeks of app use as compared with a waiting list control group. Substudies nested within this trial include questions concerning the reach and costs of online recruitment and uptake and usage of the Untire app.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The Untire app study is a waiting list RCT targeting cancer patients and survivors who experience moderate to severe fatigue via social media (Facebook and Instagram) across 4 English-speaking countries (Australia, Canada, the United Kingdom, and the United States). The Untire app includes psychoeducation and exercises concerning energy conservation, activity management, optimizing restful sleep, mindfulness-based stress reduction, psychosocial support, cognitive behavioral therapy, and physical activity. After randomization, participants in the intervention group could access the Untire app immediately, whereas control participants had no access to the Untire app until the primary follow-up assessment at 12 weeks. Participants completed questionnaires at baseline before randomization and after 4, 8, 12, and 24 weeks. The study outcomes are fatigue (primary) and quality of life (QoL; secondary). Potential moderators and mediators of the hypothesized treatment effect on levels of fatigue and QoL were also assessed. Link clicks and app activation are used to assess reach and uptake, respectively. Log data are used to explore the characteristics of app use. Sample size calculations for the primary outcome showed that we needed to include 164 participants with complete 12-week measures both in the intervention and the control groups. The intention-to-treat approach is used in the primary analyses, which refers to analyzing all participants regardless of their app use.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Participants were recruited from March to October 2018. The last participant completed the 24-week assessment in March 2019.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This mobile health (mHealth) RCT recruited participants online in multiple countries to examine the uptake and effectiveness of the Untire self-management app to reduce CRF. Many advantages of mHealth apps are assumed, such as the immediate access to the app, the low thresholds to seek support, and the absence of contact with care professionals that will reduce costs. If found effective, this app can easily be offered worldwide to patients experiencing CRF.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Netherlands Trial Register NL6642; https://www.trialregister.nl/trial/6642.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERNATIONAL REGISTERED REPORT IDENTIFIER (IRRID)" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">DERR1-10.2196/15969.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Simon S Spahrk&#xe4;s, Anne Looijmans, Robbert Sanderman, Mari&#xeb;t Hagedoorn. Originally published in JMIR Research Protocols (http://www.researchprotocols.org), 14.02.2020.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spahrk&#xe4;s</LastName><ForeName>Simon S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1039-8887</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Psychology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Looijmans</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3333-562X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Psychology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanderman</LastName><ForeName>Robbert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0823-1159</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Psychology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Health &amp; Technology, University of Twente, Enschede, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hagedoorn</LastName><ForeName>Mari&#xeb;t</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3444-3662</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Psychology, University Medical Center Groningen, University of Groningen, Groningen, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Res Protoc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101599504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1929-0748</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RCT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">app</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer patients</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer survivors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatigue</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psycho-oncology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32130185</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7055831</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/15969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v9i2e15969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Siegel RL, Torre LA, Jemal A. Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018 Nov;68(6):394&#x2013;424. doi: 10.3322/caac.21492. doi: 10.3322/caac.21492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30207593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vissers PA, Thong MS, Pouwer F, Zanders MM, Coebergh JW, van de Poll-Franse LV. The impact of comorbidity on Health-Related Quality of Life among cancer survivors: analyses of data from the PROFILES registry. J Cancer Surviv. 2013 Dec;7(4):602&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1007/s11764-013-0299-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-013-0299-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23918453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minton O, Berger A, Barsevick A, Cramp F, Goedendorp M, Mitchell SA, Stone PC. Cancer-related fatigue and its impact on functioning. Cancer. 2013 Jun 1;119(Suppl 11):2124&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1002/cncr.28058. doi: 10.1002/cncr.28058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.28058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23695924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seiler A, Klaas V, Tr&#xf6;ster G, Fagundes CP. eHealth and mHealth interventions in the treatment of fatigued cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychooncology. 2017 Sep;26(9):1239&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1002/pon.4489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28665554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Geest IC, Knoop H, Veth R, Schreuder HW, Bleijenberg G. High fatigue scores before and after surgical treatment of bone and soft tissue tumors. Exp Ther Med. 2013 Jan;5(1):205&#x2013;8. doi: 10.3892/etm.2012.786.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/etm.2012.786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3524230</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23251269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE. Cancer-related fatigue--mechanisms, risk factors, and treatments. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2014 Oct;11(10):597&#x2013;609. doi: 10.1038/nrclinonc.2014.127.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrclinonc.2014.127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4664449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogelzang NJ, Breitbart W, Cella D, Curt GA, Groopman JE, Horning SJ, Itri LM, Johnson DH, Scherr SL, Portenoy RK. Patient, caregiver, and oncologist perceptions of cancer-related fatigue: results of a tripart assessment survey. The Fatigue Coalition. Semin Hematol. 1997 Jul;34(3 Suppl 2):4&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9253778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curt GA. The impact of fatigue on patients with cancer: overview of FATIGUE 1 and 2. Oncologist. 2000;5(Suppl 2):9&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1634/theoncologist.5-suppl_2-9.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1634/theoncologist.5-suppl_2-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10896323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koornstra RH, Peters M, Donofrio S, van den Borne B, de Jong FA. Management of fatigue in patients with cancer -- a practical overview. Cancer Treat Rev. 2014 Jul;40(6):791&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.ctrv.2014.01.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctrv.2014.01.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24576643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goedendorp MM, Gielissen MF, Verhagen CA, Peters ME, Bleijenberg G. Severe fatigue and related factors in cancer patients before the initiation of treatment. Br J Cancer. 2008 Nov 4;99(9):1408&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1038/sj.bjc.6604739. doi: 10.1038/sj.bjc.6604739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.bjc.6604739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2579682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18941462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramp F, Daniel J. Exercise for the management of cancer-related fatigue in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2008 Apr 16;(2):CD006145. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD006145.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006145.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18425939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reif K, de Vries U, Petermann F. [What does really help against cancer-related fatigue? An overview of systematic reviews] Pflege. 2012 Dec;25(6):439&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1024/1012-5302/a000246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1024/1012-5302/a000246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23188754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruggeman-Everts FZ, Wolvers MD, van de Schoot R, Vollenbroek-Hutten MM, van der Lee ML. Effectiveness of two web-based interventions for chronic cancer-related fatigue compared to an active control condition: results of the 'Fitter na kanker' randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2017 Oct 19;19(10):e336. doi: 10.2196/jmir.7180.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.7180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5668634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29051138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett B, Goldstein D, Friedlander M, Hickie I, Lloyd A. The experience of cancer-related fatigue and chronic fatigue syndrome: a qualitative and comparative study. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2007 Aug;34(2):126&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2006.10.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2006.10.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17544246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE, Garet D, Sternlieb B, Ganz PA, Irwin MR, Olmstead R, Greendale G. Yoga for persistent fatigue in breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Cancer. 2012 Aug 1;118(15):3766&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1002/cncr.26702. doi: 10.1002/cncr.26702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.26702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3601551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22180393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tate EB, Spruijt-Metz D, O'Reilly G, Jordan-Marsh M, Gotsis M, Pentz MA, Dunton GF. mHealth approaches to child obesity prevention: successes, unique challenges, and next directions. Transl Behav Med. 2013 Dec;3(4):406&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1007/s13142-013-0222-3.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13142-013-0222-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3830013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24294329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray E, Khadjesari Z, White IR, Kalaitzaki E, Godfrey C, McCambridge J, Thompson SG, Wallace P. Methodological challenges in online trials. J Med Internet Res. 2009 Apr 3;11(2):e9. doi: 10.2196/jmir.1052.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762798</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Comprehensive Cancer Network.  [2019-07-19].  NCCN Clinical Practice Guidelines in Oncology https://www.nccn.org/professionals/physician_gls/default.aspx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lengacher CA, Reich RR, Ramesar S, Alinat CB, Moscoso M, Cousin L, Marino VR, Elias MN, Paterson CL, Pleasant ML, Rodriguez CS, Wang H, Kip KE, Meng H, Park JY. Feasibility of the mobile mindfulness-based stress reduction for breast cancer (mMBSR(BC)) program for symptom improvement among breast cancer survivors. Psychooncology. 2018 Feb;27(2):524&#x2013;31. doi: 10.1002/pon.4491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7771353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28665541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hann D, Jacobsen P, Azzarello L, Martin S, Curran S, Fields K, Greenberg H, Lyman G. Measurement of fatigue in cancer patients: development and validation of the fatigue symptom inventory. Qual Life Res. 1998 May;7(4):301&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1023/a:1024929829627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/a:1024929829627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9610214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hann DM, Denniston MM, Baker F. Measurement of fatigue in cancer patients: further validation of the Fatigue Symptom Inventory. Qual Life Res. 2000;9(7):847&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1023/a:1008900413113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/a:1008900413113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11297027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vink M, Vink-Niese A. Graded exercise therapy for myalgic encephalomyelitis/chronic fatigue syndrome is not effective and unsafe. Re-analysis of a Cochrane review. Health Psychol Open. 2018;5(2):2055102918805187. doi: 10.1177/2055102918805187.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2055102918805187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6176540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30305916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JE, Crosswell AD, Stanton AL, Crespi CM, Winston D, Arevalo J, Ma J, Cole SW, Ganz PA. Mindfulness meditation for younger breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Cancer. 2015 Apr 15;121(8):1231&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1002/cncr.29194. doi: 10.1002/cncr.29194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.29194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4393338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25537522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell SA, Hoffman AJ, Clark JC, DeGennaro RM, Poirier P, Robinson CB, Weisbrod BL. Putting evidence into practice: an update of evidence-based interventions for cancer-related fatigue during and following treatment. Clin J Oncol Nurs. 2014;(18 Suppl):38&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1188/14.CJON.S3.38-58.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1188/14.CJON.S3.38-58</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25427608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Lee ML, Garssen B. Mindfulness-based cognitive therapy reduces chronic cancer-related fatigue: a treatment study. Psychooncology. 2012 Mar;21(3):264&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1002/pon.1890.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.1890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22383268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikolasek M, Berg J, Witt CM, Barth J. Effectiveness of mindfulness- and relaxation-based eHealth interventions for patients with medical conditions: a systematic review and synthesis. Int J Behav Med. 2018 Feb;25(1):1&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1007/s12529-017-9679-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12529-017-9679-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28752414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrer BC, van Roekel E, Lynch BM. The role of physical activity in managing fatigue in cancer survivors. Curr Nutr Rep. 2018 Sep;7(3):59&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1007/s13668-018-0234-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13668-018-0234-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30094747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aaronson NK, Ahmedzai S, Bergman B, Bullinger M, Cull A, Duez NJ, Filiberti A, Flechtner H, Fleishman SB, de Haes JC. The European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer QLQ-C30: a quality-of-life instrument for use in international clinical trials in oncology. J Natl Cancer Inst. 1993 Mar 3;85(5):365&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1093/jnci/85.5.365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/85.5.365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8433390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown K, Ryan R. The benefits of being present: mindfulness and its role in psychological well-being. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2003 Apr;84(4):822&#x2013;48. doi: 10.1037/0022-3514.84.4.822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.84.4.822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12703651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Yount S, Rothrock N, Gershon R, Cook K, Reeve B, Ader D, Fries J, Bruce B, Rose M, PROMIS Cooperative Group  The Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS): progress of an NIH Roadmap cooperative group during its first two years. Med Care. 2007 May;45(5 Suppl 1):S3&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1097/01.mlr.0000258615.42478.55.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.mlr.0000258615.42478.55</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2829758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17443116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derogatis L, Lipman R, Covi L. SCL-90: an outpatient psychiatric rating scale--preliminary report. Psychopharmacol Bull. 1973 Jan;9(1):13&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4682398</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan MJ, Bishop SR, Pivik J. The pain catastrophizing scale: development and validation. Psychol Assess. 1995;7(4):524&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1037/1040-3590.7.4.524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1040-3590.7.4.524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brook RH, Ware JE, Davies-Avery A, Stewart AL, Donald CA, Rogers WH, Williams KN, Johnston SA. Overview of adult health measures fielded in Rand's health insurance study. Med Care. 1979 Jul;17(7 Suppl):iii-x&#x2013;1-131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">459579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anguera J, Jordan J, Castaneda D, Gazzaley A, Are&#xe1;n PA. Conducting a fully mobile and randomised clinical trial for depression: access, engagement and expense. BMJ Innov. 2016 Jan;2(1):14&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1136/bmjinnov-2015-000098.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjinnov-2015-000098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4789688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27019745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bricker JB, Copeland W, Mull KE, Zeng EY, Watson NL, Akioka KJ, Heffner JL. Single-arm trial of the second version of an acceptance &amp; commitment therapy smartphone application for smoking cessation. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2017 Jan 1;170:37&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2016.10.029.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2016.10.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5183543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27870987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howells A, Ivtzan I, Eiroa-Orosa FJ. Putting the &#x2018;app&#x2019; in happiness: a randomised controlled trial of a smartphone-based mindfulness intervention to enhance wellbeing. J Happiness Stud. 2016 Feb;17(1):163&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1007/s10902-014-9589-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10902-014-9589-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irvine AB, Russell H, Manocchia M, Mino DE, Glassen TC, Morgan R, Gau JM, Birney AJ, Ary DV. Mobile-Web app to self-manage low back pain: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2015 Jan 2;17(1):e1. doi: 10.2196/jmir.3130.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4296097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25565416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laing BY, Mangione CM, Tseng C, Leng M, Vaisberg E, Mahida M, Bholat M, Glazier E, Morisky DE, Bell DS. Effectiveness of a smartphone application for weight loss compared with usual care in overweight primary care patients: a randomized, controlled trial. Ann Intern Med. 2014 Nov 18;161(10 Suppl):S5&#x2013;12. doi: 10.7326/M13-3005.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M13-3005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4422872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25402403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naimark JS, Madar Z, Shahar D. The impact of a web-based app (eBalance) in promoting healthy lifestyles: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2015 Mar 2;17(3):e56. doi: 10.2196/jmir.3682.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4376125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25732936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuiper AJ, Wolvers MD, Vonk D, Hagenbeek A. Untire: an all-embracing self-management eHealth program to cope with cancer-related fatigue. Ecancermedicalscience. 2018;12:ed81. doi: 10.3332/ecancer.2018.ed81.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3332/ecancer.2018.ed81</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5880226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29662537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller F, Stephenson E, DeLongis A, Smink A, van Ginkel RJ, Tuinman M, Hagedoorn M. The reciprocal relationship between daily fatigue and catastrophizing following cancer treatment: affect and physical activity as potential mediators. Psychooncology. 2018 Mar;27(3):831&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1002/pon.4574.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4574</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29076568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G. The law of attrition. J Med Internet Res. 2005 Mar 31;7(1):e11. doi: 10.2196/jmir.7.1.e11.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.7.1.e11</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1550631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15829473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham JA, Kypri K, McCambridge J. Exploratory randomized controlled trial evaluating the impact of a waiting list control design. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2013 Dec 6;13:150. doi: 10.1186/1471-2288-13-150.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-13-150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4029562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24314204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>