<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">30044246</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2329-9185</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JBJS reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JBJS Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Update on the Management of Sacral Metastases.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e8</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2106/JBJS.RVW.17.00130</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mika</LastName><ForeName>Aleksander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Rochester School of Medicine and Dentistry, Rochester, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mesfin</LastName><ForeName>Addisu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0076-4185</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JBJS Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101674872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2329-9185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001859" MajorTopicYN="N">Bone Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000556" MajorTopicYN="Y">secondary</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073116" MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer Survivors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077684" MajorTopicYN="N">Cauda Equina Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019299" MajorTopicYN="N">Decompression, Surgical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071066" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Reported Outcome Measures</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011843" MajorTopicYN="N">Radiculopathy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011878" MajorTopicYN="N">Radiotherapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012447" MajorTopicYN="N">Sacrum</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="Y">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30044246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.RVW.17.00130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01874474-201807000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>National Cancer Institute. Cancer stat facts: cancer of any site. https://seer.cancer.gov/statfacts/html/all.html. Accessed 2018 Mar 6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nader R, Rhines LD, Mendel E. Metastatic sacral tumors. Neurosurg Clin N Am. 2004 Oct;15(4):453-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kollender Y, Meller I, Bickels J, Flusser G, Issakov J, Merimsky O, Marouani N, Nirkin A, Weinbroum AA. Role of adjuvant cryosurgery in intralesional treatment of sacral tumors. Cancer. 2003 Jun 1;97(11):2830-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batson OV. The function of the vertebral veins and their role in the spread of metastases. 1940. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1995 Mar;312:4-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundermeyer ML, Meropol NJ, Rogatko A, Wang H, Cohen SJ. Changing patterns of bone and brain metastases in patients with colorectal cancer. Clin Colorectal Cancer. 2005 Jul;5(2):108-13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santini D, Tampellini M, Vincenzi B, Ibrahim T, Ortega C, Virzi V, Silvestris N, Berardi R, Masini C, Calipari N, Ottaviani D, Catalano V, Badalamenti G, Giannicola R, Fabbri F, Venditti O, Fratto ME, Mazzara C, Latiano TP, Bertolini F, Petrelli F, Ottone A, Caroti C, Salvatore L, Falcone A, Giordani P, Addeo R, Aglietta M, Cascinu S, Barni S, Maiello E, Tonini G. Natural history of bone metastasis in colorectal cancer: final results of a large Italian bone metastases study. Ann Oncol. 2012 Aug;23(8):2072-7. Epub 2012 Jan 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldenzer JA, McGauley JL, McGillicuddy JE. Sacral and presacral tumors: problems in diagnosis and management. Neurosurgery. 1989 Dec;25(6):884-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finiels H, Finiels PJ, Jacquot JM, Strubel D. [Fractures of the sacrum caused by bone insufficiency. Meta-analysis of 508 cases]. Presse Med. 1997 Nov 1;26(33):1568-73. French.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kortman K, Ortiz O, Miller T, Brook A, Tutton S, Mathis J, Georgy B. Multicenter study to assess the efficacy and safety of sacroplasty in patients with osteoporotic sacral insufficiency fractures or pathologic sacral lesions. J Neurointerv Surg. 2013 Sep 1;5(5):461-6. Epub 2012 Jun 8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wuisman P, Lieshout O, Sugihara S, van Dijk M. Total sacrectomy and reconstruction: oncologic and functional outcome. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2000 Dec;381:192-203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozdemir MH, G&#xfc;rkan I, Yildiz Y, Yilmaz C, Saglik Y. Surgical treatment of malignant tumours of the sacrum. Eur J Surg Oncol. 1999 Feb;25(1):44-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quraishi NA, Giannoulis KE, Edwards KL, Boszczyk BM. Management of metastatic sacral tumours. Eur Spine J. 2012 Oct;21(10):1984-93. Epub 2012 Jun 23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miralbell R, Louis DN, O&#x2019;Keeffe D, Rosenberg AE, Suit HD. Metastatic ependymoma of the sacrum. Cancer. 1990 May 15;65(10):2353-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musahl V, Rihn JA, Fumich FE, Kang JD. Sacral intraspinal extradural primitive neuroectodermal tumor. Spine J. 2008 Nov-Dec;8(6):1024-9. Epub 2007 Jun 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorosa JK, Weintraub S, Amorosa LF, Safer JN, Rafii M. Sacral destruction: foraminal lines revisited. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 1985 Oct;145(4):773-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta AC, Chandra RV, Yoo AJ, Leslie-Mazwi TM, Bell DL, Mehta BP, Vanderboom TL, Rabinov JD, Larvie M, Hirsch JA. Safety and effectiveness of sacroplasty: a large single-center experience. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2014 Nov-Dec;35(11):2202-6. Epub 2014 Jul 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerber S, Ollivier L, Lecl&#xe8;re J, Vanel D, Missenard G, Brisse H, de Pinieux G, Neuenschwander S. Imaging of sacral tumours. Skeletal Radiol. 2008 Apr;37(4):277-89. Epub 2007 Nov 23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasir N, Aquilina K, Ryder DQ, Marks CJ, Keohane C. Garr&#xe9;&#x2019;s chronic diffuse sclerosing osteomyelitis of the sacrum: a rare condition mimicking malignancy. Br J Neurosurg. 2006 Dec;20(6):415-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbs IC, Chang SD. Radiosurgery and radiotherapy for sacral tumors. Neurosurg Focus. 2003 Aug 15;15(2):E8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClelland S 3rd, Kim E, Passias PG, Murphy JD, Attia A, Jaboin JJ. Spinal stereotactic body radiotherapy in the United States: a decade-long nationwide analysis of patient demographics, practice patterns, and trends over time. J Clin Neurosci. 2017 Dec;46:109-12. Epub 2017 Aug 31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed KA, Stauder MC, Miller RC, Bauer HJ, Rose PS, Olivier KR, Brown PD, Brinkmann DH, Laack NN. Stereotactic body radiation therapy in spinal metastases. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2012 Apr 1;82(5):e803-9. Epub 2012 Feb 11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerszten PC, Burton SA, Ozhasoglu C, Welch WC. Radiosurgery for spinal metastases: clinical experience in 500 cases from a single institution. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2007 Jan 15;32(2):193-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witham TF, Khavkin YA, Gallia GL, Wolinsky JP, Gokaslan ZL. Surgery insight: current management of epidural spinal cord compression from metastatic spine disease. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2006 Feb;2(2):87-94; quiz 116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feiz-Erfan I, Fox BD, Nader R, Suki D, Chakrabarti I, Mendel E, Gokaslan ZL, Rao G, Rhines LD. Surgical treatment of sacral metastases: indications and results. J Neurosurg Spine. 2012 Oct;17(4):285-91. Epub 2012 Aug 17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tokuhashi Y, Matsuzaki H, Oda H, Oshima M, Ryu J. A revised scoring system for preoperative evaluation of metastatic spine tumor prognosis. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2005 Oct 1;30(19):2186-91.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawahara N, Tomita K, Murakami H, Demura S. Total en bloc spondylectomy for spinal tumors: surgical techniques and related basic background. Orthop Clin North Am. 2009 Jan;40(1):47-63, vi.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Z, Guo W, Yang R, Tang X, Ji T, Li D. What is the value of surgical intervention for sacral metastases? PLoS One. 2016 Dec 19;11(12):e0168313.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fourney DR, Frangou EM, Ryken TC, Dipaola CP, Shaffrey CI, Berven SH, Bilsky MH, Harrop JS, Fehlings MG, Boriani S, Chou D, Schmidt MH, Polly DW, Biagini R, Burch S, Dekutoski MB, Ganju A, Gerszten PC, Gokaslan ZL, Groff MW, Liebsch NJ, Mendel E, Okuno SH, Patel S, Rhines LD, Rose PS, Sciubba DM, Sundaresan N, Tomita K, Varga PP, Vialle LR, Vrionis FD, Yamada Y, Fisher CG. Spinal Instability Neoplastic Score: an analysis of reliability and validity from the Spine Oncology Study Group. J Clin Oncol. 2011 Aug 1;29(22):3072-7. Epub 2011 Jun 27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Facchini G, Di Tullio P, Battaglia M, Bartalena T, Tetta C, Errani C, Mavrogenis AF, Rossi G. Palliative embolization for metastases of the spine. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol. 2016 Apr;26(3):247-52. Epub 2015 Dec 14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair S, Gobin YP, Leng LZ, Marcus JD, Bilsky M, Laufer I, Patsalides A. Preoperative embolization of hypervascular thoracic, lumbar, and sacral spinal column tumors: technique and outcomes from a single center. Interv Neuroradiol. 2013 Sep;19(3):377-85. Epub 2013 Sep 26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang X, Guo W, Yang R, Tang S, Dong S. Use of aortic balloon occlusion to decrease blood loss during sacral tumor resection. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2010 Jul 21;92(8):1747-53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masala S, Konda D, Massari F, Simonetti G. Sacroplasty and iliac osteoplasty under combined CT and fluoroscopic guidance. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2006 Aug 15;31(18):E667-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho CH, Mathis JM, Ortiz O. Sacral fractures and sacroplasty. Neuroimaging Clin N Am. 2010 May;20(2):179-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirsch JA, Barr JD, Zoarski GH. Sacroplasty: beyond the beginning. J Neurointerv Surg. 2013 Sep 1;5(5):395. Epub 2012 Jun 29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayaraman MV, Chang H, Ahn SH. An easily identifiable anatomic landmark for fluoroscopically guided sacroplasty: anatomic description and validation with treatment in 13 patients. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2009 May;30(5):1070-3. Epub 2009 Feb 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Wu CG, Gu YF, Li MH. Percutaneous sacroplasty for sacral metastatic tumors under fluoroscopic guidance only. Korean J Radiol. 2008 Nov-Dec;9(6):572-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho S, Park HS, Kim DY, Kim CH, Chung RK, Kim YJ. Percutaneous sacroplasty under fluoroscopic guidance combined with epidurogram for sacral insufficiency fracture resulting from metastatic tumor and osteoporosis. Pain Physician. 2016 Mar;19(3):E473-80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarawal JP, Swangsilpa T, van der Linden Y, Rades D, Jeremic B, Hoskin PJ. The role of external beam radiotherapy in the management of bone metastases. Clin Oncol (R Coll Radiol). 2006 Dec;18(10):747-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blomlie V, Rofstad EK, Talle K, Sundf&#xf8;r K, Winderen M, Lien HH. Incidence of radiation-induced insufficiency fractures of the female pelvis: evaluation with MR imaging. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 1996 Nov;167(5):1205-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madaelil TP, Wallace AN, Jennings JW. Radiofrequency ablation alone or in combination with cementoplasty for local control and pain palliation of sacral metastases: preliminary results in 11 patients. Skeletal Radiol. 2016 Sep;45(9):1213-9. Epub 2016 May 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moussazadeh N, Laufer I, Werner T, Krol G, Boland P, Bilsky MH, Lis E. Sacroplasty for cancer-associated insufficiency fractures. Neurosurgery. 2015 Apr;76(4):446-50; discussion 450.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andresen R, Radmer S, L&#xfc;dtke CW, Kamusella P, Wissgott C, Schober HC. Balloon sacroplasty as a palliative pain treatment in patients with metastasis-induced bone destruction and pathological fractures. Rofo. 2014 Sep;186(9):881-6. Epub 2014 Feb 20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber SM, Livingston AD, Cech DA. Sacral radiculopathy due to cement leakage from percutaneous sacroplasty, successfully treated with surgical decompression. J Neurosurg Spine. 2013 May;18(5):524-8. Epub 2013 Mar 22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace AN, Greenwood TJ, Jennings JW. Use of imaging in the management of metastatic spine disease with percutaneous ablation and vertebral augmentation. AJR Am J Roentgenol. 2015 Aug;205(2):434-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetz MP, Callstrom MR, Charboneau JW, Farrell MA, Maus TP, Welch TJ, Wong GY, Sloan JA, Novotny PJ, Petersen IA, Beres RA, Regge D, Capanna R, Saker MB, Gr&#xf6;nemeyer DH, Gevargez A, Ahrar K, Choti MA, de Baere TJ, Rubin J. Percutaneous image-guided radiofrequency ablation of painful metastases involving bone: a multicenter study. J Clin Oncol. 2004 Jan 15;22(2):300-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buraimoh MA, Yu CC, Mott MP, Graziano GP. Sacroiliac stabilization for sacral metastasis: a case series. Surg Neurol Int. 2017 Dec 6;8:287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi MK, Jo DJ, Kim SB. Pelvic reconstruction surgery using a dual-rod technique with diverse U-shaped rods after posterior en bloc partial sacrectomy for a sacral tumor: 2 case reports and a literature review. World Neurosurg. 2016 Nov;95:619.e11-8. Epub 2016 Aug 17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolan RT, Butler JS, Wilson-MacDonald J, Reynolds J, Cogswell L, Critchley P, Giele H. Quality of life and surgical outcomes after soft-tissue reconstruction of complex oncologic defects of the spine and sacrum. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2016 Jan 20;98(2):117-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesfin A, Sciubba DM, Dea N, Nater A, Bird JE, Quraishi NA, Fisher CG, Shin JH, Fehlings MG, Kumar N, Clarke MJ. Changing the adverse event profile in metastatic spine surgery: an evidence-based approach to target wound complications and instrumentation failure. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2016 Oct 15;41(Suppl 20):S262-70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okafor R, Molinari W, Molinari R, Mesfin A. Intrawound vancomycin powder for spine tumor surgery. Global Spine J. 2016 May;6(3):207-11. Epub 2015 Jul 16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Street J, Berven S, Fisher C, Ryken T. Health related quality of life assessment in metastatic disease of the spine: a systematic review. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2009 Oct 15;34(22)(Suppl):S128-34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Street J, Lenehan B, Berven S, Fisher C. Introducing a new health-related quality of life outcome tool for metastatic disease of the spine: content validation using the International Classification of Functioning, Disability, and Health; on behalf of the Spine Oncology Study Group. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2010 Jun 15;35(14):1377-86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paulino Pereira NR, Janssen SJ, Raskin KA, Hornicek FJ, Ferrone ML, Shin JH, Bramer JAM, van Dijk CN, Schwab JH. Most efficient questionnaires to measure quality of life, physical function, and pain in patients with metastatic spine disease: a cross-sectional prospective survey study. Spine J. 2017 Jul;17(7):953-61. Epub 2017 Feb 24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Wulfften Palthe ODR, Janssen SJ, Wunder JS, Ferguson PC, Wei G, Rose PS, Yaszemski MJ, Sim FH, Boland PJ, Healey JH, Hornicek FJ, Schwab JH. What questionnaires to use when measuring quality of life in sacral tumor patients: the updated Sacral Tumor Survey. Spine J. 2017 May;17(5):636-44. Epub 2016 Nov 14.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>