<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39287781</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8237</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pain and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pain Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Real-World Evidence of the Safety and Effectiveness of Atogepant Added to OnabotulinumtoxinA for the Preventive Treatment of Chronic Migraine: A Retrospective Chart Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1571</StartPage><EndPage>1587</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1571-1587</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40122-024-00649-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Combination use of atogepant and onabotulinumtoxinA has the potential to be more effective than either alone for the preventive treatment of chronic migraine (CM) due to their complementary mechanisms of action. This analysis collected real-world data to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and effectiveness of adding atogepant to onabotulinumtoxinA as a combination preventive treatment for CM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective, longitudinal, multicenter chart review included adults with CM who received&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;2 consecutive cycles of onabotulinumtoxinA before&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;1&#xa0;month of onabotulinumtoxinA and atogepant combination treatment. Charts at atogepant prescription (index date) and two subsequent onabotulinumtoxinA treatment visits (~&#x2009;3 and&#x2009;~&#x2009;6 months post-index) were reviewed for change from baseline in monthly headache days (MHDs),&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;50% reduction in MHDs, discontinuation rates, and adverse events (AEs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 55 charts that met safety analysis criteria, 31 had data on headache days at index and first post-index visit and were eligible for effectiveness analysis (mean age 46.7&#xa0;years, 94.5% female). For those with data available prior to onabotulinumtoxinA treatment (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;25), the mean MHD was 24.0 days, reduced by 8.15 days after onabotulinumtoxinA treatment. After atogepant was added, MHD was incrementally reduced by 4.53 days and 8.75 days from index date to the first (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;31) and second (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;23) post-index onabotulinumtoxinA treatment visit, respectively. A&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;50% reduction in MHDs was achieved by 45.2% of patients&#x2009;~&#x2009;3&#xa0;months post-index. Atogepant and onabotulinumtoxinA were discontinued by 16.1% and 6.5% of patients, respectively. In the safety population, 32.7% of patients experienced&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;1 AE. No serious AEs were reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This real-world study of patients with CM demonstrated that adding atogepant to onabotulinumtoxinA as a combination preventive treatment for CM was effective by providing an additional reduction in MHDs over&#x2009;~&#x2009;3 and&#x2009;~&#x2009;6&#xa0;months of combination treatment. Safety results were consistent with the known safety profiles of onabotulinumtoxinA and atogepant, with no new safety signals identified.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blumenfeld</LastName><ForeName>Andrew M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Los Angeles Headache Center, Los Angeles, CA, USA. ablumenfeldmd@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The San Diego Headache Center, San Diego, CA, USA. ablumenfeldmd@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mechtler</LastName><ForeName>Laszlo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dent Neurologic Institute, Buffalo, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cook</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Los Angeles Headache Center, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rhyne</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Norton Neuroscience Institute, Louisville, KY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jenkins</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuroscience Group, Neenah, WI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hughes</LastName><ForeName>Olivia</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ICON Plc, Blue Bell, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dabruzzo</LastName><ForeName>Brett</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie, North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manack Adams</LastName><ForeName>Aubrey</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie, North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Diamond</LastName><ForeName>Merle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diamond Headache Clinic, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Pain Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101634491</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Pain Ther. 2025 Feb;14(1):441-444. doi: 10.1007/s40122-024-00692-5.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">39718742</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atogepant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic migraine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Combination treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gepant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OnabotulinumtoxinA</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Andrew M. Blumenfeld has served on advisory boards Allergan, Aeon, Alder, Amgen, Biohaven, Lilly, Lundbeck, Novartis, Pfizer, Revance, Teva, Theranica, Tonix. AB has been a speaker for Allergan/AbbVie, Lilly, Lundbeck, Teva, Theranica. AB has consulted for Aeon, Allergan/AbbVie, Alder, Amgen, Biohaven, Lilly, Lundbeck, Pfizer, Novartis, Teva, Theranica, Tonix. AB has received grand support from Aeon, Allergan/AbbVie, Amgen, Lundbeck, Revance. AB has been a contributing author for Aeon, Allergan/AbbVie, Amgen, Biohaven, Lilly, Lundbeck, Novartis, Teva, Theranica. AB has received stock options from Haven Health Inc. and Aeon. Andrew Blumenfeld is an Editorial Board member of <i>Pain and Therapy</i>. He was not involved in the selection of peer reviewers for the manuscript nor any of the subsequent editorial decisions. Laszlo Mechtler has served on advisory boards for, consulted for, and/or been a speaker for, Amgen, Novartis, Allergan/AbbVie, Eli Lilly, Teva, Biohaven, Lundbeck, The institution of Dr. Mechtler has received research support from The Harry Dent Family Foundation, Inc., Amgen/ Novartis, Alder/ Lundbeck, AbbVie/ Allergan, Miles for Migraine, and American Migraine Foundation. Lisa Cook has served on advisory boards for, consulted for and/or been a speaker for AbbVie/Allergan, Impel, Biohaven and Teva. Christopher Rhyne has served on advisory boards for, consulted for, and/or been a speaker for AbbVie/Allergan, Amgen, Biohaven, Diamond Headache Clinic Research and Education Foundation, Lilly, Lundbeck, National Headache Foundation, Teva, and Theranica. Brian Jenkins has served on advisory boards for, consulted for, and/or been a speaker for Amgen, Novartis, Allergan/AbbVie, Eli Lilly, Teva, Biohaven, Lundbeck, Relivion. Brian Jenkins has received stock or an ownership interest from Prevacus and NeoCorTechs. Merle Diamond has served on advisory boards for, consulted for, served as an editor for, and/or been a speaker or contributing author for Allergan/AbbVie, Amgen, Assertio, Axsome Pharma, Eli Lilly, Impel NeuroPharma, Lundbeck, Promius Pharma, Supernus, Upsher-Smith, Teva. An immediate family member of Merle Diamond has received compensation for serving on a Scientific Advisory or Data Safety Monitoring board for Supernus and Teva. Olivia Hughes is an employee of ICON plc. Aubrey Manack&#xa0;Adams and Brett Dabruzzo are employees of AbbVie and may hold AbbVie stock.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39287781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11543951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40122-024-00649-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40122-024-00649-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Headache Classification Committee of the International Headache Society (IHS) The international classification of headache disorders, 3rd edition. Cephalalgia. 2018;38(1):1&#x2013;211. 10.1177/0333102417738202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102417738202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29368949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buse DC, Fanning KM, Reed ML, et al. Life with migraine: effects on relationships, career, and finances from the Chronic Migraine Epidemiology and Outcomes (CaMEO) Study. Headache. 2019;59(8):1286&#x2013;99. 10.1111/head.13613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.13613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6771487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31407321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lant&#xe9;ri-Minet M, Duru G, Mudge M, Cottrell S. Quality of life impairment, disability and economic burden associated with chronic daily headache, focusing on chronic migraine with or without medication overuse: A systematic review. Cephalalgia. 2010;31:837&#x2013;50. 10.1177/0333102411398400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102411398400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21464078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ailani J, Burch RC, Robbins MS, Board of Directors of the American Headache Society. The American Headache Society Consensus Statement: update on integrating new migraine treatments into clinical practice. Headache. 2021;61(7):1021&#x2013;39. 10.1111/head.14153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.14153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34160823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenfeld AM, Lipton RB, Silberstein S, et al. Multimodal migraine management and the pursuit of migraine freedom: a narrative review. Neurol Ther. 2023;12:1533&#x2013;51. 10.1007/s40120-023-00529-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-023-00529-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10444724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37542624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aurora SK, Dodick DW, Turkel CC, et al. OnabotulinumtoxinA for treatment of chronic migraine: Results from the double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled phase of the PREEMPT 1 trial. Cephalalgia. 2010;30:793&#x2013;803. 10.1177/0333102410364676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102410364676</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20647170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenfeld AM, Stark RJ, Freeman MC, Orejudos A, Adams AM. Long-term study of the efficacy and safety of onabotulinumtoxinA for the prevention of chronic migraine: COMPEL study. J Headache Pain. 2018;19:13. 10.1186/s10194-018-0840-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10194-018-0840-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5799088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29404713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diener HC, Dodick DW, Aurora SK, et al. OnabotulinumtoxinA for treatment of chronic migraine: Results from the double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled phase of the PREEMPT 2 trial. Cephalalgia. 2010;30:804&#x2013;14. 10.1177/0333102410364677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102410364677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20647171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed F, Gaul C, Garc&#xed;a-Monc&#xf3; JC, Sommer K, Martelletti P. An open-label prospective study of the real-life use of onabotulinumtoxinA for the treatment of chronic migraine: the REPOSE study. J Headache Pain. 2019;20:26. 10.1186/s10194-019-0976-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10194-019-0976-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6734221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30845917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothrock JF, Adams AM, Lipton RB, Silberstein SD, Jo E, Zhao X, et al. FORWARD study: evaluating the comparative effectiveness of onabotulinumtoxinA and topiramate for headache prevention in adults with chronic migraine. Headache. 2019;59:1700&#x2013;13. 10.1111/head.13653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.13653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6899480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31559634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burstein R, Blumenfeld AM, Silberstein SD, Adams AM, Brin MF. Mechanism of action of onabotulinumtoxinA in chronic migraine: a narrative review. Headache. 2020;60:1259&#x2013;72. 10.1111/head.13849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.13849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7496564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32602955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aurora SK, Brin MF. Chronic migraine: an update on physiology, imaging, and the mechanism of action of two available pharmacologic therapies. Headache. 2017;57:109&#x2013;25. 10.1111/head.12999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.12999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27910097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burstein R, Zhang X, Levy D, Aoki KR, Brin MF. Selective inhibition of meningeal nociceptors by botulinum neurotoxin type A: therapeutic implications for migraine and other pains. Cephalalgia. 2014;34:853&#x2013;69. 10.1177/0333102414527648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102414527648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4167963</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24694964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ailani J, Blumenfeld AM. Combination CGRP monoclonal antibody and onabotulinumtoxinA treatment for preventive treatment in chronic migraine. Headache. 2022;62:106&#x2013;8. 10.1111/head.14244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/head.14244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9300070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34877663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arulmani U, Maassenvandenbrink A, Villal&#xf3;n CM, Saxena PR. Calcitonin gene-related peptide and its role in migraine pathophysiology. Eur J Pharmacol. 2004;500:315&#x2013;30. 10.1016/j.ejphar.2004.07.035.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejphar.2004.07.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15464043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goadsby PJ, Holland PR, Martins-Oliveira M, Hoffmann J, Schankin C, Akerman S. Pathophysiology of migraine: a disorder of sensory processing. Physiol Rev. 2017;97:553&#x2013;622. 10.1152/physrev.00034.2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00034.2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28179394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blumenfeld AM, Frishberg BM, Schim JD, et al. Real-world evidence for control of chronic migraine patients receiving CGRP monoclonal antibody therapy added to onabotulinumtoxinA: a retrospective chart review. Pain Ther. 2021;10:809&#x2013;26. 10.1007/s40122-021-00264-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40122-021-00264-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33880725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechtler L, Saikali N, McVige J, Hughes O, Traut A, Adams AM. Real-world evidence for the safety and efficacy of CGRP monoclonal antibody therapy added to onabotulinumtoxinA treatment for migraine prevention in adult patients with chronic migraine. Front Neurol. 2022;12: 788159. 10.3389/fneur.2021.788159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2021.788159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8770868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35069416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armanious M, Khalil N, Lu Y, Jimenez-Sanders R. Erenumab and onabotulinumtoxinA combination therapy for the prevention of intractable chronic migraine without aura: a retrospective analysis. J Pain Palliat Care Pharmacother. 2021;35:1&#x2013;6. 10.1080/15360288.2020.1829249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15360288.2020.1829249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33125303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen F, Armand C, Lipton RB, Vollbracht S. Efficacy and tolerability of calcitonin gene&#x2013;related peptide&#x2013;targeted monoclonal antibody medications as add-on therapy to onabotulinumtoxinA in patients with chronic migraine. Pain Med. 2021;22:1857&#x2013;63. 10.1093/pm/pnab093.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pm/pnab093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33693863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozudogru SN, Bartell JW, Yuan H, Digre KB, Baggaley SK. The effect of adding calcitonin gene-related peptide monoclonal antibodies to onabotulinum toxin A therapy on headache burden: a retrospective observational case series. Headache. 2020;60:1442&#x2013;3. 10.21203/rs.2.22760/v1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21203/rs.2.22760/v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boudreau GP. Treatment of chronic migraine with erenumab alone or as an add on therapy: a real-world observational study. Anesth Pain Res. 2020;4:1&#x2013;4. 10.33425/2639-846X.1037.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.33425/2639-846X.1037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuan H, Cohen F, Driessen MT, et al. Real-world effectiveness of add-on fremanezumab in patients receiving onabotulinumtoxinA for the prevention of chronic migraine in a US tertiary headache center: a retrospective chart review study. Cephalalgia Rep. 2024. 10.1177/25158163241238448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/25158163241238448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scuteri D, Tonin P, Nicotera P, et al. Pooled analysis of real-world evidence supports anti-CGRP mabs and onabotulinumtoxinA combined trial in chronic migraine. Toxins. 2022;14:529. 10.3390/toxins14080529.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/toxins14080529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9413678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36006191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams AM, Hutchinson S, Engstrom E, et al. Real-world effectiveness, satisfaction, and optimization of ubrogepant for the acute treatment of migraine in combination with onabotulinumtoxinA: results from the COURAGE Study. J Headache Pain. 2023;24:102. 10.1186/s10194-023-01622-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s10194-023-01622-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10399003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37537578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>QULIPTA [atogepant]. Package Insert. AbbVie Inc.: 2023. Available at: https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2021/215206Orig1s000lbl.pdf. Accessed 15 Apr 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strassman AM, Melo-Carrillo A, Houle TT, Adams A, Brin MF, Burstein R. Atogepant &#x2013; an orally-administered CGRP antagonist &#x2013; attenuates activation of meningeal nociceptors by CSD. Cephalalgia. 2022;42:933&#x2013;43. 10.1177/03331024221083544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/03331024221083544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9329220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35332801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melo-Carrillo A, Strassman AM, Schain AJ, Adams AM, Brin MF, Burstein R. Combined onabotulinumtoxinA/atogepant treatment blocks activation/sensitization of high-threshold and wide-dynamic range neurons. Cephalalgia. 2020;41:17&#x2013;32. 10.1177/0333102420970507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0333102420970507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33200944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ailani J, Lipton RB, Goadsby PJ, et al. Atogepant for the preventive treatment of migraine. New Engl J Med. 2021;385(8):695&#x2013;706. 10.1056/nejmoa2035908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejmoa2035908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34407343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodick DW, Turkel CC, DeGryse RE, et al. OnabotulinumtoxinA for treatment of chronic migraine: pooled results from the double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled phases of the PREEMPT clinical program. Headache. 2010;50:921&#x2013;36. 10.1111/j.1526-4610.2010.01678.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1526-4610.2010.01678.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20487038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>