<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">26597802</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2016</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1476-5543</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>35 Suppl 1</Volume><Issue>Suppl 1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of perinatology : official journal of the California Perinatal Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Perinatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>NICU discharge planning and beyond: recommendations for parent psychosocial support.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>S24</StartPage><EndPage>S28</EndPage><MedlinePgn>S24-8</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/jp.2015.146</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Parents will interact with a multitude of teams from various disciplines during their child's admission to the neonatal intensive care unit. Recognition of the emotional stressors experienced by these parents is a first step in working to provide the crucial support and parenting skills needed for bonding and caring for their infant from admission through discharge and beyond. Family-centered care involves time-sensitive two-way communication between parents and the multidisciplinary team members who coordinate care transition by providing emotional, educational, medical and home visitor support for these families. To do this well, a thoughtful exchange of information between team members and parents is essential to identify psychosocial stress and ameliorate family concerns. Parents will need emotional and educational support and follow-up resources. Establishing individualized, flexible but realistic, pre- and post-discharge plans with parents is needed to start their healthy transition to home and community.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Purdy</LastName><ForeName>I B</ForeName><Initials>IB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neonatology, Department of Pediatrics, David Geffen School of Medicine, University of California at Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Craig</LastName><ForeName>J W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Occupational Therapy, Brenau University, Gainesville, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeanah</LastName><ForeName>P</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cecil Picard Center for Child Development and College of Nursing and Allied Sciences, University of Louisiana, Lafayette, LA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Perinatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8501884</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0743-8346</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001291" MajorTopicYN="N">Attitude of Health Personnel</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000066498" MajorTopicYN="Y">Emotional Adjustment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056348" MajorTopicYN="N">Emotional Intelligence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007363" MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive Care Units, Neonatal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="Y">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016487" MajorTopicYN="N">Parenting</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010290" MajorTopicYN="N">Parents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010351" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Discharge</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011368" MajorTopicYN="N">Professional-Family Relations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012944" MajorTopicYN="Y">Social Support</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2015</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26597802</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4660049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jp.2015.146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">jp2015146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>1Lefkowitz DS, Baxt C, Evans JR. Prevalence and correlates of posttraumatic stress and postpartum depression in parents of infants in neonatal intensive care units (NICU). J Clin Psychol Med Settings 2010; 17: 230&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20632076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2Joseph RA, Mackley AB, Davis CG, Spear ML, Locke RG. Stress in fathers of surgical neonatal intensive care unit babies. Adv Neonatal Care 2007; 7: 321&#x2013;325.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18097216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>3Liu WF, Laudert S, Perkins B, Macmillan-York E, Martin S, Graven S. The development of potentially better practices to support the neurodevelopment of infants in the NICU. J Perinatol 2007; 27: S48&#x2013;S74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18034182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>4Wharam JF, Grave AJ, Kozhimannil KB. Navigating the rise of high-deductible health insurance. Childbirth in the bronze age. JAMA 2015; 313(3): 245&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25602991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>5Committee on Understanding Premature Birth and Assuring Healthy Outcomes Board on Health Sciences Policy. Behrman Richard E, Adrienne Stith Butler (eds). National Academy of Sciences, National Academic Press: Washington, DC,, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>6Craig J. The Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU): Self-Efficacy of Caregiving and the Lived Experience of Parents Post-NICU Discharge. Fielding Graduate University: Santa Barbara, CA, USA, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>7Melnyk B, Crean H, Feinstein N, Fairbanks E. Maternal anxiety and depression after a premature infant's discharge from the neonatal intensive care unit: explanatory effects of the creating opportunities for parent empowerment program. Nurs Res 2008; 57(6): 383&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19018213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>8Purdy I, Melwak M. Who is at risk? High risk infant follow-up. Newborn Infant Nurs Rev 2012; 12(4): 221&#x2013;226.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>9Smith VC, Hwang SS, Dukhovy D, Young S, Pursley DM. Neonatal intensive care unit discharge preparation, family readiness and infant outcomes: connecting the dots. J Perinatol 2013; 33: 415&#x2013;421.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23492936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>10Taylor HG, Klein N, Hack M. School-age consequences of birth weight less than 750&#x2009;g: a review and update. Dev Neuropsychol 2000; 17: 289&#x2013;321.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11056846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>11Thomson G, Moran V, Axelin A, Dykes F, Flacking R. Integrating a sense of coherence into the neonatal environment. BMC Pediatr 2013; 13: 84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3663664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23697687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>12Klassen A, Lee S, Raina P, Lisonkova S. Psychosocial health of family caregivers of children admitted at birth to a NICU and healthy children: a population-based cross-sectional survey. BMC Pediatr 2004; 4: 24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC544865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15598353</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>13Barbosa VM. Teamwork in the neonatal intensive care unit. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr 2013; 33(1): 5&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23311520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>14Ohlinger J, Brown MS, Laudert S, Swanson S, Fofah O. Development of potentially better practices for the neonatal intensive care unit as a culture of collaboration: communication, accountability, respect, and empowerment. Pediatrics 2003; 111: 3471&#x2013;3481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12671167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>15Hynan M, Mounts K, Vanderbilt D. Screening parents of high-risk infants for emotional distress: rationale and recommendations. J Perinatol 2013; 33(10): 748&#x2013;753.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23807720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>16Zuckerman BS, Beardslee WR. Maternal depression: a concern for pediatricians. Pediatrics 1987; 79: 110&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3797157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>17Mackley AB, Spear ML. Forgotten parent: NICU paternal emotional response. Adv Neonatal Care 2010; 10(4): 200&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20697219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>18Wigert H, Dellenmark MB, Bry K. Parents' experiences of communication with neonatal intensive-care unit staff: an interview study. BMC Pediatr 2014; 14: 304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4276021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25492549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>19Browne J, Ayelet Talmi A. Family-based intervention to enhance infant parent relationships in the neonatal intensive care unit. J Pediatr Psychol 2005; 30: 667&#x2013;677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16260436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>20Singer LT, Fulton S, Davillier M, Koshy D, Salvator A, Baley JE. Effects of infant risk status and maternal psychological distress on maternal-infant interactions during the first year of life. J Dev Behav Pediatr 2003; 24: 233&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10246331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12915795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>21National Perinatal Association's Family Advocacy Network. Available at www.nationlperinatal.org/parentsupportgroups.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>22Preemie Parent Alliance. Available at http://preemieparentalliance.weebly.com/#/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>23The European Foundation for the Care of Newborn Infants. Available at www.efcni.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>24Parents as Teachers. Available at www.parentsasteachers.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>25Nurse Family Partnership. Available at www.nursefamilypartnership.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>26The March of Dimes Caring for your Baby, 2015. Available at www.marchofdimes.org/baby/caring-for-baby-library.aspx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>27Earls MF. The Committee on Psychosocial Aspects of Child and Family Health. Incorporating recognition and management of perinatal and postpartum depression into pediatric practice. Pediatrics 2010; 126: 1032&#x2013;1039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20974776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>28Musser AK, Ahmed AH, Foil KJ, Coddington JA. Paternal postpartum depression: what health care providers should know. J Pediatr Health Care 2013; 27: 479&#x2013;485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23182851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>29Gerstein E, Poehlmann-Tynan J, Clark R. Mother&#x2013;child interactions in the NICU: relevance and implications for later parenting. J Pediatr Psychol 2015; 40: 33&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4288303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>30Kendall-Tackett K. A new paradigm for depression in new mothers: the central role of inflammation and how breastfeeding and anti-inflammatory treatments protect maternal mental health. Int Breastfeed J 2007; 2: 6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1855049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17397549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>31Groer MW, Davis MW. Cytokines, infections, stress, and dysphoric moods in breastfeeders and formula feeders. J Obstet Gynecol Neonatal Nurs 2006; 35: 599&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16958715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>32American Academy of Pediatrics Policy Statement. Breastfeeding and the use of human milk. Pediatrics 2012; 129: e827&#x2013;3841.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>33Purdy I, Singh N, Le C, Bell C, Whiteside C, Collins M. Biophysiologic and social stress relationships with breast milk feeding pre- and post-discharge from the neonatal intensive care unit. J Obstet Gynecol Neonatal Nurs 2012; 41: 347&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3407969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22834882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>34Nugent J, Keefer C, Minear S, Johnson L, Blanchard Y. Forward by T Brazelton. Understanding Newborn Behavior and Early Relationships: The Newborn Behavioral Observations (NBO) System Handbook. Brookes Publishing: Baltimore, MD, USA, 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>35Children's Hospitals' Solutions for Patient Safety. Be Part of the Safety Team for Your Child. Available at www.solutionsforpatientsafety.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>36Hiscock H, Cook F, Bayer J, Le HND, Mensah F, Cann W et al. Preventing early infant sleep and crying problems and postnatal depression: a randomized trial. Pediatrics 2015; 133: e346&#x2013;e354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24394682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>37American Academy of Pediatrics Committee on Fetus and Newborn. Policy Statement: Hospital discharge of the high-risk neonate. Pediatrics 2008; 122(5): 1119&#x2013;1126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18977994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>38Bockli K, Andrews B, Pellerite M, Meadow W. Trends and challenges in United States neonatal intensive care units follow-up clinics. J Perinatol 2014; 34: 71&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24177221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>39Kuppala VS, Tabangin M, Haberman B, Steichen J, Yolton K. Current state of high-risk infant follow-up care from the United States: results of a national survey of academic follow-up programs. J Perinatol 2012; 32: 293&#x2013;298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21760588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>40American Association of Pediatrics. Follow-up care of high-risk infants. Pediatrics 2004; 114: 1377&#x2013;1397.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>41Raffray M, Semenic S, Galeano SO, Marin S. Barriers and facilitators of preparing families with premature infants for discharge home from the neonatal unit. Perceptions of health care providers. Invest Educ Enferm 2014; 32: 379&#x2013;392.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25504404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>42Department of Health and Children Services, California Children's Services HRIF Program. Available at http://www.dhcs.ca.gov/services/ccs/Pages/HRIF.aspx.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>43American Association of Pediatrics. The medical home. Pediatrics 2004; 113(5) Part 2): 1545&#x2013;1548.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>44Van Cleave J, Boudreau A, McAllister J, Cooley C, Maxwell A, Kuhthau K. Care Coordination over time in Medical Homes for children with special health care needs. Pediatrics 2015; 135(6): 1018&#x2013;1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8194473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25963012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>45Placentia FX, McCullough LB. Biopsychosocial risks of parental care for high-risk neonates: implications for evidence-based parental counseling. J Perinatol 2012; 32: 381&#x2013;386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21904297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>46Health Resources and Services Administration Maternal, Infant and Early Childhood Home Visitation Program Partnering with Parents to Help Children Succeed, 2015. Available at www.mchb.hrsa.gov/programs/homevisiting.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>47US Department of Health and Human Resources, Administration for Children and Families, Home Visiting Evidence of Effectiveness (HomeVee). 2015. Available at http://homvee.acf.hhs.gov.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>48Goyal N, Teeters A, Ammerman R. Home visiting and outcomes of premature infants: a systematic review. Pediatrics 2013; 32: 502&#x2013;516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3876756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23940238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>49Parker C, Warmuskerken G, Sinclair L. Enhancing neonatal wellness with home visitation. Nurs Womens Health 2015; 19: 37&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25690814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>50Dodge KA, Goodman WB, Murphy RA, O'Donnell K, Sato J. Randomized controlled trial of universal postnatal nurse home visiting: impact on emergency care. Pediatrics 2013; 132: S140&#x2013;S146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3943376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24187116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>51American Academy of Pediatrics and American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists. Perinatal Guidelines for Home Visitation. American Academy of Pediatrics and American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists: Washington, DC, USA, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>52Paul IM, Beiler JS, Schaefer EW, Hollenbeak CS, Alleman N et al. A randomized trial of single home nursing visits versus office-based care after nursery/maternity discharge: the Nurses for Infants Through Teaching and Assessment After the Nursery (NITTANY) Study. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med 2012; 166: 263&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22064874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>53Postpartum Support International. Available at www.postpartum.net.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>