<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">31639007</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1741-7015</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Age-treatment subgroup analyses in Cochrane intervention reviews: a meta-epidemiological study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>188</StartPage><MedlinePgn>188</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">188</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12916-019-1420-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">There is growing interest in evaluating differences in healthcare interventions across routinely collected demographic characteristics. However, individual subgroup analyses in randomized controlled trials are often not prespecified, adjusted for multiple testing, or conducted using the appropriate statistical test for interaction, and therefore frequently lack credibility. Meta-analyses can be used to examine the validity of potential subgroup differences by collating evidence across trials. Here, we characterize the conduct and clinical translation of age-treatment subgroup analyses in Cochrane reviews.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">For a random sample of 928 Cochrane intervention reviews of randomized trials, we determined how often subgroup analyses of age are reported, how often these analyses have a P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 from formal interaction testing, how frequently subgroup differences first observed in an individual trial are later corroborated by other trials in the same meta-analysis, and how often statistically significant results are included in commonly used clinical management resources (BMJ Best Practice, UpToDate, Cochrane Clinical Answers, Google Scholar, and Google search).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Among 928 Cochrane intervention reviews, 189 (20.4%) included plans to conduct age-treatment subgroup analyses. The vast majority (162 of 189, 85.7%) of the planned analyses were not conducted, commonly because of insufficient trial data. There were 22 reviews that conducted their planned age-treatment subgroup analyses, and another 3 reviews appeared to perform unplanned age-treatment subgroup analyses. These 25 (25 of 928, 2.7%) reviews conducted a total of 97 age-treatment subgroup analyses, of which 65 analyses (in 20 reviews) had non-overlapping subgroup levels. Among the 65 age-treatment subgroup analyses, 14 (21.5%) did not report any formal interaction testing. Seven (10.8%) reported P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.05 from formal age-treatment interaction testing; however, none of these seven analyses were in reviews that discussed the potential biological rationale or clinical significance of the subgroup findings or had results that were included in common clinical practice resources.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Age-treatment subgroup analyses in Cochrane intervention reviews were frequently planned but rarely conducted, and implications of detected interactions were not discussed in the reviews or mentioned in common clinical resources. When subgroup analyses are performed, authors should report the findings, compare the results to previous studies, and outline any potential impact on clinical care.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Patrick</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ioannidis</LastName><ForeName>John P A</ForeName><Initials>JPA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Meta-Research Innovation Center at Stanford (METRICS), Stanford School of Medicine, Stanford, CA, 94305, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Research and Policy, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA, 94305, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stanford Prevention Research Center, Department of Medicine, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA, 94305, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Statistics, Stanford University School of Humanities and Sciences, Stanford, CA, 94305, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ross</LastName><ForeName>Joseph S</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE), Yale-New Haven Health System, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of General Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Clinician Scholars Program, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Policy and Management, Yale School of Public Health, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dhruva</LastName><ForeName>Sanket S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of California, San Francisco School of Medicine, San Francisco, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Section of Cardiology, San Francisco Veterans Affairs Health Care System, San Francisco, CA, 94121, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Luxkaranayagam</LastName><ForeName>Anita T</ForeName><Initials>AT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Connecticut, Storrs, CT, 06269, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vasiliou</LastName><ForeName>Vasilis</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Health Sciences, Yale School of Public Health, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallach</LastName><ForeName>Joshua D</ForeName><Initials>JD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2816-6905</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Outcomes Research and Evaluation (CORE), Yale-New Haven Health System, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA. Joshua.wallach@yale.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Health Sciences, Yale School of Public Health, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA. Joshua.wallach@yale.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Collaboration for Research Integrity and Transparency (CRIT), Yale Law School, New Haven, CT, 06510, USA. Joshua.wallach@yale.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001863</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101190723</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1741-7015</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017677" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Distribution</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000367" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003627" MajorTopicYN="Y">Data Interpretation, Statistical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015340" MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiologic Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016021" MajorTopicYN="N">Epidemiologic Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057285" MajorTopicYN="N">Precision Medicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="Y">Research Design</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012196" MajorTopicYN="Y">Review Literature as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Age subgroups</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heterogeneity of treatment effects</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Precision medicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Subgroup analyses</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>In the past 36 months, JPAI received research support through the METRICS from the Laura and John Arnold Foundations and through an unrestricted gift from Sue and Bob O&#x2019;Donnell. JSR received research support through Yale from Johnson and Johnson to develop methods of clinical trial data sharing, from Medtronic, Inc., and the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to develop methods for postmarket surveillance of medical devices (U01FD004585), from the Centers of Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) to develop and maintain performance measures that are used for public reporting, from the FDA to establish a Center for Excellence in Regulatory Science and Innovation (CERSI) at Yale University and the Mayo Clinic (U01FD005938), from the Blue Cross Blue Shield Association to better understand medical technology evaluation, from the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (R01HS022882), and from the Laura and John Arnold Foundation. SSD received support as a Scholar in the Yale University/Mayo Clinic FDA CERSI. VV received support through the National Institutes of Health. JDW received research support through the Meta Research Innovation Center at Stanford (METRICS) and Collaboration for Research Integrity and Transparency from the Laura and John Arnold Foundation. The other authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31639007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-019-1420-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12916-019-1420-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Kent DM, Rothwell PM, Ioannidis JP, et al. Assessing and reporting heterogeneity in treatment effects in clinical trials: a proposal. Trials. 2010;11:85. doi: 10.1186/1745-6215-11-85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1745-6215-11-85</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2928211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20704705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamburg MA, Collins FS. The path to personalized medicine. N Engl J Med. 2010;363(4):301&#x2013;304. doi: 10.1056/NEJMp1006304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp1006304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20551152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins FS, Varmus H. A new initiative on precision medicine. N Engl J Med. 2015;372(9):793&#x2013;795. doi: 10.1056/NEJMp1500523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp1500523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5101938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25635347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assmann SF, Pocock SJ, Enos LE, et al. Subgroup analysis and other (mis)uses of baseline data in clinical trials. Lancet. 2000;355(9209):1064&#x2013;1069. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(00)02039-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(00)02039-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10744093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pocock SJ, Hughes MD, Lee RJ. Statistical problems in the reporting of clinical trials. A survey of three medical journals. N Engl J Med. 1987;317(7):426&#x2013;432. doi: 10.1056/NEJM198708133170706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198708133170706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3614286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallach JD, Sullivan PG, Trepanowski JF, et al. Evaluation of evidence of statistical support and corroboration of subgroup claims in randomized clinical trials. JAMA Intern Med. 2017;177(4):554&#x2013;560. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2016.9125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2016.9125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6657347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28192563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang R, Lagakos SW, Ware JH, et al. Statistics in medicine--reporting of subgroup analyses in clinical trials. N Engl J Med. 2007;357(21):2189&#x2013;2194. doi: 10.1056/NEJMsr077003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMsr077003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18032770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pocock SJ, Assmann SE, Enos LE, et al. Subgroup analysis, covariate adjustment and baseline comparisons in clinical trial reporting: current practice and problems. Stat Med. 2002;21(19):2917&#x2013;2930. doi: 10.1002/sim.1296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sim.1296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12325108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxman AD, Guyatt GH. A consumer&#x2019;s guide to subgroup analyses. Ann Intern Med. 1992;116(1):78&#x2013;84. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-116-1-78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-116-1-78</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1530753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kent DM, Steyerberg E, van Klaveren D. Personalized evidence based medicine: predictive approaches to heterogeneous treatment effects. BMJ. 2018;363:k4245. doi: 10.1136/bmj.k4245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.k4245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6889830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30530757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS). CMS releases quality data showing racial, ethnic and gender differences in Medicare Advantage health care during National Minority Health Month. Press release. 13 April 2017. https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/press-releases/cms-releases-quality-data-showing-racial-ethnic-and-gender-differences-medicare-advantagehealth-care. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Investigational new drug applications and new drug applications. 21 CFR 312, 63 FR 6854. 11 Feb 1998. https://www.govinfo.gov/app/details/FR-1998-02-11/98-3422. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). FDA action plan to enhance collection and availability of demographic subgroup data. FDA report. Silver Spring, MD: FDA; August 2014. https://www.fda.gov/downloads/RegulatoryInformation/Legislation/FederalFoodDrugandCosmeticActFDCAct/SignificantAmendmentstotheFDCAct/FDASIA/UCM410474.pdf. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Evaluating inclusion and exclusion criteria in clinical trials. FDA report. Washington, DC: FDA; 16 April 2018. https://www.fda.gov/downloads/RegulatoryInformation/LawsEnforcedbyFDA/SignificantAmendmentstotheFDCAct/FDARA/UCM613054.pdf. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tugwell P, Petkovic J, Welch V, et al. Setting priorities for knowledge translation of Cochrane reviews for health equity: evidence for equity. Int J Equity Health. 2017;16(1):208. doi: 10.1186/s12939-017-0697-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12939-017-0697-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5712153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29197403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welch VA, Norheim OF, Jull J, et al. CONSORT-Equity 2017 extension and elaboration for better reporting of health equity in randomised trials. BMJ. 2017;359:j5085. doi: 10.1136/bmj.j5085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.j5085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29170161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell and Cochrane Equity Methods Group. About us. Ottawa: Cochrane; 2019. https://methods.cochrane.org/equity/about-us. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health (NIH). NIH policy and guidelines on the inclusion of individuals across the lifespan as participants in research involving human subjects. NIH notice. Bethesda, MD: NIH; 19 December 2017. https://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/notice-files/NOT-OD-18-116.html. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Evaluation and reporting of age-, race-, and ethnicity-specific data in medical device clinical studies. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Food and Drug Administration, Center for Devices and Raiological Health (CDRH), Center for Biologics Evaluation Research (CBER), Office of the Commissioner (OC): 12 September 2017. https://www.fda.gov/downloads/MedicalDevices/DeviceRegulationandGuidance/GuidanceDocuments/UCM507278.pdf. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preston RA, Materson BJ, Reda DJ, et al. Age-race subgroup compared with renin profile as predictors of blood pressure response to antihypertensive therapy. Department of Veterans Affairs Cooperative Study Group on antihypertensive agents. JAMA. 1998;280(13):1168&#x2013;1172. doi: 10.1001/jama.280.13.1168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.280.13.1168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9777817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Liang F, Li W, et al. Subgroup analyses in reporting of phase III clinical trials in solid tumors. J Clin Oncol. 2015;33(15):1697&#x2013;1702. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2014.59.8862.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2014.59.8862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25897150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeks JJ, Higgins JPT, Altman DG (editors). Chapter 9: Analyzing and undertaking meta-analyses. In: Higgins JPT, Green S (editors). Cochrane handbook for systematic reviews of interventions version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from www.handbook.cochrane.org. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. General Accountability Office (GAO). Better oversight needed to help ensure continued progress including women in health research. GAO report. Washington, DC: GAO; 22 October 2015. https://www.gao.gov/assets/680/673276.pdf. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell and Cochrane Equity Methods Group. Sex/Gender Cochrane Corner. Ottawa: Cochrane; 2019. https://methods.cochrane.org/equity/igh-cochrane-corner. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallach JD, Sullivan PG, Trepanowski JF, et al. Sex based subgroup differences in randomized controlled trials: empirical evidence from Cochrane meta-analyses. BMJ. 2016;355:i5826. doi: 10.1136/bmj.i5826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.i5826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5122320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27884869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Collection, analysis, and availability of demographic subgroup data for FDA-approved medical products. FDA report. Silver Spring, MD: FDA; August 2013. https://www.fda.gov/downloads/RegulatoryInformation/Legislation/FederalFoodDrugandCosmeticActFDCAct/SignificantAmendmentstotheFDCAct/FDASIA/UCM365544.pdf. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rochon P. Drug prescribing for older adults. Section Editor: Schmader KE, Deputy Editor: Givens, J. UpToDate. Last updated 19 Feb 2019. https://www.uptodate.com/contents/drug-prescribing-for-older-adults. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams K, Thomson D, Seto I, et al. Standard 6: age groups for pediatric trials. Pediatrics. 2012;129(Suppl 3):S153&#x2013;S160. doi: 10.1542/peds.2012-0055I.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2012-0055I</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22661762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contopoulos-Ioannidis DG, Seto I, Hamm MP, et al. Empirical evaluation of age groups and age-subgroup analyses in pediatric randomized trials and pediatric meta-analyses. Pediatrics. 2012;129(Suppl 3):S161&#x2013;S184. doi: 10.1542/peds.2012-0055J.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2012-0055J</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22661763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandermeer B, van der Tweel I, Jansen-van der Weide MC, et al. Comparison of nuisance parameters in pediatric versus adult randomized trials: a meta-epidemiologic empirical evaluation. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2018;18(1):7. doi: 10.1186/s12874-017-0456-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12874-017-0456-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5763521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29321002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Contopoulos-Ioannidis DG, Baltogianni MS, Ioannidis JP. Comparative effectiveness of medical interventions in adults versus children. J Pediatr. 2010;157(2):322&#x2013;330. doi: 10.1016/j.jpeds.2010.02.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpeds.2010.02.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20434730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raz I, Ceriello A, Wilson PW, et al. Post hoc subgroup analysis of the HEART2D trial demonstrates lower cardiovascular risk in older patients targeting postprandial versus fasting/premeal glycemia. Diabetes Care. 2011;34(7):1511&#x2013;1513. doi: 10.2337/dc10-2375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc10-2375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3120208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21593301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meade TW, Brennan PJ. Determination of who may derive most benefit from aspirin in primary prevention: subgroup results from a randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2000;321(7252):13&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1136/bmj.321.7252.13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.321.7252.13</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC27417</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10875825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon Yoojin, Lemieux Michelle, McTavish Jill, Wathen Nadine. Identifying and removing duplicate records from systematic review searches. Journal of the Medical Library Association : JMLA. 2015;103(4):184&#x2013;188. doi: 10.3163/1536-5050.103.4.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3163/1536-5050.103.4.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4613377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26512216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Ioannidis JPA, Agoritsas T, Alba AC, Guyatt G. How to use a subgroup analysis: users&#x2019; guide to the medical literature. JAMA. 2014;311(4):405&#x2013;411. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.285063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.285063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24449319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boreinstein M, Higgins JPT. Meta-analysis and subgroups. Prev Sci. 2013;14:134&#x2013;143. doi: 10.1007/s11121-013-0377-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11121-013-0377-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23479191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sedgwick P. Meta-analyses: heterogeneity and subgroup analysis. BMJ. 2013;346:f4040. doi: 10.1136/bmj.f4040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.f4040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25778910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis JPA. The proposal to lower P value thresholds to .005. JAMA. 2018;319(14):1429&#x2013;1430. doi: 10.1001/jama.2018.1536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2018.1536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29566133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams N, Bestall JM, Jones PW. Budesonide at different doses for chronic asthma. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2001;4:CD003271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8713049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11687182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams N, Bestall JM, Jones PW. Fluticasone versus beclomethasone or budesonide for chronic asthma. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2007;4:CD002310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11869636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mbuagbaw L, Morgano GP, Lawson DO, et al. Subgroup analyses are seldom possible and subgroup effects are rare in Cochrane HIV systematic reviews. J Clin Epidemiol. 2018;104:143&#x2013;144. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.08.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2018.08.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30138701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans AT, Mints G. Evidence-based medicine. UpToDate. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes RB. What kind of evidence is it that Evidence-Based Medicine advocates want health care providers and consumers to pay attention to? BMC Health Serv Res. 2002;2:3. doi: 10.1186/1472-6963-2-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6963-2-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC99045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11882257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadad AR, Haynes RB. The Cochrane Collaboration&#x2014;advances and challenges in improving evidence-based decision making. Med Decis Mak. 1998;18(1):2&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1177/0272989X9801800102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0272989X9801800102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9456200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tse T, Williams RJ, Zarin DA. Reporting &#x201c;basic results&#x201d; in ClinicalTrials.gov. Chest. 2009;136(1):295&#x2013;303. doi: 10.1378/chest.08-3022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.08-3022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2821287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19584212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Guidance for industry: collection of race and ethnicity data in clinical trials. Washington, DC: U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Food and Drug Administration, Center for Drug Evaluation and Research (CDER), Center for Biologics Evaluation and Research (CBER), Center for Devices and Radiologic Health (CDRH), Office of the Commissioner (OC); September 2005. http://www.fda.gov/downloads/RegulatoryInformation/Guidances/ucm126396.pdf. Accessed 25 Feb 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Costa BR, Juni P. Systematic reviews and meta-analyses of randomized trials: principles and pitfalls. Eur Heart J. 2014;35(47):3336&#x2013;3345. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehu424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehu424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25416325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Briel M, Busse JW, et al. Credibility of claims of subgroup effects in randomised controlled trials: systematic review. BMJ. 2012;344:e1553. doi: 10.1136/bmj.e1553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.e1553</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22422832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun X, Briel M, Walter SD, et al. Is a subgroup effect believable? Updating criteria to evaluate the credibility of subgroup analyses. BMJ. 2010;340:c117. doi: 10.1136/bmj.c117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.c117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20354011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothwell PM. Treating individuals 2. Subgroup analysis in randomised controlled trials: importance, indications, and interpretation. Lancet. 2005;365(9454):176&#x2013;186. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(05)17709-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(05)17709-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15639301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Schulz KF, Altman DG, et al. The CONSORT statement: revised recommendations for improving the quality of reports of parallel-group randomized trials. J Am Podiatr Med Assoc. 2001;91(8):437&#x2013;442. doi: 10.7547/87507315-91-8-437.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7547/87507315-91-8-437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11574648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunne J, Rodriguez WJ, Murphy MD, et al. Extrapolation of adult data and other data in pediatric drug-development programs. Pediatrics. 2011;128(5):e1242&#x2013;e1249. doi: 10.1542/peds.2010-3487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/peds.2010-3487</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22025597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Downing NS, Shah ND, Neiman JH, et al. Participation of the elderly, women, and minorities in pivotal trials supporting 2011&#x2013;2013 U.S. Food and Drug Administration approvals. Trials. 2016;17:199. doi: 10.1186/s13063-016-1322-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-016-1322-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4832528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27079511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chandler J, Lasserson T, Higgins JPT, Tovey D, Churchill R. Standard for the planning, conduct and reporting of updates of Cochrane Intervention Reviews. In: JPT H, Lasserson T, Chandler J, Tovey D, Churchill R, editors. Methodological Expectations of Cochrane Intervention Reviews. London: Cochrane; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuit Ewoud, Li Alvin H, Ioannidis John P A. How often can meta-analyses of individual-level data individualize treatment? A meta-epidemiologic study. International Journal of Epidemiology. 2018;48(2):596&#x2013;608. doi: 10.1093/ije/dyy239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyy239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30445577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song F, Bachmann MO. Cumulative subgroup analysis to reduce waste in clinical research for individualised medicine. BMC Med. 2016;14(1):197. doi: 10.1186/s12916-016-0744-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-016-0744-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5157082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27974045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>