<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36737879</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1600-0528</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>51</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Community dentistry and oral epidemiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Community Dent Oral Epidemiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Designing complex interventions: A description of the development of an intervention to reduce inequalities in planned dental visiting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1118</StartPage><EndPage>1129</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1118-1129</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/cdoe.12842</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="UNLABELLED">There are multifaceted reasons for a social gradient in planned dental visiting involving various psycho-social variables that interact with each other and the environment. Interventions in this area are therefore inevitably complex interventions. While guidance recommends undertaking theory and modelling work before experimental work is done, there is a shortage of descriptions of how this is done, especially in the field of oral health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To describe theory, qualitative and public engagement work, and identification of behaviour change techniques (BCTs) to define features of an opportunistic dental visiting intervention for adult users of urgent dental care services.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A systematic review and synthesis of theory, qualitative and quantitative work, along with expert input, generated a list of psycho-social determinants linked to planned dental visiting intentions. Modelling involved ethnographic work in urgent dental care settings and work with members of the community from the targeted demographic. This enabled verification, in the context of their idiosyncratic expression for the target population in question, of behavioural determinants (BDs) identified in the theory phase. It also facilitated generating intervention material which was infused with the identity of the end user. BDs identified were then mapped to BCTs using an accepted BCT taxonomy and an intervention prototype developed. The prototype then underwent iterative testing with target users before it was ready for a feasibility trial.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Theory and modelling identified five key intervention focuses: affordable resources (time/ cost), the importance of oral health, trust in dentists, embarrassment of having poor oral health and dental anxiety. Short videos were developed to incorporate role modelling which were well received. Prototype testing resulted in shifting from 'if-then' plans to action planning.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Complex intervention development involves an iterative rather than sequential process of combining theory, empirical work and user involvement, of which the article provides an example.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Community Dentistry and Oral Epidemiology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harris</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca Vera</ForeName><Initials>RV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Policy and Systems, Institute of Population Health, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lowers</LastName><ForeName>Victoria</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Policy and Systems, Institute of Population Health, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Der Zande</LastName><ForeName>Marieke</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Policy and Systems, Institute of Population Health, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stanley</LastName><ForeName>Margaret</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Policy and Systems, Institute of Population Health, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooke</LastName><ForeName>Richard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health, Science and Wellbeing, Staffordshire University, Stoke on Trent, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>RP-PG-0616-20004</GrantID><Acronym>DH_</Acronym><Agency>Department of Health</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Denmark</Country><MedlineTA>Community Dent Oral Epidemiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0410263</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0301-5661</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Behavior Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D033182" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intention</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009909" MajorTopicYN="N">Oral Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dental attendance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behaviour change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complex interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implementation inequalities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention design</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">participatory research</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36737879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cdoe.12842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Listl S, Galloway PA, Mossey PA, Marcenes W. Global economic impact of dental diseases. J Dent Res. 2015;94:1355-1361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RV. Do &#x2018;poor areas&#x2019; get the services they deserve? The role of dental services in structural inequalities in oral health. Community Dent Health. 2016;33:164-167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braveman P, Gruskin S. Defining equity in health. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2003;57:254-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Listl S. Inequalities in dental attendance throughout the lifecourse. J Dent Res. 2012;91:S91-S97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGinnis JM, Williams-Russo KJR. The case for more active policy attention to health promotion. Health Aff. 2002;21:78-92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiske J, Gelbier S, Watson RM. Barriers to dental care in an elderly population resident in an inner-city area. J Dent. 1990;18:236-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris RV, Pennington A, Whitehead M. Preventive dental visiting: a critical interpretive synthesis of theory explaining how inequalities arise. Community Dent Oral Epidemiol. 2017;45:120-134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Zande M, Exley C, Wilson SA, Harris RV. Disentangling a web of causation: an ethnographic study of interlinked patient barriers to planned dental visiting, and strategies to overcome them. Community Dent Oral Epidemiol. 2021;49:144-157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyman JM, N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez GG, Talavera V. Healthcare access and barriers for unauthorised immigrants in El Paso County, Texas. Fam Community Health. 2009;32:4-21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Craig P, Dieppe P, Macintyre S, Mitchie S, Nazareth I, Petticrew M. Developing and evaluating complex interventions: the new Medical Research Council guidance. Br Med J. 2008;337:a1655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore GF, Audrey S, Barker M, et al. Process evaluation of complex interventions. Medical Research Council guidance. Br Med J. 2015;350:h1258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skivington K, Matthews L, Simpson SA, et al. A new framework for developing and evaluating complex interventions: update of Medical Research Council guidance. Br Med J. 2021;374:n2061.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Band R, Bradbury K, Morton K, et al. Intervention planning for a digital intervention for self-management of hypertension: a theory, evidence and person-based approach. Implement Sci. 2017;12:25-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yardley L, Morrison L, Bradbury K, Muller I. The person-based approach to intervention development: application to digital health-related behavior change interventions. J Med Internet Res. 2015;17:e30. doi:10.2196/jmir.4055</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardeman W, Sutton S, Griffin S, et al. A causal modelling approach to the development of theory-based behaviour change programmes for trial evaluation. Health Educ Res. 2005;20:676-687. doi:10.1093/her/cyh022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kok G, Peters LWH, Ruiter RAC. Planning theory and evidence-based behaviour change interventions: a conceptual review of the intervention mapping protocol. Psicol Reflex Crit. 2017;30:19. doi:10.1186/s41155-017-0072</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Van Stralen M, West R. The behaviour change wheel: a new method for characteristing and designing behaviour change interventions. Implement Sci. 2011;6:42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rippetoe PA, Rogers RW. Effects of components of protection-motivation theory on adaptive and maladaptive coping with a health threat. J Pers Soc Psychol. 1987;523:596-604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milne S, Orbell S, Sheeran P. Combining motivational and volitional interventions to promote exercise participation: protection motivation theory and implementation intentions. Br J Health Psychol. 2002;7:163-184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollwitzer PM, Sheeran P. Implementation intentions and goal achievement: a meta-analysis of effects and processes. Adv Exp Soc Psychol. 2006;38:69-119.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oyserman D, Fryberg SA, Yoder N. Identity-based motivation and health. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2007;93:1011-1027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Richardson M, Johnston M, et al. The behavior change technique taxonomy (v1) of 93 hierarchically clustered techniques: building an international consensus for the reporting of behavior change interventions. Ann Behav Med. 2013;46:81-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Johnston M, Francis J, Hardeman W, Eccles M. From theory to intervention mapping theoretically derived behavioural determinants to behaviour change techniques. Appl Psychol. 2008;57:660-680.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollwitzer PM. Implementation intentions: strong effects of simple plans. Am Psychol. 1999;54:493-503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R. Self-efficacy in the adoption and maintenance of health behaviors: theoretical approaches and a new model. In: Schwarzer R, ed. Self-Efficacy: Thought Control of Action. Hemisphere; 1992:217-242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Self-efficacy: toward a unifying theory of behavioral change. Psychol Rev. 1977;84:191-215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Social Foundations of Thought and Action: a Social Cognitive Theory. Prentice-Hall; 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franklin M, Lewis S, Willis K, Rogers A, Venville A, Smith L. Goals for living with a chronic condition: the relevance of temporalities, dispositions and resources. Soc Sci Med. 2019;23:13-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolfenden L, Foy R, Presseau J, et al. Designing and undertaking randomised implementation trials: guide for researchers. BMJ. 2021;372:m3721. doi:10.1136/bmj.m3721</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris R, Foskett-Tharby R. From dental contract to system reform: why an incremental approach is needed. Br Dent J. 2022;233:377-381. doi:10.1038/s41415-022-4919-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>May CR, Johnson M, Finch T. Implementation, context and complexity. Implement Sci. 2016;11:141. doi:10.1186/s13012-016-0506-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coulthard P, Thomson P, Dave M, Coulthard FP, Seoudi N, Hill M. The COVID-19 pandemic and dentistry: the clinical, legal and economic consequences - part 1: clinical. Br Dent J. 2020;229:743-747. doi:10.1038/s41415-020-2404-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonnell C, Jamal F, Melendez-Torres GJ, Cummins S. &#x2018;Dark logic&#x2019;: theorising the harmful consequences of public health interventions. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2015;69:95-98.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Minary L, Alla F, Cambon L, Kivits J, Potvin L. Addressing complexity in population health intervention research: the context/intervention interface. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2018;72:319-323. doi:10.1136/jech-2017-209921</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>