<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32286003</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2524</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Health &amp; social care in the community</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Health Soc Care Community</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Children and tutor's perspectives on a homework support program in Melbourne: A university-school partnership.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1611</StartPage><EndPage>1621</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1611-1621</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/hsc.12986</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>This study focuses on a homework program where an Australian University partnered with a school to support children from culturally and linguistically diverse backgrounds. Undergraduate tutors, paired with a child each semester, provided weekly learning support. This exploratory study aimed to understand the experiences of the children participating in the program and any benefits received. Nineteen children participated in activity-based focus groups, and seven undergraduate tutors participated in one-on-one interviews. Overarching themes identified were as follows: making homework club enjoyable, program outcomes, tutor-child relationship and transitioning to a new tutor. Although children were required to do homework they usually avoided, the task was made less onerous and even enjoyable because of the relationship the children had with their tutor, the support received and new skills learnt. The tutor-child relationship was deeply valued, with the tutor's role going beyond instructional support to also providing social and emotional support and a sense of belonging in line with Social Support Theory. Both the children and tutors expressed contrasting views about the experience of children transitioning to a new tutor each semester and this departs from the extant literature. The challenges related to the loss of connection, while positive aspects concerned the opportunity to make new friends and learn from different teaching styles. Given these contrasting findings, it is worth considering how the transition process can be managed and explained to children and increase the chances of positive adaptation. Despite the relatively short-term nature of the tutor-child relationship, the children expressed clear academic, social and emotional benefits. The findings suggest that semester-based university-school homework tutoring programs can be effective despite their short-term nature, provided due consideration is given to the transition process. These findings address the paucity of research exploring short-term programs of this nature.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gordon</LastName><ForeName>Chloe S</ForeName><Initials>CS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3648-8349</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ACU Engagement, Melbourne, Vic., Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pink</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ACU Engagement, Melbourne, Vic., Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jones</LastName><ForeName>Sandra C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ACU Engagement, Melbourne, Vic., Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Health Soc Care Community</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9306359</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0966-0410</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003159" MajorTopicYN="Y">Community-Institutional Relations</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017144" MajorTopicYN="N">Focus Groups</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070777" MajorTopicYN="N">School Teachers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012574" MajorTopicYN="N">Schools</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="Y">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="N">Students</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="Y">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014495" MajorTopicYN="N">Universities</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000458" MajorTopicYN="Y">organization &amp; administration</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">University-school tutoring</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">children</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">culturally and linguistically diverse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">homework support</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mentoring</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32286003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hsc.12986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>ACARA (The Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority). (2014). Guide to understanding 2013 index of community socio-educational advantage (ICSEA) values. Retrieved from www.myschool.edu.au</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barker, J., &amp; Weller, S. (2003). &#x201c;Is it fun?&#x201d; developing children centred research methods. The International Journal of Sociology and Social Policy, 1, 33-58. https://doi.org/10.1108/01443330310790435.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett, J., &amp; Antenucci, R. (2009). Building connection in working with new arrival immigrant and refugee students. TESOL in Context, 19(1).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck, E. (1999). Prevention and intervention programming: Lessons from an after-school program. The Urban Review, 31(1), 107-124. https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1023200500215</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg, V. D., Vos, E. E., de Groot, R. H. M., Singh, A. S., &amp; Chinapaw, M. J. M. (2018). Untapped resources: 10- to 13-year-old primary schoolchildren&#x2019;s views on additional physical activity in the school setting: A focus group study. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health, 15(12), 2713. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph15122713</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block, K., Cross, S., Riggs, E., &amp; Gibbs, L. (2014). Supporting schools to create an inclusive environment for refugee students. International Journal of Inclusive Education, 18(12), 1337-1355. https://doi.org/10.1080/13603116.2014.899636</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boswell, S., &amp; Cudmore, L. (2014). &#x2018;The children were fine&#x2019;: Acknowledging complex feelings in the move from foster care into adoption. Adoption &amp; Fostering, 38(1), 5-21. https://doi.org/10.1177/0308575914522558</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady, B., Dolan, P., &amp; Canavan, J. (2017). &#x2018;He told me to calm down and all that&#x2019;: A qualitative study of forms of social support in youth mentoring relationships. Child &amp; Family Social Work, 22(1), 266-274. https://doi.org/10.1111/cfs.12235</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun, V., &amp; Clarke, V. (2013). Successful qualitative research: A practical guide for beginners. London: SAGE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell, J. W., Hanson, W. E., Clark Plano, V. L., &amp; Morales, A. (2007). Qualitative research designs: Selection and implementation. The Counseling Psychologist, 35(2), 236-264. https://doi.org/10.1177/0011000006287390</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuBois, D., Lipman, E., Rhodes, J. E., Silverthorn, N., &amp; Valentine, J. C. (2011). How effective are mentoring programs for youth? A systematic assessment of the evidence. Psychological Science in the Public Interest, 12, 57-91. https://doi.org/10.1177/1529100611414806</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gateway, C. W. I. (2018). Helping your child transition from foster care to adoption. Factsheet for families. Retrieved from. https://www.childwelfare.gov/pubs/f-transition/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossman, J. B., Chan, C. S., Schwartz, S. E. O., &amp; Rhodes, J. E. (2011). The test of time in school-based mentoring: The role of relationship duration and re-matching on academic outcomes. American Journal of Community Psychology, 30, 199-219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamner, J. B., Wilder, B., &amp; Byrd, L. (2007). Lessons learned: Integrating a service learning community-based partnership into the curriculum. Nursing Outlook, 55(2), 106-110. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.outlook.2007.01.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanson, C. S., Craig, J. C., &amp; Tong, A. (2017). their own words: The value of qualitative research to improve the care of children with chronic kidney disease. Educational Review, 32, 1501-1507. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00467-016-3526-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heary, C., &amp; Hennessy, E. (2006). Focus groups versus individual interviews with children: A comparison of data. The Irish Journal of Psychology, 27(1/2), 58-68. https://doi.org/10.1080/03033910.2006.10446228</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karcher, M. J. (2008). The Study of Mentoring in the Learning Environment (SMILE): A randomized evaluation of the effectiveness of school-based mentoring. Prevention Science, 9(99), 99-113. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11121-008-0083-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kids Matter. (2016). Transitions matter for mental health. Retrieved from https://www.kidsmatter.edu.au/early-childhood/blog/poster-transitions-matter-for-mental-health</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komosa-Hawkins, K. (2010). Best practices in school-based mentoring programs for adolescents. Child and Youth Services, 31(3-4), 121-137. https://doi.org/10.1080/0145935X.2009.524477</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mboka, A. K. (2017). University students' relationship-based mentoring in school settings. International Journal of Offender Therapy and Comparative Criminology, 62(8), 2271-2291. https://doi.org/10.1177/0306624X17712327</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorris, B. J., Doty, J. L., Weiler, L. M., Beckman, K. J., &amp; Garcia-Huidobro, D. (2018). A Typology of school-based Mentoring Relationship Quality: Implications for Recruiting and Retaining Volunteer Mentors. Child and Youth Services Review, 90, 149-157. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.childyouth.2018.05.019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McQuillin, S., Strait, G., Smith, B., &amp; Ingram, A. (2015). Brief instrumental school-based mentoring for first- and second-year middle school students: A randomized evaluation. Journal of Community Psychology, 43(7), 885-899. https://doi.org/10.1002/jcop.21719</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore, T., &amp; McArthur, M. (2017). &#x2018;You feel it in your body&#x2019;: How Australian children and young people think about and experience feeling and being safe. Children and Society, 31, 206-218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan, M., Gibbs, S., Maxwell, K., &amp; Britten, N. (2002). Hearing children's voices: Methodological issues in conducting focus groups with children aged 7-11 years. Qualitative Research, 2(1), 5-20. https://doi.org/10.1177/1468794102002001636</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphey, D., Bandy, T., Schmitz, H., &amp; Moore, K. A. (2013). Caring Adults: Important for positive child wellbeing. Bethesda, MD. Retrieved fromhttps://www.childtrends.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/2013-54CaringAdults.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naidoo, L. (2013). Refugee Action Support: An interventionist pedagogy for supporting refugee students learning in Greater Western Sydney secondary schools. International Journal of Inclusive Education, 17(5), 449-461. https://doi.org/10.1080/13603116.2012.683048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naidoo, L. (2015). Educating refugee-background students in Australian schools and universities. Intercultural Education, 26(3), 210-217. https://doi.org/10.1080/14675986.2015.1048079</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naidoo, L., Wilkinson, J., Adoniou, M., &amp; Langat, K. (2018). School to university transitions for Australian children of refugee background: A complex journey. In M. Pavlova, J.-C.-K. Lee, &amp; R. Maclean (Eds.), Transitions to post-school life: Responsiveness to individual, social and economic needs (pp. 81-103). Singapore: Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyumba, T. O., Wilson, K., Derrick, C. J., &amp; Mukherjee, N. (2018). The use of focus group discussion methodology: Insights from two decades of application in conservation. Methods in Ecology and Evolution, 9(1), 20-32. https://doi.org/10.1111/2041-210X.12860</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raposa, E. B., Rhodes, J., Stams, G. J. J. M., Card, N., Burton, S., Schwartz, S., &#x2026; Hussain, S. (2019). The effects of youth mentoring programs: A meta-analysis of outcome studies. Journal of Youth and Adolescence, 48(3), 423-443. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10964-019-00982-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richmond, C. A. M., Ross, N. A., &amp; Egeland, G. M. (2007). Social support and thriving health: A new approach to understanding the health of indigenous Canadians. American Journal of Public Health, 97(10), 1827-1833. https://doi.org/10.2105/ajph.2006.096917</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomson, S., De Bortoli, L., Nicolas, M., Hillman, K., &amp; Buckley, S. (2011). Challenges for Australian education: Results from PISA 2009: The PISA 2009 assessment for students&#x2019; reading, mathematical and scientific literacy. PISA national reports. Available from: https://www.acer.org/files/PISA-Report-2009.pdf (Accessed 10 March 2020).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins, M., Noble, G., &amp; Wong, A. (Eds.). (2018). A review of the literature on the educational experiences of students of refugee backgrounds in Australia. In IT&#x2019;S COMPLEX! Working with Students of Refugee Backgrounds and their Families in New South Wales Public Schools. Surry Hills, NSW: New South Wales Teachers Federation.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>