<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39893774</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-8332</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>201</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lung cancer (Amsterdam, Netherlands)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lung Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>First-line nivolumab plus platinum chemotherapy and bevacizumab for advanced nonsquamous non-small cell lung cancer: A 3-year follow-up of the phase 3 randomized TASUKI-52 trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108109</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108109</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lungcan.2025.108109</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0169-5002(25)00030-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">In the randomized phase III TASUKI-52 trial, nivolumab with carboplatin, paclitaxel, and bevacizumab significantly prolonged the progression-free survival (PFS) of treatment-naive patients with advanced or recurrent nonsquamous non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Here, we report the long-term outcomes of patients treated with nivolumab plus carboplatin, paclitaxel, and bevacizumab with 3&#xa0;years of follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients with stage IIIB/IV or recurrent nonsquamous NSCLC without sensitizing EGFR, ALK, or ROS1 mutations were randomized (1:1) to receive either nivolumab or placebo, in addition to carboplatin, paclitaxel, and bevacizumab, every 3&#xa0;weeks. Treatment was continued for a maximum of six cycles. The endpoints included PFS, overall survival (OS), and safety. Exploratory analyses included efficacy and safety in subgroups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 550 patients were randomized to the nivolumab arm (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;275) and placebo arm (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;275). At the minimum follow-up of 36.1&#xa0;months, PFS was consistently longer in the nivolumab arm than in the placebo arm (median, 10.6 vs. 8.2 months; hazard ratio [HR], 0.59; 95&#xa0;% confidence interval [CI], 0.47-0.73; P&#xa0;&lt;&#xa0;0.0001), with PFS rates of 20.2&#xa0;% vs. 4.9&#xa0;%. The median OS was 31.6&#xa0;months (95&#xa0;% CI, 26.8-36.5) in the nivolumab arm and 24.7&#xa0;months (95&#xa0;% CI, 21.1-28.0) in the placebo arm (HR, 0.71; 95&#xa0;% CI, 0.57-0.88), with OS rates of 44.2&#xa0;% and 32.3&#xa0;%, respectively. Of note, PFS and OS favored the nivolumab arm across patients with different PD-L1 expression levels, and regardless of baseline brain metastasis status. Grade 3-4 treatment-related adverse events occurred in 76.2&#xa0;% and 74.9&#xa0;% of the patients in the nivolumab and placebo arms, respectively, while no new safety concerns were identified.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nivolumab, in addition to carboplatin, paclitaxel, and bevacizumab, remained to demonstrate significantly longer PFS and long-term OS benefit compared with placebo in the first-line treatment of patients with nonsquamous NSCLC. The extended follow-up identified no new safety signals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Ki Hyeong</ForeName><Initials>KH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Chungbuk National University Hospital, 776, 1Sunhwan-ro, Seowon-gu, Cheongju-si, Chungcheongbuk-do, South Korea. Electronic address: kihlee@chungbuk.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jong-Seok</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hematology and Medical Oncology, Department of Internal Medicine, Seoul National University Bundang Hospital, 82, Gumi-ro 173beon-gil, Bundang-gu, Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do, South Korea. Electronic address: jslee@snubh.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugawara</LastName><ForeName>Shunichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, 4-15, Hirosemachi, Aoba Ward, Sendai, Miyagi, Japan. Electronic address: swara357@sendai-kousei-hospital.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kang</LastName><ForeName>Jin Hyoung</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, The Catholic University of Korea Seoul St. Mary's Hospital, 222 Banpo-daero, Seocho-gu, Seoul, South Korea. Electronic address: oncologykang@naver.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hye Ryun</ForeName><Initials>HR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Medical Oncology, Yonsei Cancer Center, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Severance Hospital, Yonsei University Health System, 50-1 Yonsei-ro, Sinchon-dong, Seodaemun-gu, Seoul, South Korea. Electronic address: nobelg@yuhs.ac.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Inui</LastName><ForeName>Naoki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Hamamatsu University Hospital, 1 Chome-20-1 Handayama, Higashi Ward, Hamamatsu, Shizuoka, Japan. Electronic address: inui@hama-med.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hida</LastName><ForeName>Toyoaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Aichi Cancer Center, 1-1 Kanokoden, Chikusa Ward, Nagoya, Aichi, Japan. Electronic address: t-hida@cjimc-hp.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshida</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital, 5 Chome-1-1 Tsukiji, Chuo City, Tokyo, Japan. Electronic address: tatyoshi@ncc.go.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanaka</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Niigata Cancer Center Hospital, 2 Chome-15-3 Kawagishicho, Chuo Ward, Niigata, Japan. Electronic address: htanaka@niigata-cc.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Cheng-Ta</ForeName><Initials>CT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medicine, Chang Gung Memorial Hospital, 5, Fuxing Street, Guishan District, Taoyuan, Taiwan. Electronic address: yang1946@cgmh.org.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Inoue</LastName><ForeName>Takako</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Osaka International Cancer Institute, 3 Chome-1-69 Otemae, Chuo Ward, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: okuyama_trial@yahoo.co.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Makoto</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medical Oncology, Cancer Institute Hospital of Japanese Foundation for Cancer Research, 3 Chome-8-31 Ariake, Koto-ku, Tokyo, Japan. Electronic address: mnishio@jfcr.or.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ohe</LastName><ForeName>Yuichiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital, 5 Chome-1-1 Tsukiji, Chuo City, Tokyo, Japan. Electronic address: yohe@ncc.go.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tamura</LastName><ForeName>Tomohide</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Thoracic Center, St. Luke's International Hospital, 9-1 Akashicho, Chuo-ku, Tokyo, Japan. Electronic address: tamuratomohide@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, 811-1 Kimiidera, Wakayama-shi, Wakayama, Japan. Electronic address: nbyamamo@wakayama-med.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Chong-Jen</ForeName><Initials>CJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, National Taiwan University Hospital Hsin-Chu Branch, 2, Lane 442, Section 1, Jingguo Road, North District, Hsinchu City, Hsinchu County, Taiwan. Electronic address: jefferycjyu@ntu.edu.tw.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akamatsu</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, 811-1 Kimiidera, Wakayama-shi, Wakayama, Japan. Electronic address: h-akamat@wakayama-med.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Shigeru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncology Clinical Development Planning 1, Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 8-2, Kyutaromachi 1-chome, Chuo-ku, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: shig.takahashi@ono-pharma.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University, Faculty of Medicine, 377-2 Ohnohigashi, Osakasayama, Osaka, Japan. Electronic address: nakagawa@med.kindai.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Ireland</Country><MedlineTA>Lung Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8800805</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0169-5002</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>31YO63LBSN</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077594">Nivolumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>2S9ZZM9Q9V</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068258">Bevacizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>BG3F62OND5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016190">Carboplatin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>P88XT4IS4D</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017239">Paclitaxel</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>49DFR088MY</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010984">Platinum</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077594" MajorTopicYN="N">Nivolumab</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068258" MajorTopicYN="N">Bevacizumab</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016190" MajorTopicYN="N">Carboplatin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017239" MajorTopicYN="N">Paclitaxel</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009367" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Staging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010984" MajorTopicYN="N">Platinum</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Asian</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-squamous non-small cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PD-1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">PD-L1</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized controlled trial</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: All authors declared support for the current study from Ono and Bristol Myers Squibb (BMS). KHL reports grants from Merck Serono; consulting fees from Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme (MSD), Pfizer, Eli Lilly, Yuhan, AstraZeneca, and BMS. SS reports grants from Ono, BMS, AnHeart Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Chugai, MSD, Daiichi Sankyo, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, AbbVie, Amgen, Taiho, Takeda, and Clinipace; and honoraria from AstraZeneca, Chugai, Ono, BMS, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, Taiho, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Kyowa Kirin, Takeda, Nippon Kayaku, Merck, Amgen, AbbVie, Otsuka, Thermo Fisher Scientific, and Towa Pharmaceutical. J-HK reports grants from Ono; consulting fees from Daiichi Sankyo, Boehringer Ingelheim, Merck Serono, and AstraZeneca; honoraria from Boehringer Ingelheim, Bayer, and Pfizer; participation on an advisory board of Novartis, Yuhan, Daiichi Sankyo, and BeiGene. HRK received honoraria from AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Genentech/Roche, stock ownership in Bridgebio Therapeutics; served as a consultation or advisory role for Bayer, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Takeda, and Yuhan; and received research funding from the Yonsei Lee Youn Jae Fellowship outside of the current work. NI reports grants from Chugai, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, and Taiho; and honoraria from Chugai, Taiho, and AstraZeneca. TH reports honoraria from Ono and BMS. TY reports grants from Novartis, AbbVie, Amgen, Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca, MSD, Chugai, Astellas, Medpace, Boehringer Ingelheim, BMS, Ono, and Merck; honoraria from Novartis, Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca, MSD, Chugai, BMS, Ono, Takeda, Pfizer, Eli Lilly, and Merck; and participation on an advisory board in Novartis, MSD, Amge, Chugai, Pfizer, and Boehringer Ingelheim. HT reports grants from Ono, AstraZeneca, Chugai, MSD, BMS, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Takeda, Taiho, Merck, Boehringer Ingelheim, Amgen, and AbbVie; honoraria for lecture from Ono, AstraZeneca, Chugai, MSD, BMS, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Takeda, Taiho, Merck, Boehringer Ingelheim, Sun Pharmaceutical, Eisai, and Novartis. C-TY reports honoraria for lecture from AstraZeneca, Pfizer, Ono, MSD, Pfizer, Eli Lilly, and Roche; support from Takeda for attending a meeting and travel; and serving as the president of Taiwan Lung Cancer Society. TI reports payment for expert testimony from AstraZeneca, Chugai, BMS, Ono, and MSD. MN reports consulting fees from Ono and BMS; honoraria for lecture from Ono, Chugai, Taiho, BMS, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, AstraZeneca, MSD, AbbVie, Takeda, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Nippon Kayaku, Merck, and Janssen. YO reports grants from AstraZeneca, Chugai, Eli Lilly, Kirin, Sumitomo, Pfizer, Taiho, Novartis, Takeda, Kissei, Daiichi Sankyo, Janssen, and Loxo; honoraria from AstraZeneca, Chugai, Eli Lilly, Ono, BMS, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bayer, Pfizer, MSD, Taiho, Nippon Kayaku, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Eisai, and Daiichi Sankyo; payment for expert testimony from AstraZeneca, Chugai, Ono, BMS, Kyorin, Celltrion, Amgen, Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer Ingelheim, AnHeart Therapeutics, and PharmaMar; participation on an advisory board in Haihe Biopharma; and leaderships in Japanese Society of Medical Oncology, Japan Lung Cancer Society, and Japan Clinical Oncology Group. TT reports honoraria from Ono, Chugai, Eli Lilly, Cmic ShiftZero, Taiho, and Nihon Kayaku. NY reports grands from Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho, Chugai, Shionogi, Eli Lilly Japan, Daiichi Sankyo, Tsumura, Nippon Kayaku, Asahi Kasei Pharma, Janssen, Sanofi, Amgen, Novartis, Astellas, MSD, Eisai, BMS, AbbVie, and Tosoh; honoraria from MSD, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Ono, Otsuka, Guardant Health Japan, Tsumura, Kyowa Kirin, Kyorin, Glaxo Smith Kline, Sanofi, Daiichi Sankyo, Taiho, Takeda, Chugai, Eli Lilly Japan, Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Pfizer, BMS, Miyarisan, Merck, and Janssen; participation on an Advisory board of AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly Japan, and Takeda. HA reports grants from Amgen and Chugai; honoraria from Amgen, AstraZeneca K.K., Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, BMS, Chugai, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., MSD K.K., Nippon Kayaku, Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono, Pfizer, Takeda, and Taiho; participation on an advisory board in Amgen, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., and Sandoz. ST reports employment in Ono. KN reports honoraria from Amgen, MSD K.K., Ono, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis Pharma K.K., Pfizer Japan, BMS, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca K.K., Parexel International, PRA Health Science, EPS, Kissei, Taiho, PPD-SNBL K.K., SymBio Pharmaceuticals, IQVIA Services Japan, K.K., Syneos Health Clinical K.K., Nippon Kayaku, EP-CRSU, Mebix, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Astellas, Bayer Yakuhin, Eisai, Mochida Pharmaceutical, Labcorp Development Japan K.K. (Covance Japan Inc.), Japan Clinical Research Operations, Takeda, GlaxoSmithKline K.K., Sanofi K.K., Sysmex Corporation, Medical Research Support, Otsuka, SRI, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan GK., CMIC, Eisai, Shionogi, Kobayashi, and Ascent Development Services; consulting fees from Eli Lilly Japan K.K., and Ono; honoraria from Ono, Amgen, Nippon Kayaku, AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., MSD K.K., Pfizer Japan, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho, Bayar Yakuhin, Cmic ShiftZero K.K., Life Technologies Japan, Neo Communication, Daiichi Sankyo, Incyte Biosciences Japan, Merch Biopharma, Kyowa Kirin, Takeda, 3H Clinical Trial, Care Net, Medical Review, Medical Mobile Communication, Yodosha, Nikkei Business Publications, Japan Clinical Research Operations, Cmic, Novartis, Taiyo, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., and BMS K.K.; and a patent matter with Daiichi Sankyo.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39893774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2025.108109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0169-5002(25)00030-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>