<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40121197</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2041-1723</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature communications</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Commun</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Serum VEGF-A as a biomarker for the addition of bevacizumab to chemo-immunotherapy in metastatic NSCLC.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2825</StartPage><MedlinePgn>2825</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2825</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41467-025-58186-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Anti-vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) agents in combination with immunotherapies have improved outcomes for cancer patients, but predictive biomarkers have not been elucidated. We report here a preplanned analysis in the previously reported APPLE study, a phase 3 trial evaluating the efficacy of the bevacizumab in combination with atezolizumab, plus platinum chemotherapy in metastatic, nonsquamous non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). We investigated the correlation of serum VEGF-A and its isoforms at baseline with treatment response by using an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. We reveal that the addition of bevacizumab significantly improves the progression-free survival in patients with the low VEGF-A level. Our results demonstrate that measuring serum VEGF-A or its isoforms may identify NSCLC patients who are likely to benefit from the addition of bevacizumab to immunotherapy. These assays are easy to measure and have significant potential for further clinical development.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanaka</LastName><ForeName>Kentaro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4602-4465</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan. k9288090@kadai.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Kagoshima University, Kagoshima, Japan. k9288090@kadai.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Graduate School of Medical and Dental Sciences, Kagoshima University, Kagoshima, Japan. k9288090@kadai.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugisaka</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1000-0077</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, Sendai, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiraishi</LastName><ForeName>Yoshimasa</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watanabe</LastName><ForeName>Yasutaka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Saitama Cancer Center, Ina, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daga</LastName><ForeName>Haruko</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Osaka City General Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azuma</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respirology, Neurology, and Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kurume University School of Medicine, Kurume, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishino</LastName><ForeName>Kazumi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Osaka International Cancer Institute, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, NHO Osaka Toneyama Medical Center, Toyonaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ota</LastName><ForeName>Takayo</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1630-8301</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Breast Medical Oncology, Izumi City General Hospital, Izumi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saito</LastName><ForeName>Haruhiro</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Kanagawa Cancer Center, Yokohama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hata</LastName><ForeName>Akito</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Kobe Minimally Invasive Cancer Center, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Tadashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Center, Matsusaka Municipal Hospital, Matsusaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kozuki</LastName><ForeName>Toshiyuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology and Medicine, NHO Shikoku Cancer Center, Matsuyama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akamatsu</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Hirotaka</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hyogo Prefectural Amagasaki General Medical Center, Amagasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tachihara</LastName><ForeName>Motoko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respiratory Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakuda</LastName><ForeName>Kazushige</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Shizuoka Cancer Center Hospital, Nagaizumi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ozaki</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kishiwada City Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuchiya-Kawano</LastName><ForeName>Yuko</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kitakyushu Municipal Medical Center, Kitakyushu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology and Medicine, NHO Shikoku Cancer Center, Matsuyama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1284-9776</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okamoto</LastName><ForeName>Isamu</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Commun</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101528555</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2041-1723</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>2S9ZZM9Q9V</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068258">Bevacizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D042461">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014408">Biomarkers, Tumor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C467484">VEGFA protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>52CMI0WC3Y</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000594389">atezolizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068258" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bevacizumab</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042461" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014408" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biomarkers, Tumor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007167" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunotherapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077982" MajorTopicYN="N">Progression-Free Survival</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009362" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Metastasis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Competing interests: K.T. has received personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Merck, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, MSD, Novartis and Bristol Myers Squibb outside the submitted work. Y Shiraishi has received personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical and Bristol Myers Squibb outside the submitted work. H.D. has received personal fees from AstraZeneca outside the submitted work. K.A. has received personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical, MSD, AstraZeneca, and Bristol Myers Squibb outside the submitted work. K.N. has received grants from Ono Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, MSD, AbbVie, Daiichi Sankyo, Amgen, Eisai, Sanofi, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Novartis, Pfizer, Eli Lilly, Merck, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Chugai Pharmaceutical and AstraZeneca; and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Pfizer, Merck, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb and Nihon Kayaku outside the submitted work. M M. has received personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Daiichi-Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, MSD, Nihon Kayaku, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical and AbbVie outside the submitted work. H.S. has received grants from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical and Bristol Myers Squibb; and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical and Bristol Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim and Pfizer outside the submitted work. A.H. has received grants from MSD, Eli Lilly, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim and AstraZeneca; and personal fees from MSD, Eli Lilly, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer and AstraZeneca outside the submitted work. T.S. has received personal fees from MSD, Eli Lilly, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Merck, Ono Pharmaceutical and AstraZeneca outside the submitted work. T.K. has received grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Merck, Daiichi-Sankyo, Amgen, Abbvie, Sanofi, Labcorp development Japan, IQVIA Services Japan, Gilead Sciences, Pfizer and Bayer; consulting fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Daiichi-Sankyo, Bayer and Abbvie; and personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Pfizer, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Boehringer Ingelheim, Merck, Nihon Kayaku, Novartis, Daiichi-Sankyo, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Bayer, Sawai, Amgen and Eisai outside the submitted work. H.A. has received grants from Amgen, Boehringer Ingelheim; personal fees from Amgen, Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Merck, Nihon Kayaku, Novartis, Daiichi-Sankyo, Takeda Pharmaceutical; fees for membership of an advisory board for Amgen, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Sandoz and MSD outside the submitted work. H.M. has personal fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono Pharmaceutical, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical and MSD outside the submitted work. M.T. has received grants from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical and Eli Lilly; personal fees from Eli Lilly, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, MSD, Novartis pharmaceuticals, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Daiichi Sankyo, Pfizer and Janssen Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. K.W. has received grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Novartis, Abbvie, Amgen, MSD and Daiichi Sankyo; personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, AstraZeneca, Daiichi Sankyo, Janssen Pharmaceutical and Takeda Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Y Sato has received personal fees from AstraZeneca, MSD, Novartis, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Nihon Kayaku, Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Takeda, Kyowa Hakko Kirin and Daiichi Sankyo outside the submitted work. Y. T. K. has received personal fees from Bristol Myers Squibb, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical and Takeda Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. N.Y. has received grants from Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Shionogi, Eli Lilly, Daiichi Sankyo, Tumura, Nihon Kayaku, Asahikasei-pharma, AstraZeneca, Janssen, Sanofi, Amgen, Novartis, Astellas, MSD, Esai, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Abbvie and Tosoh; and personal fees from MSD, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Ono Pharmaceutical, Otsuka, Guardant Health Japan, Tumura, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Kyorin, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Daiichi Sankyo, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Takeda, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly, Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Pfizer, Bristol Myers Squibb, Miyarisan, Merck and Janssen; and fees for membership of a data safety monitoring board or an advisory board from AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, and Takeda outside the submitted work. K.N. has received grants from AstraZeneca, SD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Pfizer, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Merck, PAREXEL International, PRA HEALTHSCIENCES, EPS Corporation., Kissei Pharmaceutical, EPS International, Taiho Pharmaceutical, PPD-SNBL, SymBio Pharmaceuticals, IQVIA Services JAPAN, SYNEOS HEALTH CLINICAL, Nihon Kayaku, EP-CRSU, Mebix, Janssen, AbbVie, Bayer, Eisai, Mochida Pharmaceutical, Covance Japan, Japan Clinical Research Operations, Takeda, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Sysmex, Medical Reserch Support, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, SRL, and Amgen; and consulting fees from Eli Lilly, Kyorin Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical and Pfizer; and personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical, Amgen, Nippon Kayaku, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly, MSD, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bayer, CMIC ShiftZero, Life Technologies Japan, Neo Communication, Roche Diagnostics, AbbVie, Merck, Kyowa hakko Kirin, Takeda, 3H Clinical Trial, Care Net, Medical Review, Medical Mobile Communications, YODOSHA, Nikkei Business Publications, Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC, Novartis, TAIYO Pharma, Kyorin Pharmaceutical, and Bristol-Myers Squibb; and patents from Daiichi Sankyo outside submitted work. I.O. has received grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Eli Lilly, Astellas, Bristol Myers Squibb, Novartis, Pfizer, and AbbVie; and consulting fee from AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, and AbbVie; and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Eli Lilly, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Novartis, and Pfizer outside the submitted work. J.S., T Ota and T Ozaki declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40121197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11929838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-025-58186-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41467-025-58186-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gettinger, S. et al. Five-year follow-up of nivolumab in previously treated advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: results from the CA209-003 study. <i>J. Clin. Oncol.</i><b>36</b>, 1675&#x2013;1684 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29570421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chamoto, K., Hatae, R. &amp; Honjo, T. Current issues and perspectives in PD-1 blockade cancer immunotherapy. <i>Int. J. Clin. Oncol.</i><b>25</b>, 790&#x2013;800 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7192862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31900651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reck, M. et al. Pembrolizumab versus chemotherapy for PD-L1-positive non-small-cell lung cancer. <i>New Engl. J. Med.</i><b>375</b>, 1823&#x2013;1833 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27718847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gandhi, L. et al. Pembrolizumab plus chemotherapy in metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer. <i>New Engl. J. Med.</i><b>378</b>, 2078&#x2013;2092 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz-Ares, L. et al. Pembrolizumab plus chemotherapy for squamous non-small-cell lung cancer. <i>New Engl. J. Med.</i><b>379</b>, 2040&#x2013;2051 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30280635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West, H. et al. Atezolizumab in combination with carboplatin plus nab-paclitaxel chemotherapy compared with chemotherapy alone as first-line treatment for metastatic non-squamous non-small-cell lung cancer (IMpower130): a multicentre, randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial. <i>Lancet Oncol.</i><b>20</b>, 924&#x2013;937 (2019).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31122901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forde, P. M. et al. Neoadjuvant nivolumab plus chemotherapy in resectable lung cancer. <i>New Engl. J. Med.</i><b>386</b>, 1973&#x2013;1985 (2022).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9844511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35403841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heymach, J. V. et al. Perioperative durvalumab for resectable non-small-cell lung cancer. <i>New Engl. J. Med.</i><b>389</b>, 1672&#x2013;1684 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37870974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz-Ares, L. et al. First-line nivolumab plus ipilimumab combined with two cycles of chemotherapy in patients with non-small-cell lung cancer (CheckMate 9LA): an international, randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial. <i>Lancet Oncol.</i><b>22</b>, 198&#x2013;211 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33476593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson, M. L. et al. Durvalumab with or without tremelimumab in combination with chemotherapy as first-line therapy for metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer: the phase III POSEIDON study. <i>J. Clin. Oncol.</i><b>41</b>, 1213&#x2013;1227 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9937097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36327426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan, D. S. W. et al. Canakinumab versus placebo in combination with first-line pembrolizumab plus chemotherapy for advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: results from the CANOPY-1 trial. <i>J. Clin. Oncol.</i><b>42</b>, 192&#x2013;204 (2024).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38039427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel, S. A. et al. Molecular mechanisms and future implications of VEGF/VEGFR in cancer therapy. <i>Clin. Cancer Res.</i><b>29</b>, 30&#x2013;39 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10274152</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35969170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabrilovich, D. I. et al. Production of vascular endothelial growth factor by human tumors inhibits the functional maturation of dendritic cells. <i>Nat. Med.</i><b>2</b>, 1096&#x2013;1103 (1996).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8837607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dikov, M. M. et al. Differential roles of vascular endothelial growth factor receptors 1 and 2 in dendritic cell differentiation. <i>J. Immunol.</i><b>174</b>, 215&#x2013;222 (2005).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15611243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voron, T. et al. VEGF-A modulates expression of inhibitory checkpoints on CD8+ T cells in tumors. <i>J. Exp. Med.</i><b>212</b>, 139&#x2013;148 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4322048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker, K. H., Beury, D. W. &amp; Ostrand-Rosenberg, S. Myeloid-derived suppressor cells: critical cells driving immune suppression in the tumor microenvironment. <i>Adv. Cancer Res.</i><b>128</b>, 95&#x2013;139 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4662416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26216631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Socinski, M. A. et al. Atezolizumab for first-line treatment of metastatic nonsquamous NSCLC. <i>New Engl. J. Med.</i><b>378</b>, 2288&#x2013;2301 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29863955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finn, R. S. et al. Atezolizumab plus bevacizumab in unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma. <i>New Engl. J. Med.</i><b>382</b>, 1894&#x2013;1905 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32402160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiraishi, Y. et al. Atezolizumab and platinum plus pemetrexed with or without bevacizumab for metastatic nonsquamous non-small cell lung cancer: a phase 3 randomized clinical trial. <i>JAMA Oncol.</i><b>10</b>, 315&#x2013;324 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10739077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38127362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamakuchi, M. et al. VEGF-A165 is the predominant VEGF-A isoform in platelets, while VEGF-A121 is abundant in serum and plasma from healthy individuals. <i>PLoS ONE</i><b>18</b>, e0284131 (2023).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10081782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37027444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegde, P. S. et al. Predictive impact of circulating vascular endothelial growth factor in four phase III trials evaluating bevacizumab. <i>Clin. Cancer Res.</i><b>19</b>, 929&#x2013;937 (2013).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23169435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Cutsem, E. et al. Bevacizumab in combination with chemotherapy as first-line therapy in advanced gastric cancer: a biomarker evaluation from the AVAGAST randomized phase III trial. <i>J. Clin. Oncol.</i><b>30</b>, 2119&#x2013;2127 (2012).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22565005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miles, D. et al. Bevacizumab plus paclitaxel versus placebo plus paclitaxel as first-line therapy for HER2-negative metastatic breast cancer (MERiDiAN): a double-blind placebo-controlled randomised phase III trial with prospective biomarker evaluation. <i>Eur. J. Cancer</i><b>70</b>, 146&#x2013;155 (2017).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27817944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandler, A. et al. Paclitaxel-carboplatin alone or with bevacizumab for non-small-cell lung cancer. <i>New Engl. J. Med.</i><b>355</b>, 2542&#x2013;2550 (2006).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrara, N., Gerber, H. P. &amp; LeCouter, J. The biology of VEGF and its receptors. <i>Nat. Med.</i><b>9</b>, 669&#x2013;676 (2003).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12778165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrer, A. et al. Neuropilin-1 identifies a subset of bone marrow Gr1- monocytes that can induce tumor vessel normalization and inhibit tumor growth. <i>Cancer Res.</i><b>72</b>, 6371&#x2013;6381 (2012).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23222303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazemi, M. et al. VEGF121 and VEGF165 differentially promote vessel maturation and tumor growth in mice and humans. <i>Cancer Gene Ther.</i><b>23</b>, 125&#x2013;132 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27033458</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung, M. S. et al. Epidermal growth factor receptor mutation enhances expression of vascular endothelial growth factor in lung cancer. <i>Oncol. Lett.</i><b>12</b>, 4598&#x2013;4604 (2016).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5228119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28101216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooney, M. S., Shukla, S. A., Wu, C. J., Getz, G. &amp; Hacohen, N. Molecular and genetic properties of tumors associated with local immune cytolytic activity. <i>Cell</i><b>160</b>, 48&#x2013;61 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4856474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25594174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito, M. et al. Development of lung adenocarcinomas with exclusive dependence on oncogene fusions. <i>Cancer Res.</i><b>75</b>, 2264&#x2013;2271 (2015).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25855381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugiyama, E. et al. Blockade of EGFR improves responsiveness to PD-1 blockade in EGFR-mutated non-small cell lung cancer. <i>Sci. Immunol</i>. <b>5</b>, eaav3937 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32005679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schalper, K. A. et al. Elevated serum interleukin-8 is associated with enhanced intratumor neutrophils and reduced clinical benefit of immune-checkpoint inhibitors. <i>Nat. Med.</i><b>26</b>, 688&#x2013;692 (2020).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8127102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32405062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariathasan, S. et al. TGFbeta attenuates tumour response to PD-L1 blockade by contributing to exclusion of T cells. <i>Nature</i><b>554</b>, 544&#x2013;548 (2018).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6028240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29443960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinter, M., Jain, R. K. &amp; Duda, D. G. The current landscape of immune checkpoint blockade in hepatocellular carcinoma: a review. <i>JAMA Oncol.</i><b>7</b>, 113&#x2013;123 (2021).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8265820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33090190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>