<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40336674</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-3643</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JTO clinical and research reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JTO Clin Res Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Intensity-Modulated Radiotherapy for Locally Advanced Lung Cancer in the Immunotherapy Era: A Prospective Study WJOG12019L.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100828</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100828</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100828</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2025.100828</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Chemoradiotherapy (CRT) followed by durvalumab is the standard of care for unresectable locally advanced NSCLC. Limited prospective data have been reported on intensity-modulated radiotherapy (IMRT)-adapted CRT in the immunotherapy era.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this multicenter prospective observational study, patients underwent IMRT-adapted CRT (platinum-doublet chemotherapy plus 60 Gy IMRT in 30 fractions under a prespecified radiation protocol), followed by consolidative durvalumab. The primary outcome was the durvalumab introduction rate within 42 days post-CRT.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Thirty-two patients with unresectable locally advanced NSCLC were enrolled between November 2019 and February 2021. Among the 28 evaluable cases, durvalumab was introduced in 24 (85.7%, 90% confidence interval: 70.2%-95.0%) of 28 patients after CRT, achieving the primary end point. All 29 patients who received IMRT completed the scheduled 60 Gy radiotherapy dose. One year of durvalumab treatment was completed in 12 of 24 patients (50%). In the 24 patients who were durvalumab-introduced, the median progression-free survival and overall survival were 20.9 (95% confidence interval: 6.9-not evaluable) months and not reached, respectively. Two-year progression-free survival and overall survival rates were 44% and 73%, respectively. Among the 29 patients in the safety analysis set, there were no treatment-related deaths or grade 4 nonhematological adverse events. Pneumonitis grade 1 was observed in 13 patients (45%), grade 2 in seven (24%), and grade 3 in one (3%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">High durvalumab introduction rate was reported after the completion of IMRT-adapted CRT under a prespecified radiation protocol. Its efficacy has been suggested, with favorable safety profiles, including a low incidence of severe pneumonitis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">University Hospital Medical Information Network database ID: UMIN000038366.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harada</LastName><ForeName>Hideyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiation and Proton Therapy Center, Shizuoka Cancer Center, Nagaizumi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hata</LastName><ForeName>Akito</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Kobe Minimally Invasive Cancer Center, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Konno</LastName><ForeName>Masahiro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiation and Proton Therapy Center, Shizuoka Cancer Center, Nagaizumi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mamesaya</LastName><ForeName>Nobuaki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Shizuoka Cancer Center, Nagaizumi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamatsu</LastName><ForeName>Kiyoshi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haratani</LastName><ForeName>Koji</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Takaya</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Tohoku University Graduate School of Medicine, Sendai, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saito</LastName><ForeName>Ryota</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Tohoku University Graduate School of Medicine, Sendai, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mayahara</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Kobe Minimally Invasive Cancer Center, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kokubo</LastName><ForeName>Masaki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Imano</LastName><ForeName>Nobuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Hiroshima University Hospital, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masuda</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hiroshima University Hospital, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukuda</LastName><ForeName>Haruyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Osaka Saiseikai Nakatsu Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sado</LastName><ForeName>Toshikatsu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Osaka Saiseikai Nakatsu Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshimura</LastName><ForeName>Kenichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Health Data Science, Graduate School of Medical Science, Nagoya City University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishimura</LastName><ForeName>Yasumasa</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Radiation Therapy Center, Fuchu Hospital, Izumi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okamoto</LastName><ForeName>Isamu</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JTO Clin Res Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101769967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-3643</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemoradiotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Durvalumab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intensity-modulated radiation therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Dr. Harada has received personal fees from AstraZeneca, Accuray, Chugai, Takeda, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Pfizer, Brainlab, Hitachi, Novartis, Guerbet Japan, GE Healthcare, Nihon Medi-Physics, and Taiho. Dr. Hata has received grants from Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Eli Lilly, Chugai, Taiho, Boehringer Ingelheim, AstraZeneca, AbbVie, and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Chugai, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, and Taiho. Dr. Mamesaya has received grants from 10.13039/100009947Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Chugai, Arrivent Biopharma, and personal fees from Chugai, Boehringer Ingelheim, AstraZeneca, Taiho, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Ono, and Novartis. Dr. Haratani has received grants from 10.13039/100004325AstraZeneca, Mochida Memorial Foundation, 10.13039/100008731Nakatomi Foundation, 10.13039/501100008880KANAE Foundation for the Promotion of Medical Science, Osaka Cancer Society, SGH Foundation, YOKOYAMA Foundation for Clinical Pharmacology, Takeda Science Foundation, The Osaka Medical Research Foundation for Intractable Disease, and personal fees from AstraZeneca; Dr. Yamamoto has received personal fees from AstraZeneca, Amgen, AiRato Inc., and Takeda. Dr. Saito has received personal fees from AstraZeneca, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Chugai, and Taiho. Dr. Mayahara has received personal fees from AstraZeneca. Dr. Kokubo has received personal fees from AstraZeneca, Varian, Daiichi Sankyo, and Hitachi. Dr. Sato has received personal fees from AstraZeneca, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Chugai, Ono, Pfizer, Taiho, Nippon Kayaku, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Takeda, Kyowa Kirin, Daiichi Sankyo, and Boehringer Ingelheim. Dr. Masuda has received personal fees from Daiichi Sankyo, Taiho, Boehringer Ingelheim, Kyowa Kirin, Ono, Eli Lilly, Otsuka, Chugai, and AstraZeneca. Dr. Yoshimura has received personal fees from AstraZeneca. Dr. Nakagawa has received grants from AstraZeneca, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Ono, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Pfizer, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Merck, Parexel International, PRA Health Sciences, EPS Corporation., Kissei, EPS International, Taiho, PPD-SNBL, SymBio, IQVIA Services Japan, Syneos Health Clinical, Nippon Kayaku, EP-CRSU, Mebix, Janssen, AbbVie, Bayer, Eisai, Mochida, Covance Japan, Japan Clinical Research Operations, Takeda, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Sysmex, Medical Reserch Support, Otsuka, SRL, Amgen, personal fees from Ono, Amgen, Nippon Kayaku, AstraZeneca, Chugai, Eli Lilly, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho, Bayer, CMIC ShiftZero, Life Technologies Japan, Neo Communication, Roche Diagnostics, AbbVie, Merck, Kyowa hakko Kirin, Takeda, 3H Clinical Trial, Care Net, Medical Review, Medical Mobile Communications, YODOSHA, Nikkei Business Publications, Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC, Novartis, Taiyo Pharma, Kyorin Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, and patents from Daiichi Sankyo. Dr. Okamoto has received grants from AstraZeneca, Taiho, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Eli Lilly, Astellas, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Novartis, Pfizer, AbbVie, and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Taiho, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Eli Lilly, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Novartis, Pfizer, and AbbVie. Dr. Yamamoto has received grants from Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho, 10.13039/100010795Chugai, 10.13039/501100005612Shionogi, Eli Lilly, Daiichi Sankyo, 10.13039/501100013420Tsumura, 10.13039/100018046Nippon Kayaku, Asahikasei-pharma, AstraZeneca, Janssen, Sanofi, Amgen, Novartis, Astellas, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Esai, Bristol-Myers Squibb, AbbVie, Tosoh, and personal fees from Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Ono, Otsuka, Guardant Health Japan, Tsumura, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Kyorin, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Daiichi Sankyo, Taiho, Takeda, Chugai, Eli Lilly, Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Pfizer, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Miyarisan, Merck, and Janssen. The remaining authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40336674</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12053000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2025.100828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-3643(25)00044-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Antonia S.J., Villegas A., Daniel D., et al. Durvalumab after chemoradiotherapy in stage III non-small-cell lung cancer. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2017;377:1919&#x2013;1929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28885881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonia S.J., Villegas A., Daniel D., et al. Overall survival with durvalumab after chemoradiotherapy in stage III NSCLC. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2018;379:2342&#x2013;2350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30280658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosoya K., Fujimoto D., Kawachi H., et al. Ineligibility for the PACIFIC trial in unresectable stage III non-small cell lung cancer patients. Cancer Chemother Pharmacol. 2019;84:275&#x2013;280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31201490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakaguchi T., Ito K., Furuhashi K., et al. Patients with unresectable stage III non-small cell lung cancer eligible to receive consolidation therapy with durvalumab in clinical practice based on PACIFIC study criteria. Respir Investig. 2019;57:466&#x2013;471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31104989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun S.G., Hu C., Choy H., et al. Impact of intensity-modulated radiation therapy technique for locally advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: A secondary analysis of the NRG oncology RTOG 0617 randomized clinical trial. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2017;35:56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5455690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28034064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun S.G., Hu C., Komaki R.U., et al. Long-term prospective outcomes of intensity modulated radiotherapy for locally advanced lung cancer: A secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Oncol. 2024;10:1111&#x2013;1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11211986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38935373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu X., He W., Wen S., et al. Is IMRT superior or inferior to 3DCRT in radiotherapy for NSCLC? A meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2016;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4839644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27100968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsukita Y., Yamamoto T., Mayahara H., et al. Intensity-modulated radiation therapy with concurrent chemotherapy followed by durvalumab for stage III non-small cell lung cancer: a multi-center retrospective study. Radiother Oncol. 2021;160:266&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34023330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuo M., Shinohara E., Kitano M., et al. A&#xa0;comparison of the incidence of &#x2265; grade 2 radiation pneumonitis between intensity-modulated radiotherapy and three-dimensional conformal radiotherapy in patients with unresectable non-small cell lung cancer treated with durvalumab after concurrent chemoradiotherapy. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2024;54:312&#x2013;318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38010609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spigel D.R., Faivre-Finn C., Gray J.E., et al. Five-year survival outcomes from the PACIFIC trial: durvalumab after chemoradiotherapy in stage III non-small-cell lung cancer. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2022;40:1301&#x2013;1311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9015199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35108059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto N., Nakagawa K., Nishimura Y., et al. Phase III study comparing second- and third-generation regimens with concurrent thoracic radiotherapy in patients with unresectable stage III non-small-cell lung cancer: West Japan Thoracic Oncology Group WJTOG0105. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2010;28:3739&#x2013;3745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20625120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>