<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40462299</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1598-9100</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Intestinal research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Intest Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The duration of prior anti-tumor necrosis factor agents is associated with the effectiveness of vedolizumab in patients with ulcerative colitis: a real-world multicenter retrospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>281</StartPage><EndPage>292</EndPage><MedlinePgn>281-292</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5217/ir.2024.00126</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND/AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Previous literature suggests that the response of patients with ulcerative colitis to vedolizumab may be affected by previous biologic therapy exposure. This real-world study evaluated vedolizumab treatment effectiveness in biologicnon-na&#xef;ve patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a multicenter, retrospective, observational chart review of records from 16 hospitals in Japan (December 1, 2018, to February 29, 2020). Included patients who had ulcerative colitis, were aged &#x2265; 20 years, and received at least 1 dose of vedolizumab. Outcomes included clinical remission rates from weeks 2 to 54 according to prior biologic exposure status and factors associated with clinical remission up to week 54.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 370 eligible patients were included. Clinical remission rates were significantly higher in biologic-na&#xef;ve (n=197) than in biologic-non-na&#xef;ve (n=173) patients for weeks 2 to 54 of vedolizumab treatment. Higher clinical remission rates up to week 54 were significantly associated with lower disease severity (partial Mayo score &#x2264; 4, P= 0.001; albumin &#x2265; 3.0, P= 0.019) and the duration of prior anti-tumor necrosis factor &#x3b1; (anti-TNF&#x3b1;) therapy (P= 0.026). Patients with anti-TNF&#x3b1; therapy durations of &lt; 3 months, 3 to &lt; 12 months, and &#x2265; 12 months had clinical remission rates of 28.1%, 32.7%, and 60.0%, respectively (P= 0.001 across groups).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The effectiveness of vedolizumab in biologic-non-na&#xef;ve patients was significantly influenced by duration of prior anti-TNF&#x3b1; therapy. (Japanese Registry of Clinical Trials: jRCT-1080225363).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobayashi</LastName><ForeName>Taku</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced IBD Research and Treatment, Kitasato University Kitasato Institute Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hisamatsu</LastName><ForeName>Tadakazu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Kyorin University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Motoya</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inflammatory Bowel Disease Center, Sapporo-Kosei General Hospital, Sapporo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsuura</LastName><ForeName>Minoru</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Kyorin University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujii</LastName><ForeName>Toshimitsu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Institute of Science Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kunisaki</LastName><ForeName>Reiko</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inflammatory Bowel Disease Center, Yokohama City University Medical Center, Yokohama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shibuya</LastName><ForeName>Tomoyoshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Juntendo University School of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takeuchi</LastName><ForeName>Ken</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, IBD Center, Tsujinaka Hospital Kashiwanoha, Kashiwa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hiraoka</LastName><ForeName>Sakiko</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Okayama University Hospital, Okayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yasuda</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, St. Marianna University School of Medicine, Kawasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokoyama</LastName><ForeName>Kaoru</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Kitasato University School of Medicine, Sagamihara, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takatsu</LastName><ForeName>Noritaka</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inflammatory Bowel Disease Center, Fukuoka University Chikushi Hospital, Chikushino, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maemoto</LastName><ForeName>Atsuo</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inflammatory Bowel Disease Center, Sapporo Higashi Tokushukai Hospital, Sapporo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tahara</LastName><ForeName>Toshiyuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Saiseikai Utsunomiya Hospital, Utsunomiya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tominaga</LastName><ForeName>Keiichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Dokkyo Medical University, Mibu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimada</LastName><ForeName>Masaaki</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, NHO Nagoya Medical Center, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuno</LastName><ForeName>Nobuaki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Medicine, Fukuoka University Hospital, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cavaliere</LastName><ForeName>Mary</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Medical Office, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishiguro</LastName><ForeName>Kaori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Medical Office, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fernandez</LastName><ForeName>Jovelle L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Medical Office, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hibi</LastName><ForeName>Toshifumi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Advanced IBD Research and Treatment, Kitasato University Kitasato Institute Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Intest Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101572802</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1598-9100</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Colitis, ulcerative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Real-world evidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sequencing</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor necrosis factor-alpha</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vedolizumab</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>
<b>Conflict of Interest</b>
. Kobayashi T reports grants/contracts from AbbVie GK, Activaid, Alfresa Pharma Corporation, Bristol Myers Squibb, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Ferring Pharmaceuticals, Gilead Sciences, Inc., Google Asia Pacific Pte. Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., JIMRO Co., Ltd., JMDC Inc., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Otsuka Holdings, Pfizer Japan Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, Activaid, Alfresa Pharma Corporation, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., JIMRO Co., Ltd., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., Thermo Fisher Diagnostics K.K., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; and payment for expert testimony from AbbVie GK, Activaid, Alfresa Pharma Corporation, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Galapagos, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. Hisamatsu T reports grants/contracts from AbbVie GK, Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., JIMRO Co., Ltd., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Pfizer Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; advisory fees from AbbVie GK, Bristol Myers Squibb, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly and Company, Gilead Sciences, Inc., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Nichi-Iko Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Inc., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; and payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., JIMRO Co., Ltd., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Pfizer Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Motoya S reports grants/contracts from Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K.; and payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, and Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Matsuura M reports consulting fees from AbbVie GK, Pfizer Japan Inc., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; and payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., JIMRO Co., Ltd., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Viatris Inc., and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Fujii T reports grants/contracts from AbbVie GK, Alfresa Pharma Corporation, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene Corporation, Celltrion Healthcare, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly and Company, Gilead Sciences, Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mebix, Inc., Sanofi, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; payment for lectures/presentations and speaker bureaus from AbbVie GK, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nichi-Iko Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Pfizer Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; and is a councillor for the Japanese Society of Gastroenterology. Kunisaki R reports support from Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited for the present manuscript; grants/contracts from AbbVie GK and Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K.; consulting fees from Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd.; payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Pfizer Inc., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; and participation on a data safety monitoring board/advisory board for Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd. Shibuya T reports support from Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited for the present manuscript. Takeuchi K reports grants/contracts from AbbVie GK, Amgen K.K., AstraZeneca K.K., Bristol Myers Squibb K.K., EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Ferring Pharmaceuticals, Iqvia Inc., Nippon Shinyaku Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; consulting fees from Thermo Fisher Diagnostics K.K.; payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, Ayumi Pharmaceutical Corporation, Celltrion Healthcare, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Gilead Sciences, Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., JIMRO Co., Ltd., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Otsuka Holdings, Pfizer Japan Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Viatris Inc., and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Hiraoka S reports payments/honoraria (lecture fees) from AbbVie GK, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. Yasuda H reports grants/contracts from Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., and support from Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited for the present manuscript. Yokoyama K reports payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Gilead Sciences, Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. Maemoto A reports support from Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited for the present manuscript; grants/contracts from AbbVie GK, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Gilead Sciences, Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Kaken Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan K.K., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; and payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., JIMRO Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. Cavaliere M was an employee of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited at the time of the study. Ishiguro K was an employee of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited at the time of the study. Fernandez JL was an employee of Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited at the time of the study and reports stock or share ownership in Cococell Nanotech, Inc., GlaxoSmithKline, Immunorock Co., Ltd., Mirai Biotech Inc., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; and other financial interests in Jovelle Fernandez LLC. Hibi T reports grants/contracts from AbbVie GK, Activaid, Alfresa Pharma Corporation, Celltrion Healthcare, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Gilead Sciences, Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., JMDC Inc., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Nichi-Iko Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; payments/honoraria from AbbVie GK, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., JIMRO Co., Ltd., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Inc., Sandoz K.K., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Zeria Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; and payment for expert testimony from AbbVie GK, Celltrion Healthcare, EA Pharma Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Gilead Sciences, Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma Corporation, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. Hibi T is on the Editorial Board of Intestinal Research and recused himself from all editorial decisions pertaining to this manuscript. Takatsu N, Tahara T, Tominaga K, Shimada M, and Kuno N have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40462299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13153848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5217/ir.2024.00126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ir.2024.00126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Armuzzi A, Liguori G. Quality of life in patients with moderate to severe ulcerative colitis and the impact of treatment: a narrative review. Dig Liver Dis. 2021;53:803&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33744172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raine T, Bonovas S, Burisch J, et al. ECCO guidelines on therapeutics in ulcerative colitis: medical treatment. J Crohns Colitis. 2022;16:2&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34635919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roda G, Jharap B, Neeraj N, Colombel JF. Loss of response to anti-TNFs: definition, epidemiology, and management. Clin Transl Gastroenterol. 2016;7:e135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4737871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26741065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soler D, Chapman T, Yang LL, Wyant T, Egan R, Fedyk ER. The binding specificity and selective antagonism of vedolizumab, an anti-alpha4beta7 integrin therapeutic antibody in development for inflammatory bowel diseases. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2009;330:864&#x2013;875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19509315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feagan BG, Rutgeerts P, Sands BE, et al. Vedolizumab as induction and maintenance therapy for ulcerative colitis. N Engl J Med. 2013;369:699&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23964932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attauabi M, Madsen GR, Bendtsen F, Seidelin JB, Burisch J. Vedolizumab as the first line of biologic therapy for ulcerative colitis and Crohn&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review with meta-analysis. Dig Liver Dis. 2022;54:1168&#x2013;1178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34903497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pulusu SSR, Srinivasan A, Krishnaprasad K, et al. Vedolizumab for ulcerative colitis: real world outcomes from a multicenter observational cohort of Australia and Oxford. World J Gastroenterol. 2020;26:4428&#x2013;4441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7438197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumgart DC, Bokemeyer B, Drabik A, Stallmach A, Schreiber S; Vedolizumab Germany Consortium. Vedolizumab induction therapy for inflammatory bowel disease in clinical practice: a nationwide consecutive German cohort study. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2016;43:1090&#x2013;1102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27038247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feuerstein JD, Isaacs KL, Schneider Y, et al. AGA Clinical Practice Guidelines on the management of moderate to severe ulcerative colitis. Gastroenterology. 2020;158:1450&#x2013;1461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7175923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31945371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reenaers C, Cremer A, Dewit O, et al. Effectiveness and persistence of vedolizumab in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: results from the Belgian REal-LIfe study with VEdolizumab (Be-RELIVE) Acta Gastroenterol Belg. 2020;83:15&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32233267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim HH, Chan PW, Chuah SW, Schwender BJ, Kong SC, Ling KL. A review of vedolizumab and ustekinumab for the treatment of inflammatory bowel diseases. JGH Open. 2018;2:223&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6207060</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30483594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, George J, Boland BS, Vande Casteele N, Sandborn WJ. Primary non-response to tumor necrosis factor antagonists is associated with inferior response to second-line biologics in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Crohns Colitis. 2018;12:635&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7189966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29370397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>