<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40632416</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1436-3305</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>28</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Gastric cancer : official journal of the International Gastric Cancer Association and the Japanese Gastric Cancer Association</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Gastric Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>An observational study of the effectiveness and safety of nivolumab plus chemotherapy for untreated advanced or recurrent gastric cancer in Japanese real-world settings: the G-KNIGHT study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>955</StartPage><EndPage>967</EndPage><MedlinePgn>955-967</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10120-025-01641-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Nivolumab plus chemotherapy has shown efficacy in clinical trials for advanced or recurrent gastric cancer (GC). However, real-world utilization data are limited. In this study, we aimed to assess the effectiveness, safety, and treatment status of first line nivolumab plus chemotherapy in Japanese patients with treatment-na&#xef;ve advanced or recurrent GC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Untreated patients with advanced or recurrent GC who initiated nivolumab plus chemotherapy as first line treatment from November 2021 to June 2023 across 23 Japanese sites were enrolled in this observational study (G-KNIGHT). This report focused on the objective response rate (ORR), real-world progression-free survival (rwPFS), and the treatment-related adverse event (TRAE) incidence. Furthermore, subgroup analyses for ORR and rwPFS were conducted for patients stratified by various factors including age and the programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1) combined positive score (CPS).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Among 527 patients (median age, 70.3&#xa0;years; 25.2% aged&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;75&#xa0;years; 65.5% male; 84.3% with advanced GC), the median follow-up period was 10.4 (interquartile range, 6.7-15.2) months. The ORR was 65.6% (95% confidence interval [CI], 59.9-70.9%). The median rwPFS (months, 95% CI) was 6.9 (6.2-7.6); by subgroups: age&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;75&#xa0;years, 6.7 (6.0-7.5); age&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;75&#xa0;years, 7.4 (6.2-8.6); PD-L1 CPS&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;1, 7.5 (6.5-9.0); CPS 1-5, 6.2 (5.5-8.0); and CPS&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;5, 7.0 (6.2-8.2). TRAEs occurred in 91.3% of patients, with 40.4% experiencing grade&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;3 events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This large-scale real-world study supports the effectiveness and safety of nivolumab plus chemotherapy in untreated Japanese patients with advanced or recurrent GC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kadowaki</LastName><ForeName>Shigenori</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Aichi Cancer Center Hospital, Aichi, Japan. skadowaki@aichi-cc.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otsuka</LastName><ForeName>Tomoyuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Osaka International Cancer Institute, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minashi</LastName><ForeName>Keiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Trial Promotion Department, Chiba Cancer Center, Chiba, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishina</LastName><ForeName>Shinichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kurashiki Central Hospital, Okayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yabusaki</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Niigata Cancer Center Hospital, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Inagaki</LastName><ForeName>Chiaki</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Faculty of Medicine, Kindai University, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishina</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastrointestinal Medical Oncology, NHO Shikoku Cancer Center, Ehime, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yasui</LastName><ForeName>Hisateru</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsuoka</LastName><ForeName>Hiroshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Fujita Health University, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Machida</LastName><ForeName>Nozomu</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Kanagawa Cancer Center, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuda</LastName><ForeName>Masahiro</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Oncology, Hyogo Cancer Center, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagashima</LastName><ForeName>Fumio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Faculty of Medicine, Kyorin University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hosaka</LastName><ForeName>Hisashi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Gunma Prefectural Cancer Center, Gunma, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsubara</LastName><ForeName>Junichi</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arai</LastName><ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, St. Marianna University School of Medicine, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ida</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterological Surgery, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kumamoto University, Kumamoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kimijima</LastName><ForeName>Yuya</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncology Medical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsuda</LastName><ForeName>Yuko</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Affairs, Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muto</LastName><ForeName>Manabu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Muro</LastName><ForeName>Kei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Aichi Cancer Center Hospital, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Gastric Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100886238</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1436-3291</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>31YO63LBSN</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000077594">Nivolumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Population" UI="C000724324">Japanese people</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077594" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nivolumab</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013274" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stomach Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009364" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasm Recurrence, Local</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007564" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Japan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077982" MajorTopicYN="N">Progression-Free Survival</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015996" MajorTopicYN="N">Survival Rate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000095225" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">East Asian People</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Japan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nivolumab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Observational study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stomach neoplasms</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: Shigenori Kadowaki has received research funding from Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., MSD K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., DAIICHI SANKYO COMPANY, LIMITED, AstraZeneca K.K., TAIHO PHARMACEUTICAL, CO., LTD., Nobelpharma Co., Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and AbbVie GK; and honoraria from Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., MSD K.K., Merck KgaA, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., TAIHO PHARMACEUTICAL, CO., LTD., DAIICHI SANKYO COMPANY, LIMITED, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Eisai Co., Ltd. Tomoyuki Otsuka has received honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb and Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Keiko Minashi has received research funding from Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., TAIHO PHARMACEUTICAL, CO., LTD., DAIICHI SANKYO COMPANY, LIMITED, and MSD K.K.; and honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb and Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Shinichi Nishina has received from Bristol Myers Squibb and Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Hiroshi Yabusaki has no conflict of interest. Chiaki Inagaki has received honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., DAIICHI SANKYO COMPANY, LIMITED, Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Astellas Pharma Inc. Tomohiro Nishina has received honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., TAIHO PHARMACEUTICAL, CO., LTD., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., DAIICHI SANKYO COMPANY, LIMITED, Astellas Pharma Inc., and MSD K.K. Hisateru Yasui has received research funding from Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd.; and honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb, TAIHO PHARMACEUTICAL, CO., LTD., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Yakult Honsha Co., Ltd. Hiroshi Matsuoka has received honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb and DAIICHI SANKYO COMPANY, LIMITED. Nozomu Machida has received honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb and Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Masahiro Tsuda has received honoraria from Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb, and MSD K.K. Fumio Nagashima has received honoraria from TAIHO PHARMACEUTICAL, CO., LTD., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Yakult Honsha Co., Ltd., DAIICHI SANKYO COMPANY, LIMITED, Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Hisashi Hosaka has no conflict of interest. Junichi Matsubara has no conflict of interest. Hiroyuki Arai has received research funding from Novartis Pharma K.K. and honoraria from Bristol Myers Squibb. Satoshi Ida has no conflict of interest. Yuya Kimijima is an employee of Bristol Myers Squibb. Yuko Matsuda is an employee of Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Manabu Muto has received research funding from Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. and Meiji Seika Pharma Co., Ltd.; and honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., MSD K.K., AstraZeneca K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., and Meiji Seika Pharma Co., Ltd. Kei Muro has received research funding from Amgen Inc., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Astellas Pharma Inc., Sanofi K.K., TAIHO PHARMACEUTICAL, CO., LTD., PRA Health Sciences, Inc., Parexel International Inc., Novartis Pharma K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and MSD K.K.; consulting fees from Amgen Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Astellas Pharma Inc., and Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; honoraria from Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., TAIHO PHARMACEUTICAL, CO., LTD., Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., MSD K.K., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and DAIICHI SANKYO COMPANY, LIMITED; and served as a member of the Data Safety Monitoring Board or Advisory Board for Astellas Pharma Inc., Amgen Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Ethics approval: This study was approved by Non-Profit Organization MINS Research Ethics Committee (MINS-REC-220205) and was conducted in compliance with the Japanese Ethical Guidelines for Medical and Health Research Involving Human Subjects and the Act on the Protection of Personal Information. All study procedures were conducted in accordance with the principles of the World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki. Consent to participate: The authors thank the patients and families who are making the study possible and the investigators at the centers participating in the study. The authors also thank the clinical study teams. The data system was provided by Prime Research Institute for Medical RWD, Inc. Writing and editorial assistance was provided by Mebix, Inc., funded by Bristol Myers Squibb and Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>20</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40632416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12378153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10120-025-01641-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10120-025-01641-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Laversanne M, Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, Soerjomataram I, et al. Global cancer statistics 2022: globocan estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2024;74:229&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carioli G, Malvezzi M, Bertuccio P, Hashim D, Waxman S, Negri E, et al. Cancer mortality in the elderly in 11 countries worldwide, 1970&#x2013;2015. Ann Oncol. 2019;30:1344&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31147682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higashi T, Kurokawa Y. Incidence, mortality, survival, and treatment statistics of cancers in digestive organs&#x2014;Japanese cancer statistics 2024. Ann Gastroenterol Surg. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11533006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39502737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cancer Statistics. Cancer information service, national cancer center, Japan. 2024. https://ganjoho.jp/reg_stat/statistics/data/dl/excel/cancer_incidenceNCR(2016-2020).xls; https://ganjoho.jp/reg_stat/statistics/data/dl/excel/cancer_mortality(1958-2022).xls (accessed May 26, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekiguchi M, Oda I, Matsuda T, Saito Y. Epidemiological trends and future perspectives of gastric cancer in Eastern Asia. Digestion. 2022;103:22&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34515086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association JGC. Japanese gastric cancer treatment guidelines 2025. 7th ed. Tokyo: Kanehara &amp; Co., Ltd.; 2025. p. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang YK, Boku N, Satoh T, Ryu MH, Chao Y, Kato K, et al. Nivolumab in patients with advanced gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction cancer refractory to, or intolerant of, at least two previous chemotherapy regimens (ONO-4538-12, ATTRACTION-2): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2017;390:2461&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28993052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janjigian YY, Shitara K, Moehler M, Garrido M, Salman P, Shen L, et al. First-line nivolumab plus chemotherapy versus chemotherapy alone for advanced gastric, gastro-oesophageal junction, and oesophageal adenocarcinoma (CheckMate 649): a randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2021;398:27&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8436782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34102137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang YK, Chen LT, Ryu MH, Oh DY, Oh SC, Chung HC, et al. Nivolumab plus chemotherapy versus placebo plus chemotherapy in patients with HER2-negative, untreated, unresectable advanced or recurrent gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction cancer (ATTRACTION-4): a randomised, multicentre, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2022;23:234&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35030335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janjigian YY, Ajani JA, Moehler M, Shen L, Garrido M, Gallardo C, et al. First-line nivolumab plus chemotherapy for advanced gastric, gastroesophageal junction, and esophageal adenocarcinoma: 3-year follow-up of the phase III CheckMate 649 trial. J Clin Oncol. 2024;42:2012&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11185916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38382001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boku N, Omori T, Shitara K, Sakuramoto S, Yamaguchi K, Kato K, et al. Nivolumab plus chemotherapy in patients with HER2-negative, previously untreated, unresectable, advanced, or recurrent gastric/gastroesophageal junction cancer: 3-year follow-up of the ATTRACTION-4 randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Gastric Cancer. 2024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11513732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39162872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajani JA, D&#x2019;Amico TA, Bentrem DJ, Chao J, Cooke D, Corvera C, et al. Gastric cancer, version 2.2022 NCCN clinical practice guidelines in oncology. J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2022;20:167&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35130500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lordick F, Carneiro F, Cascinu S, Fleitas T, Haustermans K, Piessen G, et al. Gastric cancer: ESMO clinical practice guideline for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann Oncol. 2022;33:1005&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35914639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shitara K, Lordick F, Bang YJ, Enzinger P, Ilson D, Shah MA, et al. Zolbetuximab plus mFOLFOX6 in patients with CLDN18.2-positive, HER2-negative, untreated, locally advanced unresectable or metastatic gastric or gastro-oesophageal junction adenocarcinoma (SPOTLIGHT): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2023;401:1655&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37068504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah MA, Shitara K, Ajani JA, Bang YJ, Enzinger P, Ilson D, et al. Zolbetuximab plus CAPOX in CLDN18.2-positive gastric or gastroesophageal junction adenocarcinoma: the randomized, phase 3 GLOW trial. Nat Med. 2023;29:2133&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10427418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37524953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rha SY, Oh DY, Yanez P, Bai Y, Ryu MH, Lee J, et al. Pembrolizumab plus chemotherapy versus placebo plus chemotherapy for HER2-negative advanced gastric cancer (KEYNOTE-859): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2023;24:1181&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37875143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Association JGC. Japanese classification of gastric carcinoma (in Japanese). 15th ed. Tokyo: Kanehara &amp; Co., Ltd.; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japanese Gastric Cancer Association. Guide to biomarker testing for unresectable advanced or recurrent gastric cancer (in Japanese). August 30, 2024. https://www.jgca.jp/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/tebiki_01.1_202408.pdf (accessed May 26, 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shitara K, Fleitas T, Kawakami H, Curigliano G, Narita Y, Wang F, et al. Pan-Asian adapted ESMO clinical practice guidelines for the diagnosis, treatment and follow-up of patients with gastric cancer. ESMO Open. 2024;9:102226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10937212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38458658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimozaki K, Fukuda K, Ooki A, Nakayama I, Yoshino K, Tamba M, et al. Safety and efficacy of first-line nivolumab plus chemotherapy for HER2-negative advanced gastric or gastroesophageal junction adenocarcinoma: Real-world data analysis. ESMO Gastrointestinal Oncology. 2024;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komori A, Hironaka S, Kadowaki S, Mitani S, Furuta M, Kawakami T, et al. Prevalence and clinicopathological features of microsatellite instability-high metastatic or recurrent gastric and esophagogastric junction cancer: WJOG13320GPS. Gastric Cancer. 2025;28:301&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39738793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shitara K, Ajani JA, Moehler M, Garrido M, Gallardo C, Shen L, et al. Nivolumab plus chemotherapy or ipilimumab in gastro-oesophageal cancer. Nature. 2022;603:942&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35322232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang YK, Morita S, Satoh T, Ryu MH, Chao Y, Kato K, et al. Exploration of predictors of benefit from nivolumab monotherapy for patients with pretreated advanced gastric and gastroesophageal junction cancer: post hoc subanalysis from the ATTRACTION-2 study. Gastric Cancer. 2022;25:207&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8732926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34480657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahari D, Boku N, Mizusawa J, Takashima A, Yamada Y, Yoshino T, et al. Determination of prognostic factors in Japanese patients with advanced gastric cancer using the data from a randomized controlled trial, Japan Clinical Oncology Group 9912. Oncologist. 2014;19:358&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3983816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24668328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwasa S, Kudo T, Takahari D, Hara H, Kato K, Satoh T. Practical guidance for the evaluation of disease progression and the decision to change treatment in patients with advanced gastric cancer receiving chemotherapy. Int J Clin Oncol. 2020;25:1223&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7329754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32347434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y, Ma Y, Guan H, Dai G. Pre-treatment of hyponatremia as a biomarker for poor immune prognosis in advanced or metastatic gastric cancer: a retrospective case analysis. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2024;20:2414546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11486141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39411929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Masuishi T, Kadowaki S, Kondo M, Komori A, Sugiyama K, Mitani S, et al. Folfox as first-line therapy for gastric cancer with severe peritoneal metastasis. Anticancer Res. 2017;37:7037&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29187492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>