<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39709077</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-6787</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>92</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Acad Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The association between obesity and efficacy of psoriasis therapies: An expert consensus panel.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>807</StartPage><EndPage>815</EndPage><MedlinePgn>807-815</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jaad.2024.12.016</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0190-9622(24)03390-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Psoriasis is a chronic inflammatory skin disease often associated with obesity. Psoriasis therapies may be less effective in patients with obese. The purpose of this expert consensus panel is to evaluate the relationship between obesity and efficacy of psoriasis therapies, thereby optimizing patient care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A comprehensive literature search was completed on July 19, 2024, using the keywords "psoriasis," "obesity," "efficacy," "treatments," and "therapies." A panel of 11 dermatologists with significant expertise in treatment of psoriasis gathered to review the articles and create consensus statements. A modified Delphi process was used to approve each statement and a strength of recommendation was assigned.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The literature search produced 500 articles. A screening of the studies resulted in 22 articles that met criteria. The panel unanimously voted to adopt 10 consensus statements and recommendations, 6 were given a strength of "A," 2 were given a strength of "B," and 2 were given a strength of "C."</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Psoriasis and obesity have a strong association. Obesity decreases efficacy of biologics and may decrease efficacy and potentiate side effects of conventional therapies. It also impacts drug survival. Weight control is a vital component of caring for patients with psoriasis and the number of therapeutic options available is rising.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 American Academy of Dermatology, Inc. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burshtein</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Illinois Chicago, Chicago, Illinois. Electronic address: jburshtein13@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Armstrong</LastName><ForeName>April</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, David Geffen School of Medicine at University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chow</LastName><ForeName>May</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Specialty Physicians of Illinois, Olympia Fields, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>DeBusk</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brad Glick</LastName><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Glick Skin Institute, Margate, Florida; Department of Dermatology, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus Dermatology Resident Program, Hialeah, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gottlieb</LastName><ForeName>Alice B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gold</LastName><ForeName>Linda Stein</ForeName><Initials>LS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Henry Ford Health System, Detroit, Michigan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Korman</LastName><ForeName>Neil J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center, Cleveland, Ohio.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lio</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Dermatology Associates of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merola</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosmarin</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, Indiana.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenberg</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Voorhees</LastName><ForeName>Abby</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Eastern Virginia Medical School, Norfolk, Virginia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lebwohl</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Larkin Community Hospital Palm Springs Campus Dermatology Resident Program, Hialeah, Florida.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016446">Consensus Statement</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Acad Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7907132</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0190-9622</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001688">Biological Products</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003879">Dermatologic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001688" MajorTopicYN="Y">Biological Products</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032921" MajorTopicYN="N">Consensus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003697" MajorTopicYN="N">Delphi Technique</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003879" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatologic Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011565" MajorTopicYN="Y">Psoriasis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TNF inhibitors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biologics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">new therapies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psoriasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest Dr Armstrong has served as a research investigator, scientific adviser, or speaker to AbbVie, Almirall, Arcutis, ASLAN, Beiersdorf, BI, BMS, EPI, Incyte, Leo, UCB, Janssen, Lilly, Nimbus, Novartis, Ortho Dermatologics, Sun, Dermavant, Dermira, Sanofi, Regeneron, and Pfizer. Dr Glick has served as an adviser, consultant, speaker, or investigator for Amgen, AbbVie, AstraZeneca, Almirall, Arcutis, Bausch Health/Valeant, Ortho Dermatologics, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Brickell Biotech, Cara, ChemoCentryx, Dermavant, Dermira, Eli Lilly, EPI/Novan, Incyte, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, LEO Pharma, Galderma, Nimbus Lakshmi, Inc, Novartis, Sun Pharma, Pfizer, Sanofi, Regeneron, UCB and the CorEvitas AD, CorEvitas PSO, and PROSE Registries and is a shareholder of Top MD. Dr Gottlieb has received research/educational grants from Highlights Therapeutics, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Janssen, and UCB Pharma (all paid to Mount Sinai School of Medicine) and has received honoraria as an advisory board member and consultant for Amgen, AnaptysBio, Avotres Therapeutics, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Dice Therapeutics, Eli Lilly, Highlights Therapeutics, Janssen, Novartis, Sanofi, Teva, UCB, and XBiotech (stock options for RA). Dr Gold has served as an adviser, consultant, speaker, or investigator for Amgen, AbbVie, Almirall, Arcutis, Bausch Health/Valeant, Ortho Dermatologics, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Cara, Dermavant, Dermira, Eli Lilly, Incyte, Janssen Pharmaceuticals, LEO Pharma, Galderma, Novartis, Sun Pharma, Pfizer, Sanofi, Regeneron, and UCB. Dr Korman has served as an adviser, consultant, speaker, or investigator for AbbVie, Abcentra, Amgen, Argenx, Astrazeneca, Biogen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Castle Bioscience, Celgene, ChemoCentryx, Dermavant, Eli Lilly, Galderma, Incyte, Janssen, Kyowa Hakko Kirin Pharma, Leo Pharma, Menlo Therapeutics, Novartis, Olix, Pfizer, Principia, Regeneron, Sun Pharma, Trevi, UCB, and XBiotech. Dr Lio reports research grants/funding from AbbVie and AOBiome, is on the speaker&#x2019;s bureau for AbbVie, Arcutis, Eli Lilly, Galderma, Hyphens Pharma, Incyte, La Roche-Posay/L&#x2019;Oreal, MyOR Diagnostics, ParentMD, Pfizer, Pierre-Fabre Dermatologie, Regeneron/Sanofi Genzyme, and Verrica, reports consulting/advisory boards for Alphyn, AbbVie, Almirall, Amyris, Arcutis, ASLAN, Boston Skin Science, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Burt&#x2019;s Bees, Castle Biosciences, Codex Labs, Concerto Biosci, Dermavant, Eli Lilly, Galderma, Janssen, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Kimberly-Clark, LEO Pharma, Lipidor, L&#x2019;Oreal, Merck, Micreos, MyOR Diagnostics, Regeneron/Sanofi Genzyme, Skinfix, Theraplex, UCB, Unilever, Verrica, and Yobee Care, stock options with Codex, Concerto Biosciences, and Yobee Care, and has a patent pending for a Theraplex product with royalties paid and is a Board Member and Scientific Advisory Committee Member of the National Eczema Association. Dr Merola is a consultant and/or investigator for Amgen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, AbbVie, Dermavant, Eli Lilly, Incyte, Novartis, Janssen, UCB, Sanofi-Regeneron, Sun Pharma, Biogen, Pfizer and Leo Pharma. Dr Rosmarin has consulted, spoken for, or conducted trials for AbbVie, Abcuro, Almirall, AltruBio, Amgen, Astria, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Meyers Squibb, Celgene, Concert, CSL Behring, Dermavant, Dermira, Dualitas, Galderma, Incyte, Janssen, Kymera, Kyowa Kirin, Lilly, Merck, Nektar, Novartis, Pfizer, RAPT, Regeneron, Recludix, Revolo Biotherapeutics, Sanofi, Sun Pharmaceuticals, UCB, Viela Bio, and Zura Bio. Dr Van Voorhees has served as a consultant for BMS, BI, and Eluciderm. Dr Lebwohl is an employee of Mount Sinai and receives research funds from AbbVie, Amgen, Arcutis, Avotres, Boehringer Ingelheim, Cara therapeutics, Dermavant Sciences, Eli Lilly, Incyte, Inozyme, Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC, Ortho Dermatologics, Pfizer, Sanofi-Regeneron, and UCB, Inc, and is a consultant for Almirall, AltruBio Inc, AnaptyBio, Apogee, Arcutis, Inc, AstraZeneca, Atomwise, Avotres Therapeutics, Brickell Biotech, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Castle Biosciences, Celltrion, CorEvitas, Dermavant Sciences, EPI, Evommune, Inc, Facilitation of International Dermatology Education, Forte biosciences, Foundation for Research and Education in Dermatology, Galderma, Genentech, Incyte, LEO Pharma, Meiji Seika Pharma, Mindera, Pfizer, Sanofi-Regeneron, Seanergy, Strata, Takeda, Trevi, and Verrica. The other authors have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39709077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2024.12.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0190-9622(24)03390-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>