<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41533560</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1662-4033</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Obesity facts</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Obes Facts</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characteristics of Individuals Living with Obesity in Germany, Weight Loss Methods Attempted, and Response over a 12-Month Period: Results from a Cross-Sectional Survey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>12</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-12</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000550050</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study aimed to describe the demographic and clinical characteristics of individuals with obesity (IWO) in Germany and to explore weight loss methods and their effectiveness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Data were drawn from a cross-sectional survey of adults with obesity (&#x2265;18 years of age) conducted in Germany between November and December 2022 through an online consumer panel. Data were captured using a self-administered questionnaire and included demographic and clinical characteristics, weight loss methods attempted in the last 12 months, and how successful these attempts were. Logistic regression analysis assessed the effect of variables including age, sex, and weight loss method on the odds of weight reduction. Data were presented as odds ratios, p values and confidence intervals. For descriptive statistics, continuous variables were presented as means and standard deviations (SDs). Categorical variables were presented as frequency counts and percentages.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Overall, the 1,000 IWO in this study had a mean age (SD) of 42.8 (10.7) years, 94% were White, 45% were female, and mean (SD) body mass index was 37.6 (8.3) kg/m2. In total, 73% had &#x2265;1 comorbid conditions, the most common being musculoskeletal pain (19%). Just 43% were being managed for a weight condition; however, 95% had attempted to lose weight over the previous 12 months, with 33% utilizing an anti-obesity medication and 26% utilizing a calorie-controlled diet. IWO on a calorie-controlled diet or a digital health application was more likely to lose weight than people using other methods (p &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results highlight gaps in obesity recognition and management in Germany, underscoring the importance of enhancing access to effective interventions and improving support systems for this population.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lautenbach</LastName><ForeName>Anne</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany, a.lautenbach@uke.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seitz</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novo Nordisk Pharma GmbH, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knerr-Rupp</LastName><ForeName>Katrin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novo Nordisk Pharma GmbH, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartmann</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novo Nordisk Pharma GmbH, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McMillan</LastName><ForeName>Abigail</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adelphi Real World, Bollington, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cooper</LastName><ForeName>Charley</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adelphi Real World, Bollington, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meadows</LastName><ForeName>Rachael</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Adelphi Real World, Bollington, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Obes Facts</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101469429</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1662-4025</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Body mass index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-sectional survey</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weight loss</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>A.L. received honoraria as a consultant and speaker from Novo Nordisk, Eli Lilly and Company, Boehringer Ingelheim, AstraZeneca and Oviva Direkt. L.S., K.K.-R., and C.H. are employees of Novo Nordisk. A.M., C.C., and R.M. are employees of Adelphi Real World which received consulting fees from Novo Nordisk to perform this analysis.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41533560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12885559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000550050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000550050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aronne LJ. Classification of obesity and assessment of obesity&#x2010;related health risks. Obes Res. 2002;10(Suppl 2):105S&#x2013;15S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12490659</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
World Health Organisation . World Health Statistics. 2023. (electronic version) ISBN 978-92-4-007432-3 (electronic version): ISBN 978-92-4-007432-3 (electronic version); 2023 [Available from]: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240074323</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schienkiewitz A, Kuhnert R, Blume M, Mensink GBM. Overweight and obesity among adults in Germany: results from GEDA 2019/2020-EHIS. J Health Monit. 2022;7(3):21&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9520353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36188152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guh DP, Zhang W, Bansback N, Amarsi Z, Birmingham CL, Anis AH. The incidence of co-morbidities related to obesity and overweight: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Public Health. 2009;9:88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2667420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19320986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luppino FS, de Wit LM, Bouvy PF, Stijnen T, Cuijpers P, Penninx BW, et al. Overweight, obesity, and depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis of longitudinal studies. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2010;67(3):220&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20194822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering RP, Goldstein RB, Hasin DS, Blanco C, Smith SM, Huang B, et al. Temporal relationships between overweight and obesity and DSM-IV substance use, mood, and anxiety disorders: results from a prospective study, the National Epidemiologic Survey on Alcohol and Related Conditions. J Clin Psychiatry. 2011;72(11):1494&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3227748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21457678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakajima T, Fujioka S, Tokunaga K, Hirobe K, Matsuzawa Y, Tarui S. Noninvasive study of left ventricular performance in obese patients: influence of duration of obesity. Circulation. 1985;71(3):481&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3971522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ndumele CE, Cobb L, Lazo M, Bello NA, Shah A, Nambi V, et al. Weight history and subclinical myocardial damage. Clin Chem. 2018;64(1):201&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6219376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29158254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyen B, Weng S, Vinogradova Y, Akyea RK, Qureshi N, Kai J. Long-term body mass index changes in overweight and obese adults and the risk of heart failure, cardiovascular disease and mortality: a cohort study of over 260,000 adults in the UK. BMC Public Health. 2021;21(1):576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8048253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33853578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mejaddam A, Krantz E, H&#xf6;skuldsd&#xf3;ttir G, F&#xe4;ndriks L, Mossberg K, Eliasson B, et al. Comorbidity and quality of life in obesity-a comparative study with the general population in Gothenburg, Sweden. PLoS One. 2022;17(10):e0273553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9531784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36194568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ul-Haq Z, Mackay DF, Fenwick E, Pell JP. Impact of metabolic comorbidity on the association between body mass index and health-related quality of life: a Scotland-wide cross-sectional study of 5,608 participants. BMC Public Health. 2012;12:143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3299597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22364437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berrington de Gonzalez A, Hartge P, Cerhan JR, Flint AJ, Hannan L, MacInnis RJ, et al. Body-mass index and mortality among 1.46 million white adults. N Engl J Med. 2010;363(23):2211&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3066051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21121834</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flegal KM, Kit BK, Orpana H, Graubard BI. Association of all-cause mortality with overweight and obesity using standard body mass index categories: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA. 2013;309(1):71&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4855514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23280227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global BMIMC, Di Angelantonio E, Bhupathiraju SN, Wormser D, Gao P, Kaptoge S, et al. Body-mass index and all-cause mortality: individual-participant-data meta-analysis of 239 prospective studies in four continents. Lancet. 2016;388(10046):776&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4995441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrington M, Gibson S, Cottrell RC. A review and meta-analysis of the effect of weight loss on all-cause mortality risk. Nutr Res Rev. 2009;22(1):93&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19555520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans M, de Courcy J, de Laguiche E, Faurby M, Haase CL, Matthiessen KS, et al. Obesity-related complications, healthcare resource use and weight loss strategies in six European countries: the RESOURCE survey. Int J Obes. 2023;47(8):750&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10359184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37258646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuckler D, McKee M, Ebrahim S, Basu S. Manufacturing epidemics: the role of global producers in increased consumption of unhealthy commodities including processed foods, alcohol, and tobacco. PLoS Med. 2012;9(6):e1001235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3383750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22745605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenway FL. Physiological adaptations to weight loss and factors favouring weight regain. Int J Obes. 2015;39(8):1188&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4766925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25896063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
German Obesity Alliance . Obesity in Germany. 2020. Available from: https://obesityopen.org/open-germany/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Bundesministerium der Justiz . Sozialgesetzbuch (SGB) F&#xfc;nftes Buch (V): Gesetzliche Krankenversicherung &#x2013; (Article 1 of the law of December 20, 1988, BGBl. I p. 2477) &#xa7; 34 Excluded medicinal products, remedies and aids. 1988. Available from: https://www.gesetze-im-internet.de/sgb_5/__34.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>StataCorp . Stata statistical software: release 17. College Station, TX: StataCorp LLC; 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Pharmaceutical Market Research Association [EphMRA] . Code of Conduct. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services . Summary of the HIPAA privacy rule; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koenen M, Hill MA, Cohen P, Sowers JR. Obesity, adipose tissue and vascular dysfunction. Circ Res. 2021;128(7):951&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8026272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33793327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall JE, do Carmo JM, da Silva AA, Wang Z, Hall ME. Obesity-induced hypertension: interaction of neurohumoral and renal mechanisms. Circ Res. 2015;116(6):991&#x2013;1006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4363087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25767285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah A, Stoelwinder J, Shortreed S, Wolfe R, Stevenson C, Walls H, et al. The duration of obesity and the risk of type 2 diabetes. Public Health Nutr. 2011;14(1):119&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20587115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah A, Wolfe R, Mannan H, Stoelwinder JU, Stevenson C, Peeters A. Epidemiologic merit of obese-years, the combination of degree and duration of obesity. Am J Epidemiol. 2012;176(2):99&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22759723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hossain MA, Amin A, Paul A, Qaisar H, Akula M, Amirpour A, et al. Recognizing obesity in adult hospitalized patients: a retrospective cohort Study assessing rates of documentation and prevalence of obesity. J Clin Med. 2018;7(8):203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6111619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30087233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim TN. Barriers to obesity management: patient and physician factors. J Obes Metab Syndr. 2020;29(4):244&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Post RE, Mainous AG 3rd, Gregorie SH, Knoll ME, Diaz VA, Saxena SK. The influence of physician acknowledgment of patients&#x2019; weight status on patient perceptions of overweight and obesity in the United States. Arch Intern Med. 2011;171(4):316&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21357807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patterson L, Kee F, Hughes C, O&#x2019;Reilly D. The relationship between BMI and the prescription of anti-obesity medication according to social factors: a population cross sectional study. BMC Public Health. 2014;14:87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3914727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24472650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabiri M, Sexton Ward A, Ramasamy A, van Eijndhoven E, Ganguly R, Smolarz BG, et al. The societal value of broader access to antiobesity medications. Obesity. 2020;28(2):429&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7003734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31869002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomez G, Stanford FC. US health policy and prescription drug coverage of FDA-approved medications for the treatment of obesity. Int J Obes. 2018;42(3):495&#x2013;500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6082126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green L, Taddei-Allen P. Shifting paradigms: reframing coverage of antiobesity medications for plan sponsors. J Manag Care Spec Pharm. 2023;29(5):564&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10387974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37121250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drucker DJ. Prevention of cardiorenal complications in people with type 2 diabetes and obesity. Cell Metab. 2024;36(2):338&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38198966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
National Institute for Health and Care Excellence . Appraisal consultation document Semaglutide for managing overweight and obesity. 2022. Available from: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ta875/documents/129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40080622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Susanto A, Burk J, Hocking S, Markovic T, Gill T. Differences in weight loss outcomes for males and females on a low-carbohydrate diet: a systematic review. Obes Res Clin Pract. 2022;16(6):447&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36244957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elliott M, Gillison F, Barnett J. Exploring the influences on men&#x2019;s engagement with weight loss services: a qualitative study. BMC Public Health. 2020;20(1):249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7041184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantowski T, Schulze Zur Wiesch C, Aberle J, Lautenbach A. Obesity management: sex-specific considerations. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2024;309(5):1745&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11018683</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38329549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saxon DR, Iwamoto SJ, Mettenbrink CJ, McCormick E, Arterburn D, Daley MF, et al. Antiobesity medication use in 2.2 million adults across eight large health care Organizations: 2009-2015. Obesity. 2019;27(12):1975&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6868321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31603630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas K, Hayoz S, Maurer-Wiesner S. Effectiveness and feasibility of a remote lifestyle intervention by dietitians for overweight and obese adults: pilot Study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2019;7(4):e12289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6482396</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30973338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehmann M, Jones L, Schirmann F. App engagement as a predictor of weight loss in blended-care interventions: retrospective observational study using large-scale real-world data. J Med Internet Res. 2024;26:e45469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11193074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38848556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>