<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">20816308</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-6752</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>138</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of orthodontics and dentofacial orthopedics : official publication of the American Association of Orthodontists, its constituent societies, and the American Board of Orthodontics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Three-dimensional surgical simulation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>361</StartPage><EndPage>371</EndPage><MedlinePgn>361-71</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ajodo.2009.08.026</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this article, we discuss the development of methods for computer-aided jaw surgery, which allows us to incorporate the high level of precision necessary for transferring virtual plans into the operating room. We also present a complete computer-aided surgery system developed in close collaboration with surgeons. Surgery planning and simulation include construction of 3-dimensional surface models from cone-beam computed tomography, dynamic cephalometry, semiautomatic mirroring, interactive cutting of bone, and bony segment repositioning. A virtual setup can be used to manufacture positioning splints for intraoperative guidance. The system provides further intraoperative assistance with a computer display showing jaw positions and 3-dimensional positioning guides updated in real time during the surgical procedure. The computer-aided surgery system aids in dealing with complex cases with benefits for the patient, with surgical practice, and for orthodontic finishing. Advanced software tools for diagnosis and treatment planning allow preparation of detailed operative plans, osteotomy repositioning, bone reconstructions, surgical resident training, and assessing the difficulties of the surgical procedures before the surgery. Computer-aided surgery can make the elaboration of the surgical plan a more flexible process, increase the level of detail and accuracy of the plan, yield higher operative precision and control, and enhance documentation of cases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>2010 American Association of Orthodontists. Published by Mosby, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cevidanes</LastName><ForeName>Lucia H C</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthodontics, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 27599, USA. cevidanl@dentistry.unc.edu</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tucker</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Styner</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>Hyungmin</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chapuis</LastName><ForeName>Jonas</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reyes</LastName><ForeName>Mauricio</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Proffit</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turvey</LastName><ForeName>Timothy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaskolka</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>DE 018962</GrantID><Acronym>DE</Acronym><Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U54 EB005149</GrantID><Acronym>EB</Acronym><Agency>NIBIB NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DE 005215</GrantID><Acronym>DE</Acronym><Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 DE017727</GrantID><Acronym>DE</Acronym><Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1RR025747</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 DE005215</GrantID><Acronym>DE</Acronym><Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R03 DE018962</GrantID><Acronym>DE</Acronym><Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>DE017727</GrantID><Acronym>DE</Acronym><Agency>NIDCR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8610224</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0889-5406</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002508" MajorTopicYN="N">Cephalometry</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003198" MajorTopicYN="Y">Computer Simulation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054893" MajorTopicYN="N">Cone-Beam Computed Tomography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003626" MajorTopicYN="N">Data Display</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020342" MajorTopicYN="N">Finite Element Analysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007091" MajorTopicYN="N">Image Processing, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D021621" MajorTopicYN="N">Imaging, Three-Dimensional</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007256" MajorTopicYN="N">Information Systems</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007430" MajorTopicYN="N">Intraoperative Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003765" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Dental</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056948" MajorTopicYN="N">Orthognathic Surgical Procedures</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010027" MajorTopicYN="N">Osteotomy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010347" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Care Planning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019651" MajorTopicYN="N">Plastic Surgery Procedures</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012984" MajorTopicYN="N">Software</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D025321" MajorTopicYN="N">Surgery, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014584" MajorTopicYN="N">User-Computer Interface</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Statement</b>. There is no conflict of interest for any of the contributing authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2009</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2009</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20816308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS146605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2994415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajodo.2009.08.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0889-5406(10)00397-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Caloss R, Atkins K, Stella JP. Three-dimensional imaging for virtual assessment and treatment simulation in orthognathic surgery. Oral Maxillofac Surg Clin North Am. 2007;19(3):287&#x2013;309. v.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18088886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altobelli DE, Kikinis R, Mulliken JB, Cline H, Lorensen W, Jolesz F. Computer-assisted three-dimensional planning in craniofacial surgery. Plast Reconstr Surg. 1993;92(4):576&#x2013;85. discussion 586&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8356120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arai Y, Tammisalo E, Iwai K, Hashimoto K, Shinoda K. Development of a compact computed tomographic apparatus for dental use. Dentomaxillofac Radiol. 1999;28(4):245&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10455389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapuis J. Computer-Aided Cranio-Maxillofacial Surgery. University of Bern; 2006. PhD thesis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapuis J, Schramm A, Pappas I, Hallermann W, Schwenzer-Zimmerer K, Langlotz F, et al. A new system for computer-aided preoperative planning and intraoperative navigation during corrective jaw surgery. IEEE Trans Inf Technol Biomed. 2007;11(3):274&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17521077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Momi E, Chapuis J, Pappas I, Ferrigno G, Hallermann W, Schramm A, et al. Automatic extraction of the mid-facial plane for cranio-maxillofacial surgery planning. Int J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2006;35(7):636&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16542822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krol Z, Chapuis J, Schwenzer-Zimmerer K, Langlotz F, Zeilhofer HF. Preoperative Planning and Intraoperative Navigation in the Reconstructive Craniofacial Surgery. J Med Inform Tech. 2005;9:83&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapuis J, Langlotz F, Blaeuer M, Hallermann W, Schramm A, Caversaccio M. A Novel Approach for Computer-Aided Corrective Jaw Surgery. 3rd International Conference on Computer-Aided Surgery around the Head; Berlin, Germany. 2005 August.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapuis J, Ryan P, Blaeuer M, Langlotz F, Hallermann W, Schramm A, et al. A New Approach for 3D Computer-Assisted Orthognathic Surgery - First Clinical Case. Computer Assisted Radiology and Surgery; Berlin, Germany. 2005 June.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapuis J, Rudolph T, Borgeson B, De Momi E, Pappas I, Hallermann W, et al. 3D Surgical Planning and Navigation for CMF Surgery. SPIE Medical Imaging; San Diego, California, USA. 2004 February.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yushkevich PA, Piven J, Hazlett HC, Smith RG, Ho S, Gee JC, et al. User-guided 3D active contour segmentation of anatomical structures: significantly improved efficiency and reliability. Neuroimage. 2006;31(3):1116&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16545965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hemmy DC, Tessier PL. CT of dry skulls with craniofacial deformities: accuracy of three-dimensional reconstruction. Radiology. 1985;157(1):113&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3929326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swennen GR, Mollemans W, De Clercq C, Abeloos J, Lamoral P, Lippens F, et al. A Cone-Beam Computed Tomography Triple Scan Procedure to Obtain a Three-Dimensional Augmented Virtual Skull Model Appropriate for Orthognathic Surgery Planning. J Craniofac Surg. 2009;20(2):297&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia JJ, Phillips CV, Gateno J, Teichgraeber JF, Christensen AM, Gliddon MJ, et al. Cost-effectiveness analysis for computer-aided surgical simulation in complex cranio-maxillofacial surgery. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2006;64(12):1780&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17113445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pommert A, Riemer M, Schiemann T, Schubert R, Tiede U, Hohne KH. Three-Dimensional Imaging in Medicine: Methods and Applications. In: Taylor R, Lavallee S, Burdea G, Mosges R, editors. Computer Integrated Surgery. MIT press; Cambridge, MA: 1996. pp. 155&#x2013;74.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettega G, Payan Y, Mollard B, Boyer A, Raphael B, Lavallee S. A simulator for maxillofacial surgery integrating 3D cephalometry and orthodontia. Comput Aided Surg. 2000;5(3):156&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10964087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swennen GR, Barth EL, Schutyser F, De Groeve P, Lemaitre A. Three-Dimensional (3-D) Cephalometry: The Basics for Virtual Planning. XVII European Congress for Cranio-Maxillofacial Surgery; Tours, France. 2004 September.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swennen GR, Schutyser F, Hausamen JE. Three Dimensional Cephalometry: A Color Atlas and Manual. Springer; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cutting CB, Bookstein FL, Taylor RH. Applications of Simulation, Morphometrics, and Robotics in Craniofacial Surgery. In: Taylor R, Lavallee S, Burdea G, Mosges R, editors. Computer Integrated Surgery. MIT press; Cambridge, MA: 1996. pp. 641&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subsol G, Thirion JP, Ayache N. A scheme for automatically building three-dimensional morphometric anatomical atlases: application to a skull atlas. Med Image Anal. 1998;2(1):37&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10638852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhadidi A, Cevidanes LHS, Mol A, Ludlow J, Styner MA. 3D Analysis of Facial Asymmetry based on Midsaggital Plane Computation. J Dent Res. 2009;88(Spec Issue A):311.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tung-Yui W, Jing-Jing F, Tung-Chin W. In: A Novel Method of Quantifying Facial Asymmetry. Lemke HU, Inamura K, Doi K, Vannier MW, Farman AG, editors. Computer Assisted Radiology and Surgery; Berlin, Germany: 2005. Jun,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangel FA, Maal TJ, Berge SJ, van Vlijmen OJ, Plooij JM, Schutyser F, et al. Integration of digital dental casts in 3-dimensional facial photographs. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 2008;134(6):820&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19061810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutyser F, Van Cleynenbreugel J, Ferrant M, Schoenaers J, Suetens P. Image-Based 3D Planning of Maxillofacial Distraction Procedures including Soft Tissue Implications. Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention. 2000;1935:999&#x2013;1007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia J, Samman N, Yeung RW, Shen SG, Wang D, Ip HH, et al. Three-dimensional virtual reality surgical planning and simulation workbench for orthognathic surgery. Int J Adult Orthod Orthognath Surg. 2000;15(4):265&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11307184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teschner M, Girod S, Girod B. 3-D simulation of craniofacial surgical procedures. Stud Health Technol Inform. 2001;81:502&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11317798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeve E, Girod B, Girod S. In: Computer-Aided Craniofacial Surgery. Lemke HU, editor. Computer Assisted Radiology; Paris, France: 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollemans W, Schutyser F, Nadjmi N, Maes F, Suetens P. Predicting soft tissue deformations for a maxillofacial surgery planning system: from computational strategies to a complete clinical validation. Med Image Anal. 2007;11(3):282&#x2013;301.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17493864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westermark A, Zachow S, Eppley BL. Three-dimensional osteotomy planning in maxillofacial surgery including soft tissue prediction. J Craniofac Surg. 2005;16(1):100&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chabanas M, Luboz V, Payan Y. Patient specific finite element model of the face soft tissues for computer-assisted maxillofacial surgery. Med Image Anal. 2003;7(2):131&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12868618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schendel SA, Montgomery K. A web-based, integrated simulation system for craniofacial surgical planning. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2009;123(3):1009&#x2013;1106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19319079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeve E, Girod S, Kikinis R, Girod B. Deformable modeling of facial tissue for craniofacial surgery simulation. Comput Aided Surg. 1998;3(5):228&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10207647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zachow S, Gladilin E, Zeilhofer HF, Sader R. Improved 3D Osteotomy Planning in Craniomaxillofacial Surgery. Medical Image Computing and Computer-Assisted Intervention: 4th International Conference Ultrecht; The Netherlands. 2001 October.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gladilin E, Zachow S, Deuflhard P, Hege HC. Anatomy- and physics-based facial animation for craniofacial surgery simulations. Med Biol Eng Comput. 2004;42(2):167&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15125145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gateno J, Teichgraeber JF, Xia JJ. Three-dimensional surgical planning for maxillary and midface distraction osteogenesis. J Craniofac Surg. 2003;14(6):833&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14600624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vandewalle P, Schutyser F, Van Cleynenbreugel J, Suetens P. Modeling of Facial Soft Tissue Growth for Maxillofacial Surgery Planning Environments. IS4TH. 2003:27&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langlotz F. Localizers and trackers for computer assisted freehand navigation. In: Picard F, Nolte L-P, Digiola AM, Jamaraz B, editors. Hip and Knee Surgery &#x2013; Navigation, Robotics, and Computer Assisted Surgical Tools. Oxford University Press; 2004. pp. 51&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Jurgen P, Krol Z, Caversaccio M, Nolte LP, Zeilhofer HF, Gonzales MA. Clinical applications of computer-aided planning and navigation system for cranio-maxillofacial surgery. Leipzig, Germany: CAS-H 2009. Book of Abstracts.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H, Nolte NP, Gonzalez Ballester M, Caversaccio M, Zeilhofer HF. CARS 2008. Barcelona; Spain: p. 031.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>