<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">25822514</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-0911</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Advances in neonatal care : official journal of the National Association of Neonatal Nurses</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Adv Neonatal Care</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Newborn physiological immaturity: a concept analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>86</StartPage><EndPage>93</EndPage><MedlinePgn>86-93</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ANC.0000000000000162</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Most standardized nursing care plans for healthy neonates include multiple nursing diagnoses to reflect nurses' judgments on the infant's status; however scientific literature concerning this issue is scarce. Newborn physiological immaturity is a concept in the ATIC terminology (architecture, terminology, interface, information, nursing [infermeria], and knowledge [coneixement]) to represent the natural status of vulnerability of the healthy neonate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To identify the essential attributes of the concept and provide its conceptual and operational definition, using the Wilsonian approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The concept under analysis embeds a natural cluster of vulnerabilities and environmental interactions that enhance the evolving maturation process.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS FOR PRACTICE" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The use of this diagnosis may simplify the process of charting the nursing care plans and reduce time needed for documentation while maintaining the integrity of the information.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS FOR RESEARCH" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Consistent development and use of nursing concepts is essential for knowledge building. Studies on the actual use of nursing diagnoses are needed to inform decision making.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Juv&#xe9;-Udina</LastName><ForeName>Maria-Eul&#xe0;lia</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IDIBELL Institute of Research, University of Barcelona School of Nursing, Catalonia, Spain (Drs Juv&#xe9;-Udina, Fabrellas-Padr&#xe9;s, and Delgado-Hito); Sant Joan de D&#xe9;u School of Nursing, Catalonia, Spain (Mrs Hurtado-Pardos); Department of Nursing Informatics and Knowledge, Verge de la Cinta Community Hospital, and Rovira i Virgili University School of Nursing, Tortosa, Catalonia, Spain (Mrs Mart&#xed;-Cavall&#xe9;); Department of Nursing Informatics and Knowledge, Dr. Josep Trueta University Hospital, Girona, Catalonia, Spain (Mrs Giron&#xe8;s-Nogu&#xe9;); Vall d'Hebron University Hospital, Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain (Mrs Garc&#xed;a-Berman); and Germans Trias i Pujol University Hospital, Badalona, Catalonia, Spain (Mr Alonso-Fernandez).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fabrellas-Padr&#xe9;s</LastName><ForeName>N&#xfa;ria</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Delgado-Hito</LastName><ForeName>Pilar</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hurtado-Pardos</LastName><ForeName>B&#xe1;rbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mart&#xed;-Cavall&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Montserrat</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giron&#xe8;s-Nogu&#xe9;</LastName><ForeName>Marta</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garc&#xed;a-Berman</LastName><ForeName>Rosa-Maria</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alonso-Fernandez</LastName><ForeName>Sergio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Adv Neonatal Care</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101125644</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1536-0903</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002657" MajorTopicYN="Y">Child Development</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004282" MajorTopicYN="N">Documentation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007231" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant, Newborn</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017283" MajorTopicYN="N">Neonatal Nursing</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010347" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Care Planning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2016</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25822514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4961275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ANC.0000000000000162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00149525-201504000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rogers BL, Knalf KA. Concept Development in Nursing: Foundations, Techniques and Applications. 2nd ed. Philadelphia, PA: WB Saunders; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juv&#xe9;-Udina ME. Philosophical and theoretical foundations for the development and validation of a nursing interface terminology. Part I. Rev Enferm. 2012;35(4):20&#x2013;25. [Spanish]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22745996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juv&#xe9;-Udina ME. Inductive evaluation of a Nursing Interface Terminology: conceptualization of the nursing process. Nursing (Spanish ed.). 2012;30(7):62&#x2013;66. [Spanish]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juv&#xe9;-Udina ME, Gonzalez-Samartino M, Matud-Calvo C. Mapping the diagnosis axis of a new interface terminology to the NANDA International Taxonomy. ISRN Nurs. 2012;676905;6. 10.5402/2012/676905.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3399394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22830046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juv&#xe9;-Udina ME. Is the ATIC terminology oriented to nursing phenomena? Open J Nurs. 2012;2(4):388&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juv&#xe9;-Udina ME. What patients' problems do nurses e-chart? Longitudinal study to evaluate the usability of an interface terminology. Int J Nurs Stud. 2013;50(12):1698&#x2013;1710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23684394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juv&#xe9;-Udina ME, Zuriguel Perez E, Fabrellas Padres N, et al. Basic nursing care: retrospective evaluation of communication and psychosocial interventions documented by nurses in the acute care setting. J Nurs Scholarsh. 2014;46(1):65&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24354414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma A, Ford S, Calvert J. Adaptation for life: a review of neonatal physiology. Anesth Int Care Med. 2010;12(3):85&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premji SS, Young M, Rogers C, Reilly S. Transitions in the early-life of late preterm infants: vulnerabilities and implications for postpartum care. J Perinat Neonatal Nurs. 2012;26(1):57&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22293643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry SH, Hockenberry MJ, Lowdermilk DL, Wilson D. Maternal-Child Nursing Care. 4th ed. Maryland Height, MI: Mosby Elsevier; 2010:644&#x2013;687.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neves-In&#xe1;cio CC, Camelo-Chaves EM, Freitas MC, Siebra e Silva AV, Rodrigues Alves A, Monteiro AR. Nursing diagnoses in in-rooming units. Rev Bras Enferm. 2010;63(6):894&#x2013;899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21308219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrington JM. The usefulness of nursing languages to communicate a clinical event. Comp Inform Nurs. 2012;30(2):82&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22015978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Online Merriam-Webster's Collegiate Dictionary. Encyclopaedia Britannica Company, 2013. http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary. Accessed February 28, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rohan AJ, Golombek SG. Hypoxia in the term newborn: part two-primary pulmonary disease, obstruction, and extrinsic compression. MCN Am J Matern Child Nurs. 2009;34(3):144&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19550255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mance MJ. Keeping infants warm. Challenges of hypothermia. Adv Neonatal Care. 2008;8(1):6&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18300733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elzouki AY, Harfi HA, Nazer HM, Bruder Stapleton William Oh F, Whitley RJ, eds. Textbook of Clinical Pediatrics. 2nd edn. Berlin Heidelberg: Springer-Verlag; 2012:268.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker GE, Remmington S, Remmington T. Early additional food and fluids for healthy breastfed full-term infants. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2011;12:CD006462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22161404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holcomb SS. Hyperbilirubinemia in neonates. Prevention, early identification and treatment. Adv Neonatal Care. 2011;11(5S):S22&#x2013;S27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22123450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrington DJ, Clarke P, Card DJ, Mitchell SJ, Shearer MJ. Urinary excretion of vitamin K metabolites in term and preterm infants: relationship to vitamin K status and prophylaxis. Pediatr Res. 2010;68(6):508&#x2013;512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20814348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kramer MS, Kakuma R. Optimal duration of exclusive breastfeeding. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012;8:CD003517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7154583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22895934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vain NE, Fari&#xf1;a D, V&#xe1;zquez LN. Neonatology in the emerging countries: the strategies and health-economics challenges related to prevention of neonatal and infant infections. Early Hum Dev. 2012;88(suppl 2):S53&#x2013;S59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22633515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakalidis VS, Kent JC, Garbin CP, Hepworth AR, Hartmann PE, Geddes DT. Longitudinal changes in suck-swallow-breathe, oxygen saturation, and heart rate patterns in term breastfeeding infants. J Hum Lact. 2013;29(2):236&#x2013;245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23492760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moral A, Bolibar I, Seguranyes G, et al. Mechanics of sucking: comparison between bottle feeding and breastfeeding. BMC Pediatr. 2010;11:10:6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2837866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20149217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni A, Kaushik JS, Gupta P, Sharma H, Agrawal RK. Massage and touch therapy in neonates: the current evidence. Indian Pediatr. 2010;47:771&#x2013;776.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21048258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ang JY, Lua JL, Mathur A, et al. A randomized placebo-controlled trial of massage therapy on the immune system of preterm infants. Pediatrics. 2012;130(6):e1549&#x2013;e1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3507248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23147978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duhn L. The importance of touch in the development of attachment. Adv Neonatal Care. 2010;10(6):294&#x2013;300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21102171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell AF, Lucas R, White-Traut RC. Concept clarification of neonatal neurobehavioural organization. J Adv Nurs. 2008;61(5):570&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2573022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18261065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elverson CA, Wilson ME. Social regulation of the stress response in the transitional newborn. Adv Neonatal Care. 2008;8(2):133&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen KA. Promoting and protecting infant sleep. Adv Neonatal Care. 2012;12(5):288&#x2013;291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3439810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22964605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke AL, Field K, Morrison JJ. Natural history of fetal trisomy 18 after prenatal diagnosis. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2013;98(2):F152&#x2013;F154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22562870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazza V, Latella S, Fenu V, et al. Prenatal diagnosis and postnatal follow-up of a child with mosaic trisomy 22 with several levels of mosaicism in different tissues. J Obstet Gynaecol Res. 2010;36(5):1116&#x2013;1120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20722987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boghossian NS, Hansen NI, Bell EF, et al. Mortality and morbidity of VLBW infants with trisomy 13 or trisomy 18. Pediatrics. 2014;133(2):226&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24446439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elser HE, Holditch-Davis D, Levy J, Brandon DH. The effects of environmental noise and infant position on cerebral oxygenation. Adv Neonatal Care. 2012;12(5S):S18&#x2013;S27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3448929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22968001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liaw JJ, Yang L, Hua YM, Chang PW, Teng CC, Li CC. Preterm infants' biobehavioral responses to caregiving and positioning over 24 hours in a neonatal unit in Taiwan. Res Nurs Health. 2012;35(6):634&#x2013;646.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22753226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma AA, Jen R, Butler A, Lavoie PM. The developing human preterm neonatal immune system: a case for more research in this area. Clin Immunol. 2012;145(1):61&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4556448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22926079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson K, Scott SD, Fraser KD. Oxygen use for preterm infants: factors that may influence clinical decisions surrounding oxygen titration. Adv Neonatal Care. 2011;11(1):8&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21285649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gephart SM, Hanson CK. Preventing necrotizing enterocolitis with standardized feeding protocols: not only possible, but imperative. Adv Neonatal Care. 2013;13(1):48&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23360859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokowski LA. Fundamentals of phototherapy for neonatal jaundice. Adv Neonatal Care. 2011;11(5 suppl):S10&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22123449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockcroft S. How can family centred care be improved to meet the needs of parents with a premature baby in neonatal intensive care? J Neonat Nurs. 2012;18:105&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson T, Ivey J. Neonate with cardiac issues. Pediatr Nurs. 2006;32(6):566&#x2013;567.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17256295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahle WT, Newburger JW, Matherne GP, et al. Role of pulse oximetry in examining newborns for congenital heart disease: a scientific statement from the AHA and AAP. Pediatrics. 2009;124(2):823&#x2013;836.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19581259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rourke L, Leduc D, Constantin E, Carsley S, Rourke J. Update on well-baby and well-child care from 0 to 5 years: What's new in the Rourke Baby Record? Can Fam Physician. 2010;56(12):1285&#x2013;1590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3001919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21156890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savage C, Kub J. Public health and nursing: a natural partnership. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2009;6(11):2843&#x2013;2848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20049229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juv&#xe9;-Udina ME, Farrero S, Monterde D, et al. Expertise threshold required for nursing competency performance. Metas Enferm. 2008;11(10):8&#x2013;15. [Spanish]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson C, Dalgleish L, Bucknall T, et al. The effects of time pressure and experience on nurses' risk assessment decisions: a signal detection analysis. Nurs Res. 2008;57(5);302&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18794714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>