<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">26447009</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2018</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2202-4433</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JBI database of systematic reviews and implementation reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JBI Database System Rev Implement Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The patient experience of patient-centered communication with nurses in the hospital setting: a qualitative systematic review protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>76</StartPage><EndPage>87</EndPage><MedlinePgn>76-87</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.11124/jbisrir-2015-1072</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="REVIEW QUESTION/OBJECTIVE">The objective of this systematic review is to synthesize the eligible evidence of patients' experience of engaging and interacting with nurses, in the medical-surgical ward setting.This review will consider the following questions:</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Communication is a way in which humans make sense of the world around them. Communication takes place as an interactive two-way process or interaction, involving two or more people and can occur by nonverbal, verbal, face-to-face or non-face-to-face methods. Effective communication is described to occur when the sender of a message sends their message in a way that conveys the intent of their message and then is understood by the receiver of the message. As a result of the communication from both the sender and the receiver of the message a shared meaning is created between both parties.Communication can therefore be viewed as a reciprocal process. In the health care literature the terms communication and interaction are used interchangeably.Communication failures between clinicians are the most common primary cause of errors and adverse events in health care. Communication is a significant factor in patient satisfaction and complaints about care. Communication plays an integral role in service quality in all service professions including health care professions.Within healthcare, quality care has been defined by the Institute of Medicine as 'care that is safe, effective, timely, efficient, equitable and patient-centred'. Patient-centered care is defined as 'care that is respectful of and responsive to individual patient preferences, needs and values, and ensuring that patient's values guide all clinical decisions. Patient centered-care encompasses the 'individual experiences of a patient, the clinical service, the organizational and the regulatory levels of health care'. At the individual patient level, patient-centered care is care that is 'provided in a respectful manner, assures open and ongoing sharing of useful information in an ongoing manner and supports and encourages the participation of patients and their families'. Healthcare organizations that are patient-centered engage patients as partners and hold human interactions as a pillar of their service.The deepening evidence base for principles and practice of patient-centered care has resulted in increasing recognition of, and greater focus on, the engagement of patients, and the value and benefit of patient engagement. Contemporary healthcare policy across the globe increasingly supports the engagement of patients as partners in all aspects of their own health care and also in systemic quality improvement. In 2005, the World Health Organization's (WHO) World Alliance for Patient Safety established the Patients for Patient Safety program, to improve patient safety globally in collaboration with patient advocates across the world. As a global initiative, Patients for Patient Safety 'believes that safety will be improved if patients are placed at the center of care and included as full partners'.In 2011 the United States of America Department of Health and Human Services announced its commitment of one billion US dollars of federal funding under The Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act 2010 and launched the Partnership for Patients initiative. The Partnership for Patients public-private consortium, which focuses on patient safety improvements and draws membership from federal government agencies and over 8000 health care providing organizations and individuals, views patients 'as essential partners in improving safety and quality' and 'their participation as active members of their own healthcare team is an essential component of making healthcare safer and reducing readmission'.In Australia, as part of national health care reforms to improve access to care, the efficiency of care and public transparency of the performance and funding of health services, the Australian Health Ministers endorsed the 10 National Safety and Quality Health Service Standards (NSQHSS) in 2011 and the Australian Safety and Quality Goals for Health Care (The Goals) in 2012. The NSQHSS focus on partnerships with health consumers in their own care and treatment and also in health service planning, the design of care and service monitoring and evaluation. Standard 1 - Governance for Safety and Quality, and Standard 2 - Partnering with Consumers, are required to be integrated within all of the other eight Standards.With patient safety and quality being core to the delivery of care the Safety of Care, Appropriateness of Care and Partnering with Consumers goals have been identified as the three areas that will make up the goals over the next five years until 2017. The Australian Commission on Safety and Quality in Health Care, in providing further justification for the focus on these three areas, states:The third priority area of The Goals, Partnering with Consumers, reflects patient-centered care practice by ensuring 'that there are effective partnerships between consumers and healthcare providers and organizations at all levels of healthcare provision, planning and evaluation'. Specifically, 'Consumers and healthcare providers understand each other when communicating about care and treatment and health care organizations are health literate organizations''.As healthcare focuses on providing services that are patient-centered and methods to ensure this occurs, patients' voice and experience of health care provision is increasingly being sought from an organizational quality improvement perspective. Patients are being surveyed on their healthcare experience across interpersonal areas such as being provided the opportunity by their health professional to ask questions, the level of involvement in their own care and whether they were shown courtesy, treated with respect and listened to carefully by their health professional.Surveys of patients' satisfaction with their care are now being superseded by surveys of patient experiences of care. However, current methods used to collect and use information from patients about their care is often retrospective, provides inadequate real time data and is not effective in creating action to produce change at the individual patient level. Methods which focus on including the patient and their information in real-time are considered by many to be crucial to the advancement of improved health outcomes and the reduced costs that are required of health care to be sustainable. One such method is patient-centered communication.The nurse-patient interaction is a core component of nursing science and high quality nursing care. Fleisher et al. contend that 'the main intention of communication and interaction, in the health setting, is to influence the patient's health status or state of well-being'. As a profession, nursing predominately requires communicating with, and relating to, patients at the individual level. In the hospital setting nurses undertake many of their patient related duties in a face-to-face manner with the patient at the bedside and these moments can facilitate effective interaction to occur between the nurse and the patient, which is patient-centered. McCabe et al. state that patient-centered communication as "defined by Langewitz et al. as 'communication that invites and encourages the patient to participate and negotiate in decision-making regarding their own care'.''However, qualitative studies by McCabe and Wellard et al, highlighted that nurses interact with patients only when performing administrative or functional activities and nursing 'practice was predominately task-orientated'. The outcome of these studies are supported by Maurer et al. in their report on the tools and strategies available to support patient and family engagement in the hospital setting. Maurer et al. identified that current strategies 'are not attuned to patient and family member experiences of hospitalization' and that most tools and strategies were 'more reflective of health professional and hospital views and the organization of their work'. The report identified a gap in the initiation of engagement, which is not driven by the patients and families' needs and preferences as they occur but by the 'opportunities that the hospital makes available'.McCabe et al. also argue that nurses' attending behavior, that is their 'accessibility and readiness to listen to patients through the use of non-verbal communication' requires that they have the underpinning elements of 'genuineness, warmth and empathy' all of which are components of patient-centered communication. McCabe et al. observed that 'that nurses do not always communicate in a patient-centered way'.According to Fleischer et al. 'The listening behavior in the way of listening and asking actually is the beginning of the nurse-patient communication relationship' McCabe et al. state that the lack of recognition and support by healthcare organizations of the connection and subsequent importance of patient-centered communication in the provision of high quality care has promulgated a culture averse to patient centered communication and is a significant factor in reducing the value that nurses place on providing patient-centered communication to patients.It is apparent that tensions exist between service quality and patient-centered care principles and practice. The impact of this tension on care and the patient as an individual is reflected in the literature. McCabe et al. claim that the use of non-patient-centered types of communication can negatively affect a patient's sense of well-being and security. Horvey et al. detail patient and family member experiences of not being listened to by their health care providers and describe the resulting consequences to be as severe as the death of the patient during their hospital stay. (ABSTRACT TRUNCATED)</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Newell</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>1 The Joanna Briggs Institute, School of Translational Health Science, Faculty of Health Sciences, University of Adelaide, South Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jordan</LastName><ForeName>Zoe</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Australia</Country><MedlineTA>JBI Database System Rev Implement Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101648258</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2202-4433</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001315" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Australia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003142" MajorTopicYN="Y">Communication</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003657" MajorTopicYN="N">Decision Making</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004645" MajorTopicYN="N">Empathy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000941" MajorTopicYN="N">ethics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005190" MajorTopicYN="N">Family</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018166" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Care Reform</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000331" MajorTopicYN="N">legislation &amp; jurisprudence</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006761" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitals</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007297" MajorTopicYN="N">Inpatients</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009726" MajorTopicYN="N">Nurses</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058991" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017060" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Satisfaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018802" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient-Centered Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000078202" MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic Reviews as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26447009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11124/jbisrir-2015-1072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>