<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39774180</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-9774</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>43</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Computers, informatics, nursing : CIN</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Comput Inform Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Self-efficacy Through Digital Care Plan Participation.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e01220</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CIN.0000000000001220</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The concept of self-care is a foundational construct of individual health and wellness. Facilitated self-care is the next logical step in society's uptake of technology for previously high-touch clinical activities, such as patient education and frequent biometric data tracking. This retrospective study aimed to assess whether participation in a digital interactive care plan correlated with an increase in participants' perceived self-efficacy as measured by a change in the Shortened Perceived Medical Condition Self-management Scale score from baseline to end-of-care plan. We included adult patients who were enrolled in at least one of 15 different interactive care plans at our institution between October 21, 2021, and December 30, 2022. Among 3196 patients included, 48.7% of participants did not complete the Shortened Perceived Medical Condition Self-management Scale assessment at baseline, and 73.5% did not complete it at end-of-care plan. For those who completed both assessments (n = 848), 52.2% had no change in their reported self-efficacy on completion of care plan. Similar percentages of patients had increased and decreased scores (25.6% vs 21.9%). The low completion rates were not sufficient to answer the research questions and generalize results. They also underscore the importance of patient engagement for understanding health outcomes associated with implementation of digital health solutions.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Justin M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8057-8800</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Author Affiliations: Department of Nursing (Dr Smith), Center for Digital Health (Ms Christopherson), and Division of Clinical Trials and Biostatistics (Mr Harmsen), Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN; and Artificial Intelligence and Bioinformatics (Ms Harper), Mayo Clinic Health System - Northwest Wisconsin region, Eau Claire, WI.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Christopherson</LastName><ForeName>Laura A</ForeName><Initials>LA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harper</LastName><ForeName>Sarah B</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harmsen</LastName><ForeName>William S</ForeName><Initials>WS</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Comput Inform Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101141667</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1538-2931</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020377" MajorTopicYN="Y">Self Efficacy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012648" MajorTopicYN="Y">Self Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010358" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Participation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010347" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Care Planning</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="N">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital self-care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39774180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CIN.0000000000001220</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00024665-990000000-00256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson A, Whitehead L. Evolution of the concept of self-care and implications for nurses: a literature review. International Journal of Nursing Studies . 2009;46(8): 1143&#x2013;1147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orem DE, Taylor SG, Renpenning KM. Nursing: Concepts of Practice . 6th ed. St Louis, MO: Mosby; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor SG, Geden E, Isaramalai S, Wongvatunyu S. Orem&#x2019;s self-care deficit nursing theory: its philosophic foundation and the state of the science. Nursing Science Quarterly . 2000;13(2): 104&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abe EN, Abe II, Adisa O. Future of work: skill obsolescence, acquisition of new skills, and upskilling in the 4IR. In: Abe EN, ed. Future of Work, Work-Family Satisfaction, and Employee Well-being in the Fourth Industrial Revolution . Hershey, PA: IGI Global; 2021: 217&#x2013;231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynn M, Garwood-Cross L, Vasilica C, Griffiths M, Heaslip V, Phillips N. Digitizing nursing: a theoretical and holistic exploration to understand the adoption and use of digital technologies by nurses. Journal of Advanced Nursing . 2023;79(10): 3737&#x2013;3747.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borges do Nascimento IJ, Abdulazeem H, Vasanthan LT, et al. Barriers and facilitators to utilizing digital health technologies by healthcare professionals. NPJ Digital Medicine . 2023;6(1): 161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asch DA, Nicholson S, Berger ML. Toward facilitated self-service in health care. The New England Journal of Medicine . 2019;380(20): 1891&#x2013;1893.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatia RS, Chu C, Pang A, Tadrous M, Stamenova V, Cram P. Virtual care use before and during the COVID-19 pandemic: a repeated cross-sectional study. CMAJ Open . 2021;9(1): E107&#x2013;E114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Predmore ZS, Roth E, Breslau J, Fischer SH, Uscher-Pines L. Assessment of patient preferences for telehealth in post&#x2013;COVID-19 pandemic health care. JAMA Network Open . 2021;4(12): e2136405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Arkee S, Mason J, Lane DA, et al. Mobile apps to improve medication adherence in cardiovascular disease: systematic review and meta-analysis. Journal of Medical Internet Research . 2021;23(5): e24190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle J, Murphy E, Gavin S, et al. A digital platform to support self-management of multiple chronic conditions (ProACT): findings in relation to engagement during a one-year proof-of-concept trial. Journal of Medical Internet Research . 2021;23(12): e22672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magalhaes B, Fernandes C, Santos C, Martinez-Galiano JM. The use of mobile applications for managing care processes during chemotherapy treatments: a systematic review. Cancer Nursing . 2021;44(6): E339&#x2013;E360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaverson M. How COVID-19 has accelerated digital transformation in healthcare. https://healthtechmagazine.net/article/2020/12/how-covid-19-has-accelerated-digital-transformation-healthcare .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eze CE, West BT, Dorsch MP, et al. Predictors of smartphone and tablet use among patients with hypertension: secondary analysis of health information National Trends Survey Data. Journal of Medical Internet Research . 2022;24(1): e33188.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders R, Seaman K, Emery L, et al. Comparing an eHealth program (my hip journey) with standard care for total hip arthroplasty: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Rehabilitation and Assistive Technologies . 2021;8(1): e22944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith JM, Pearson KK, Roberson AE. Interface of clinical nurse specialist practice and healthcare technology. Clinical Nurse Specialist . 2023;37(4): 169&#x2013;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Resnick B. Self-efficacy. In: Peterson SJ, Bredow TS, eds. Middle Range Theories: Application to Nursing Research and Practice . 5th ed.&#xa0;Wolters Kluwer; 2020: 91&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wild MG, Ostini R, Harrington M, Cavanaugh KL, Wallston KA. Validation of the shortened perceived medical condition self-management scale in patients with chronic disease. Psychological Assessment . 2018;30(10): 1300&#x2013;1307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian L, Sy LS, Hong V, et al. Disparities in outpatient and telehealth visits during the COVID-19 pandemic in a large integrated health care organization: retrospective cohort study. Journal of Medical Internet Research . 2021;23(9): e29959.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee EW, McCloud RF, Viswanath K. Designing effective eHealth interventions for underserved groups: five lessons from a decade of eHealth intervention design and deployment. Journal of Medical Internet Research . 2022;24(1): e25419.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebbert JO, Khan RG, Leibovich BC. Health care transformations merging traditional and digital medical practices. Mayo Clinic Proceedings: Digital Health . 2023;1(2): 63&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>