<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">24025397</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1660-4601</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2013</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of environmental research and public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Environ Res Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Achieving smoke-free mental health services: lessons from the past decade of implementation research.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>4224</StartPage><EndPage>4244</EndPage><MedlinePgn>4224-44</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ijerph10094224</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The culture of smoking by patients and staff within mental health systems of care has a long and entrenched history. Cigarettes have been used as currency between patients and as a patient management tool by staff. These settings have traditionally been exempt from smoke-free policy because of complex held views about the capacity of people with mental disorder to tolerate such policy whilst they are acutely unwell, with stakeholders' continuing fierce debate about rights, choice and duty of care. This culture has played a significant role in perpetuating physical, social and economic smoking associated impacts experienced by people with mental disorder who receive care within mental health care settings. The past decade has seen a clear policy shift towards smoke-free mental health settings in several countries. While many services have been successful in implementing this change, many issues remain to be resolved for genuine smoke-free policy in mental health settings to be realized. This literature review draws on evidence from the international published research, including national audits of smoke-free policy implementation in mental health units in Australia and England, in order to synthesise what we know works, why it works, and the remaining barriers to smoke-free policy and how appropriate interventions are provided to people with mental disorder.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lawn</LastName><ForeName>Sharon</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Flinders Human Behaviour and Health Research Unit, Flinders University, Room 4T306, Margaret Tobin Centre, Flinders University, GPO Box 2100, Adelaide 5001, Australia. sharon.lawn@flinders.edu.au</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Campion</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2013</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Environ Res Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101238455</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1660-4601</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006778" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitals, Psychiatric</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000331" MajorTopicYN="Y">legislation &amp; jurisprudence</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008605" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health Services</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000331" MajorTopicYN="Y">legislation &amp; jurisprudence</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016134" MajorTopicYN="N">Organizational Policy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061845" MajorTopicYN="Y">Smoke-Free Policy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2013</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24025397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph10094224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijerph10094224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lasser K., Boyd J.W., Woolhandler S., Himmelstein D.U., McCormick D., Bor D.H. Smoking and mental illness: A population based prevalence study. JAMA. 2010;284:2606&#x2013;2610.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11086367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Access Economics. Smoking and Mental Illness: Costs, 2007. SANE Australia; South Melbourne, Australia: 2007.  [(accessed on 4 April 2013)].  Available online: http://www.sane.org/images/stories/information/research/0712_info_smokecosts.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McManus S., Meltzer H., Campion J.  Data from the Adult Psychiatric Morbidity Survey. National Centre for Social Research, 2010. NatCen Social Research; London, UK: 2010.  [(accessed on 4 April 2013)]. Cigarette Smoking and Mental Health in England. Available online: http://www.natcen.ac.uk/study/cigarette-smoking--mental-health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gfroerer J., Dube S.R., King B.A., Garrett B.E., Babb S., McAfee T. Vital signs: Current cigarette smoking among adults aged &#x2265;18 years with mental illness&#x2014;United States, 2009&#x2013;2011. MMWR. 2013;62:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4604817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23388551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobias M., Templeton R., Collings S. How much do mental disorders contribute to New Zealand&#x2019;s tobacco epidemic? Tob. Control. 2008;17:347&#x2013;350. doi: 10.1136/tc.2008.026005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tc.2008.026005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18669558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S. The Culture of Smoking in Mental Health Service Populations. Lambert Academic Publishing; Berlin, Germany: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S.J. Ph.D. Thesis. Flinders University of South Australia; Adelaide, Australia: 2001. Systemic Barriers to Quitting Smoking among Institutionalised Public Mental Health Service Populations.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15511114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S.J. Cigarette smoking in psychiatric settings: Occupational health, safety, welfare and legal concerns. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2005;39:886&#x2013;891. doi: 10.1080/j.1440-1614.2005.01698.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/j.1440-1614.2005.01698.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16168015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S. Systemic barriers to quitting smoking among institutionalised public mental health service populations: A comparison of two Australian sites. Int. J. Soc. Psychiatry. 2004;50:204&#x2013;215. doi: 10.1177/0020764004043129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0020764004043129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15511114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jochelson K., Majrowski W. Clearing the Air: Debating Smoke-Free Policies in Psychiatric Units. King&#x2019;s Fund; London, UK: 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNeill A. Smoking and Mental Health: A Review of the Literature. SmokeFree London Programme, London Region National Health Service; London, UK: 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Royal College of Physicians. Royal College of Psychiatrists . Smoking and Mental Health. Royal College of Physicians; London, UK: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper H. Synthesizing Research: A Guide to Literature Reviews. 3rd ed. Sage; Thousand Oaks, CA, USA: 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torraco R.J. Writing integrative literature reviews: Guidelines and examples. Hum. Resour. Dev. Rev. 2005;4:356&#x2013;367. doi: 10.1177/1534484305278283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1534484305278283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S., Pols R. Smoking bans in psychiatric inpatient settings? A review of the research. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2005;39:866&#x2013;885. doi: 10.1080/j.1440-1614.2005.01697.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/j.1440-1614.2005.01697.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16168014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campion J., Checinski K., Nurse J. Review of smoking cessation treatments for people with mental illness. Adv. Psychiatr. Treat. 2008;14:208&#x2013;216. doi: 10.1192/apt.bp.107.003483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/apt.bp.107.003483</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campion J., Checinski K., Nurse J., McNeill A. Smoking by people with mental illness and benefits of smoke-free mental health services. Adv. Psychiatr. Treat. 2008;14:217&#x2013;228. doi: 10.1192/apt.bp.108.005710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/apt.bp.108.005710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campion J., Lawn S., Brownlie A., Hunter E., Gynther B., Pols R. Implementing smoke-free policies in mental health inpatient units: Learning from unsuccessful experience. Austr. Psychiatr. 2008;16:92&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1080/10398560701851976.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10398560701851976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18335364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardi-Bee J., Jayes L., O&#x2019;Mara-Eves A., Stansfield C., Gibson K., Ratschen E., McNeil A. Review 4: Effectiveness of Smoking Cessation Interventions in Mental Health Services. NICE Evidence Reviews: Smoking Cessation Acute, Maternity and Mental Health Services. Draft 5.0.  [(accessed on 15 June 2013)].  Available online: http://guidance.nice.org.uk/PHG/51/Consultation/Latest.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonardi-Bee J., Jayes L., O&#x2019;Mara-Eves A., Stansfield C., Gibson K., Ratschen E., McNeil A. Review 5: Barriers to and Facilitators for Smoking Cessation Interventions in Mental Health Services. NICE Evidence Reviews: Smoking Cessation Acute, Maternity and Mental Health Services. Draft 3.0.  [(accessed on15 June 2013)].  Available online: http://guidance.nice.org.uk/PHG/51/Consultation/Latest.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angus K., Murray R., MacDonald L., Eadie D., O&#x2019;Mara-Eves A., Stansfield C., Leonardi-Bee J. Review 6: A Review of the Effectiveness of Smokefree Strategies and Interventions in Secondary Care Settings. NICE Evidence Reviews: Smoking Cessation Acute, Maternity and Mental Health Services. Draft 3.0.  [(accessed on 15 June 2013)].  Available online: http://guidance.nice.org.uk/PHG/51/Consultation/Latest.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eadie D., MacDonald L., Angus K., Murray R., O&#x2019;Mara-Eves A., Stansfield C., Leonardi-Bee J. Review 7: A Review of the Barriers to and Facilitators for Implementing Smokefree Strategies and Interventions in Secondary Care Settings. NICE Evidence Reviews: Smoking Cessation Acute, Maternity and Mental Health Services. Draft 3.0.  [(accessed on 15 June 2013)].  Available online: http://guidance.nice.org.uk/PHG/51/Consultation/Latest.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S., Campion J. Factors associated with success of smoke-free initiatives in Australian psychiatric inpatient units. Psych. Serv. 2010;61:300&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.61.3.300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.61.3.300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20194408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S., Campion J. Smoke-Free Initiatives in Psychiatric Inpatient Units: A National Survey of Australian Sites. Independent Report for Flinders University; Adelaide, Australia: 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tobacco Coordinating Collaboration Centre/Chartered Institute of Environmental Health. Review of Smokefree Mental Health. Draft Final Report for the Department of Health, CIEH; London, UK: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parker C., McNeill A., Ratschen E. Tailored tobacco dependence support for mental health patients: A model for inpatient and community services. Addiction. 2012;107:18&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1111/j.1360-0443.2012.04082.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1360-0443.2012.04082.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23121356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stubbs J., Haw C., Garner L. Survey of staff attitudes to smoking in a large psychiatric hospital. Psychiatry Bull. 2004;28:204&#x2013;207. doi: 10.1192/pb.28.6.204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/pb.28.6.204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickens G., Stubbs J., Popham R. Smoking in a forensic psychiatric service: A survey of inpatients&#x2019; views. J. Psychiatr. Ment. Hlt. 2005;12:672&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16336591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prochaska J.J. Smoking and mental illness: Breaking the link. N. Engl. J. Med. 2011;365:196&#x2013;198. doi: 10.1056/NEJMp1105248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp1105248</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4457781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21774707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. The Health Consequences of Involuntary Exposure to Tobacco Smoke: A Report of the Surgeon General. CDCP Coordinating Center for Health Promotion, National Center for Chronic Disease Prevention and Health Promotion, Office on Smoking and Health; Atlanta, GA, USA: 2006.  [(accessed on 4 April 2013)].  Available online: http://wwwsurgeongeneralgov/library/secondhandsmoke/report/chapter10pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. How Tobacco Smoke Causes Disease: The Biology and Behavioural Basis for Smoking-Attributable Disease: A Report of the Surgeon General. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services; Atlanta, GA, USA: 2010.  [(accessed on 4 April 2013)].  Available online: http://www.surgeongeneral.gov/library/reports/tobaccosmoke/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballbe M., Sureda X., Martinez-Sanchez J.M., Salto E.L., Gual A., Fernandez E. Second-hand smoke in mental healthcare settings: Time to implement total smoke-free bans? Int. J. Epidemiol. 2013 doi: 10.1093/ije/dyt014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyt014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23543600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willemsen M.C., Gort C.A., van Soelen P., Jonkers R., Hilberink S.R. Exposure to environmental tobacco smoke (ETS) and determinants of support for complete smoking bans in psychiatric settings. Tob. Control. 2004;13:180&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1136/tc.2003.004804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tc.2003.004804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1747858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15175537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keizer I., Descloux V., Eytan A. Variation in smoking after admission to psychiatric inpatient units and impact of a partial ban on smoking and on smoking-related perceptions. Int. J. Soc. Psychiatry. 2009;55:109&#x2013;123. doi: 10.1177/0020764008092357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0020764008092357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19240201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S. In it together: Physical health and well-being for people with mental illness. The annual bruce woodcock memorial lecture. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2012;46:14&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1177/0004867411432079.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0004867411432079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22247088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galletly C., Foley D.L., Waterreus A., Watts G.F., Castle D.I., Mackinnon A., Morgan V.A. Cardiometabolic risk factors in people with psychotic disorders: The second Australian national survey of psychosis. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2012;46:753&#x2013;761. doi: 10.1177/0004867412453089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0004867412453089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22761397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manderscheid R., Druss B., Freeman E. Data to manage the mortality crisis. Int. J. Ment. Health. 2008;37:49&#x2013;68. doi: 10.2753/IMH0020-7411370202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2753/IMH0020-7411370202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown S., Kim M., Mitchell C., Inskip H. Twenty-five year mortality of a community cohort with schizophrenia. Brit. J. Psychiatr. 2010;196:116&#x2013;121. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.109.067512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.109.067512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4560167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20118455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang C.K., Hayes R.D., Perera G., Broadbent M.T.M., Fernandes A.C., Lee W.E., Hotopf M., Stewart R. Life expectancy at birth for people with serious mental illness and other major disorders form a secondary mental health care case register in London. PLoS One. 2011;6:e19590. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0019590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0019590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3097201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21611123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mykletun A., Bjerkeset O., Overland S., Prince M., Dewey M., Stewart R. Levels of anxiety and depression as predictors of mortality: The HUNT study. Brit. J. Psychiatry. 2009;195:118&#x2013;125. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.108.054866.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.108.054866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19648541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osborn D.P., Levy G., Nazareth I., Petersen I., Islam A., King M.B. Relative risk of cardiovascular and cancer mortality in people with severe mental illness from the United Kingdom&#x2019;s general practice rsearch database. Arch. Gen. Psychiatr. 2007;64:242&#x2013;249. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.64.2.242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.64.2.242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17283292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saha S., Chant D., McGrath J.A. Systematic review of mortality in schizophrenia: Is the differential mortality gap worsening over time? Arch. Gen. Psychiatr. 2007;64:1123&#x2013;1131. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.64.10.1123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.64.10.1123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17909124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris C.D., Waxmonsky J.A., May M.G., Tinkelman D.G., Dickinson M., Giese A.A. Smoking reduction for persons with mental illnesses: 6-Month results from community-based interventions. Community Ment. Health J. 2011 doi: 10.1007/s10597-011-9411-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10597-011-9411-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21556784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahab L., West R. Do ex-smokers report feeling happier following cessation? Evidence from a cross-sectional survey. Nicotine Tob. Res. 2009;11:553&#x2013;557. doi: 10.1093/ntr/ntp031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntp031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19351779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campion J., Bhugra D., Bailey S., Marmot M. Inequality and mental disorder: Opportunities for action. Lancet. 2013;382:183&#x2013;184. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)61411-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(13)61411-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23870520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S.J. Australians with mental illness who smoke. Brit. J. Psychiatr. 2001;178 doi: 10.1192/bjp.178.1.85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.178.1.85</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11136222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S.J., Pols R.G., Barber J.G. Smoking and quitting: A qualitative study with community-living psychiatric clients. Soc. Sci. Med. 2002;54:93&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/S0277-9536(01)00008-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0277-9536(01)00008-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11820684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson R., Marmot M. Social Determinants of Health: The Solid Facts. 2nd ed. World Health Organization; Copenhagen, Denmark: 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams J.M., Ziedonis D. Addressing tobacco among individuals with a mental illness or an addiction. Addict. Behav. 2004;29:1067&#x2013;1083. doi: 10.1016/j.addbeh.2004.03.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2004.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15236808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khantzian E.J. The self-medication hypothesis of addictive disorders: Focus on heroin and cocaine dependence. Am. J. Psychiatr. 1985;142:1259&#x2013;1265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3904487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levander S., Eberhard J., Lindstr&#xf6;m E. Nicotine use and its correlates in patients with psychosis. Acta Psychiatr. Scand. 2007;116:27&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1111/j.1600-0447.2007.01085.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0447.2007.01085.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17953523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siru R., Hulse G.K., Tait R.J. Assessing motivation to quit smoking in people with mental illness: A review. Addiction. 2009;104:719&#x2013;733. doi: 10.1111/j.1360-0443.2009.02545.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1360-0443.2009.02545.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19413788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S. Tobacco control policies, social inequality and mental health populations: Time for a comprehensive treatment response. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2008;42:353&#x2013;356. doi: 10.1080/00048670801961180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00048670801961180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18473253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S.J., Pols R.G. Nicotine withdrawal: Pathway to aggression and assault in the locked psychiatric ward. Austr. Psychiatr. 2003;11:199&#x2013;203. doi: 10.1046/j.1039-8562.2003.00548.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1039-8562.2003.00548.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Association of State Mental Health Program Directors (NASMHPD) Tobacco-Free Living in Psychiatric Settings: A Best-Practice Toolkit Promoting Wellness and Recovery. NASMHPD; Alexandria, VA, USA: 2007.  [(accessed on 4 April 2013)].  Available online: http://www.nasmhpd.org/general_files/publications/NASMHPD.toolkitfinalupdated90707.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horst W., Klein M.W., Williams D., Werder S.F. Extended use of nicotine replacement therapy to maintain smoking cessation for people with schizophrenia. Neuropsychiatr. Dis. Treat. 2005;1:349&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2424122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18568115</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnoll R.A., Patterson F., Wileyto E.P., Heitjan D., Shields A.E., Asch D., Lerman C. Effectiveness of extended duration transdermal nicotine therapy: A randomized trial. Ann. Intern. Med. 2010;152:144&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3782858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20124230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hehir A., Indig D., Prosser S., Archer V. Evaluation of a smoke-free forensic mental health inpatient hospital: The patient perspective. Drug. Alcohol. Rev. 2012 doi: 10.1111/j.1456-3362.2012.00456.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1456-3362.2012.00456.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22524262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollen M.A., Glorimar O., Schacht L., Mojarrad M.G., Lane G.M., Parks J.J. Effects of adopting a smoke-free policy in state psychiatric hospitals. Psychiatr. Serv. 2010;61:899&#x2013;904. doi: 10.1176/appi.ps.61.9.899.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ps.61.9.899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20810588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratschen E., Britton J., Doody G.A., McNeill A. Smoke-free policy in acute mental health wards: Avoiding the pitfalls. Gen. Hosp. Psychiatr. 2009;31:131&#x2013;136. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2008.10.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2008.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19269533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ratschen E., Britton J., McNeill A. Implementation of smoke-free policies in mental health in-patient settings in England. Brit. J. Psychiatr. 2009;194:547&#x2013;551. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.108.051052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.108.051052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19478296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voci S., Bondy S., Zawertailo L., Walker L., George T.P., Selby P. Impact of a smoke free policy in a large psychiatric hospital on staff attitudes and patient behaviour. Gen. Hosp. Psychiatr. 2010;32:623&#x2013;630. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2010.08.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2010.08.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21112455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hempel A., Kownacki R., Malin D.H., Ozone S.J., Cormack T.S., Sandoval B.G., Leinbach A.E. Effect of a total smoking ban in a maximum security psychiatric hospital. Behav. Sci. Law. 2002;20:507&#x2013;522. doi: 10.1002/bsl.503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bsl.503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12239709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quinn J., Inman J.D., Falow P. Results of the conversion to a tobacco-free environment in a state psychiatric hospital. Adm. Policy Ment. Health. 2000;27:451&#x2013;452. doi: 10.1023/A:1021398427332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1021398427332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11077707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole M.L., Trogoboff E., Demler T.L., Opler L.A. Impact of smoking cessation on psychiatric inpatients treated with clozapine or olanzapine. Psychiatr. Pract. 2010;16:75&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1097/01.pra.0000369968.80155.3f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.pra.0000369968.80155.3f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20511731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurdyak P., Cairney J., Sarnocinska-Hart A., Callahan R.C., Strike C. The Impact of a smoking cessation policy on visits to a psychiatric emergency department. Can. J. Psychiatr. 2008;53:779&#x2013;782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19087472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg S., Shenoy S., Badee M., Varghese J., Quinn P., Kent J. Survey of staff attitudes to the smoking ban in a medium secure unit. J. Forensic Legal Med. 2009;16:378&#x2013;380. doi: 10.1016/j.jflm.2009.04.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jflm.2009.04.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19733324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iglesias C., Lopez G., Alonso M.J. Effects of smoking ban in a general hospital psychiatric unit. Actas Esp. Psiquiatr. 2008;36:60&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18286401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss T.G., Weinberger A.H., Vessicchio J.C., Mancuso V., Cushing S.J., Pett M., Kitchen K., Selby P., George T.P. A tobacco reconceptualization in psychiatry: Toward the development of tobacco-free psychiatric facilities. Am. J. Addict. 2010;19:293&#x2013;311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20653636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hehir A.M., Indig D., Prosser S., Archer V.A. Implementation of a smoke free policy in a high secure mental health inpatient facility: Staff experience and attitudes. Int. J. Ment. Health Nurs. 2013;13:315&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3648483</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23566256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton M., Miller C.L., Bowden J.A., Bertossa S. People with mental illness can tackle tobacco. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2010;44:1021&#x2013;1028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21034185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton M., Rigby A., Galletly C. What do 1000 smokers with mental illness say about their tobacco use? Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2013;47:631&#x2013;636. doi: 10.1177/0004867413482008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0004867413482008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23493757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawai A., Abe H. The smoking situation of patients and staff in a psychiatry hospital. The smoking issue in psychiatry can be considered a neglected problem. Jpn. J. Pub. Health. 2007;54:626&#x2013;632.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17972433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stockings E., Bowman J., McElwaine K., Baker A., Terry M., Bartlem K., Wye P., Bridge P., Knight J., Wiggers J. Readiness to quit smoking and quit attempts among australian mental health inpatients. Nicotine Tob. Res. 2013;15:942&#x2013;949. doi: 10.1093/ntr/nts206.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/nts206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3621580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23089486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malpass D., Higgs S. How is cigarette smoking maintained in depression? Experiences of cigarette smoking in people diagnosed with depression. Addict. Res. Theory. 2009;17:64&#x2013;79. doi: 10.1080/16066350802079356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16066350802079356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prochaska J.J., Hall S.E., Delucchi K., Hall S.M. Efficacy of initiating tobacco dependence treatment in inpatient psychiatry: A randomized controlled trial. Am. J. Public Health. 2013 doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2013.301403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2013.301403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4103208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23948001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prochaska J.J., Fletcher L., Hall S.E., Hall S.M. Return to smoking following a smoke free psychiatric hospitalization. Am. J. Addict. 2006;15:15&#x2013;22. doi: 10.1080/10550490500419011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10550490500419011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16449089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etter J.F., Khan N., Etter M. Acceptability and impact of partial smoking ban, followed by a total smoking ban in a psychiatric hospital. Eur. Psychiatr. 2007;22:572&#x2013;578.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18289658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeAzevedo R.C.S., Leme J.R.L., Miranda F.Z., Botega N.J. Implementation of a smoke-free Psychiatric Unit in a general hospital. Rev. Bras. Psiquiatr. 2010;32:197&#x2013;198. doi: 10.1590/S1516-44462010000200019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1516-44462010000200019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20658061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shmueli D., Fletcher L., Hall S.E., Hall S.M., Prochaska J.J. Changes in psychiatric patients&#x2019; thoughts about quitting smoking during a smoke-free hospitalization. Nicotine Tob. Res. 2008;10:875&#x2013;881. doi: 10.1080/14622200802027198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14622200802027198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4457782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18569762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West R., Sohal T. &#x201c;Catastrophic&#x201d; pathways to smoking cessation: Findings from a national survey. BMJ. 2006;332:458&#x2013;460. doi: 10.1136/bmj.38723.573866.AE.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.38723.573866.AE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1382540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16443610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West R.  PRIME Theory of Motivation, 2011. Wiley-Blackwell; Oxford, UK: 2011.  [(accessed on 4 April 2013)].  Available online: http://www.primetheor.com/index.php.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Long C.G., Jones K. Issues in running smoking cessation groups with forensic psychiatric inpatients: Results of a pilot study and lessons learnt. Brit. J. Forensic Pract. 2005;7:22&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1108/14636646200500011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/14636646200500011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivier D., Lubman D.I., Fraser R. Tobacco smoking within psychiatric inpatient settings: Biopsychosocial perspective. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2007;41:572&#x2013;580. doi: 10.1080/00048670701392809.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00048670701392809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17558619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Happell B. Determining the effectiveness of mental health services from a consumer perspective: Part 1: Enhancing recovery. Int. J. Ment. Health Nurs. 2008;17:116&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1111/j.1447-0349.2008.00519.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1447-0349.2008.00519.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18307600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shattell M., Andes M. Smoking bans in acute care settings: A machiavellian smoke screen? Issues Ment. Health Nurs. 2008;29:201&#x2013;203. doi: 10.1080/01612840701792274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01612840701792274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18293226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warner J. Smoking, stigma and human rights in mental health: Going up in smoke? Soc. Pol. Soc. 2009;8:275&#x2013;286. doi: 10.1017/S1474746408004788.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1474746408004788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hackett M. Smoke-free state psychiatric facility grounds: Is legislation necessary and appropriate to remove tobacco from these treatment settings. N. Y. Law Sch. Law Rev. 2008;53:99&#x2013;131.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz A.S.H., Finegan B., Nykiforuk C.I.J., Kvern M.A. A qualitative investigation of smoke-free policies on hospital property. CMAJ. 2011;183:E1334&#x2013;E1344. doi: 10.1503/cmaj.110235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.110235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3255146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22042991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wye P., Bowman J., Wiggers J., Baker A., Carr V., Terry M., Knight J., Clancy R. Providing nicotine dependence treatment to psychiatric inpatients: The views of Australian nurse managers. J. Psychiatr. Ment. Hlt. 2010;17:319&#x2013;327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20529182</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wye P., Bowman J., Wiggers J., Baker A., Knight J., Carr V., Terry M., Clancy R. Total smoking bans in psychiatric inpatient services: A survey of perceived benefits, barriers and support among staff. BMC Public Health. 2010;10:372&#x2013;382. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-10-372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-10-372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3091547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20576163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashton M., Lawn S., Hosking J.R. Mental health workers&#x2019; views on addressing tobacco use. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2010;44:846&#x2013;851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20815672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jochelson K. Smoke-free legislation and mental health units: The challenges ahead. Brit. J. Psychiatr. 2006;189:479&#x2013;480. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.106.029942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.106.029942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17139029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S., Condon J. Psychiatric nurses&#x2019; ethical stance on cigarette smoking by patients: Determinants and dilemmas in their role in supporting cessation. Int. J. Ment. Health Nurs. 2006;15:111&#x2013;118. doi: 10.1111/j.1447-0349.2006.00410.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1447-0349.2006.00410.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16643346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prochaska J.J. Ten critical reasons for treating tobacco dependence in inpatient psychiatry. J. Am. Psychiatr. Nurs. Assoc. 2009;15:404&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1177/1078390309355318.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1078390309355318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2844659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20336177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams J.M. Eliminating tobacco use in mental health facilities. JAMA. 2008;299:571&#x2013;573. doi: 10.1001/jama.299.5.571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.299.5.571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18252888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapman S., Borland R., Scollo M., Brownson R., Dominello A., Woodward S. The impact of smoke free workplaces on declining cigarette consumption in Australia and the United States. Am. J. Public Health. 1999;89:1018&#x2013;1023. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.89.7.1018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.89.7.1018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1508862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10394309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg M., Davidson L. The nature of recovery as lived experience in everyday experience. J. Ment. Health. 2008;17:129&#x2013;140. doi: 10.1080/09638230701498382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638230701498382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNally L., Oyefeso A., Annan J., Perryman K., Bloor R., Freeman S., Ghodse A.H. A survey of staff attitudes to smoking-related policy and intervention in psychiatric and general health care settings. J. Public Health. 2006;28:192&#x2013;196. doi: 10.1093/pubmed/fdl029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pubmed/fdl029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16809790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trinkoff A., Storr C. Substance use among nurses: Differences between specialities. J. Addict. Nurs. 1998;10:77&#x2013;83. doi: 10.3109/10884609809041784.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10884609809041784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1508454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9550998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziedonis D., Hitsman B., Beckham J.C., Zvolensky M., Adler L.E., Audrain-McGovern J., Breslau N., Brown R.A., George T.P., Williams J., et al. Tobacco use and cessation in psychiatric disorders: National Institute of Mental Health report. Nicotine Tob. Res. 2008;10:1691&#x2013;1715. doi: 10.1080/14622200802443569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14622200802443569</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19023823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Essenmacher C., Karvonen-Gutierrez C., Lynch-Sauer J., Duffy S.A. Staff&#x2019;s attitudes toward the delivery of tobacco cessation services in a primary psychiatric veterans&#x2019; affairs hospital. Arch. Psychiatr. Nurs. 2009;23:231&#x2013;242.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19446778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wernz F.D., Friederich H.M., Buchkremer G., Batra A. Acceptance of smoke-free policy in a psychiatric department by in-patients and staff. Wiener Med. Wochenschr. 2009;159:33&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1007/s10354-008-0638-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10354-008-0638-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19225733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence D., Lawn S., Kisely S., Bates A., Mitrou S., Zubrich R. The potential impact of smoke free facilities on smoking cessation in people with mental illness. Aust. N. Z. J. Psychiatr. 2011;45:1053&#x2013;1060. doi: 10.3109/00048674.2011.619961.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00048674.2011.619961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22017657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittchen H.U., Jacobi F., Rehm J., Gustavsson A., Svensson M., Jonsson B., Olesen J., Allgulander C., Alonso J., Faravelli C., et al. The size and burden of mental disorder and other disorder of the brain in Europe 2010. Eur. Neuropsychopharmacol. 2011;21:655&#x2013;679. doi: 10.1016/j.euroneuro.2011.07.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euroneuro.2011.07.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21896369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>