<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35372980</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2641-7650</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>28</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Kidney360</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Kidney360</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Value-Based Care in Nephrology: The Kidney Care Choices Model and Other Reforms.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1677</StartPage><EndPage>1683</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1677-1683</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.34067/KID.0004552021</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The Advancing American Kidney Health (AAKH) initiative has reinvigorated the focus on improving the care of patients with advanced CKD. Multiple interventions have been planned, focusing on education campaigns for both clinicians and patients, delaying the progression of kidney disease and improving utilization of home dialysis modalities and kidney transplantation. Value-based care models for patients with advanced kidney disease are being rolled out, with the ESKD treatment choices model starting in January 2021, and the Kidney Care Choices model planned to start in January 2022. There is increasing emphasis on the role of the nephrologist as the "captain of the ship," leading efforts in care coordination as physician leaders. The transplant reforms have focused on changes to organ procurement organizations aiming to increase availability of organs, and transplants performed, both deceased and living donor, and removing financial disincentives from live organ donation. The American Society of Nephrology (ASN) and the National Kidney Foundation (NKF) are partnering with the Department of Health and Human Services to develop educational material for clinicians and patients. In this review, we discuss these reforms, potential challenges that have arisen, and potential solutions, with emphasis on the Kidney Care Choices model.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2021 by the American Society of Nephrology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>Gaurav</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1331-141</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, University of Alabama in Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiner</LastName><ForeName>Daniel E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8775-394</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Tufts Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Kidney360</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101766381</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2641-7650</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007668" MajorTopicYN="N">Kidney</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016030" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Transplantation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019520" MajorTopicYN="N">Living Donors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009398" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nephrology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Tissue and Organ Procurement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ETC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KCC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic kidney disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical nephrology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dialysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kidney care choices</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient activation measure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">value-based care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>D.E. Weiner reports consultancy agreements by participating in Medical Advisory Boards for Akebia (2020, 2021), Cara Therapeutics (2020), Janssen Biopharmaceuticals (2019), and Tricida (2019); reports receiving honoraria for Akebia paid to Dialysis Clinic, Inc. (DCI); reports receiving research funding with all compensation paid to AstraZeneca (site principal investigator [PI], completed 2020), CSL Behring (site PI, ongoing), Goldfinch Bio (site PI, ongoing), Janssen Biopharmaceuticals (site PI, completed 2019), Tufts MC: DCI (site PI for trials contracted with DCI including Ardelyx, ongoing, and Cara Therapeutics, completed); reports receiving honoraria from the NKF for editorial positions at Kidney Medicine and the American Journal of Kidney Disease, Elsevier for royalties from the NKF's Primer on Kidney Diseases; and reports being a scientific advisor or member of as Co-Editor-in-Chief, NKF Primer on Kidney Diseases, 8th Edition, Editor-in-Chief, Kidney Medicine, Medical Director of Clinical Research, DCI, Member, ASN Quality and Policy Committees and ASN representative to Kidney Care Partners, Scientific Advisory Board, NKF Other Interests/Relationships, Chair, adjudications committee, Evaluation of Effect of TRC101 in Progression of CKD in Subjects with Metabolic Acidosis (VALOR-CKD Trial, George Institute, Clinical Research Organization, sponsored by Tricida), and Member, Data Monitoring Committee, &#x201c;Feasibility of Hemodialysis with GARNET? in Chronic Hemodialysis Patients with a Bloodstream Infection&#x201d; Trial (Avania Clinical Research Organization). All remaining authors have nothing to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35372980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8785791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34067/KID.0004552021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">02200512-202110000-00019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mendu ML, Weiner DE: Health policy and kidney care in the United States: Core curriculum 2020. Am J Kidney Dis 76: 720&#x2013;730, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32771281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tummalapalli SL, Peralta CA: Preparing the nephrology workforce for the transformation to value-based kidney care: Needs assessment for advancing American kidney health. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 14: 1802&#x2013;1804, 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6895481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31699811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehrotra R: Advancing American kidney health: An introduction. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 14: 1788, 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6895493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31690694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health and Human Services : Medicare and Medicaid Programs; Organ procurement organizations conditions for coverage: Revisions to the outcome measure requirements for organ procurement organizations. Federal Register, the Daily Journal of the United States Government, 2020. pp 77898&#x2013;77949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lentine KL, Mannon RB: The Advancing American Kidney Health (AAKH) executive order: Promise and caveats for expanding access to kidney transplantation. Kidney360 1: 557&#x2013;460, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32587954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health and Human Services : <i>Removing Financial Disincentives to Living Organ Donation 85 FR 59438</i>. Federal Register, the Daily Journal of the United States Government, 2020. pp 59438&#x2013;59445. Available at: https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2020/09/22/2020-20804/removing-financial-disincentives-to-living-organ-donation. Accessed September 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Kidney Foundation : Are you the 33%?, 2020. Available at: https://www.kidney.org/newsletter/are-you-33-percent. Accessed June 20, 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Society of Nephrology : We&#x2019;re United 4 Kidney Health, 2021. Available at: https://4kidneyhealth.org/. Accessed July 10, 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services : End Stage Renal Disease (ESRD) Prospective Payment System (PPS) calendar year (CY) 2022 proposed rule (CMS-1749-P), 2021.  [CMS fact sheet]. Available at: https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/fact-sheets/end-stage-renal-disease-esrd-prospective-payment-system-pps-calendar-year-cy-2022-proposed-rule-cms. Accessed June 10, 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services : Kidney Care Choices (KCC) Model, 2019.  [CMS fact sheet]. Available at: https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/fact-sheets/kidney-care-choices-kcc-model. Accessed June 10, 2021</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrokhi F, Abedi N, Beyene J, Kurdyak P, Jassal SV: Association between depression and mortality in patients receiving long-term dialysis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Kidney Dis 63: 623&#x2013;635, 2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24183836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King-Wing Ma T, Kam-Tao Li P: Depression in dialysis patients. Nephrology (Carlton) 21: 639&#x2013;646, 2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26860073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer S, Vecchio M, Craig JC, Tonelli M, Johnson DW, Nicolucci A, Pellegrini F, Saglimbene V, Logroscino G, Fishbane S, Strippoli GF: Prevalence of depression in chronic kidney disease: Systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. Kidney Int 84: 179&#x2013;191, 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23486521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SD, Norris L, Acquaviva K, Peterson RA, Kimmel PL: Screening, diagnosis, and treatment of depression in patients with end-stage renal disease. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 2: 1332&#x2013;1342, 2007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17942763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair D, Cavanaugh KL: Measuring patient activation as part of kidney disease policy: Are we there yet? J Am Soc Nephrol 31: 1435&#x2013;1443, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7350992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drew DA, Lok CE, Cohen JT, Wagner M, Tangri N, Weiner DE: Vascular access choice in incident hemodialysis patients: A decision analysis. J Am Soc Nephrol 26: 183&#x2013;191, 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4279737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25063436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>