<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41986753</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1759-5053</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature reviews. Gastroenterology &amp; hepatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Global position statement supporting a World Health Assembly resolution on steatotic liver disease.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>449</StartPage><EndPage>451</EndPage><MedlinePgn>449-451</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41575-026-01201-z</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lazarus</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey V</ForeName><Initials>JV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9618-2299</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>City University of New York Graduate School of Public Health and Health Policy (CUNY SPH), New York, NY, USA. Jeffrey.Lazarus@isglobal.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barcelona Institute for Global Health (ISGlobal), Barcelona, Spain. Jeffrey.Lazarus@isglobal.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Halpern</LastName><ForeName>Bruno</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0973-5065</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>World Obesity Federation, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwarz</LastName><ForeName>Peter E H</ForeName><Initials>PEH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>International Diabetes Federation, Brussels, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Prevention and Care of Diabetes, Medizinische Klinik und Poliklinik III, Universit&#xe4;tsklinikum Carl Gustav Carus, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Boudou</LastName><ForeName>Delfina</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Barcelona Institute for Global Health (ISGlobal), Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Spall</LastName><ForeName>Harriette G C</ForeName><Initials>HGC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8370-4569</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences, McMaster University, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Population Health Research Institute, Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miller</LastName><ForeName>Veronica</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6543-3224</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Forum for Collaborative Research, University of California Berkeley School of Public Health, Berkeley, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duseja</LastName><ForeName>Ajay</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hepatology, Postgraduate Institute of Medical Education and Research (PGIMER), Chandigarh, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101500079</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1759-5045</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: J.V.L. received grants to his institutions from Boehringer Ingelheim, Echosens, Gilead Sciences, Madrigal Pharmaceuticals, MSD, Novo Nordisk and Pfizer; consulting fees from Echosens, GSK, Madrigal Pharmaceuticals, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer and Takeda; a paid leadership role at the Global NASH Council (ended); and honoraria for lectures from Echosens, Gilead Sciences, GSK, MSD, Novo Nordisk and Pfizer, outside of the submitted work. H.G.C.V.S. receives salary support from the Population Health Research Institute Mid-Career Award and research funding from Canadian Institutes of Health Research; and speaker&#x2019;s honoraria or clinical trial consulting fees from Bayer, Novo Nordisk, Medtronic, Pfizer, Cardiovascular Research Foundation, Baim Insitute of Clinical Research and CPC Clinical Research. B.H. has served as a consultant for Novo Nordisk, AstraZeneca, Merck, Eli Lilly and Company, Boehringer Ingelheim and Currax; and gave paid lectures for Novo Nordisk, Eli Lilly and Company, Merck, Boehringer Ingelheim and Novartis. P.E.H.S. acknowledges serving as the President of the International Diabetes Federation. He has received grant/research support from Deutsches Zentrum f&#xfc;r Diabetesforschung (DZD), the National Institutes of Health, the European Commission, the EU Directorate Public Health, BMBF, BZgA, European Public Health Authorities, SAB, Bayer Vital, Ascensia, Novartis, Astra, Eli Lilly and Company, Sanofi, AOK, the German Diabetes Organisation (DDG), the University of Dresden, MSD, Emperra Health Care, Bodytel, Impeto Health Care, Vitadio, Mebix, VIDEAmedical and UNA. He has received speaker honoraria from the European Commission, AOKplus, AOK, MDK, Ascensia, Novartis, Merck, Novo Nordisk, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Lifescan, Eli Lilly and Company, MSD, Boehringer Ingelheim, REHASAN, Servier, Sanofi, Leo Pharma, GSK, TUMAINI Institut f&#xfc;r Pr&#xe4;ventionsmanagement, the German Diabetes Organisation (DDG), Emperra, Zanadio, Vitadio, DiaExpert, Dexcom, the International Diabetes Federation, Janssen, USB and Protina. He has served on advisory boards for the European Commission, Ascensia, Eli Lilly and Company, GSK, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, REHASAN, Zanadio, Novo Nordisk, Servier, AOKplus, CCM International, Astra, DDG, EASD, EUDF, the International Diabetes Federation, VIDEAmedical, Dexcom, Abbott and Emperra AG. He has acted as a consultant for the European Commission, the International Diabetes Federation, AOKplus, TUMAINI Institut f&#xfc;r Pr&#xe4;ventionsmanagement, Deutsche Herzstiftung, REHASAN, Emperra, Impeto Health Care, Ascensia, Eli Lilly and Company, Philips, GWT, GLG, IT Industry, Infomedica, TK, Hapag-Lloyd, PwC, Pathways Public Health, Novo Nordisk, Lifescan, Vitadio, Perfood, LIVA, ONETWO, Zanadio, Mebix, VIDEAmedical, DIA Expert, UNA Health, HEDIA, Signal Iduna, GRO Health, Diaxilo, Oviva, Mementor and DiaNow. His family owns the TUMAINI Institut f&#xfc;r Pr&#xe4;ventionsmanagement and ISA Investment, and operates the portals &#x2018;ambulantesfasten&#x2019; and &#x2018;profschwarzfastet&#x2019; on Patreon. All this is outside of the submitted work. V.M. declares grant payments made to the Forum for Collaborative Research from the Gates Foundation to support salary. D.B. and A.D. declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>9</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>39</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41986753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41575-026-01201-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41575-026-01201-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Huang, D. Q. et al. Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease in adults. Nat. Rev. Dis. Primers 11, 14 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41572-025-00599-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40050362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tilg, H., Petta, S., Stefan, N. &amp; Targher, G. Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease in adults: a review. JAMA 335, 163&#x2013;174 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2025.19615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41212550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus, J. V. et al. A global action agenda for turning the tide on fatty liver disease. Hepatology 79, 502&#x2013;523 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HEP.0000000000000545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37540183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus, J. V. et al. A call to action from the Global Think-tank on Steatotic Liver Disease. Nat. Health https://doi.org/10.1038/s44360-025-00042-5 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44360-025-00042-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krag, A. et al. Uniting to defeat steatotic liver disease: a global mission to promote healthy livers and healthy lives. J. Hepatol 79, 1076&#x2013;1078 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2023.07.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37634993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. Steatotic liver disease: a missing piece in the global noncommunicable disease response. WHO Executive Board 158th session https://go.nature.com/4rZH4l4 (2026).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinella, M. E. et al. A multisociety Delphi consensus statement on new fatty liver disease nomenclature. Hepatology 78, 1966&#x2013;1986 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HEP.0000000000000520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37363821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10653297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Targher, G., Valenti, L. &amp; Byrne, C. D. Metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease. N. Engl. J. Med. 393, 683&#x2013;698 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra2412865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40802944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagstr&#xf6;m, H., Shang, Y., Hegmar, H. &amp; Nasr, P. Natural history and progression of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease. Lancet Gastroenterol. Hepatol. 9, 944&#x2013;956 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-1253(24)00193-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39243773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus, J. V. et al. The global NAFLD policy review and preparedness index: are countries ready to address this silent public health challenge? J. Hepatol. 76, 771&#x2013;780 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2021.10.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34895743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus, J. V. et al. Best buys for metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease and metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis: a global Delphi study. Lancet Gastroenterol. Hepatol. 11, 232&#x2013;242 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-1253(25)00300-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41397405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, M. S. et al. The basics of metabolic dysfunction&#x2013;associated steatotic liver disease for cardiologists: pathophysiology, diagnosis, and treatment. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 86, 1861&#x2013;1884 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2025.08.100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41224405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chew, N. W. S. et al. Cardiovascular-liver-metabolic health: recommendations in screening, diagnosis, and management of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease in cardiovascular disease via modified Delphi approach. Circulation 151, 98&#x2013;119 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.070535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39723980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazarus, J. V. et al. Name MASLD/MASH &#x2014; and act on it. Hepatol. Commun. 10, e0897 (2026).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HC9.0000000000000897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41521966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12788892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>