<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">39628430</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1866-0452</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>122</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Deutsches Arzteblatt international</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dtsch Arztebl Int</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>App-Based Psychotherapy of Panic Disorder With Self-Guided Exposure in Virtual Reality&#x2014;A Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>6</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-6</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3238/arztebl.m2024.0246</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">arztebl.m2024.0246</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Patients with panic disorder often suffer from tempo rary unavailability of care. The smartphone app Invirto (IVT) provides digital treatment for panic disorder comprising self-guided exposure in virtual reality. The aim of this trial was to assess the efficacy of Invirto.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">In a randomized, controlled, non-blinded trial, IVT was compared with care as usual (CAU) in patients with panic disorder (preregistration: DRKS00027585). The endpoints were assessed online before treatment (t0) and at 3 months (t1). The primary endpoint was the change in symptoms of anxiety, as measured with the Beck Anxiety Inventory (BAI), between the groups. The secondary endpoints were the patients' scores on the following assessment instruments, all in their German versions: the Panic and Agoraphobia Scale (PAS), the Beck Depression Inventory (BDI-II), a questionnaire on patient satisfaction (Client Satisfaction Questionnaire, CSQ-8), the Acceptance and Action Questionnaire (AAQ-II), and quality of life as a global item in the World Health Organization Quality of Life Questionnaire (WHOQOL-BREF).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">One hundred twenty-four participants were included. The intention-to-treat analysis revealed greater improvement with IVT than with CAU with respect to both the primary endpoint (BAI, d = -0.46; 95% confidence interval [-0.87; -0.04]) and the secondary endpoints (PAS, d = -0.63 [-1.05; -0.22]; BDI-II, d = -0.44 [-0.86; -0.02]; AAQ-II, d = -0.42 [-0.84; -0.01]), except for WHOQOL-BREF (p = 0.216).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">A digital treatment with virtual exposure can lessen anxiety, panic, and depressive symptoms and improve mental flexibility. In further studies, IVT should be compared with an active control group.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schultz</LastName><ForeName>Josephine</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baumeister</LastName><ForeName>Anna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schmotz</LastName><ForeName>Stella</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuurmans</LastName><ForeName>Lea</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jelinek</LastName><ForeName>Lena</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Dtsch Arztebl Int</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101475967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1866-0452</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016584" MajorTopicYN="Y">Panic Disorder</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063731" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mobile Applications</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063367" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007171" MajorTopicYN="Y">Implosive Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017060" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Satisfaction</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076142" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virtual Reality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012648" MajorTopicYN="Y">Self Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39628430</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12415993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3238/arztebl.m2024.0246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">arztebl.m2024.0246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Olaya B, Moneta MV, Miret M, Ayuso-Mateos JL, Haro JM. Epidemiology of panic attacks, panic disorder and the moderating role of age: results from a population-based study. J Affect Disord. 2018;241:627&#x2013;633.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30172214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Jonge P, Roest AM, Lim CCW, et al. Cross-national epidemiology of panic disorder and panic attacks in the world mental health surveys. Depress Anxiety. 2016;33:1155&#x2013;1177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5143159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27775828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKnight PE, Monfort SS, Kashdan TB, Blalock D V, Calton JM. Anxiety symptoms and functional impairment: a systematic review of the correlation between the two measures. Clin Psychol Rev. 2016;45:115&#x2013;130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26953005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilmer MT, Anderson K, Reynolds M. Correlates of quality of life in anxiety disorders: review of recent research. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2021;23:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8493947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34613508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandelow B, Werner AM, Kopp I, Rudolf S, Wiltink J, Beutel ME. The German guidelines for the treatment of anxiety disorders: first revision. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2022;272:571&#x2013;582.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8490968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34609587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abramowitz JS, Deacon BJ, Whiteside SPH. Exposure therapy for anxiety: principles and practice. Guilford Publications. 2019</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beesdo-Baum K, H&#xf6;fler M, Jacobi F, Wittchen HU. Epidemiologische Beitr&#xe4;ge zur Klinischen Psychologie BT&#x2014;Klinische Psychologie &amp; Psychotherapie. In: Hoyer J, Knappe S, editors. Berlin, Heidelberg: Springer; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clement S, Schauman O, Graham T, et al. What is the impact of mental health-related stigma on help-seeking? A systematic review of quantitative and qualitative studies. Psychol Med. 2015;45:11&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24569086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Titov N. Advantages and limitations of Internet-based interventions for common mental disorders. World Psychiatry. 2014;13:4&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3918007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24497236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Firth J, Torous J, Nicholas J, Carney R, Rosenbaum S, Sarris J. Can smartphone mental health interventions reduce symptoms of anxiety? A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Affect Disord. 2017;218:15&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28456072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlbring P, Andersson G, Cuijpers P, Riper H, Hedman-Lagerl&#xf6;f E. Internet-based vs. face-to-face cognitive behavior therapy for psychiatric and somatic disorders: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Cogn Behav Ther. 2018;47:1&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29215315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedman E, Lj&#xf3;tsson B, Lindefors N. Cognitive behavior therapy via the internet: a systematic review of applications, clinical efficacy and cost-effectiveness. Expert Rev Pharmacoecon Outcomes Res. 2012;12:745&#x2013;764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23252357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perugi G, Frare F, Toni C. Diagnosis and treatment of agoraphobia with panic disorder. CNS Drugs. 2007;21:741&#x2013;764.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17696574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Berglund P, Demler O, Jin R, Merikangas KR, Walters EE. Lifetime prevalence and age-of-onset distributions of DSM-IV disorders in the National Comorbidity Survey Replication. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005;62:593&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15939837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beesdo K, Pine DS, Lieb R, Wittchen HU. Incidence and risk patterns of anxiety and depressive disorders and categorization of generalized anxiety disorder. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2010;67:47&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20048222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pompoli A, Furukawa TA, Efthimiou O, Imai H, Tajika A, Salanti G. Dismantling cognitive-behaviour therapy for panic disorder: a systematic review and component network meta-analysis. Psychol Med. 2018;48:1945&#x2013;1953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6137372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29368665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton PJ, Price EC. A meta-analytic review of adult cognitive-behavioral treatment outcome across the anxiety disorders. J Nerv Ment Dis. 2007;195:521&#x2013;531.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17568301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carl E, Stein AT, Levihn-Coon A, et al. Virtual reality exposure therapy for anxiety and related disorders: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Anxiety Disord. 2019;61:27&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30287083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polak M, Tanzer NK, Bauernhofer K, Andersson G. Disorder-specific internet-based cognitive-behavioral therapy in treating panic disorder, comorbid symptoms and improving quality of life: a meta-analytic evaluation of randomized controlled trials. Internet Interv. 2021;24 100364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7889983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schultz J, Baumeister A, Schmotz S, Moritz S, Jelinek L. Efficacy of an internet-based intervention with self-applied exposure therapy in virtual reality for people with panic disorder: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2023;24:521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10422760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37573377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>First MB, Williams JBW, Karg RS, Spitzer RL. Arlington, VA: American Psychiatric Association; 2016. SCID-5-CV: structured clinical interview for DSM-5 disorders: clinician version.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helbig-Lang S, Hagestedt D, Lang T, Petermann F. Therapeutische Hausaufgaben in der klinischen Praxis: Einsatz, Erledigung und Beziehungen zum Therapieverlauf. Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Psychiatr Psychol und Psychother. 2012;60:111&#x2013;119. DOI: 101024/1661-4747/a000106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagena S, Gebauer M. Weinheim, Basel: Beltz-Verlag; 2014. Angstst&#xf6;rungen.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neudeck P, Lang T. Klinische Psychologie &amp; Psychotherapie. Springer; 2020. Reizkonfrontationsmethoden.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Epstein N, Brown G, Steer RA. An inventory for measuring clinical anxiety: psychometric properties. Journal of consulting and clinical psychology. 1988;56:893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3204199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margraf J, Ehlers A. Springer; 2007. Das Beck-Angstinventar (BAI)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson NS, Truax P. Clinical significance: a statistical approach to defining meaningful change in psychotherapy research. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1991;59:12&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2002127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. Routledge. 2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domhardt M, Letsch J, Kybelka J, Koenigbauer J, Doebler P, Baumeister H. Are internet- and mobile-based interventions effective in adults with diagnosed panic disorder and/or agoraphobia? A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2020;276:169&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haug T, Nordgreen T, &#xd6;st LG, Havik OE. Self-help treatment of anxiety disorders: a meta-analysis and meta-regression of effects and potential moderators. Clin Psychol Rev. 2012;32:425&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22681915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Chiu WT, Jin R, Ruscio AM, Shear K, Walters EE. The epidemiology of panic attacks, panic disorder, and agoraphobia in the National Comorbidity Survey Replication. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2006;63:415&#x2013;424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1958997</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16585471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe4;uerle A, Teufel M, Musche V, et al. Increased generalized anxiety, depression and distress during the COVID-19 pandemic: a cross-sectional study in Germany. J Public Health (Bangkok) 2020;42:672&#x2013;678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32657323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang JJ, Ji Y, Li YH, Pan HF, Su PY. Prevalence of anxiety symptom and depressive symptom among college students during COVID-19 pandemic: a meta-analysis. J Affect Disord. 2021;292:242&#x2013;254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8595068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34134022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keefe JR, Chambless DL, Barber JP, Milrod BL. Treatment of anxiety and mood comorbidities in cognitive-behavioral and psychodynamic therapies for panic disorder. J Psychiatr Res. 2019;114:34&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31015099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendlowicz M V, Stein MB. Quality of life in individuals with anxiety disorders. Am J Psychiatry. 2000;157:669&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10784456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olatunji BO, Cisler JM, Tolin DF. Quality of life in the anxiety disorders: a meta-analytic review. Clin Psychol Rev. 2007;27:572&#x2013;581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17343963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes SC, Strosahl K, Wilson KG, et al. Measuring experiential avoidance: a preliminary test of a working model. Psychol Rec. 2004;54:553&#x2013;578.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoyer J, Gloster AT. Psychologische Flexibilit&#xe4;t messen = measuring psychological flexibility: Der Fragebogen zu Akzeptanz und Handeln-II (FAH-II): the acceptance and action questionnaire-II (AAQ-II) Verhaltenstherapie. 2013;23:42&#x2013;44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming T, Bavin L, Lucassen M, Stasiak K, Hopkins S, Merry S. Beyond the trial: systematic review of real-world uptake and engagement with digital self-help interventions for depression, low mood, or anxiety. J Med Internet Res. 2018;20 e199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6010835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29875089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guiney H, Mahoney A, Elders A, David C, Poulton R. Internet-based cognitive behavioural therapy in the real world: naturalistic use and effectiveness of an evidence-based platform in New Zealand. Aust New Zeal J Psychiatry. 2024;58:238&#x2013;249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10903121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37366145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekker MH, van Mens-Verhulst J. Anxiety disorders: sex differences in prevalence, degree, and background, but gender-neutral treatment. Gend Med. 2007;4:178&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18156102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39:175&#x2013;191.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geissner E, Huetteroth A. Beck Anxiety Inventory deutsch - Ein reliables, valides und praxisgeeignetes Instrument zur Messung klinischer Angst. Psychother Psychosom Med Psychol. 2018;68:118&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandelow B. G&#xf6;ttingen: Hogrefe, Verlag f&#xfc;r Psychologie; 1997. Panik-und Agoraphobie-Skala (PAS)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Steer RA, Brown G. San Antonio, TX: Psychological Corporation; 1996. Manual for the Beck Depression Inventory-II.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Batista ZE, Guerra-Pe&#xf1;a K, Cano-Vindel A, Herrera-Mart&#xed;nez SX, Medrano LA. Validity and reliability of the Beck Depression Inventory (BDI-II) in general and hospital population of Dominican Republic. PLoS One. 2018;13 e0199750.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6025862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29958268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Development of the World Health Organization WHOQOL-BREF quality of life assessment. The WHOQOL Group. Psychol Med. 1998;28:551&#x2013;558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9626712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skevington SM, Lotfy M, O&#x2019;Connell KA. The World Health Organization&#x2019;s WHOQOL-BREF quality of life assessment: psychometric properties and results of the international field trial. A report from the WHOQOL Group. Qual Life Res. 2004;13:299&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15085902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt J, Wittmann WW. Diagnostische Verfahren in der Psychotherapie. G&#xf6;ttingen: Hogrefe; 2002. Fragebogen zur Messung der Patientenzufriedenheit; pp. 392&#x2013;396.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinnear PR, Gray CD. IBM SPSS Statistics 18 made simple. Psychology Press. 2011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E, Efthimiou O, Miguel C, et al. Internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy for depression: a systematic review and individual patient data network meta-analysis. JAMA psychiatry. 2021;78:361&#x2013;371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027916</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33471111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Ballegooijen W, Cuijpers P, van Straten A, et al. Adherence to internet-based and face-to-face cognitive behavioural therapy for depression: a meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2014;9 e100674.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4100736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25029507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;dtke T, Pult LK, Schr&#xf6;der J, Moritz S, B&#xfc;cker L. A randomized controlled trial on a smartphone self-help application (Be Good to Yourself) to reduce depressive symptoms. Psychiatry Res. 2018;269:753&#x2013;762.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30273901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titov N, Dear BF, Johnston L, et al. Improving adherence and clinical outcomes in self-guided internet treatment for anxiety and depression: randomised controlled trial. PLoS One. 2013;8 e62873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3701078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23843932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deterding S, Dixon D, Khaled R, Nacke L. From game design elements to gamefulness: defining &#x201c;gamification&#x201c;. Proceedings of the 15th international academic MindTrek conference: envisioning future media environments. 2011:9&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>