<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">37676681</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2374-2445</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JAMA oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Durvalumab Plus Concurrent Radiotherapy for Treatment of Locally Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer: The DOLPHIN Phase 2 Nonrandomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1505</StartPage><EndPage>1513</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1505-1513</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamaoncol.2023.3309</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE">Administration of durvalumab after concurrent chemoradiotherapy is the standard treatment of unresectable, locally advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC); however, 20% to 30% of patients do not receive durvalumab because of adverse events (AEs) during concurrent chemoradiotherapy. In addition, radiotherapy and immunotherapy have a synergistic effect.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the efficacy and safety of durvalumab immunotherapy plus concurrent radiotherapy followed by maintenance with durvalumab therapy for treatment of locally advanced NSCLC without chemotherapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS">The multicenter, single-arm DOLPHIN (Phase II Study of Durvalumab [MEDI4736] Plus Concurrent Radiation Therapy in Advanced Localized NSCLC Patients) nonrandomized controlled trial was performed by 12 institutions in Japan from September 13, 2019, to May 31, 2022. Participants in the primary registration phase included 74 patients with programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1)-positive, unresectable, locally advanced NSCLC. The current analyses were conducted from June 1, 2022, to October 31, 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS">Patients received radiotherapy (60 Gy) in combination with concurrent and maintenance durvalumab immunotherapy, 10 mg/kg every 2 weeks, for up to 1 year.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES">The primary end point of the rate of 12-month progression-free survival (PFS), as assessed by an independent central review, was estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method and evaluated with 90% CIs calculated using the Greenwood formula. The key secondary end points were PFS, objective response rate, treatment completion rate, and AEs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Data from 35 patients (median [range] age, 72 [44-83] years; 31 [88.6%] men) were included in the full analysis set of the evaluable population. The 12-month PFS rate was 72.1% (90% CI, 59.1%-85.1%), and the median PFS was 25.6 months (95% CI, 13.1 months to not estimable) at a median follow-up of 22.8 months (range, 4.3-31.8 months). Scheduled radiation therapy was completed in 97.1% of patients. The confirmed objective response rate was 90.9% (95% CI, 75.7%-98.1%), and the treatment completion rate was 57.6% (95% CI, 39.2%-74.5%). Among 34 patients evaluated in the safety analysis set, AEs of grade 3 or 4 occurred in 18 patients (52.9%), and of grade 5 in 2 patients (5.9%). Pneumonitis or radiation pneumonitis of any grade occurred in 23 patients (67.6%), and of grades 3 or 4 in 4 patients (11.8%).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE">Findings from this phase 2 nonrandomized controlled trial indicate that durvalumab immunotherapy combined with curative radiotherapy for patients with PD-L1-positive, unresectable, locally advanced NSCLC is a promising treatment with tolerable AEs and is appropriate as a study treatment for phase 3 clinical trials.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">Japan Registry of Clinical Trials ID: jRCT2080224763.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tachihara</LastName><ForeName>Motoko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respiratory Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsujino</LastName><ForeName>Kayoko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Hyogo Cancer Center, Akashi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ishihara</LastName><ForeName>Takeaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Radiation Oncology, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University, Osakasayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurata</LastName><ForeName>Takayasu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Kansai Medical University Hospital, Hirakata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugawara</LastName><ForeName>Shunichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, Sendai, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiraishi</LastName><ForeName>Yoshimasa</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teraoka</LastName><ForeName>Shunsuke</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azuma</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respirology, Neurology, and Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kurume University School of Medicine, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daga</LastName><ForeName>Haruko</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Osaka City General Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Masafumi</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Hospital Organization Kyushu Cancer Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kodaira</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiation Oncology, Aichi Cancer Center Hospital, Nagoya, Aichi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Satouchi</LastName><ForeName>Miyako</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Hyogo Cancer Center, Akashi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimokawa</LastName><ForeName>Mototsugu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Yamaguchi University Graduate School of Medicine, Ube, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University, Osakasayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>West Japan Oncology Group (WJOG)</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>JPRN</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>jRCT2080224763</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017427">Clinical Trial, Phase II</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D018848">Controlled Clinical Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JAMA Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101652861</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2374-2437</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060890">B7-H1 Antigen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>28X28X9OKV</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000613593">durvalumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000911">Antibodies, Monoclonal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>JAMA Oncol. 2024 Jun 1;10(6):828-829. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2024.0231.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">38573631</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060890" MajorTopicYN="N">B7-H1 Antigen</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000532" MajorTopicYN="N">radiotherapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059248" MajorTopicYN="N">Chemoradiotherapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018572" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease-Free Survival</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000532" MajorTopicYN="N">radiotherapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009367" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Staging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000911" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</b> Dr Tachihara reported receiving grants from AstraZeneca and personal fees from AstraZeneca during the conduct of the study; receiving grants from Eli Lilly Japan and Chugai Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work; and receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, Ono Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, and Novartis Pharmaceuticals outside the submitted work. Dr Tsujino reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca outside the submitted work. Dr Hayashi reported receiving grants from AstraZeneca, Astellas Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis Pharma, Pfizer Japan, Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly Japan, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Merck Serono, Merck Biopharma, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, SymBio Pharmaceuticals, AbbVie, inVentiv Health Japan, ICON Japan, Gritstone Oncology, Parexel International Corp, Kissei Pharmaceutical, EPS Corp, Syneos Health, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan, A2 Healthcare Corp, Quintiles Inc, IQVIA Services Japan, EP-CRSU, Linical, Eisai, CMIC Shift Zero, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Bayer Yakuhin, EPS International, and Otsuka Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work; receiving personal fees from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly Japan, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Merck Biopharma, MSD, Novartis Pharmaceuticals, Ono Pharmaceutical, and Takeda Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work; receiving consulting fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, Guardant Health, Pfizer Japan, Takeda Pharmaceutical, and Merck Biopharma outside the submitted work; and holding a patent for Sysmex. Dr Sato reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca during the conduct of the study; and receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Novartis, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Nippon Kayaku Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly &amp; Co, Takeda, and Kyowa Kirin outside the submitted work. Dr Kurata reported receiving grants, personal fees, and honoraria from AstraZeneca during the conduct of the study; receiving grants from MSD, Bristol Myers Squibb, Amgen, Daiichi Sankyo, and Takeda outside the submitted work; and receiving personal fees from MSD, Chugai Honoraria, Bristol Myers Squibb, Pfizer Honoraria, Ono, Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer Ingelheim, and Takeda outside the submitted work. Dr Sugawara reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca during the conduct of the study; and receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharma, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Takeda, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Eli Lilly Japan, Novartis, Kyowa Kirin, Nippon Kayaku, Merck, Amgen, AbbVie, Otsuka, Thermo Fisher Scientific, and Towa Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Shiraishi reported receiving grants from Chugai Pharma outside the submitted work; and receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, and Taiho Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Teraoka reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, Novartis Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan, Taiho Pharmaceutical, and Thermo Fisher Scientific outside the submitted work. Dr Azuma reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, and Chugai Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Daga reported receiving personal fees from Chugai, AstraZeneca, and Eli Lilly Japan outside the submitted work. Dr Yamaguchi reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Novartis Pharma, Bristol Myers Squibb, and Chugai Pharma during the conduct of the study. Dr Kodaira reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical, Takeda, Otsuka, and Merck Biopharma outside the submitted work. Dr Satouchi reported receiving grants and personal fees from AstraZeneca during the conduct of the study; grants from MSD, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Bristol Myers Squibb, GlaxoSmithKline, Novartis, Amgen, AbbVie, Takeda, Daiichi Sankyo, and Janssen outside the submitted work; and receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical, Novartis, MSD, Eisai Merck, Amgen, and Bayer outside the submitted work. Dr Yamamoto receiving reported grants from AstraZeneca during the conduct of the study; receiving grants from Eli Lilly Japan, MSD, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Chugai Pharmaceutical, and AstraZeneca outside the submitted work; and receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Chugai Pharmaceutical, MSD, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Daiichi-Sankyo, Merck Biopharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical, and Eli Lilly Japan outside the submitted work. Dr Nakagawa reported receiving grants from AstraZeneca, MSD, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co, and Ono Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; receiving personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, and MSD during the conduct of the study; receiving grants from Labcorp Development Japan, Japan Clinical Research Operations, Takeda Pharmaceutical, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Ascent Development Services, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Amgen, Novartis Pharma, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, SRL Pharma, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan, Bayer Yakuhin, Sysmex Corporation, Eisai, Mochida Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, Medical Research Support, Parexel International Corp, PRA Health Sciences, EPS Corporation, Kissei Pharmaceutical, EPS International, Daiichi Sankyo, PPD-SNBL, SymBio Pharmaceuticals, IQVIA Services Japan, Syneos Health, Nippon Kayaku, EP-CRSU, Mebix, Bristol Myers Squibb, Janssen Pharmaceutical, CMIC Group, Shionogi &amp; Co, Astellas Pharma, and Kobayashi Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work; receiving personal fees from Amgen, Nippon Kayaku, Eli Lilly Japan, Pfizer Japan, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bayer Yakuhin, CMIC ShiftZero, Life Technologies Japan, Neo Communication, Daiichi Sankyo, Incyte Biosciences Japan, Merck Biopharma, Kyowa Kirin, Takeda Pharmaceutical, 3H Clinical Trial, Care Net, Medical Review, Medical Mobile Communications, Yodosha, Nikkei Business Publications, Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC Group, Novartis Pharma, TAIYO Pharma, Bristol Myers Squibb, and Janssen Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work; and holding a patent for Daiichi Sankyo. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37676681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10485744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2023.3309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2809271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, et al. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2021;71(3):209-249. doi: 10.3322/caac.21660</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33538338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Cancer Institute Surveillance, Epidemiology and End Results Program. SEER cancer statistics review (CRS) 1975-2016. Updated April 9, 2020. Accessed July 14, 2023. (https://seer.cancer.gov/csr/1975_2016/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldstraw P, Chansky K, Crowley J, et al. ; International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer Staging and Prognostic Factors Committee, Advisory Boards, and Participating Institutions; International Association for the Study of Lung Cancer Staging and Prognostic Factors Committee Advisory Boards and Participating Institutions . The IASLC Lung Cancer Staging Project: proposals for revision of the TNM stage groupings in the forthcoming (eighth) edition of the TNM classification for lung cancer. J Thorac Oncol. 2016;11(1):39-51. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2015.09.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2015.09.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26762738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenke Y, Tsuboi M, Chiba Y, et al. Effect of second-generation vs third-generation chemotherapy regimens with thoracic radiotherapy on unresectable stage III non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer: 10-year follow-up of a WJTOG0105 phase 3 randomized clinical trial. JAMA Oncol. 2021;7(6):904-909. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2021.0113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2021.0113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7974833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33734289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonia SJ, Villegas A, Daniel D, et al. ; PACIFIC Investigators . Durvalumab after chemoradiotherapy in stage III non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(20):1919-1929. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1709937</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1709937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28885881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau SCM, Ryan M, Weiss J, et al. Concurrent chemoradiation with or without durvalumab in elderly patients with unresectable stage III NSCLC: safety and efficacy. JTO Clin Res Rep. 2021;2(12):100251. doi: 10.1016/j.jtocrr.2021.100251</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2021.100251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8665356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34917991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito G, Oya Y, Taniguchi Y, et al. Real-world survey of pneumonitis and its impact on durvalumab consolidation therapy in patients with non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer who received chemoradiotherapy after durvalumab approval (HOPE-005/CRIMSON). Lung Cancer. 2021;161:86-93. doi: 10.1016/j.lungcan.2021.08.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2021.08.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34543942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senan S, Brade A, Wang LH, et al. PROCLAIM: randomized phase III trial of pemetrexed-cisplatin or etoposide-cisplatin plus thoracic radiation therapy followed by consolidation chemotherapy in locally advanced nonsquamous non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34(9):953-962. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2015.64.8824</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2015.64.8824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26811519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto N, Nakagawa K, Nishimura Y, et al. Phase III study comparing second- and third-generation regimens with concurrent thoracic radiotherapy in patients with unresectable stage III non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer: West Japan Thoracic Oncology Group WJTOG0105. J Clin Oncol. 2010;28(23):3739-3745. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2009.24.5050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2009.24.5050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20625120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng L, Liang H, Burnette B, et al. Irradiation and anti-PD-L1 treatment synergistically promote antitumor immunity in mice. J Clin Invest. 2014;124(2):687-695. doi: 10.1172/JCI67313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI67313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24382348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dovedi SJ, Adlard AL, Lipowska-Bhalla G, et al. Acquired resistance to fractionated radiotherapy can be overcome by concurrent PD-L1 blockade. Cancer Res. 2014;74(19):5458-5468. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-14-1258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-14-1258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25274032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reck M, Rodr&#xed;guez-Abreu D, Robinson AG, et al. ; KEYNOTE-024 Investigators . Pembrolizumab versus chemotherapy for PD-L1-positive non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2016;375(19):1823-1833. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1606774</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1606774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27718847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mok TSK, Wu YL, Kudaba I, et al. ; KEYNOTE-042 Investigators . Pembrolizumab versus chemotherapy for previously untreated, PD-L1-expressing, locally advanced or metastatic non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer (KEYNOTE-042): a randomised, open-label, controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2019;393(10183):1819-1830. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32409-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32409-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30955977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbst RS, Giaccone G, de Marinis F, et al. Atezolizumab for first-line treatment of PD-L1-selected patients with NSCLC. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(14):1328-1339. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1917346</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1917346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32997907</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association . World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191-2194. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.281053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.281053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Union for International Cancer Control. In: Brierley JD, Gospodarowicz MK, Wittekind C, eds. <i>TNM Classification of Malignant Tumours.</i> 8th ed. Wiley-Blackwell; 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley JD, Hu C, Komaki RR, et al. Long-term results of NRG Oncology RTOG 0617: standard- versus high-dose chemoradiotherapy with or without cetuximab for unresectable stage III non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2020;38(7):706-714. doi: 10.1200/JCO.19.01162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.19.01162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7048161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31841363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theelen WSME, Chen D, Verma V, et al. Pembrolizumab with or without radiotherapy for metastatic non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer: a pooled analysis of two randomised trials. <i>Lancet Respir Med</i>. 2021;9(5):467-475. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30391-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30391-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33096027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katsurada M, Nagano T, Tachihara M, et al. Baseline tumor size as a predictive and prognostic factor of immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy for non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer. Anticancer Res. 2019;39(2):815-825. doi: 10.21873/anticanres.13180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21873/anticanres.13180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atagi S, Kawahara M, Yokoyama A, et al. ; Japan Clinical Oncology Group Lung Cancer Study Group . Thoracic radiotherapy with or without daily low-dose carboplatin in elderly patients with non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer: a randomised, controlled, phase 3 trial by the Japan Clinical Oncology Group (JCOG0301). Lancet Oncol. 2012;13(7):671-678. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(12)70139-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(12)70139-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22622008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peters S, Felip E, Dafni U, et al. Progression-free and overall survival for concurrent nivolumab with standard concurrent chemoradiotherapy in locally advanced stage IIIA-B NSCLC: results from the European Thoracic Oncology Platform NICOLAS Phase II Trial (European Thoracic Oncology Platform 6-14). J Thorac Oncol. 2021;16(2):278-288. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2020.10.129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2020.10.129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33188912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin SH, Lin Y, Yao L, et al. Phase II trial of concurrent atezolizumab with chemoradiation for unresectable NSCLC. J Thorac Oncol. 2020;15(2):248-257. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2019.10.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2019.10.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31778797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbour SK, Berman AT, Decker RH, et al. Phase 1 trial of pembrolizumab administered concurrently with chemoradiotherapy for locally advanced non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer: a nonrandomized controlled trial. JAMA Oncol. 2020;6(6):848-855. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2019.6731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2019.6731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin SH, Lin Y, Yao L, et al. Phase II trial of concurrent atezolizumab with chemoradiation for unresectable NSCLC. <i>J Thorac Oncol</i>. 2020;15(2):248&#x2013;257. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2019.10.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2019.10.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31778797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbour SK, Berman AT, Decker RH, et al. Phase 1 trial of pembrolizumab administered concurrently with chemoradiotherapy for locally advanced non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer: a nonrandomized controlled trial. <i>JAMA Oncol</i>. 2020;6(6):848&#x2013;855. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2019.6731</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2019.6731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7042914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32077891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley JD, Nishio M, Okamoto I, et al. PACIFIC-2: phase 3 study of concurrent durvalumab and platinum-based chemoradiotherapy in patients with unresectable, stage III NSCLC. <i>J Clin Oncol</i><i>.</i>
2019;37(15):suppl. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2019.37.15_suppl.TPS8573</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2019.37.15_suppl.TPS8573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herbst RS, Majem M, Barlesi F, et al. COAST: an open-label, phase II, multidrug platform study of durvalumab alone or in combination with oleclumab or monalizumab in patients with unresectable, stage III non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2022;40(29):3383-3393. doi: 10.1200/JCO.22.00227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.22.00227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35452273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>