<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37797293</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1876-4479</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of Crohn's &amp; colitis</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Crohns Colitis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Maintenance Risankizumab Sustains Induction Response in Patients with Crohn's Disease in a Randomized Phase 3 Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>416</StartPage><EndPage>423</EndPage><MedlinePgn>416-423</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjad168</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Durable clinical remission, endoscopic healing, and biomarker normalization are key treatment goals for Crohn's disease. The selective anti-interleukin-23 p19 inhibitor risankizumab has demonstrated efficacy and safety in moderately to severely active Crohn's disease. This post-hoc analysis of data from the pivotal risankizumab maintenance study assessed whether risankizumab maintenance therapy sustained the clinical and endoscopic outcomes achieved with risankizumab induction therapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We evaluated 462 patients who achieved a clinical response to risankizumab intravenous induction treatment and were re-randomized to receive subcutaneous risankizumab 360 mg, subcutaneous risankizumab 180 mg, or placebo [withdrawal] every 8 weeks for 52 weeks in the randomized, controlled FORTIFY maintenance study. Maintenance of clinical, endoscopic, and biomarker endpoints at week 52 among patients who achieved these endpoints after 12 weeks of induction treatment was evaluated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A significantly higher proportion of patients receiving maintenance treatment with risankizumab 360 or 180 mg compared with placebo [withdrawal] maintained Crohn's Disease Activity Index remission [68.6%, 70.8%, vs 56.3%; p&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.05], stool frequency/abdominal pain remission [69.2%, 64.1%, vs 50.5%; p&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.01], endoscopic response [70.2%, 68.2%, vs 38.4%; p&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.001], endoscopic remission [74.4%, 45.5%, vs 23.9%; p&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;0.05], and Simple Endoscopic Score for Crohn's Disease of 0-2 [65.5%, 36.7%, vs 21.9%]. Most patients [56.8-83.3%] who achieved normalized faecal calprotectin or C-reactive protein during induction sustained them with maintenance risankizumab.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Subcutaneous risankizumab maintenance therapy results in durable improvement in clinical and endoscopic outcomes over 1 year in patients with moderately to severely active Crohn's disease.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION NUMBER" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">NCT03105102.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of European Crohn&#x2019;s and Colitis Organisation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferrante</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1492-0716</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, University Hospitals Leuven, KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Irving</LastName><ForeName>Peter M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0972-8148</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IBD Centre, Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abreu</LastName><ForeName>Maria T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, Miami, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Axler</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Toronto Digestive Disease Associates Inc., Vaughan, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gao</LastName><ForeName>Xiang</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, The Center for Inflammatory Bowel Disease, The Sixth Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Qian</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Sir Run Run Shaw Hospital, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujii</LastName><ForeName>Toshimitsu</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Tokyo Medical and Dental University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rausch</LastName><ForeName>Astrid</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastroenterology Department, British Hospital, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Torres</LastName><ForeName>Joana</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2895-5821</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Hospital Beatriz &#xc2;ngelo, Loures, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hospital da Luz, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculdade de Medicina, Universidade de Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neimark</LastName><ForeName>Ezequiel</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie Inc., North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie Inc., North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Kori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie Inc., North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kligys</LastName><ForeName>Kristina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie Inc., North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berg</LastName><ForeName>Sofie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie Inc., North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Xiaomei</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie Inc., North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie Inc., North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalabic</LastName><ForeName>Jasmina</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AbbVie Deutschland GmbH &amp; Co. KG, Ludwigshafen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feagan</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Western Ontario, London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Panaccione</LastName><ForeName>Remo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5247-940X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT03105102</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>AbbVie</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Crohns Colitis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101318676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1873-9946</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>90ZX3Q3FR7</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000601773">risankizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000911">Antibodies, Monoclonal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003424" MajorTopicYN="Y">Crohn Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015746" MajorTopicYN="N">Abdominal Pain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061605" MajorTopicYN="N">Administration, Intravenous</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000911" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Crohn&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Risankizumab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">durability</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>M.F. has received research grants from AbbVie, Amgen, Biogen, EG, Janssen, Pfizer, Takeda, and Viatris; consultancy fees from AbbVie, Agomab Therapeutics, Boehringer Ingelheim, Celgene, Celltrion, Eli Lilly, Janssen-Cilag, Medtronic, MSD, Pfizer, Regeneron, Samsung Bioepis, Sandoz, Takeda, and Thermo Fisher; and speakers&#x2019; fees from AbbVie, Amgen, Biogen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Dr Falk, Ferring, Janssen-Cilag, Lamepro, MSD, Pfizer, Sandoz, Takeda, Truvion Healthcare, and Viatris. P.M.I. has received speaking fees from AbbVie, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene, Celltrion, Falk Pharma, Ferring, Galapagos, Gilead, MSD, Janssen, Lilly, Pfizer, Takeda, Tillotts, Sapphire Medical, Sandoz, Shire, and Warner Chilcott; research grants from Celltrion, Galapagos, MSD, Pfizer, and Takeda; and advisory fees from AbbVie, Arena, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene, Celltrion, Genentech, Gilead, Hospira, Janssen, Lilly, MSD, Pfizer, Pharmacosmos, Prometheus, Roche, Sandoz, Samsung Bioepis, Takeda, Topivert, VH2, Vifor, and Warner Chilcott. M.T.A. has served as a consultant for AbbVie, Allergan, Amgen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Celgene, Cornerstones Health, Focus Medical Communications, Gilead Sciences, Imedex, Janssen Biotech, Landos, Lilly, Nestec, Pfizer, Prometheus Laboratories, Roche Pharmaceuticals, Shire, Takeda, and Vindico Medical Education. J.A. has served as a consultant for AbbVie, Janssen Pharmaceutical, and Takeda. X.G. and QC. report no conflicts of interest. T.F. has received research grants from AbbVie, Alfresa, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene, EA Pharma, Eisai, Gilead, Janssen, Kissei, Lilly, Mebix, Sanofi, and Takeda; and speaking honoraria from AbbVie, Ajinomoto Pharma, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Daiichi Sankyo, EA Pharma, Eisai, Janssen, Kissei, Kyorin, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Kissei Pharma, Mitsubishi Tanabe, Mochida, Nichiiko, Nippon Kayaku, Pfizer, Taiho, Takeda, and Zeria Pharma. A.R. has received speaking fees from AbbVie, Ferring, Janssen, and Takeda. J.T. has received speaker&#x2019;s fees from AbbVie, Galapagos, Janssen, and Pfizer; advisory fees from AbbVie, Janssen, and Pfizer; and research grants from AbbVie and Janssen. E.N., A.S., K.W., K.K., S.B., Q.Z., and J.K. are employees of AbbVie and may own AbbVie stock or options. X.L. is a former employee of AbbVie and may own AbbVie stock or options. B.F. has received consulting fees from AbbVie, Allergan, ActoGeniX, Albireo, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Atlantic Pharma, Avaxia Biologics, Axcan, Baxter Healthcare Corp, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene, Centocor, Elan/Biogen, enGene, Ferring, Genentech, GICare, Gilead, Given Imaging Inc, GlaxoSmithKline, Ironwood, Johnson &amp; Johnson/Janssen, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Lycera, Lexicon, Lilly, Merck, Mesoblast, Millennium, Nektar, Novartis Novo Nordisk, Prometheus, Pfizer, Protagonist, Receptos, Salix, Serono, Shire, Sigmoid, Synergy, Takeda, Teva, Tillotts, TiGenix, UCB, Warner-Chilcott, Wyeth, Zealand, and Zyngenia; speaker fees from AbbVie, Johnson &amp; Johnson/Janssen, Takeda, and UCB; financial support for research from AbbVie, Amgen, AstraZeneca/MedImmune, Atlantic Pharmaceuticals, Boehringer Ingelheim, Celgene Corporation, Celltech, Genentech Inc/Hoffmann&#x2013;La Roche, Gilead, GlaxoSmithKline, Janssen Research &amp; Development, Pfizer, Receptos/Celgene, Sanofi, Santarus, Takeda Development Center Americas, Tillotts, and UCB; and has served as a member of the board of directors of Robarts Clinical Trials, Inc. R.P. has served as a consultant for Abbott, AbbVie, Alimentiv, Amgen, Arena Pharmaceuticals, AstraZeneca, Biogen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Celgene, Celltrion, Cosmos Pharmaceuticals, Eisai, Elan, Ferring, Galapagos, Fresenius Kabi, Genentech, Gilead Sciences, Glaxo-Smith Kline, JAMP Bio, Janssen, Lilly, Merck, Mylan, Novartis, Oppilan Pharma, Organon, Pandion Pharma, Pendopharm, Pfizer, Progenity, Protagonist Therapeutics, Roche, Sandoz, Satisfai Health, Shire, Sublimity Therapeutics, Takeda, Theravance Biopharma, Trellus, Viatris, and UCB. He has received speaking fees from AbbVie, Amgen, Arena Pharmaceuticals, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Celgene, Ferring, Fresenius Kabi, Gilead Sciences, Janssen, Lilly, Merck, Organon, Pfizer, Roche, Sandoz, Shire, and Takeda Pharmaceuticals; and advisory fees from AbbVie, Alimentiv, Amgen, Arena Pharmaceuticals, AstraZeneca, Biogen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Celgene, Ferring, Fresenius Kabi, Genentech, Gilead Sciences, Glaxo-Smith Kline, JAMP Bio, Janssen, Lilly, Merck, Mylan, Novartis, Oppilan Pharma, Organon, Pandion Pharma, Pfizer, Progenity, Protagonist, Roche, Sandoz, Shire, Sublimity Therapeutics, and Takeda.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37797293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10906949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjad168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">7292875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Roda G, Chien Ng S, Kotze PG, et al. Crohn&#x2019;s disease. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2020;6:22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32242028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roda G, Jharap B, Neeraj N, Colombel J-F.. Loss of response to anti-TNFs: definition, epidemiology, and management. Clin Transl Gastroenterol 2016;7:e135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4737871</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26741065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barber GE, Yajnik V, Khalili H, et al. Genetic markers predict primary non-response and durable response to anti-TNF biologic therapies in Crohn&#x2019;s disease. Am J Gastroenterol 2016;111:1816&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5143156</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27596696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Privitera G, Pugliese D, Rapaccini GL, Gasbarrini A, Armuzzi A, Guidi L.. Predictors and early markers of response to biological therapies in inflammatory bowel diseases. J Clin Med 2021;10:853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7922976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33669579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Selinger CP, Parkes GC, Bassi A, et al. A multi-centre audit of excess steroid use in 1176 patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2017;46:964&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28949018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Irvine EJ, Feagan B, Rochon J, et al. Quality of life: a valid and reliable measure of therapeutic efficacy in the treatment of inflammatory bowel disease Canadian Crohn&#x2019;s Relapse Prevention Trial Study Group. Gastroenterology 1994;106:287&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8299896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Have M, van der Aalst KS, Kaptein AA, et al. Determinants of health-related quality of life in Crohn&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Crohns Colitis 2014;8:93&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23746864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner D, Ricciuto A, Lewis A, et al. ; International Organization for the Study of IBD. STRIDE-II: an update on the selecting therapeutic targets in inflammatory bowel disease (STRIDE) initiative of the International Organization for the Study of IBD (IOIBD): determining therapeutic goals for treat-to-target strategies in IBD. Gastroenterology 2021;160:1570&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33359090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Kroe-Barrett RR, Canada KA, et al. Selective targeting of the IL23 pathway: generation and characterization of a novel high-affinity humanized anti-IL23A antibody. MAbs 2015;7:778&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4622456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25905918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krueger JG, Ferris LK, Menter A, et al. Anti-IL-23A mAb BI 655066 for treatment of moderate-to-severe psoriasis: safety, efficacy, pharmacokinetics, and biomarker results of a single-rising-dose, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2015;136:116&#x2013;124.e7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25769911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#x2019;Haens G, Pannacione R, Baert F, Bossuyt P, et al. Risankizumab as induction therapy for Crohn&#x2019;s disease: results from the phase 3 ADVANCE and MOTIVATE induction trials. Lancet 2022;399:2015&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35644154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrante M, Pannacione R, Baert F, Bossuyt P, et al. Risankizumab as maintenance therapy for moderately to severely active Crohn&#x2019;s disease: results from the multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, withdrawal phase 3 FORTIFY maintenance trial. Lancet 2022;399:2031&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35644155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma C, Jairath V, Khanna R, Feagan BG.. Investigational drugs in phase I and phase II clinical trials targeting interleukin 23 (IL23) for the treatment of Crohn&#x2019;s disease. Expert Opin Investig Drugs 2018;27:649&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30056776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozgur I, Kulle CB, Buyuk M, et al. What are the predictors for recurrence of Crohn&#x2019;s disease after surgery? Medicine (Baltim) 2021;100:e25340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8036018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33832109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>