<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40995949</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1744-8301</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>24</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Future oncology (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Future Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>RELAY: safety and efficacy of ramucirumab plus erlotinib in elderly Japanese patients with metastatic <i>EGFR</i>-mutated NSCLC.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3197</StartPage><EndPage>3206</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3197-3206</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/14796694.2025.2560225</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The global phase III RELAY trial demonstrated the efficacy of ramucirumab (RAM) plus erlotinib (ERL) in patients with untreated metastatic epidermal growth factor receptor (<i>EGFR</i>)-mutated non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). We present safety and efficacy profiles of RAM+ERL in Japanese elderly (aged &#x2265; 75&#x2009;years) patients in RELAY.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients were randomized (1:1) to RAM (10&#x2009;mg/kg) or placebo (PL) intravenously every 2&#x2009;weeks plus 150&#x2009;mg/day ERL orally. Primary endpoint was progression-free survival (reported elsewhere). This report describes response rates, study drug exposure, dose adjustments, safety, and post-study treatment discontinuation therapies in Japanese elderly patients (RAM+ERL, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;12; PL+ERL, n&#x2009;=&#x2009;17).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Overall response rate was similar in RAM+ERL (83.3%) and PL+ERL (82.4%) arms. Median treatment duration of RAM and ERL was 6.0 and 15.4&#x2009;months, respectively. Most patients had RAM and/or ERL dose adjustments. Adverse events, including grade&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;3 events, were similar in both treatment arms, although proteinuria occurred exclusively in the RAM+ERL arm (six patients; no grade&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;3 events). All patients received subsequent therapy after first-line study treatment; various subsequent therapies were used.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">These results suggest that RAM+ERL may be a suitable first-line treatment option for elderly patients with <i>EGFR</i>-mutated NSCLC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">www.clinicaltrials.gov identifier is NCT02411448.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishino</LastName><ForeName>Kazumi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2000-7472</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Osaka International Cancer Institute, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seto</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, NHO Kyushu Cancer Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Makoto</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medical Oncology, The Cancer Institute Hospital, Japanese Foundation for Cancer Research, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kasahara</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine and Oncology, Nippon Medical School Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Satouchi</LastName><ForeName>Miyako</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Hyogo Cancer Center, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoh</LastName><ForeName>Kiyotaka</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital East, Kashiwa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8787-5587</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Enatsu</LastName><ForeName>Sotaro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsui</LastName><ForeName>Tomoko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varughese</LastName><ForeName>Sunoj Chacko</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statistics, Eli Lilly Services India Pvt. Ltd., Bengaluru, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Visseren-Grul</LastName><ForeName>Carla</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly Netherlands, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02411448</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Future Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101256629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1479-6694</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>D99YVK4L0X</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000096662">Ramucirumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>DA87705X9K</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000069347">Erlotinib Hydrochloride</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D066246">ErbB Receptors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C512478">EGFR protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><SupplMeshList><SupplMeshName Type="Population" UI="C000724324">Japanese people</SupplMeshName></SupplMeshList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000096662" MajorTopicYN="N">Ramucirumab</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069347" MajorTopicYN="N">Erlotinib Hydrochloride</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066246" MajorTopicYN="N">ErbB Receptors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009154" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mutation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007564" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Japan</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000095225" MajorTopicYN="N" AutoHM="Y">East Asian People</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Most people with lung cancer, especially in Japan, are elderly (aged 75&#x2009;years or older). Elderly people are more likely to have side effects from cancer treatments, particularly chemotherapy. Newer cancer treatments, called &#x201c;targeted therapies,&#x201d; are thought to be effective and have fewer side effects, but not many studies have been done in elderly people. In the global RELAY study, people with advanced lung cancer caused by an <i>EGFR</i> gene mutation were treated with a combination of two drugs, ramucirumab (RAM) and erlotinib (ERL). This was the first cancer treatment the patients had for this advanced stage of cancer. The combination (RAM+ERL) resulted in better control of tumor growth and longer life compared with ERL treatment alone. In this paper, we report that the effect of RAM+ERL on tumor growth and lifespan in elderly Japanese patients from RELAY was similar to the effect in all Japanese patients, as well as all global patients, enrolled in the study. Side effects in elderly Japanese patients were also similar to the whole study group, although the dose of one or both of the drugs sometimes had to be reduced to help cope with a side effect. Most cancer treatments, particularly ERL, stop working after a while, so it is important to have different treatment options that can be used one after another. When RAM+ERL stopped working, most elderly Japanese patients were treated with other targeted therapies. This meant that the patients could live longer before needing chemotherapy.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EGFR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Japan</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">carcinoma, non-small-cell lung</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dose adjustment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ramucirumab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">safety</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Kazumi Nishino reports grants or contracts to their institution from AbbVie, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eisai Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Gilead Sciences, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Merus N.V., Novartis, Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Pfizer, Sanofi K.K., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; payments or honoraria from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Novartis, Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Pfizer, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; and participation on safety/advisory boards with AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., and Pfizer. Takashi Seto reports payments or honoraria from Amgen, AnHeart Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., GlaxoSmithKline, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Pfizer Japan Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Towa Pharmaceutical; and is an employee of Precision Medicine Asia. Makoto Nishio reports payments or honoraria from AbbVie, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Janssen, Merck, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Pfizer Japan Inc., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. Kazuto Nishio reports grants or contracts from Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Hitachi, Nichirei Biosciences Inc., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Sysmex Corporation, and West Japan Oncology Group; honoraria for lectures from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Fujirebio Diagnostics, Guardant Health, Invitae Japan, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Maruho Co., Ltd., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd, MSD K.K., Nichirei Biosciences Inc., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Pfizer, and Yakult Honsha Co., Ltd. Kazuo Kasahara reports payments or honoraria from AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Kyowa Kirin Co., Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, and Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Miyako Satouchi reports grants or contracts to their institution from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eisai Co., Ltd., GlaxoSmithKline, Janssen, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer Japan Inc., and Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.; and payments or honoraria from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eisai Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Janssen, Merck, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Pfizer Japan Inc., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. Kiyotaka Yoh reports grants or contracts to their institution from AbbVie, Amgen, ArriVent BioPharma, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; consulting fees from AbbVie and Boehringer Ingelheim; and payments or honoraria from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Kyowa Kirin Co., Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited. Hidetoshi Hayashi reports grants or contracts from A2 Healthcare Corporation, AbbVie, Amgen, Ascent Pharmaceuticals, Astellas Pharma Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Clinical Research Support Center Kyushu, CMIC Co., Ltd., Comprehensive Support Project for Oncological Research of Breast Cancer, Covance Japan Inc., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eisai Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., EP-CRSU Co., Ltd., EPS Corporation, EPS International Co., Ltd., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., Iqvia Services Japan K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Japan Clinical Cancer Research Organization, Japan Clinical Research Operations, Japanese Gastric Cancer Association, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Kyowa Kirin Co., Ltd., Labcorp Development Japan K.K., Mebix, Inc., Medical Research Support, Medpace Japan K.K., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd, MSD K.K., Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., PRA Health Sciences, Inc., Sanofi K.K., Shionogi &amp; Co., Ltd., SRL Medisearch Inc., Syneos Health Clinical K.K., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Thoracic Oncology Research Group, and West Japan Oncology Group; and payments or honoraria from 3H Clinical Trial Inc., Amgen, AstraZeneca K.K., Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Guardant Health, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd, MSD K.K., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Pfizer Japan Inc., Sysmex Corporation, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; and participation on safety/advisory boards with AbbVie, AstraZeneca K.K., Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., and Novocure K.K. Sotaro Enatsu and Tomoko Matsui are employees of Eli Lilly Japan K.K. and minor shareholders of Eli Lilly and Company. Sunoj Chacko Varughese is an employee of Eli Lilly Services India Pvt. Ltd. and a minor shareholder of Eli Lilly and Company. Carla Visseren-Grul is an employee and minor shareholder of Eli Lilly and Company. Kazuhiko Nakagawa reports grants or contracts to their institution from Amgen, Ascent Pharmaceuticals, Astellas Pharma Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd, Bristol-Myers Squibb K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., CMIC Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eisai Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., EP-CRSU Co., Ltd., EPS Corporation, EPS International Co., Ltd., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., Iqvia Services Japan K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Japan Clinical Research Operations, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Labcorp Development Japan K.K. (Covance Japan Inc.), Mebix, Inc., Medical Research Support, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., MSD K.K., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., PRA Health Sciences, Inc., Sanofi K.K., Shionogi &amp; Co., Ltd., SRL Medisearch Inc., Syneos Health Clinical K.K., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited; consulting fees from Eli Lilly Japan K.K. and Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd; payments or honoraria from Amgen, AstraZeneca K.K., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd, Bristol-Myers Squibb K.K., CareNet, Inc., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., CMIC Co., Ltd., CMIC ShiftZero K.K., Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Global Health Consulting Japan Co., Ltd., Hisamitsu Pharmaceutical Co., Inc., Incyte Biosciences Japan G.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Japan Clinical Research Operations, Life Technologies Japan Ltd., M3, Inc., Medical Mobile Communications Co., Ltd., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd, MSD K.K., Neo Communication A.G., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd, Otsuka Pharmaceutical Factory, Inc., Pfizer Japan Inc., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Taiyo Pharma Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, The Yomiuri Shimbun, and Yodosha Co., Ltd.; and patents planned, issued, or pending with Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited and their institution. Medical writing assistance was provided by Rebecca Lew, PhD, CMPP, and Prudence Stanford, PhD, CMPP, of ProScribe &#x2013; Envision Pharma Group, and was funded by Eli Lilly Japan K.K. ProScribe&#x2019;s services complied with international guidelines for Good Publication Practice. The authors have no other relevant affiliations or financial involvement with any organization or entity with a financial interest in or financial conflict with the subject matter or materials discussed in the manuscript apart from those disclosed.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40995949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12520095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14796694.2025.2560225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bray F, Laversanne M, Sung H, et al. Global cancer statistics 2022: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2024;74(3):229&#x2013;263. doi: 10.3322/caac.21834</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38572751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oser MG, Niederst MJ, Sequist LV, et al. Transformation from non-small-cell lung cancer to small-cell lung cancer: molecular drivers and cells of origin. Lancet Oncol. 2015;16(4):e165&#x2013;e172. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(14)71180-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(14)71180-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4470698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25846096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahed H, Feng X, Sheikh M, et al. Age at diagnosis for lung, colon, breast and prostate cancers: an international comparative study. Int J Cancer. 2024;154(1):28&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1002/ijc.34671</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijc.34671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11153845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37615573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almodovar T, Teixeira E, Barroso A, et al. Elderly patients with advanced NSCLC: the value of geriatric evaluation and the feasibility of CGA alternatives in predicting chemotherapy toxicity. Pulmonology. 2019;25(1):40&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/j.pulmoe.2018.07.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pulmoe.2018.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30266308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>II. Non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) . 7: Stage IV non-small cell lung cancer [Internet]: The Japan Lung Cancer Society. 2024.  [cited 2025 May
19]. Available from:
https://www.haigan.gr.jp/publication/guideline/examination/2024/1/2/240102070100.html</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang YL, Yuan JQ, Wang KF, et al. The prevalence of EGFR mutation in patients with non-small cell lung cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Oncotarget. 2016;7(48):78985&#x2013;78993. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.12587</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.12587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5346692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27738317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham RP, Treece AL, Lindeman NI, et al. Worldwide frequency of commonly detected EGFR mutations. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2018;142(2):163&#x2013;167. doi: 10.5858/arpa.2016-0579-CP</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5858/arpa.2016-0579-CP</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29106293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Araki T, Kanda S, Horinouchi H, et al. Current treatment strategies for EGFR-mutated non-small cell lung cancer: from first line to beyond osimertinib resistance. Jpn J Clin Oncol. 2023;53(7):547&#x2013;561. doi: 10.1093/jjco/hyad052</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jjco/hyad052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10311169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37279591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninomiya K, Teraoka S, Zenke Y, et al. Japanese Lung Cancer Society guidelines for stage IV NSCLC with <i>EGFR</i> mutations. JTO Clin Res Rep. 2020;2(1):100107. doi: 10.1016/j.jtocrr.2020.100107
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2020.100107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34589972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planchard D, Popat S, Kerr K, et al. Metastatic non-small cell lung cancer: ESMO Clinical Practice Guidelines for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann Oncol. 2018;29(Suppl 4):iv192&#x2013;iv237. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdy275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdy275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30285222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oxnard GR, Arcila ME, Chmielecki J, et al. New strategies in overcoming acquired resistance to epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitors in lung cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2011;17(17):5530&#x2013;5537. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-10-2571</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-10-2571</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3166976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21775534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planchard D, J&#xe4;nne PA, Cheng Y, et al. Osimertinib with or without chemotherapy in EGFR-mutated advanced NSCLC. N Engl J Med. 2023;389(21):1935&#x2013;1948. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2306434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2306434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37937763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho BC, Lu S, Felip E, et al. Amivantamab plus lazertinib in previously untreated <i>EGFR</i>-mutated advanced NSCLC. N Engl J Med. 2024;391(16):1486&#x2013;1498. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2403614
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2403614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38924756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa K, Garon EB, Seto T, et al. RELAY: final overall survival for erlotinib plus ramucirumab or placebo in untreated, EGFR-mutated metastatic NSCLC. J Thorac Oncol. 2025;20(4):487&#x2013;499. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2024.11.032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2024.11.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39622410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa K, Garon EB, Seto T, et al. Ramucirumab plus erlotinib in patients with untreated, EGFR-mutated, advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (RELAY): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2019;20(12):1655&#x2013;1669. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30634-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30634-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31591063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishio K, Seto T, Nishio M, et al. Ramucirumab plus erlotinib versus placebo plus erlotinib in patients with untreated metastatic <i>EGFR</i>-mutated NSCLC: RELAY Japanese subset. JTO Clin Res Rep. 2021;2(6):100171. doi: 10.1016/j.jtocrr.2021.100171
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2021.100171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34590023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishio M, Seto T, Reck M, et al. Final survival outcomes with ramucirumab plus erlotinib versus placebo plus erlotinib in patients with untreated <i>EGFR</i>-mutated metastatic NSCLC: RELAY Japanese subset. JTO Clin Res Rep. 2025;6(6):100819. doi: 10.1016/j.jtocrr.2025.100819
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2025.100819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12127625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40458541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishihara M, Kawamura T, Namba Y, et al. Ramucirumab and erlotinib combination as first-line treatment for advanced or recurrent non-small cell lung cancer harboring <i>EGFR</i> Exon21 L858R mutation: a multicenter retrospective observational cohort study in Japan (REAL-SPEED). Ther Adv Med Oncol. 2025;17:17588359251344010. doi: 10.1177/17588359251344010
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17588359251344010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12174667</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40535732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco R, Maestu I, de la Torre MG, et al. A review of the management of elderly patients with non-small-cell lung cancer. Ann Oncol. 2015;26(3):451&#x2013;463. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdu268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdu268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25060421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glotzer OS, Fabian T, Chandra A, et al. Non-small cell lung cancer therapy: safety and efficacy in the elderly. Drug Healthc Patient Saf. 2013;5:113&#x2013;121. doi: 10.2147/DHPS.S41199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DHPS.S41199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3639018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23637560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maione P, Rossi A, Sacco PC, et al. Review: treating advanced non-small cell lung cancer in the elderly. Ther Adv Med Oncol. 2010;2(4):251&#x2013;260. doi: 10.1177/1758834010366707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1758834010366707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3126022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21789138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oizumi S, Valdiviezo N, Okamoto I, et al. Osimertinib &#xb1; platinum-pemetrexed in EGFRm advanced NSCLC: FLAURA2 post-progression outcomes. Presented at: The 65th Annual Meeting of the Japan Lung Cancer Society; Yokohama North, Japan; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A study of amivantamab and lazertinib combination therapy versus osimertinib in locally advanced or metastatic non-small cell lung cancer (MARIPOSA) [internet]. ClinicalTrials.gov;  [cited
2025. 
Jul
24]. Available from:
https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT04487080</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam SS, P&#xe9;rol M, Reck M, et al. Efficacy and safety of ramucirumab with docetaxel versus placebo with docetaxel as second-line treatment of advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: a subgroup analysis according to patient age in the REVEL trial. Clin Lung Cancer. 2018;19(3):270&#x2013;279.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.cllc.2017.12.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cllc.2017.12.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29373274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakata Y, Saito G, Sakata S, et al. Osimertinib as first-line treatment for elderly patients with advanced EGFR mutation-positive non-small cell lung cancer in a real-world setting (OSI-FACT-EP). Lung Cancer. 2023;186:107426. doi: 10.1016/j.lungcan.2023.107426</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2023.107426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37992594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakao M, Muramatsu H, Sone K, et al. Epidermal growth factor receptor-tyrosine kinase inhibitors for non-small-cell lung cancer patients aged 80 years or older: a retrospective analysis. Mol Clin Oncol. 2015;3(2):403&#x2013;407. doi: 10.3892/mco.2014.453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/mco.2014.453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4360513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25798276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mochizuki A, Matsumoto H, Maezawa Y, et al. Dose reduction of <i>EGFR</i>-TKIs for <i>EGFR</i>-positive non-small cell lung cancer: a retrospective study. Cancer Diagn Progn. 2025;5(2):207&#x2013;215. doi: 10.21873/cdp.10431
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21873/cdp.10431</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11871860</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40034956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenmotsu H, Imamura CK, Kawamura T, et al. Prospective evaluation of the relationship between response and exposure of total and unbound erlotinib in non-small cell lung cancer patients. Cancer Chemother Pharmacol. 2022;90(2):115&#x2013;123. doi: 10.1007/s00280-022-04452-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00280-022-04452-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35821437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>