<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40991184</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8253</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurology and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurol Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Adjunctive Istradefylline on Dyskinesia Onset in Patients with Parkinson's Disease Exhibiting Wearing-Off: An Open-Label Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2411</StartPage><EndPage>2427</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2411-2427</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40120-025-00809-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Motor complications become major treatment challenges in patients with Parkinson's disease (PD). Istradefylline (IST) is used as an adjunct to levodopa in patients with PD exhibiting wearing-off (WO), but its impact on the onset of dyskinesia remains unclear. The objective of this study was to investigate the effect of IST on dyskinesia onset in patients with PD exhibiting WO.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In this 3-year, multicenter, randomized, open-label, parallel-group, controlled study, 214 patients with levodopa-treated PD exhibiting WO without pre-existing dyskinesia were randomized (1:1) to either adjunctive IST (IST group) or to adding another or increasing the dose of other anti-PD drugs (non-IST group). The primary endpoint was the time to onset of dyskinesia.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Over 3&#xa0;years, the incidence of dyskinesia was 37.9% and 41.1% in the IST and non-IST groups, respectively. The time to onset of dyskinesia was not significantly different between the IST versus non-IST groups (median: 1100.00 vs. 1082.00&#xa0;days). When dividing patients by age, the rate of time to onset of dyskinesia was lower in the IST group in patients aged&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;68&#xa0;years (median) and in the non-IST group for patients aged&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;68&#xa0;years and patients aged&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;60&#xa0;years at PD onset. The levodopa-equivalent daily dose (LEDD) was significantly lower throughout the study period, by 57&#xa0;mg on average, in the IST group than in the non-IST group. Efficacy and safety indexes were not significantly different between the two groups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Adjunctive IST showed no difference in the onset of dyskinesia compared with adding another or increasing the dose of other anti-PD drugs, and displayed equivalent efficacy and tolerability, while maintaining a lower LEDD in this long-term study of patients with PD exhibiting WO. These findings support the use of adjunctive IST as a viable treatment option for patients with PD exhibiting WO.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">University hospital Medical Information Network clinical trials registry (UMIN000024536) and Japan Registry of Clinical Trials (jRCTs071180014).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuboi</LastName><ForeName>Yoshio</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6758-0981</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine, Fukuoka University, 7-45-1 Nanakuma, Johnan-ku, Fukuoka, Fukuoka, 814-0180, Japan. tsuboi0202@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tsutsumi Clinic Fukuoka Parkinson's Disease Center, Hakata Urban Square 1F, 1-31 Tenyamachi, Hakata-ku, Fukuoka, Fukuoka, 812-0025, Japan. tsuboi0202@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Long-Term Observation Research, Juntendo University, 2-1-1 Hongo, Bunkyo-ku, Tokyo, 113-8421, Japan. tsuboi0202@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hasegawa</LastName><ForeName>Takafumi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Department of Neuroscience and Sensory Organs, Tohoku University Graduate School of Medicine, 1-1 Seiryo-machi, Aoba-ku, Sendai, Miyagi, 980-8574, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, National Hospital Organization Sendai Nishitaga Hospital, 2-11-11 Kagitorihoncho, Taihaku-ku, Sendai, Miyagi, 982-8555, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimo</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Juntendo University Nerima Hospital, 3-1-10 Takanodai, Nerima-ku, Tokyo, 177-8521, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaneko</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Kansai Medical University, 2-5-1 Shin-machi, Hirakata, Osaka, 573-1010, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Medical Research Institute Kitano Hospital, 2-4-20 Ohgimachi, Kita-ku, Osaka, 530-8480, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomiyama</LastName><ForeName>Masahiko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Institute of Brain Science, Hirosaki University Graduate School of Medicine, 53 Honcho, Hirosaki, Aomori, 036-8563, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kashihara</LastName><ForeName>Kenichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Okayama Kyokuto Hospital, 567-1 Kurata, Naka-ku, Okayama, Okayama, 703-8265, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Okayama Neurology Clinic, 104-16 Ezaki, Naka-ku, Okayama, Okayama, 702-8005, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiu</LastName><ForeName>Shih-Wei</ForeName><Initials>SW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics, Tohoku University Graduate School of Medicine, 2-1 Seiryo-machi, Aoba-ku, Sendai, Miyagi, 980-8575, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamaguchi</LastName><ForeName>Takuhiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Biostatistics, Tohoku University Graduate School of Medicine, 2-1 Seiryo-machi, Aoba-ku, Sendai, Miyagi, 980-8575, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>ODYSSEI study group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Neurol Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101637818</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2193-6536</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dyskinesia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Istradefylline</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wearing-off</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: Yoshio Tsuboi received consulting fees and support for attending meetings and/or travel from Kyowa Kirin; and has received payments or honoraria for lectures, presentations, speakers&#x2019; bureaus, manuscript writing, or educational events from Sumitomo Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceutical, and Eisai. Yasushi Shimo received honoraria from Kyowa Kirin; and has received honoraria from Takeda Pharmaceutical, AbbVie, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Sumitomo Pharma, Boston Scientific, Medtronic, FP Pharmaceutical, and Ono Pharmaceutical. Kenichi Kashihara received consulting fees and honoraria from Kyowa Kirin; and has received honoraria from Sumitomo Pharma and Takeda Pharmaceutical. Shih-Wei Chiu received support for the present manuscript from Kyowa Kirin. Takuhiro Yamaguchi received support for the present manuscript from Kyowa Kirin; and has received grants from AC Medical, A2 Healthcare, ClinChoice, Japan Tobacco, Japan Media, Medidata Solutions, Ono Pharmaceutical, Medrio, NIPRO, intellim, Welby, 3H Medi Solution, Baseconnect, NOBORI, Puravida Technologies, Hemp Kitchen, Tsumura &amp; Co., Daiichi Sankyo, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Solasia Pharma, Cordis, and NTT DOCOMO; consulting fees from Public Health Research Foundation, EPS, Japan Tobacco, Medidata Solutions, Ono Pharmaceutical, Kowa Company, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Eisai, 3H Clinical Trial, intellim, AstraZeneca, Sonire Therapeutics, Seikagaku, Merck &amp; Co., Mebix, and Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim; and participated on an advisory board for Incyte Biosciences Japan. Takafumi Hasegawa, Satoshi Kaneko, and Masahiko Tomiyama have nothing to declare. Ethical Approval: This RCT was performed in compliance with the Declaration of Helsinki and the Clinical Research Act of Japan (Act No. 16 of 2017). It was approved by the Fukuoka University Medical Ethics Review Board (December 1, 2016, approval ID 2016M020), the Clinical Research Network Fukuoka Certified Review Board (October 31, 2018, approval ID 18-C08), and the responsible ethics committee/institutional review board at all of the participating sites listed in the Supplementary Materials. The RCT was registered on the University hospital Medical Information Network clinical trials registry (identifier UMIN000024536; https://center6.umin.ac.jp/cgi-open-bin/ctr_e/ctr_view.cgi?recptno=R000028214 ; October 25, 2016) and Japan Registry of Clinical Trials (identifier jRCTs071180014; https://jrct.mhlw.go.jp/en-latest-detail/jRCTs071180014 ; January 29, 2019). All data were collected and processed anonymously at a central site (Clinical Trial Data Center, Tohoku University Hospital). Written informed consent to participate was provided by the patients or by their representative once the patient had provided oral consent. We confirm that we have read the Journal&#x2019;s position on issues involved in ethical publication and affirm that this work is consistent with those guidelines.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40991184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12623527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-025-00809-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40120-025-00809-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Chou KL, Stacy M, Simuni T, Miyasaki J, Oertel WH, Sethi K, et al. The spectrum of &#x201c;off&#x201d; in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: what have we learned over 40 years? Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2018;51:9&#x2013;16. 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2018.02.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2018.02.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29456046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tran TN, Vo TNN, Frei K, Truong DD. Levodopa-induced dyskinesia: clinical features, incidence, and risk factors. J Neural Transm (Vienna). 2018;125:1109&#x2013;17. 10.1007/s00702-018-1900-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-018-1900-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29971495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenner P, Mori A, Aradi SD, Hauser RA. Istradefylline - a first generation adenosine A(2A) antagonist for the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Expert Rev Neurother. 2021;21:317&#x2013;33. 10.1080/14737175.2021.1880896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737175.2021.1880896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33507105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills AM, Eberly S, Tennis M, Lang AE, Messing S, Togasaki D, et al. Caffeine consumption and risk of dyskinesia in CALM-PD. Mov Disord. 2013;28:380&#x2013;3. 10.1002/mds.25319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.25319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3608707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23339054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibbiani F, Oh JD, Petzer JP, Castagnoli N Jr, Chen JF, Schwarzschild MA, et al. A2A antagonist prevents dopamine agonist-induced motor complications in animal models of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Exp Neurol. 2003;184:285&#x2013;94. 10.1016/s0014-4886(03)00250-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0014-4886(03)00250-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14637099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi M, Ito S, Tsuji Y, Horiguchi S. Safety and effectiveness of istradefylline as add-on therapy to levodopa in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: final report of a post-marketing surveillance study in Japan. J Neurol Sci. 2022;443:120479. 10.1016/j.jns.2022.120479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2022.120479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36395674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauser RA, Hattori N, Fernandez H, Isaacson SH, Mochizuki H, Rascol O, et al. Efficacy of istradefylline, an adenosine A<sub>2A</sub> receptor antagonist, as adjunctive therapy to levodopa in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a pooled analysis of 8 Phase 2b/3 trials. J Parkinsons Dis. 2021;11:1663&#x2013;75. 10.3233/jpd-212672.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/jpd-212672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8609697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34486986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishima T, Chiu SW, Saiki H, Yamaguchi T, Shimo Y, Maeda T, et al. Risk factors for developing dyskinesia among Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients with wearing-off: J-FIRST. J Neurol Sci. 2023;448: 120619. 10.1016/j.jns.2023.120619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2023.120619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37023638</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahlskog JE, Muenter MD. Frequency of levodopa-related dyskinesias and motor fluctuations as estimated from the cumulative literature. Mov Disord. 2001;16(3):448&#x2013;58. 10.1002/mds.1090.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.1090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11391738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar N, Van Gerpen JA, Bower JH, Ahlskog JE. Levodopa-dyskinesia incidence by age of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease onset. Mov Disord. 2005;20(3):342&#x2013;4. 10.1002/mds.20360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.20360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15580606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren Olanow C, Kieburtz K, Rascol O, et al. Factors predictive of the development of levodopa-induced dyskinesia and wearing-off in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2013;28(8):1064&#x2013;71. 10.1002/mds.25364.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.25364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23630119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomlinson CL, Stowe R, Patel S, Rick C, Gray R, Clarke CE. Systematic review of levodopa dose equivalency reporting in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2010;25(15):2649&#x2013;53. 10.1002/mds.23429.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21069833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schade S, Mollenhauer B, Trenkwalder C. Levodopa equivalent dose conversion factors: an updated proposal including opicapone and safinamide. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2020;7(3):343&#x2013;5. 10.1002/mdc3.12921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mdc3.12921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7111582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32258239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchida E, Nomoto M, Terahara T, Okawa K, Takahashi E. Pharmacokinetics of ropinirole patch (HP-3000) in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and healthy adults. J New Rem Clin. 2022;71:87&#x2013;106 (<b>In Japanese with English abstract</b>).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno Y, Kondo T. Adenosine A<sub>2A</sub> receptor antagonist istradefylline reduces daily OFF time in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2013;28:1138&#x2013;41. 10.1002/mds.25418.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.25418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3842830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23483627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kondo T, Mizuno Y. A long-term study of istradefylline safety and efficacy in patients with Parkinson disease. Clin Neuropharmacol. 2015;38:41&#x2013;6. 10.1097/wnf.0000000000000073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/wnf.0000000000000073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25768849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez HH, Greeley DR, Zweig RM, Wojcieszek J, Mori A, Sussman NM. Istradefylline as monotherapy for Parkinson disease: results of the 6002-US-051 trial. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2010;16:16&#x2013;20. 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2009.06.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2009.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19616987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Doorduin J, Elsinga PH, Dierckx RAJO, de Vries EFJ, Casteels C. Altered adenosine 2A and dopamine D2 receptor availability in the 6-hydroxydopamine-treated rats with and without levodopa-induced dyskinesia. Neuroimage. 2017;157:209&#x2013;18. 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.05.066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.05.066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28583881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomiyama M, Kimura T, Maeda T, Tanaka H, Kannari K, Baba M. Upregulation of striatal adenosine A<sub>2A</sub> receptor mRNA in 6-hydroxydopamine-lesioned rats intermittently treated with L-DOPA. Synapse. 2004;52:218&#x2013;22. 10.1002/syn.20011.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/syn.20011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15065221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calon F, Dridi M, Hornykiewicz O, B&#xe9;dard PJ, Rajput AH, Di Paolo T. Increased adenosine A<sub>2A</sub> receptors in the brain of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients with dyskinesias. Brain. 2004;127:1075&#x2013;84. 10.1093/brain/awh128.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awh128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15033896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishina M, Ishiwata K. Adenosine receptor PET imaging in human brain. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2014;119:51&#x2013;69. 10.1016/b978-0-12-801022-8.00002-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/b978-0-12-801022-8.00002-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25175960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishina M, Ishiwata K, Naganawa M, Kimura Y, Kitamura S, Suzuki M, et al. Adenosine A(2A) receptors measured with [C]TMSX PET in the striata of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients. PLoS ONE. 2011;6:e17338. 10.1371/journal.pone.0017338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0017338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21386999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morelli M, Di Paolo T, Wardas J, Calon F, Xiao D, Schwarzschild MA. Role of adenosine A<sub>2A</sub> receptors in parkinsonian motor impairment and l-DOPA-induced motor complications. Prog Neurobiol. 2007;83:293&#x2013;309. 10.1016/j.pneurobio.2007.07.001.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pneurobio.2007.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17826884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramlackhansingh AF, Bose SK, Ahmed I, Turkheimer FE, Pavese N, Brooks DJ. Adenosine 2A receptor availability in dyskinetic and nondyskinetic patients with Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2011;76:1811&#x2013;6. 10.1212/WNL.0b013e31821ccce4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31821ccce4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3100120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21606452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morigaki R, Okita S, Goto S. Dopamine-induced changes in G&#x3b1;(olf) protein levels in striatonigral and striatopallidal medium spiny neurons underlie the genesis of L-DOPA-induced dyskinesia in Parkinsonian mice. Front Cell Neurosci. 2017;11:26. 10.3389/fncel.2017.00026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncel.2017.00026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5300978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28239340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeLong MR. Primate models of movement disorders of basal ganglia origin. Trends Neurosci. 1990;13:281&#x2013;5. 10.1016/0166-2236(90)90110-v.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0166-2236(90)90110-v</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1695404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kravitz AV, Freeze BS, Parker PR, et al. Regulation of parkinsonian motor behaviours by optogenetic control of basal ganglia circuitry. Nature. 2010;466:622&#x2013;6. 10.1038/nature09159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature09159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3552484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20613723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cenci MA. Dopamine dysregulation of movement control in L-DOPA-induced dyskinesia. Trends Neurosci. 2007;30:236&#x2013;43. 10.1016/j.tins.2007.03.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tins.2007.03.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17400300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishijima H, Kimura T, Mori F, Wakabayashi K, Kinoshita I, Nakamura T, et al. Effects of aging on levo-dihydroxyphenylalanine-induced dyskinesia in a rat model of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021;13:650350. 10.3389/fnagi.2021.650350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2021.650350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8155371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34054505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishijima H, Mori F, Arai A, Zhu G, Wakabayashi K, Okada M, et al. GABA storage and release in the medial globus pallidus in L-DOPA-induced dyskinesia priming. Neurobiol Dis. 2020;143:104979. 10.1016/j.nbd.2020.104979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2020.104979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32590036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasamo S, Takeuchi M, Ikuno M, Kawasaki Y, Tanaka S, Takahashi R, et al. Real-world pharmacological treatment patterns of patients with young-onset Parkinson&#x2019;s disease in Japan: a medical claims database analysis. J Neurol. 2019;266:1944&#x2013;52. 10.1007/s00415-019-09360-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-019-09360-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31076875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seki M, Kawata Y, Hayashi A, Arai M, Fujimoto S. Prescribing patterns and determinants for elderly patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease in Japan: a retrospective observational study using insurance claims databases. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1162016. 10.3389/fneur.2023.1162016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2023.1162016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10327598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37426443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prange S, Danaila T, Laurencin C, Caire C, Metereau E, Merle H, et al. Age and time course of long-term motor and nonmotor complications in Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2019;92:e148&#x2013;60. 10.1212/wnl.0000000000006737.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.0000000000006737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30541866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatano T, Sengoku R, Nagayama H, Yanagisawa N, Yoritaka A, Suzuki K, et al. Impact of istradefylline on levodopa dose escalation in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: ISTRA ADJUST PD study, a multicenter, open-label, randomized, parallel-group controlled study. Neurol Ther. 2024;13:323&#x2013;38. 10.1007/s40120-023-00574-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-023-00574-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10951171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38227133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mizuno Y, Hasegawa K, Kondo T, Kuno S, Yamamoto M. Clinical efficacy of istradefylline (KW-6002) in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized, controlled study. Mov Disord. 2010;25:1437&#x2013;43. 10.1002/mds.23107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20629136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi M, Shimokawa T, Koh J, Takeshima T, Yamashita H, Kajimoto Y, et al. Efficacy and safety of istradefylline in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease presenting with postural abnormalities: Results from a multicenter, prospective, and open-label exploratory study in Japan. J Neurol Sci. 2022;432:120078. 10.1016/j.jns.2021.120078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2021.120078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34923334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yabe I, Kitagawa M, Takahashi I, Matsushima M, Sasaki H. The efficacy of istradefylline for treating mild wearing-off in Parkinson Disease. Clin Neuropharmacol. 2017;40:261&#x2013;3. 10.1097/wnf.0000000000000249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/wnf.0000000000000249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28976411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>