<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40999180</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8253</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurology and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurol Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safety and Effectiveness of Satralizumab in Japanese Patients with Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum Disorder: A 30&#x2011;Month Interim Analysis of Post&#x2011;marketing Surveillance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2429</StartPage><EndPage>2451</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2429-2451</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40120-025-00799-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">A large-scale post-marketing surveillance (PMS) study is ongoing to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of satralizumab over 6&#xa0;years in Japanese patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD) in real-world settings. We present the results of a 30-month interim analysis of the study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This PMS is being conducted across 234 sites in Japan. In this 30-month interim analysis, the end of the observation period was defined as either the date of data lock for the 30-month case report form for all patients or the last observation date for patients with satralizumab discontinuation. Primary outcomes include proportion of patients experiencing adverse drug reactions (ADRs), event rate, and oral glucocorticoid use. Secondary outcomes include time to relapse and relapse rate.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of 571 patients included (mean age: 52.4&#xa0;years), 91.76% were female. At baseline, 85.98% of patients received oral glucocorticoids. ADRs were reported in 28.72% of patients (event rate: 27.69&#xa0;events/100 person-years), with infections being most common (11.73%; 8.97 events/100 person-years). Univariate analysis showed that at 30&#xa0;months, serious infections occurred in 6.83% of patients (5.00&#xa0;events/100 person-years vs 8.13 events/100 person-years during 0-6&#xa0;months) and were more frequent in patients aged&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;75&#xa0;years, with diagnosis-to-treatment initiation duration&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;10&#xa0;years,&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;3 relapses within 2&#xa0;years, and Expanded Disability Status Scale score&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;6. Mean glucocorticoid dose decreased from 12.27&#xa0;mg/day (baseline) to 3.48&#xa0;mg/day (30&#xa0;months). Kaplan-Meier cumulative relapse-free rate was 85.86% at 30&#xa0;months. The annualized relapse rate was 0.08/person-year. Overall, 9.63% and 3.50% of patients discontinued treatment because of adverse events and relapses, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Serious infections were more common during the satralizumab treatment period, occurring most frequently within the first 6&#xa0;months, highlighting the need for continuous monitoring of infections throughout satralizumab treatment. Satralizumab was found to be safe, without new safety concerns over 30&#xa0;months. A reduction in concomitant immunosuppressive therapy usage was observed. The study demonstrated the effectiveness of satralizumab in preventing relapses in Japanese patients with NMOSD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">UMIN Clinical Trials Registry, UMIN000041047.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamura</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9048-0375</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, National Institute of Neuroscience, National Centre of Neurology and Psychiatry, 4-1-1 Ogawa-Higashi, Kodaira, Tokyo, 187-8511, Japan. yamamura@ncnp.go.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isobe</LastName><ForeName>Noriko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9525-4254</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Neurological Institute, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, 812-8582, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawachi</LastName><ForeName>Izumi</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7140-8500</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Niigata, 951-8585, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Center, Niigata University School of Medicine, Niigata, 951-8510, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nohara</LastName><ForeName>Chiyoko</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Tokyo Metropolitan Ebara Hospital, Tokyo, 145-0065, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyazaki</LastName><ForeName>Yusei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8235-7569</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research, National Hospital Organization Hokkaido Medical Center, Sapporo, 063-0005, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomita</LastName><ForeName>Minami</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-3201-305X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Safety Division, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Tokyo, 103-8324, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kamei</LastName><ForeName>Yuta</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-3220-0084</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Safety Division, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Tokyo, 103-8324, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamashita</LastName><ForeName>Katsuhisa</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5761-1609</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Affairs Division, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Tokyo, 103-8324, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakahara</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5858-0998</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Keio University School of Medicine, Tokyo, 160-8582, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakashima</LastName><ForeName>Ichiro</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2612-8948</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Tohoku Medical and Pharmaceutical University, Sendai, 983-8512, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujihara</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3096-4156</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Multiple Sclerosis Therapeutics, Fukushima Medical University School of Medicine, Fukushima, 960-1295, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multiple Sclerosis and Neuromyelitis Optica Center, Southern TOHOKU Research Institute for Neuroscience, Koriyama, 963-8563, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Neurol Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101637818</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2193-6536</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adverse drug reactions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti&#x2013;IL-6 receptor antibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glucocorticoids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infections</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-term</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-marketing surveillance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Relapse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Satralizumab</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: Takashi Yamamura served on scientific advisory boards for Chugai Pharmaceutical, Roche, Biogen Japan, Biogen MA, Novartis Pharma, and Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma; received research grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Novartis Pharma, Biogen Japan, Chiome Bioscience, Sanofi, UCB Japan, and Mebix; received research funding from Alexion G.K.; and received speaker honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Biogen Japan, Novartis Pharma, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, Miyarisan Pharmaceutical, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Sumitomo Pharma, and Teijin Pharma. Noriko Isobe has received speaker honoraria from Biogen Japan, Novartis Pharma, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, Ono Pharmaceutical, Eisai, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Kyowa Kirin, EA Pharma, FP Pharmaceutical, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, UCB Japan, Japan Blood Product Organization, Argenx, Sanofi, Amgen, and Alnylam. She has also received research grants for her department from Sumitomo Pharma, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Biogen Japan, and Kyowa Kirin. Izumi Kawachi received a grant from JSPS KAKENHI (grant number: 20K07899, JP23K06923) and the MHLW Research Program on Rare and Intractable Diseases, Grant/Award (JPMH 20FC1030, JPMH 23FC1009); funding for research, travel, and/or speaker honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Novartis Pharma, Biogen Japan, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, Teijin Pharma, Argenx, UCB, and Daiichi Sankyo; and is a scientific advisory board member for Chugai Pharmaceutical and UCB. Chiyoko Nohara received speaker honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Biogen Japan, Novartis Pharma, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, and Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma. Yusei Miyazaki received funding for travel and/or speaker honoraria from Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Biogen Japan, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Novartis Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, and Teijin Pharma. Minami Tomita, Yuta Kamei, and Katsuhisa Yamashita are employees of Chugai Pharmaceutical. Jin Nakahara received speaker honoraria from Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, and Roche; served as a paid consultant for Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Horizon, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, and Roche; and received research grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, MEXT, and MHLW. Ichiro Nakashima serves on the scientific advisory boards for Biogen Japan, and Novartis Pharma; and receives honoraria for speaking engagements with Chugai Pharmaceutical, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Biogen Japan, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, and Novartis Pharma. Ichiro Nakashima is a member of advisory board of Chugai Pharmaceutical and received consultancy and speaker&#x2019;s bureau fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical. Kazuo Fujihara&#xa0;serves as an advisor on the scientific advisory boards for Biogen, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Novartis Pharma, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Roche, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Viela Bio/Horizon Therapeutics, UCB, Merck, Japan Tobacco, and AbbVie; has received funding for travel and speaker honoraria from Biogen, Eisai, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Novartis Pharma, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Roche, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Viela Bio, Teijin, Asahi Kasei, Merck, and Takeda Pharmaceuticals; and has received Grants-in-Aid for scientific research from the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology of Japan and Grants-in-Aid for scientific research from the Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare of Japan. Ethical Approval: The study followed the same ethical considerations as disclosed previously [16]. This PMS study is ongoing in compliance with Japanese regulations (Ministerial Ordinance on Good Post-marketing Study Practice for Drugs [GPSP], MHLW Ministerial Ordinance No. 38, March 23, 2005), as is the case with general PMS studies in Japan. The study did not undergo review by the ethics committee of the participating medical institutions or follow procedures for informed consent, as this was not required for PMS studies according to Japanese regulations of the Act on Securing Quality, Efficacy and Safety of Products including Pharmaceuticals and Medical Devices. The study was designed to collect information from physicians in daily medical practice. Therefore, there are no disadvantages for patients because alternative treatments (such as those in the control group), placebo administration, or an increased frequency of hospital visits or tests beyond routine medical care are not being implemented. In addition, patients routinely have the opportunity to request treatment discontinuation or modification.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40999180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12623530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-025-00799-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40120-025-00799-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Holroyd KB, Manzano GS, Levy M. Update on neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Curr Opin Ophthalmol. 2020;31:462&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ICU.0000000000000703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7771018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33009077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wingerchuk DM, Banwell B, Bennett JL, Cabre P, Carroll W, Chitnis T, et al. International consensus diagnostic criteria for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Neurology. 2015;85:177&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4515040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolilo RB, da Paz JA, Ap&#xf3;stolos-Pereira SL, Rimkus CDM, Callegaro D, Sato DK. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: a review with a focus on children and adolescents. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2023;81:201&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-1761432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10033201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36948203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe M, Isobe N, Niino M, Nakashima I, Matsushita T, Sakai Y, et al. Prevalence of, and disability due to, multiple sclerosis and neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder in Japan by the fifth nationwide survey. Neurology. 2024;103:e209992.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000209992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39475688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma X, Kermode AG, Hu X, Qiu W. Risk of relapse in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: recognition and preventive strategy. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2020;46:102522.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2020.102522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33007726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niino M, Isobe N, Araki M, Ohashi T, Okamoto T, Ogino M, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for multiple sclerosis, neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder, and myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein antibody-associated disease 2023 in Japan. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2024;90:105829.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2024.105829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39182455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uzawa A, Mori M, Sawai S, Masuda S, Muto M, Uchida T, et al. Cerebrospinal fluid interleukin-6 and glial fibrillary acidic protein levels are increased during initial neuromyelitis optica attacks. Clin Chim Acta. 2013;421:181&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cca.2013.03.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23535508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaneko K, Sato DK, Nakashima I, Ogawa R, Akaishi T, Takai Y, et al. CSF cytokine profile in MOG-IgG+ neurological disease is similar to AQP4-IgG+ NMOSD but distinct from MS: a cross-sectional study and potential therapeutic implications. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:927&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2018-317969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6109242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29875186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosso M, Saxena S, Chitnis T. Targeting IL-6 receptor in the treatment of neuromyelitis optica spectrum: a review of emerging treatment options. Expert Rev Neurother. 2020;20:509&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737175.2020.1757434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32306778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waliszewska-Pros&#xf3;&#x142; M, Chojdak-&#x141;ukasiewicz J, Budrewicz S, Pokryszko-Dragan A. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder treatment&#x2014;current and future prospects. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:2801.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22062801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7998461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traboulsee A, Greenberg BM, Bennett JL, Szczechowski L, Fox E, Shkrobot S, et al. Safety and efficacy of satralizumab monotherapy in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a randomised, double-blind, multicentre, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:402&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30078-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7935419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamura T, Kleiter I, Fujihara K, Palace J, Greenberg B, Zakrzewska-Pniewska B, et al. Trial of satralizumab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. N Engl J Med. 2019;381:2114&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1901747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31774956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamura T, Weinshenker B, Yeaman MR, De Seze J, Patti F, Lobo P, et al. Long-term safety of satralizumab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD) from SAkuraSky and SAkuraStar. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;66:104025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2022.104025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36007339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chugai. Chugai&#x2019;s Enspryng (satralizumab) subcutaneous injection 120 mg syringe approved in Japan for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Chugai news release. 2020 [cited 2024 Nov 4]. https://www.chugai-pharm.co.jp/english/news/detail/20200629170000_738.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo Y-A. Satralizumab: first approval. Drugs. 2020;80:1477&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-020-01380-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7522096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32797372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamura T, Isobe N, Kawachi I, Nohara C, Miyazaki Y, Tomita M, et al. Safety and effectiveness of satralizumab in Japanese patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a 6-month interim analysis of post-marketing surveillance. Neurol Ther. 2024;13:1361&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-024-00640-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11393251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39012406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cacciaguerra L, Tortorella P, Rocca MA, Filippi M. Targeting neuromyelitis optica pathogenesis: results from randomized controlled trials of biologics. Neurotherapeutics. 2021;18:1623&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-021-01055-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8608970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg BM, Fujihara K, Weinshenker B, Patti F, Kleiter I, Bennett JL, et al. Analysis of infection rates in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: comparing satralizumab treatment in SAkuraMoon, post-marketing, and US-based health claims data. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2025;99:106444.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2025.106444</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40288333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto K, Goto H, Hirao K, Nakajima A, Origasa H, Tanaka K, et al. Longterm safety of tocilizumab: results from 3 years of followup postmarketing surveillance of 5573 patients with rheumatoid arthritis in Japan. J Rheumatol. 2015;42:1368&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.141210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26034149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Declemy A, Chesnel C, Charlanes A, Le Breton F, Ismael SS, Amarenco G. Specificity of lower urinary tract symptoms in neuromyelitis optica in comparison with multiple sclerosis patients. Int Neurourol J. 2018;22:185&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5213/inj.1836050.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6177731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30286581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Habib AA, Zhao C, Aban I, Fran&#xe7;a MC, Jos&#xe9; JG, zu H&#xf6;rste GM, et al. Safety and efficacy of satralizumab in patients with generalised myasthenia gravis (LUMINESCE): a randomised, double-blind, multicentre, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet Neurol. 2025;24:117&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(24)00514-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39862880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mealy MA, Boscoe A, Caro J, Levy M. Assessment of patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder using the EQ-5D. Int J MS Care. 2019;21:129&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7224/1537-2073.2017-076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6552992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tavares LCP, Caetano LDVN, Ianhez M. Side effects of chronic systemic glucocorticoid therapy: what dermatologists should know. An Bras Dermatol. 2024;99:259&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.abd.2023.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10943326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38007314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trikudanathan S, McMahon GT. Optimum management of glucocorticoid-treated patients. Nat Clin Pract Endocrinol Metab. 2008;4:262&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncpendmet0791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18349823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima I, Nakahara J, Yasunaga H, Yamashita M, Nishijima N, Satomura A, et al. Real-world management of patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder using satralizumab: results from a Japanese claims database. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2024;84:105502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2024.105502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38401202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>