<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41001033</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2234-943X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Case Report: A small cell lung cancer transformed from an <i>EGFR</i>-mutated Adenocarcinoma demonstrated a long-term remission to anti PD-1 antibody.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1651248</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1651248</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1651248</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fonc.2025.1651248</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Transformation to small cell lung cancer (SCLC) is a resistance mechanism in epidermal growth factor receptor (<i>EGFR</i>)-mutated non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) after EGFR-tyrosine kinase inhibitor (EGFR-TKI) treatment. The efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitor (ICI) in transformed SCLC remains to be elucidated. The present case report highlights a patient whose tumor underwent transformation to SCLC after developing resistance to an EGFR-TKI treatment. The patient subsequently achieved long-term remission lasting more than 5 years through treatment with an anti-PD-1 antibody nivolumab. Generally, the efficacy of ICI is inferior in <i>EGFR</i>-mutated NSCLC compared to those with <i>EGFR</i> wild-type NSCLC. However, some cases that have transformed to SCLC may be sensitive to ICI treatment. Further investigation is necessary to determine the efficacy of ICI in cases that have undergone transformation to SCLC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Kawanaka, Yonesaka, Tanizaki, Maenishi, Sakai, Kakimi, Nishio and Hayashi.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawanaka</LastName><ForeName>Yusuke</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-sayama, Osaka,&#xa0;Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yonesaka</LastName><ForeName>Kimio</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-sayama, Osaka,&#xa0;Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanizaki</LastName><ForeName>Junko</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-sayama, Osaka,&#xa0;Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maenishi</LastName><ForeName>Osamu</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-sayama, Osaka,&#xa0;Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakai</LastName><ForeName>Kazuko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-sayama, Osaka,&#xa0;Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kakimi</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-sayama, Osaka,&#xa0;Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-sayama, Osaka,&#xa0;Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-sayama, Osaka,&#xa0;Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101568867</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2234-943X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EGFR</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EGFR-TKI</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-small cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">small cell lung cancer transformation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>KY has received honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., MSD K.K., Amgen Inc., and Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. HH has received grants or contracts from IQVIA Services JAPAN K.K., Eisai Co., Ltd., Syneos Health Clinical K.K., EP-CRSU Co., Ltd., EPS Corporation., Shionogi &amp;amp; Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., MSD K.K., Sanofi K.K., Amgen Inc., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, PRA Health Sciences Inc., CMIC CO., Ltd., Astellas Pharma Inc., Pfizer R&amp;amp;D Japan G.K., Ascent Development Services, Labcorp Development Japan K.K., Eisai Inc., Kobayashi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., AbbVie Inc., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., A2 Healthcare Corp., Novartis Pharma K.K., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd, Medpace Japan K.K., Kyowa Kirin Co., Ltd., Japanese Gastric Cancer Association, Thoracic Oncology Research Group, Clinical Research Support Center Kyushu, West Japan Oncology Group, Japan Clinical Cancer Research Organization, Comprehensive Support Project for Oncological Research of Breast Cancer, EPS International Co., Ltd., Mebix, Inc., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Covance Japan Inc., Japan Clinical Research Operations and Medical Research Support; payment or honoraria from Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., 3H Clinical Trial Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., Novartis Pharma K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Amgen Inc., MSD K.K., Sysmex Corporation, Pfizer Japan Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K. and Guardant Health Japan Corp.; and has participated on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board of Bristol Myers Squibb Company, AbbVie Inc., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Novocure K.K., AstraZeneca K.K., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be constructed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41001033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12457102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2025.1651248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Zhou X, Zeng L, Huang Z, Ruan Z, Yan H, Zou C, et al. Strategies beyond 3rd EGFR-TKI acquired resistance: opportunities and challenges. Cancer Med. (2025) 14:e70921. doi:&#xa0; 10.1002/cam4.70921, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.70921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12051098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40322930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh S, Sadhukhan S, Sonawane A. 20 years since the approval of first EGFR-TKI, gefitinib: Insight and foresight. Biochim Biophys Acta Rev Cancer. (2023) 1878:188967. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.bbcan.2023.188967, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbcan.2023.188967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37657684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Gao H, Gao P, Liu H, Chen J. Molecular mechanisms and therapeutic strategies for small&#x2212;cell lung cancer transformation after TKI therapy in EGFR&#x2212;mutated lung adenocarcinoma (Review). Mol Clin Oncol. (2025) 23:62. doi:&#xa0; 10.3892/mco.2025.2857, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/mco.2025.2857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12082387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40384936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raskova Kafkova L, Mierzwicka JM, Chakraborty P, Jakubec P, Fischer O, Skarda J, et al. NSCLC: from tumorigenesis, immune checkpoint misuse to current and future&#xa0;targeted therapy. Front Immunol. (2024) 15:1342086. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fimmu.2024.1342086, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2024.1342086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10879685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38384472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi H, Sugawara S, Fukuda Y, Fujimoto D, Miura S, Ota K, et al. A randomized phase II study comparing nivolumab with carboplatin-pemetrexed for EGFR-mutated NSCLC with resistance to EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors (WJOG8515L). Clin Cancer Res. (2022) 28:893&#x2013;902. doi:&#xa0; 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-21-3194, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-21-3194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9397372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34921023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu P, Li Z, Sun Y, Liu T, Yin R. Persist or resist: Immune checkpoint inhibitors in EGFR-mutated NSCLC. Cancer Sci. (2025) 116:581&#x2013;91. doi:&#xa0; 10.1111/cas.16428, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cas.16428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11875763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39673162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn L, Mansfield AS, Szcz&#x119;sna A, Havel L, Krzakowski M, Hochmair MJ, et al. First-line atezolizumab plus chemotherapy in extensive-stage small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. (2018) 379:2220&#x2013;9. doi:&#xa0; 10.1056/NEJMoa1809064, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1809064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30280641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paz-Ares L, Dvorkin M, Chen Y, Reinmuth N, Hotta K, Trukhin D, et al. Durvalumab plus platinum-etoposide versus platinum-etoposide in first-line treatment of extensive-stage small-cell lung cancer (CASPIAN): a randomised, controlled, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet. (2019) 394:1929&#x2013;39. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32222-6, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32222-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31590988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qian X, Guo X, Li T, Hu W, Zhang L, Wu C, et al. Efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitors in EGFR-Mutant NSCLC patients with EGFR-TKI resistance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Pharmacol. (2022) 13:926890. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fphar.2022.926890, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.926890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9442341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36071838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saalfeld FC, M&#xf6;ller J, Christopoulos P, Wenzel C, Rasokat A, Wang XA, et al. Small cell transformation in EGFR-mutated non-small cell lung cancer: DLL3 expression and efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitors or tyrosine kinase inhibitors combined with chemotherapy. Eur J Cancer. (2024) 213:115065. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.ejca.2024.115065, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2024.115065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39423775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang CY, Sun H, Su JW, Chen YQ, Zhang SL, Zheng MY, et al. A potential treatment option for transformed small-cell lung cancer on PD-L1 inhibitor-based combination therapy improved survival. Lung Cancer. (2023) 175:68&#x2013;78. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.lungcan.2022.11.016, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2022.11.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36473332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujimoto D, Akamatsu H, Morimoto T, Wakuda K, Sato Y, Kawa Y, et al. Histologic transformation of epidermal growth factor receptor-mutated lung cancer. Eur J Cancer. (2022) 166:41&#x2013;50. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.ejca.2022.02.006, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2022.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35278824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marcoux N, Gettinger SN, O&#x2019;Kane G, Arbour KC, Neal JW, Husain H, et al. EGFR-mutant adenocarcinomas that transform to small-cell lung cancer and other neuroendocrine carcinomas: clinical outcomes. J Clin Oncol. (2019) 37:278&#x2013;85. doi:&#xa0; 10.1200/JCO.18.01585, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.18.01585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7001776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30550363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galvano A, Gristina V, Malapelle U, Pisapia P, Pepe F, Barraco N, et al. The prognostic impact of tumor mutational burden (TMB) in the first-line management of advanced non-oncogene addicted non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC): a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. ESMO Open. (2021) 6:100124. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.esmoop.2021.100124, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esmoop.2021.100124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8111593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33940346</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu W, Huo G, Chen P. Clinical benefit of pembrolizumab in treatment of first line non-small cell lung cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical characteristics. BMC Cancer. (2023) 23:458. doi:&#xa0; 10.1186/s12885-023-10959-3, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-023-10959-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10197372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37202730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rother C, John T, Wong A. Biomarkers for immunotherapy resistance in non-small cell lung cancer. Front Oncol. (2024) 14:1489977. doi:&#xa0; 10.3389/fonc.2024.1489977, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2024.1489977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11693593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39749035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guan M, Jiao Y, Zhou L. Immune infiltration analysis with the CIBERSORT method in lung cancer. Dis Markers. (2022) 2022:3186427. doi:&#xa0; 10.1155/2022/3186427, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/3186427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8956442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35340416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haratani K, Hayashi H, Tanaka T, Kaneda H, Togashi Y, Sakai K, et al. Tumor immune microenvironment and nivolumab efficacy in EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer based on T790M status after disease progression during EGFR-TKI treatment. Ann Oncol. (2017) 28:1532&#x2013;9. doi:&#xa0; 10.1093/annonc/mdx183, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdx183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28407039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shirasawa M, Yoshida T, Shiraishi K, Takigami A, Takayanagi D, Imabayashi T, et al. Identification of inflamed-phenotype of small cell lung cancer leading to the efficacy of anti-PD-L1 antibody and chemotherapy. Lung Cancer. (2023) 179:107183. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.lungcan.2023.107183, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2023.107183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37037178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pujol JL, Greillier L, Audigier-Valette C, Moro-Sibilot D, Uwer L, Hureaux J, et al. A randomized non-comparative phase II study of anti-programmed cell death-ligand 1 atezolizumab or chemotherapy as second-line therapy in patients with small cell lung cancer: results from the IFCT-1603 trial. J Thorac Oncol. (2019) 14:903&#x2013;13. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.jtho.2019.01.008, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2019.01.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30664989</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonia SJ, L&#xf3;pez-Martin JA, Bendell J, Ott PA, Taylor M, Eder JP, et al. Nivolumab alone and nivolumab plus ipilimumab in recurrent small-cell lung cancer (CheckMate 032): a multicentre, open-label, phase 1/2 trial. Lancet Oncol. (2016) 17:883&#x2013;95. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/S1470-2045(16)30098-5, PMID:</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(16)30098-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27269741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>