<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41082893</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1474-5488</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Lancet. Oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Radiotherapy-free pembrolizumab combined with chemotherapy for locally advanced non-small-cell lung cancer with PD-L1 tumour proportion score of 50% or higher (Evolution trial): a multicentre, single-arm, phase 2 study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1432</StartPage><EndPage>1442</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1432-1442</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S1470-2045(25)00462-0</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1470-2045(25)00462-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The standard of care for unresectable, locally advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC) is chemoradiotherapy followed by durvalumab. This study (Evolution trial WJOG11819L) aimed to evaluate the efficacy and safety of radiotherapy-free pembrolizumab and chemotherapy in patients with unresectable, locally advanced NSCLC with a PD-L1 tumour proportion score (TPS) of 50% or higher.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This prospective, multicentre, single-arm, phase 2 study was conducted in nine institutes in Japan. Inclusion criteria were age 20 years or older, histologically confirmed unresectable, locally advanced NSCLC with a PD-L1 TPS of 50% or higher, an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status of 0 or 1, at least one measurable lesion, no previous systemic therapy, and adequate organ function. Patients received intravenous induction therapy comprising pembrolizumab 200 mg every 3 weeks plus platinum-based chemotherapy for four cycles: either cisplatin 75 mg/m<sup>2</sup> or carboplatin (area under the curve [AUC] 5 for non-squamous NSCLC, AUC 6 for squamous NSCLC) plus pemetrexed 500 mg/m<sup>2</sup> (non-squamous NSCLC) or nanoparticle albumin-bound paclitaxel 100 mg/m<sup>2</sup> on days 1, 8, and 15 (squamous NSCLC). This was followed by maintenance therapy comprising intravenous pembrolizumab (200 mg) with or without intravenous pemetrexed (500 mg/m<sup>2</sup>) every 3 weeks for up to 2 years. The primary endpoint was 2-year progression-free survival and was assessed in the full analysis set (ie, all patients who met the eligibility criteria and received at least one dose of study treatment). The safety analysis set included all patients who received at least one dose of study treatment and had at least one post-treatment safety assessment. This trial was registered with ClinicalTrials.gov (NCT04153734) and is complete.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Between May 18, 2020, and Feb 22, 2022, 21 patients were assessed for eligibility and all were enrolled. Median age was 73 years (IQR 68-80); 16 (76%) patients were male; race and ethnicity data were not collected. Three (14%) patients discontinued and 18 (86%) patients completed the induction therapy; eight (38%) patients discontinued during maintenance therapy and ten (48%) patients completed the maintenance therapy. Median follow-up was 32&#xb7;5 months (IQR 26&#xb7;2-39&#xb7;5). The 2-year progression-free survival rate was 67% (90% CI 46-83). The most common grade 3 or worse adverse events were neutropenia (eight [38%] of 21 patients), leukopenia (four [19%]), and pneumonia (three [14%]). Serious adverse events occurred in seven (33%) patients. No treatment-related deaths were reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings suggest that pembrolizumab combined with platinum-based chemotherapy, without radiotherapy, might provide a feasible and promising alternative treatment strategy for patients with unresectable, locally advanced NSCLC with a PD-L1 TPS of 50% or higher.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved, including those for text and data mining, AI training, and similar technologies.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hata</LastName><ForeName>Akito</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Kobe Minimally Invasive Cancer Center, Kobe, Japan. Electronic address: a_hata@k-mcc.net.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ninomaru</LastName><ForeName>Taira</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Kobe Minimally Invasive Cancer Center, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okada</LastName><ForeName>Hideaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Kobe Minimally Invasive Cancer Center, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kogure</LastName><ForeName>Yoshihito</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, NHO Nagoya Medical Center, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oki</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, NHO Nagoya Medical Center, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Katakami</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Takarazuka City Hospital, Takarazuka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kijima</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine and Hematology, Hyogo Medical University, Nishinomiya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokoyama</LastName><ForeName>Toshihide</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kurashiki Central Hospital, Kurashiki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Hirotaka</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hyogo Prefectural Amagasaki General Medical Center, Amagasaki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kato</LastName><ForeName>Terufumi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Kanagawa Cancer Center, Yokohama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugawara</LastName><ForeName>Shunichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, Sendai, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sawada</LastName><ForeName>Takeshi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Early Clinical Development, Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoshimura</LastName><ForeName>Kenichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Health Data Science, Nagoya City University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seto</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, NHO Kyushu Cancer Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okamoto</LastName><ForeName>Isamu</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Third Department of Internal Medicine, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>West Japan Oncology Group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04153734</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017427">Clinical Trial, Phase II</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100957246</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1470-2045</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>DPT0O3T46P</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C582435">pembrolizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060890">B7-H1 Antigen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C423236">CD274 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>BG3F62OND5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016190">Carboplatin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>Q20Q21Q62J</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002945">Cisplatin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>P88XT4IS4D</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017239">Paclitaxel</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060890" MajorTopicYN="Y">B7-H1 Antigen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016190" MajorTopicYN="N">Carboplatin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002945" MajorTopicYN="N">Cisplatin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017239" MajorTopicYN="N">Paclitaxel</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declaration of interests AH reports grant support for the current study from Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme (MSD; grant number MISP 57924); grant support from MSD, Eli Lilly, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho, AbbVie and Pfizer; and honoraria from Chugai, Eli Lilly, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, MSD, and Taiho. YK reports grant support from MSD; and honoraria from AstraZeneca, MSD, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Kyowa Kirin, Nippon Kayaku, Glaxo Smith Kline, Takeda Pharmaceutical, and Daiichi Sankyo. MO reports grant support from AbbVie, GlaxoSmithKline, MSD, Parexel, Sanofi, AstraZeneca, ArriVent Biopharma, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Gilead Sciences, Kaneka Medix, and Ono Pharmaceutical; and honoraria from AstraZeneca, Novartis Pharma, Canon Medical Systems, Eli Lilly Japan, MSD, Merit Medical Japan, Olympus Marketing, and Fujifilm. NK reports grant support from MSD. TKi reports honoraria from MSD. TY reports grants support from MSD, Eli Lilly, Chugai, Boehringer Ingelheim, Astrazeneca, AbbVie, and Bristol-Myers Squibb; and honoraria from Eli Lilly, MSD, Chugai, Pfizer, Astrazeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, and Ono Pharmaceutical. HM reports honoraria from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono Pharmaceutical, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical, MSD, Nippon Kayaku, Kyowa Kirin, and Eli Lilly. YS reports honoraria from AstraZeneca, MSD, Novartis, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Nippon Kayaku, Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Takeda, Kyowa Kirin, Daiichi Sankyo, Boehringer Ingelheim, and Janssen Pharmaceutical. Tka reports grants support from Abbvie, Amgen, Arrivent, AstraZeneca, Bayer, BeiGene, BluePrint, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Meyers Squibb, Chugai, Daiichi-Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Gilead, GlaxoSmithKline, Haihe, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Merck, MSD, Novartis, Novocure, Pfizer, Regeneron and Takeda; honoraria from Amgen, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Meyers Squibb, Chugai, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Ono, Pfizer, Taiho, and Takeda; honoraria for Independent Data Monitoring Committee or advisory board meeting from Abbvie, AstraZeneca, Daiichi-Sankyo, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Merck, MSD, and Novocure; and other financial or non-financial interests from Eli Lilly. SS reports grant support from AnHeart, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, MSD, Daiichi Sankyo, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, AbbVie, Amgen, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Accerise, A2 Healthcare, Parexel, EPS, Pharmaceutical Product Development (PPD), and Syneos; and honoraria from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Kyowa Kirin, Takeda, Nippon Kayaku, Merck, Amgen, Thermo Fisher Scientific, Sysmex, and Eisai. KY reports honoraria from AstraZeneka. TSe reports honoraria from Amgen, AnHeart Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eisai, Eli Lilly Japan, GlaxoSmithKline, Merck Biopharma, MSD, Novartis Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer Japan, and Takeda Pharmaceutical; and other financial or non-financial interests from Precision Medicine Asia. KN reports grant support from Pfizer R&amp;D Japan, Labcorp Development Japan, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical, Pfizer Japan, AbbVie, Japan Clinical Cancer Research Organization, Eisai, Epidemiological and Clinical Research Support Unit, Shionogi &amp; Co, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, SRL Medisearch, PRA Health Sciences, Astellas Pharma, Ascent Development Services, Eisai, Bayer Yakuhin, AstraZeneca, A2 Healthcare, Thoracic Oncology Research Group; and honoraria from Ono Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, MSD, Pfizer Japan, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Incyte Biosciences Japan, Otsuka Pharmaceutical Factory, Hisamitsu Pharmaceutical, Patientricity MedPartners, Merck Biopharma, Bayer Yakuhin, Novartis Pharma, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Medical Mobile Communications, YODOSHA, M3, Global Health Consulting Japan, The Yomiuri Shimbun, and 3H Medi Solution. IO reports grant support from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, MSD, Daiichi Sankyo, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, AbbVie, Amgen, Taiho Pharmaceutical, GlaxoSmithKline, Parexel, EPS, PPD, and Syneos; and honoraria from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly and Company, Novartis, Takeda, Nippon Kayaku, Amgen, and Thermo Fisher Scientific. NY reports grant support from A2 Healthcare Corporation, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly Japan, Mebix, AbbVie, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan, Chugai Pharmaceutical, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, PRiME-R, IQVIA Solutions Japan, Novartis Japan, EPS Corporation, Medpace Japan, and Syneos Health Clinical; honoraria from Amgen, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, AbbVie, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Accuray Japan, Guardant Health Japan, Taiho Oncology, Tsumura &amp; Co, Nippon Kayaku, Merck Biopharma, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Miyarisan Pharmaceutical, Kyowa Kirin, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly Japan, Novartis Japan, Bristol Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Terumo, Pfizer Japan, USACO, KYORIN Pharmaceutical, Medical Review, Kowa Company; and honoraria for participation on a Data Safety Monitoring Board or Advisory Board from MSD, Amgen, Daiichi Sankyo, USACO Corporation, AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical, and Novartis Japan. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41082893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(25)00462-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1470-2045(25)00462-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>