<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41088723</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1744-8301</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>25</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Future oncology (London, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Future Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>HERTHENA-PanTumor01: a phase II study of patritumab deruxtecan (HER3-DXd) in previously treated advanced solid tumors.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3283</StartPage><EndPage>3292</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3283-3292</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/14796694.2025.2561539</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Human epidermal growth factor receptor 3 (HER3) is a receptor tyrosine kinase that is expressed in numerous solid tumors. Higher levels of HER3 expression in multiple tumor types are associated with adverse clinical outcomes, such as reduced survival. However, there is currently no HER3-directed antibody-drug conjugate approved for the treatment of any cancer. Improved treatment options are needed, in particular for patients who progress on standard therapies. HER3-DXd is an investigational HER3-directed antibody-drug conjugate composed of an anti-HER3 monoclonal antibody linked to a topoisomerase I inhibitor payload via a stable tetrapeptide-based cleavable linker. In previous clinical trials, HER3-DXd demonstrated a manageable safety profile and durable efficacy in previously treated, advanced <i>EGFR</i>-mutated NSCLC and advanced breast cancer across a range of baseline tumor HER3 expression levels. HER3-DXd has also shown preclinical antitumor efficacy in HER3-expressing cancers including cutaneous melanoma, gastric cancer, and prostate cancer, among others. The aim of this global phase II HERTHENA-PanTumor01 multicohort study is to assess the efficacy and safety of HER3-DXd in patients with relapsed or refractory locally advanced or metastatic solid tumors including melanoma, head and neck squamous cell, gastric/gastroesophageal junction, ovarian, cervical, endometrial, bladder, esophageal squamous cell, pancreatic, and prostate cancers.<b>Clinical trial registration:</b> NCT06172478 (ClinicalTrials.gov); 2023-507641-29-00 (EudraCT); jRCT2031230575 (Japan Registry of Clinical Trials).</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Powles</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7760-4724</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Genitourinary Oncology, Bart's Cancer Institute, Queen Mary University of London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatia</LastName><ForeName>Aarti</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0491-4454</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Oncology, Yale School of Medicine, Yale Cancer Center, New Haven, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burtness</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4660-1859</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Oncology, Yale School of Medicine, Yale Cancer Center, New Haven, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kogawa</LastName><ForeName>Takahiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3730-6591</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Early Clinical Development for Cancer, The Cancer Institute Hospital of JFCR, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishina</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4073-3757</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastrointestinal Medical Oncology, National Hospital Organization Shikoku Cancer Center, Matsuyama, Ehime, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakayama</LastName><ForeName>Izuma</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4987-1934</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gastrointestinal Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital East, Kashiwa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fountzilas</LastName><ForeName>Christos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3837-5644</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Roswell Park Comprehensive Cancer Center, Buffalo, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Castillo</LastName><ForeName>Dani R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5762-6683</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Oncology, City of Hope Comprehensive Cancer Center, Duarte, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McKean</LastName><ForeName>Meredith</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0944-7418</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Melanoma and Skin Cancer Research, Sarah Cannon Research Institute, Nashville, TN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meric-Bernstam</LastName><ForeName>Funda</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6816-6072</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Investigational Cancer Therapeutics, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Colombo</LastName><ForeName>Nicoletta</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gynecologic Oncology, Universit&#xe0; degli Studi di Milano-Bicocca, IEO - Istituto Europeo di Oncologia, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smithy</LastName><ForeName>James W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3126-1193</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medicine, Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fayette</LastName><ForeName>J&#xe9;rome</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8126-7019</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Oncology, Centre L&#xe9;on B&#xe9;rard, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chandra</LastName><ForeName>Sunandana</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7936-5069</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Hematology/Oncology, Robert H. Lurie Comprehensive Cancer Center, Northwestern University, Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sternberg</LastName><ForeName>David W</ForeName><Initials>DW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncology Clinical Development, Daiichi Sankyo, Inc., Basking Ridge, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jin</LastName><ForeName>Fan</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-7975-0016</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical, Merck &amp; Co., Inc., North Wales, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sullivan</LastName><ForeName>Kendall</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical, Daiichi Sankyo, Inc., Basking Ridge, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yueh</LastName><ForeName>Sue</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Daiichi Sankyo, Inc., Basking Ridge, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Clinthorne</LastName><ForeName>Graham</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-0425-8717</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pantumor, Medical Affairs, Daiichi Sankyo, Inc., Basking Ridge, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aguilo</LastName><ForeName>Ariel E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5002-1748</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oncology R&amp;D, Daiichi Sankyo, Inc., Basking Ridge, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kudchadkar</LastName><ForeName>Ragini</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Daiichi Sankyo, Inc., Basking Ridge, NJ, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8787-5587</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Oncology, Kindai University, Osaka-Sayama, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT06172478</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 CA008748</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Future Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101256629</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1479-6694</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020893">Receptor, ErbB-3</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D018796">Immunoconjugates</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>86780VJI1Q</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C585471">patritumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C581292">ERBB3 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>XT3Z54Z28A</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002166">Camptothecin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000080908">Broadly Neutralizing Antibodies</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020893" MajorTopicYN="Y">Receptor, ErbB-3</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018796" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immunoconjugates</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009369" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017322" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials, Phase II as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002166" MajorTopicYN="Y">Camptothecin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000031" MajorTopicYN="N">analogs &amp; derivatives</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000080908" MajorTopicYN="N">Broadly Neutralizing Antibodies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Effective and tolerable treatment options are needed for patients with advanced cancer that stops responding to standard therapy. Human epidermal growth factor receptor 3, or HER3, is a protein that is found on the surface of tumor cells in many types of cancer. However, there is currently no approved treatment that targets only HER3. Patritumab deruxtecan (also called HER3&#x2011;DXd) is a type of targeted cancer drug called an antibody-drug conjugate, or ADC. It consists of a specially designed antibody (patritumab) linked to a chemotherapy drug (deruxtecan). The antibody in HER3-DXd attaches to HER3 on the surface of a tumor cell and then moves inside the cancer cell, where the chemotherapy is released, killing the cell. This article describes a clinical study called HERTHENA-PanTumor01 that is evaluating HER3-DXd in patients with cancer that stopped responding to standard therapy. All participants will have cancer that cannot be removed by surgery (unresectable), and in some cases has spread (metastatic). The study will enroll patients with different types of cancer, including skin, head and neck, stomach, ovarian, cervical, endometrial, bladder, esophageal, pancreatic, and prostate cancer. HERTHENA-PanTumor01 is an open-label study, meaning the doctor and the participant will know what treatment is being given. All study participants will receive HER3-DXd every 3&#x2009;weeks through an IV infusion. HERTHENA-PanTumor01 will help doctors know more about how well HER3-DXd can shrink a patient&#x2019;s tumor, and the side effects patients have while being treated. Currently, HER3-DXd is an investigational treatment, and doctors are not able to prescribe it.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ADC</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastric cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HER3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HER3-DXd</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bladder cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">esophageal cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gynecologic cancers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">head and neck carcinoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">melanoma</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pancreatic cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prostate cancer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>T. Powles</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board: AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Exelixis, Incyte, Ipsen, Merck, Novartis, Pfizer, Seagen, Merck Serono, Astellas, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Eisai, Roche, MSD; Financial Interests, Personal, Other, Travel/Accommodation/Expenses: Roche, Pfizer, MSD, AstraZeneca, Ipsen; Financial Interests, Personal, Other, Sponsorship for The Uromigos podcast: Mashup Ltd; Financial Interests, Institutional, Other, Honoraria: Gilead; Financial Interests, Institutional, Research Grant: AstraZeneca, Roche, Bristol Myers Squibb, Exelixis, Ipsen, Merck, MSD, Seagen, Novartis, Pfizer, Merck Serono, Astellas, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Eisai; Financial Interests, Institutional, Other, Honoraria: Gilead. <b>A. Bhatia</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board: Daiichi Sankyo, Coherus, Regeneron, Bristol Myers Squibb; Financial Interests, Personal, Invited Speaker: Merck, PeerView, Medscape; Financial Interests, Personal, Writing Engagement: Clinical Care Options; Financial Interests, Personal, Royalties: UpToDate; Financial Interests, Personal and Institutional, Coordinating PI: Boehringer Ingelheim, Genentech; Non-Financial Interests, PI: Janssen. <b>B. Burtness</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board: GSK, Merck, Merck KGaA, ALX Oncology, IO Biotech, Cue Biopharma, Seagen, Coherus, Janssen, Arnold and Porter, Rakuten, AstraZeneca, Merus; Financial Interests, Personal, Royalties: UpToDate; Financial Interests, Personal and Institutional, Coordinating PI: IO Biotech, GSK; Financial Interests, Personal and Institutional, Local PI: Merck, Cue Biopharma, Seagen; Financial Interests, Institutional, Coordinating PI: Daiichi Sankyo; Non-Financial Interests, Institutional, Proprietary Information: Merck; Non-Financial Interests, Institutional, Product Samples: VITRAC Therapeutics. <b>T. Kogawa</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Invited Speaker: Daiichi Sankyo, Pfizer; Financial Interests, Institutional, Research Grant: Eli Lilly, Daiichi Sankyo. <b>T. Nishina</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Invited Speaker: Taiho Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Institutional, Local PI: MSD, Daiichi Sankyo, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Astellas. <b>I. Nakayama</b>: Financial Interests, Institutional, Local PI: Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, MSD. <b>C. Fountzilas</b>: Financial Interests, Institutional, Research Grant: Pfizer, Taiho Oncology, MSD; Financial Interests, Institutional, Local PI: Seagen, TransThera Sciences, AstraZeneca, Aravive, MSD, Kadmon, Astellas, Dragonfly Therapeutics, Rafael Pharmaceuticals, Ipsen, CG Pharmaceuticals, Biomea Fusion, Bellicum, Amgen, Legend Biotech; Non-Financial Interests, Institutional, Other, PI on clinical trial evaluating biomarker for treatment selection in pancreatic cancer: Valar Labs. <b>D.R. Castillo</b>: Nothing to disclose. <b>M. McKean</b>: Financial Interests, Institutional, Other, Consulting: Pfizer, Castle Biosciences, IQVIA, Merck, Moderna; Financial Interests, Institutional, Research Grant: Ascentage Pharma Group, Bicycle Therapeutics, Dragonfly Therapeutics, Epizyme, Exelixis, Genentech, GSK, Ideaya Biosciences, Ikena Oncology, Infinity Pharmaceuticals, Jacobio Pharmaceuticals, Moderna, NBE Therapeutics, Novartis, Oncorus, Plexxikon, Prelude Therapeutics, Regeneron, Sapience Therapeutics, Seagen, Tizona Therapeutics, Tmunity Therapeutics, TopAlliance Biosciences, Aadi Biosciences, Alpine Immune Sciences, Arcus Biosciences, Arvinas, American Society of Clinical Oncology (ASCO), Astellas, Bayer, BioMed Valley Discoveries, BioNTech, C4 Therapeutics, EMD Serono, Erasca, Foghorn Therapeutics, G1 Therapeutics, Gilead Sciences, ImmVira Pharma, Shanghai Kechow Pharma, Kezar Life Sciences, Kinnate Biopharma, MedImmune, Mereo BioPharma, Metabomed, Nektar, OncoC4, PACT Pharma, Pfizer, Poseida, Pyramid Biosciences, Scholar Rock, Synthrox, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Teneobio, Tempest Therapeutics, Xilio, Aulos Bioscience, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Daiichi Sankyo, IconOVir, Jazz Pharmaceuticals, Krystal Biotech, NucMito Pharmaceuticals, OnKure, Remix Therapeutics. <b>F. Meric-Bernstam</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Other, Consultant: AstraZeneca, OnCusp Therapeutics, Zymeworks; Financial Interests, Personal, Other, Consulting: Calibr, EcoR1, Exelixis, GT Aperion, Infinity Pharmaceuticals, Loxo Oncology, LegoChem Bio, Lengo Therapeutics, Tallac Therapeutics, Becton Dickinson, eFFECTOR Therapeutics, Jazz Pharmaceuticals; Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board: Daiichi Sankyo, Incyte, Karyopharm, Protai, TheraTechnologies, Zentalis, Parabilis Medicines, Harbinger Health, Mersana Therapeutics, Sanofi Pharmaceuticals; Financial Interests, Personal, Other, Consulting: Menarini Group; Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board/Consultant: Seagen; Financial Interests, Personal, Invited Speaker: Dava Oncology; Financial Interests, Institutional, Other, Local PI/Research Grant: Aileron Therapeutics, Bayer Healthcare, CytomX Therapeutics, Daiichi Sankyo, eFFECTOR Therapeutics, Taiho Pharmaceutical; Financial Interests, Institutional, Other, Local PI/Research Grant/Coordinating PI: AstraZeneca; Financial Interests, Institutional, Local PI: Calithera Biosciences, Curis Inc, Debiopharm International, Guardant Health, KLUS Pharma, Novartis, Jazz Pharmaceuticals, Zymeworks; Financial Interests, Institutional, Other, Local PI/Steering Committee Member: Genentech; Financial Interests, Institutional, Research Grant: Takeda Pharmaceutical, Puma Biotechnology, Repare; Other, Travel Support: European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC), European Society for Medical Oncology (ESMO); Other, Travel Support: Cholangiocarcinoma Foundation, Dava Oncology. <b>N. Colombo</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board, Various: Roche, AstraZeneca, MSD/Merck, Clovis Oncology, GSK, Immunogen, Mersana; Financial Interests, Personal, Invited Speaker, Congress, Symposia, Lectures: AstraZeneca; Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board, Lectures: Eisai; Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board, Advisory Role: Nuvation Bio, Pieris; Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board, Advisory Role: OncXerna; Financial Interests, Personal, Invited Speaker: MSD/Merck; Financial Interests, Personal, Invited Speaker, Speaker: GSK; Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board: Novocure, BioNTech; Financial Interests, Institutional, Research Grant: AstraZeneca, Roche, GSK; Non-Financial Interests, Leadership Role, Chair, Scientific Committee: ACTO (Alleanza contro il Tumore Ovarico). <b>J.W. Smithy</b>: Financial Interests, Institutional, Coordinating PI: IO Biotech. <b>J. Fayette</b>:Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board: AstraZeneca, MSD, Innate Pharma, Merck Serono, Roche, Pfizer, Hookipa; Non-Financial Interests, PI: AstraZeneca, MSD, Pfizer, Meru, Calliditas, ISA Pharmaceuticals. <b>S. Chandra</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board: Bristol Myers Squibb, Novartis, Pfizer, Regeneron; Financial Interests, Institutional, Local PI: Bristol Myers Squibb, Novartis, Regeneron, Pfizer, Merck; Financial Interests, Personal and Institutional, Steering Committee Member: Bristol Myers Squibb; Financial Interests, Other, Data Monitoring Committee Member: Alkermes. <b>D.W. Sternberg</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Full- or Part-Time Employment: Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Personal, Stocks or Ownership: Daiichi Sankyo. <b>F. Jin</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Full- or Part-Time Employment: Merck; Financial Interests, Personal, Stocks or Ownership: Merck. <b>K. Sullivan</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Full- or Part-Time Employment: Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Personal, Stocks or Ownership: Daiichi Sankyo. <b>S. Yueh</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Full- or Part-Time Employment: Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Personal, Stocks or Ownership: Daiichi Sankyo. <b>G. Clinthorne</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Full- or Part-Time Employment: Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Personal, Stocks or Ownership: Daiichi Sankyo. <b>A.E. Aguilo</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Full- or Part-Time Employment: Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Personal, Stocks or Ownership: Daiichi Sankyo. <b>R. Kudchadkar</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Full- or Part-Time Employment: Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Personal, Stocks or Ownership: Daiichi Sankyo. <b>H. Hayashi</b>: Financial Interests, Personal, Invited Speaker: Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, AstraZeneca K.K., Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo K.K., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Merck Biopharma, MSD K.K., Novartis Pharmaceuticals K.K., Pfizer, Takeda Pharmaceutical; Financial Interests, Personal, Advisory Board: Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Pfizer, AstraZeneca K.K., Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Personal, Royalties: Sysmex; Financial Interests, Personal, Steering Committee Member: Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., GSK, Daiichi Sankyo; Financial Interests, Institutional, Local PI: IQVIA Services Japan K.K., Syneos Health Clinical K.K., EPS Corporation, Nippon Kayaku, Takeda Pharmaceutical, MSD K.K., Amgen, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., CMIC, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., Labcorp Development Japan K.K., Kobayashi Pharmaceutical, Pfizer Japan, AbbVie, A2 Healthcare, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Medpace Japan K.K., EPS International, Covance Japan, EP-CRSU, GSK K.K., Sanofi K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, PRA Health Sciences, Astellas, Ascent Development Services, AstraZeneca K.K., Daiichi Sankyo, Novartis Pharma K.K., Merck Biopharma, Mochida Pharmaceutical, Japan Clinical Research Operations; Financial Interests, Institutional, Research Grant: Japanese Gastric Cancer Association, Clinical Research Support Center Kyushu, Japan Clinical Cancer Research Organization, Ono Pharmaceutical, Medical Research Support, Eisai, Shionogi &amp; Co, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Bayer Yakuhin, Kyowa Kirin; Financial Interests, Institutional, Funding: SRL Medisearch, Eisai, Thoracic Oncology Research Group (TORG), West Japan Oncology Group (WJOG), Comprehensive Support Project for Oncological Research of Breast Cancer (CSPOR-BC), Mebix; Non-Financial Interests, Member: WJOG, Japanese Society of Medical Oncology. The authors have no other relevant affiliations or financial involvement with any organization or entity with a financial interest in or financial conflict with the subject matter or materials discussed in the manuscript apart from those disclosed. Medical writing and editorial support was provided by Erinn Gideons, PhD, CMPP (Nucleus Global, an Inizio company), and was funded by the Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited and Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme LLC, a subsidiary of Merck &amp; Co., Inc., Rahway, NJ, USA. Editorial support was provided in accordance with Good Publication Practice guidelines (ismpp.org/gpp-2022).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41088723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12536771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14796694.2025.2561539</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Mishra R, Patel H, Alanazi S, et al. HER3 signaling and targeted therapy in cancer. Oncol Rev. 2018;12(1):355. doi: 10.4081/oncol.2018.355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/oncol.2018.355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6047885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30057690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haikala HM, Janne PA.. Thirty years of HER3: from basic biology to therapeutic interventions. Clin Cancer Res. 2021;27(13):3528&#x2013;3539. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-20-4465</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-20-4465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8254743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33608318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roskoski R Jr. ErbB/HER protein-tyrosine kinases: structures and small molecule inhibitors. Pharmacol Res. 2014;87:42&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.phrs.2014.06.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2014.06.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24928736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ocana A, Vera-Badillo F, Seruga B, et al. HER3 overexpression and survival in solid tumors: a meta-analysis. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2013;105(4):266&#x2013;273. doi: 10.1093/jnci/djs501</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/djs501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23221996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reschke M, Mihic-Probst D, van der Horst EH, et al. HER3 is a determinant for poor prognosis in melanoma. Clin Cancer Res. 2008;14(16):5188&#x2013;5197. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-08-0186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-08-0186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18698037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shteinman ER, Vergara IA, Rawson RV, et al. Molecular and clinical correlates of HER3 expression highlights its potential role as a therapeutic target in melanoma. Pathology. 2023;55(5):629&#x2013;636. doi: 10.1016/j.pathol.2023.03.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pathol.2023.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37286471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wimmer E, Kraehn-Senftleben G, Issing WJ. HER3 expression in cutaneous tumors. Anticancer Res. 2008;28(2a):973&#x2013;979.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18507044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inaki K, Shibutani T, Maeda N, et al. Pan-cancer gene expression analysis of tissue microarray using EdgeSeq oncology biomarker panel and a cross-comparison with HER2 and HER3 immunohistochemical analysis. PLoS One. 2022;17(9):e0274140. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0274140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0274140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9498941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36137139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi M, Inokuchi M, Takagi Y, et al. High expression of HER3 is associated with a decreased survival in gastric cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2008;14(23):7843&#x2013;7849. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-08-1064</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-08-1064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19047113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Yang H, Duan G. HER3 over-expression and overall survival in gastrointestinal cancers. Oncotarget. 2015;6(40):42868&#x2013;42878. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.5998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.5998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4767477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26517355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang D, Liu CY, Shen D, et al. Assessment and prognostic analysis of EGFR, HER2, and HER3 protein expression in surgically resected gastric adenocarcinomas. Onco Targets Ther. 2015;8:7&#x2013;14. doi: 10.2147/OTT.S70922</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/OTT.S70922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4274138</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25565860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brand TM, Hartmann S, Bhola NE, et al. Human papillomavirus regulates HER3 expression in head and neck cancer: implications for targeted HER3 therapy in HPV(+) patients. Clin Cancer Res. 2017;23(12):3072&#x2013;3083. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-16-2203</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-16-2203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5474133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shames DS, Carbon J, Walter K, et al. High heregulin expression is associated with activated HER3 and may define an actionable biomarker in patients with squamous cell carcinomas of the head and neck. PLoS One. 2013;8(2):e56765. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0056765</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0056765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3586092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takikita M, Xie R, Chung JY, et al. Membranous expression of Her3 is associated with a decreased survival in head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. J Transl Med. 2011;9(1):126. doi: 10.1186/1479-5876-9-126</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1479-5876-9-126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3162511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21801427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima Y, Sudo K, Yoshida H, et al. Changes in HER3 expression profiles between primary and recurrent gynecological cancers. Cancer Cell Int. 2023;23(1):18. doi: 10.1186/s12935-022-02844-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12935-022-02844-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9898949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36737733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang CS, Shim JI, Byeon SJ, et al. Prognostic significance of HER3 expression in patients with cervical cancer. Cancers (Basel). 2022;14(9):2139. doi: 10.3390/cancers14092139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers14092139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9104480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35565268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memon AA, Sorensen BS, Meldgaard P, et al. The relation between survival and expression of HER1 and HER2 depends on the expression of HER3 and HER4: a study in bladder cancer patients. Br J Cancer. 2006;94(11):1703&#x2013;1709. doi: 10.1038/sj.bjc.6603154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.bjc.6603154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2361308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16685269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wei Q, Chen L, Sheng L, et al. EGFR, HER2 and HER3 expression in esophageal primary tumours and corresponding metastases. Int J Oncol. 2007;31(3):493&#x2013;499. doi: 10.3892/ijo.31.3.493</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijo.31.3.493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17671674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirakawa T, Nakata B, Amano R, et al. HER3 overexpression as an independent indicator of poor prognosis for patients with curatively resected pancreatic cancer. Oncology. 2011;81(3&#x2013;4):192&#x2013;198. doi: 10.1159/000333825</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000333825</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22067729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gil V, Miranda S, Riisnaes R, et al. HER3 is an actionable target in advanced prostate cancer. Cancer Res. 2021;81(24):6207&#x2013;6218. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-21-3360</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-21-3360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8932336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34753775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Begnami MD, Fukuda E, Fregnani JH, et al. Prognostic implications of altered human epidermal growth factor receptors (HERs) in gastric carcinomas: HER2 and HER3 are predictors of poor outcome. J Clin Oncol. 2011;29(22):3030&#x2013;3036. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2010.33.6313</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2010.33.6313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21709195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner B, Hasenclever D, Stern K, et al. ErbB-3 predicts survival in ovarian cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2006;24(26):4317&#x2013;4323. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2005.04.8397</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2005.04.8397</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16896008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan E, Alkhasawneh A, Duckworth LV, et al. EGFR family and cMet expression profiles and prognostic significance in esophagogastric adenocarcinoma. J Gastrointest Oncol. 2016;7(6):838&#x2013;847. doi: 10.21037/jgo.2016.06.09</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/jgo.2016.06.09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5177589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28078108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koumakpayi IH, Diallo JS, Le Page C, et al. Low nuclear ErbB3 predicts biochemical recurrence in patients with prostate cancer. BJU Int. 2007;100(2):303&#x2013;309. doi: 10.1111/j.1464-410X.2007.06992.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1464-410X.2007.06992.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17532856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CM, Shrieve DC, Zempolich KA, et al. Correlation between human epidermal growth factor receptor family (EGFR, HER2, HER3, HER4), phosphorylated Akt (P-Akt), and clinical outcomes after radiation therapy in carcinoma of the cervix. Gynecol Oncol. 2005;99(2):415&#x2013;421. doi: 10.1016/j.ygyno.2005.05.045</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygyno.2005.05.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16157365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baro M, Lopez Sambrooks C, Burtness BA, et al. Neuregulin signaling is a mechanism of therapeutic resistance in head and neck squamous cell carcinoma. Mol Cancer Ther. 2019;18(11):2124&#x2013;2134. doi: 10.1158/1535-7163.MCT-19-0163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1535-7163.MCT-19-0163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6825559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31387891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen EEW, Licitra LF, Burtness B, et al. Biomarkers predict enhanced clinical outcomes with afatinib versus methotrexate in patients with second-line recurrent and/or metastatic head and neck cancer. Ann Oncol. 2017;28(10):2526&#x2013;2532. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdx344</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdx344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5834024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28961833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haratani K, Yonesaka K, Takamura S, et al. U3-1402 sensitizes HER3-expressing tumors to PD-1 blockade by immune activation. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(1):374&#x2013;388. doi: 10.1172/JCI126598</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI126598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6934205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31661465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto Y, Koyama K, Kamai Y, et al. A novel HER3-targeting antibody-drug conjugate, U3-1402, exhibits potent therapeutic efficacy through the delivery of cytotoxic payload by efficient internalization. Clin Cancer Res. 2019;25(23):7151&#x2013;7161. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-19-1745</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-19-1745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31471314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koganemaru S, Kuboki Y, Koga Y, et al. U3-1402, a novel HER3-targeting antibody-drug conjugate, for the treatment of colorectal cancer. Mol Cancer Ther. 2019;18(11):2043&#x2013;2050. doi: 10.1158/1535-7163.MCT-19-0452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1535-7163.MCT-19-0452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31395690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakada T, Sugihara K, Jikoh T, et al. The latest research and development into the antibody-drug conjugate, [fam-] trastuzumab deruxtecan (DS-8201a), for HER2 cancer therapy. Chem Pharm Bull (Tokyo). 2019;67(3):173&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1248/cpb.c18-00744</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/cpb.c18-00744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30827997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogitani Y, Aida T, Hagihara K, et al. DS-8201a, a novel HER2-targeting ADC with a novel DNA topoisomerase I inhibitor, demonstrates a promising antitumor efficacy with differentiation from T-DM1. Clin Cancer Res. 2016;22(20):5097&#x2013;5108. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-15-2822</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-15-2822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27026201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogitani Y, Hagihara K, Oitate M, et al. Bystander killing effect of DS-8201a, a novel anti-human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 antibody-drug conjugate, in tumors with human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 heterogeneity. Cancer Sci. 2016;107(7):1039&#x2013;1046. doi: 10.1111/cas.12966</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cas.12966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4946713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27166974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yonesaka K, Takegawa N, Watanabe S, et al. An HER3-targeting antibody-drug conjugate incorporating a DNA topoisomerase I inhibitor U3-1402 conquers EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor-resistant NSCLC. Oncogene. 2019;38(9):1398&#x2013;1409. doi: 10.1038/s41388-018-0517-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41388-018-0517-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30302022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu HA, Baik C, Kim DW, et al. Translational insights and overall survival in the U31402-A-U102 study of patritumab deruxtecan (HER3-DXd) in EGFR-mutated NSCLC. Ann Oncol. 2024;35(5):437&#x2013;447. doi: 10.1016/j.annonc.2024.02.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2024.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38369013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu HA, Goto Y, Hayashi H, et al. HERTHENA-Lung01, a phase II trial of patritumab deruxtecan (HER3-DXd) in epidermal growth factor receptor-mutated non-small-cell lung cancer after epidermal growth factor receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor therapy and platinum-based chemotherapy. J Clin Oncol. 2023;41(35):5363&#x2013;5375. doi: 10.1200/JCO.23.01476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.23.01476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10713116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37689979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krop IE, Masuda N, Mukohara T, et al. Patritumab deruxtecan (HER3-DXd), a human epidermal growth factor receptor 3-directed antibody-drug conjugate, in patients with previously treated human epidermal growth factor receptor 3-expressing metastatic breast cancer: a multicenter, phase I/II trial. J Clin Oncol. 2023;41(36):5550&#x2013;5560. doi: 10.1200/JCO.23.00882</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.23.00882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10730028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37801674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton EP, Dosunmu O, Shastry M, et al. A phase 2 study of HER3-DXd in patients (pts) with metastatic breast cancer (MBC). J Clin Oncol. 2023;41(16_suppl):1004. (Abstract). doi: 10.1200/JCO.2023.41.16_suppl.1004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2023.41.16_suppl.1004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakayama I, Takahari D. The role of angiogenesis targeted therapies in metastatic advanced gastric cancer: a narrative review. J Clin Med. 2023;12(9):3226. doi: 10.3390/jcm12093226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm12093226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10178968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37176668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert J, Cmelak A, Shyr Y, et al. Phase II trial of irinotecan plus cisplatin in patients with recurrent or metastatic squamous carcinoma of the head and neck. Cancer. 2008;113(1):186&#x2013;192. doi: 10.1002/cncr.23545</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.23545</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18484593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chekerov R, Hilpert F, Mahner S, et al. Sorafenib plus topotecan versus placebo plus topotecan for platinum-resistant ovarian cancer (TRIAS): a multicentre, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2018;19(9):1247&#x2013;1258. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(18)30372-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(18)30372-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30100379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gass P, Thiel FC, Haberle L, et al. Primary results of the AGO-Zervix-1 study: a prospective, randomized phase III study to compare the effects of paclitaxel and topotecan with those of cisplatin and topotecan in the treatment of patients with recurrent and persistent cervical cancer. Gynecol Oncol. 2024;183:25&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1016/j.ygyno.2024.03.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ygyno.2024.03.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38490057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadler S, Levy DE, Lincoln ST, et al. Topotecan is an active agent in the first-line treatment of metastatic or recurrent endometrial carcinoma: Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group study E3E93. J Clin Oncol. 2003;21(11):2110&#x2013;2114. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2003.12.093</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2003.12.093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12775736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary UB, Verma N, Keane T, et al. A phase II study of gemcitabine and irinotecan in patients with locally advanced or metastatic bladder cancer. Am J Clin Oncol. 2014;37(2):188&#x2013;193. doi: 10.1097/COC.0b013e318271b306</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/COC.0b013e318271b306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23241501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai X, Tao L, Wang J, et al. Efficacy and safety of irinotecan combined with raltitrexed or irinotecan monotherapy for salvage chemotherapy of esophageal squamous cell cancer: a prospective, open label, randomized phase II study. Cancer Med. 2023;12(15):16108&#x2013;16118. doi: 10.1002/cam4.6264</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.6264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10469638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37325938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang-Gillam A, Hubner RA, Siveke JT, et al. NAPOLI-1 phase 3 study of liposomal irinotecan in metastatic pancreatic cancer: final overall survival analysis and characteristics of long-term survivors. Eur J Cancer. 2019;108:78&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2018.12.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2018.12.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30654298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan XL, Le A, Tang H, et al. Burden and risk factors of brain metastases in melanoma: a systematic literature review. Cancers (Basel). 2022;14(24):6108. doi: 10.3390/cancers14246108</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers14246108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9777047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36551594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>