<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41467267</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1028-768X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>34</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Acta neurologica Taiwanica</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acta Neurol Taiwan</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fatal Recurrent Cardioembolic Stroke Related to Thyroid Storm: A Case Report.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>251</StartPage><EndPage>257</EndPage><MedlinePgn>251-257</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/ant.ANT-D-24-00012</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Thyroid storm is a rare and life-threatening condition that develops in thyrotoxic patients with multiple systems involved. A 50-year-old woman with a history of hyperthyroidism and paroxysmal atrial fibrillation (AF) without regular treatment presented with acute left limb weakness and slurred speech. Electrocardiography indicated AF with a rapid ventricular rate of 165 beats per minute. Chest radiography revealed cardiomegaly with bilateral pleural effusion. The patient received thrombolytic therapy at 78 min after symptom onset. Brain computed tomography angiography revealed normal results. Laboratory tests revealed elevated free thyroxine, triiodothyronine, antithyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH) receptor antibody, and reduced TSH content. We immediately initiated intravenous digoxin, oral propranolol, and propylthiouracil. Echocardiography revealed global left ventricular hypokinesia. Recurrent fatal large infarction involving the bilateral hemispheres resulted in coma with quadriplegia on day 3. Thyroid storm should be diagnosed with early as possible. Simultaneous treatment of ischemic stroke and thyroid storm is challenging.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Acta Neurologica Taiwanica.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cheng</LastName><ForeName>Chu-Fang</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Taipei Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Chih-Yang</ForeName><Initials>CY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Taipei Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Shinn-Kuang</ForeName><Initials>SK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Taipei Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation, Taipei, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tzu Chi University, Hualien, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>Acta Neurol Taiwan</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9815355</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1028-768X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013958" MajorTopicYN="Y">Thyroid Crisis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017809" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatal Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000083262" MajorTopicYN="Y">Embolic Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012008" MajorTopicYN="N">Recurrence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atrial fibrillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardioembolic stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">case report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">recurrent stroke</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thyroid storm</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thyrotoxicosis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41467267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ant.ANT-D-24-00012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00127883-202510000-00011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Akamizu T. Thyroid storm: A Japanese perspective. Thyroid 2018;28:32-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galindo RJ, Hurtado CR, Pasquel FJ, Garc&#xed;a Tome R, Peng L, Umpierrez GE. National trends in incidence, mortality, and clinical outcomes of patients hospitalized for thyrotoxicosis with and without thyroid storm in the United States, 2004-2013. Thyroid 2019;29:36-43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kornelius E, Chang KL, Yang YS, Huang JY, Ku MS, Lee KY, et al. Epidemiology and factors associated with mortality of thyroid storm in Taiwan: A nationwide population-based study. Intern Emerg Med 2021;16:601-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burch HB, Wartofsky L. Life-threatening thyrotoxicosis. Thyroid storm. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am 1993;22:263-77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akamizu T, Satoh T, Isozaki O, Suzuki A, Wakino S, Iburi T, et al. Diagnostic criteria, clinical features, and incidence of thyroid storm based on nationwide surveys. Thyroid 2012;22:661-79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orgiazzi J. Anti-TSH receptor antibodies in clinical practice. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am 2000;29:339-55, vii.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourcier S, Coutrot M, Kimmoun A, Sonneville R, de Montmollin E, Persichini R, et al. Thyroid storm in the ICU: A retrospective multicenter study. Crit Care Med 2020;48:83-90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarlis NJ, Gourgiotis L. Thyroid emergencies. Rev Endocr Metab Disord 2003;4:129-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooks MH, Waldstein SS. Free thyroxine concentrations in thyroid storm. Ann Intern Med 1980;93:694-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiha M, Samarasinghe S, Kabaker AS. Thyroid storm: An updated review. J Intensive Care Med 2015;30:131-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder S, Joseph M. The perfect storm: A case of ischemic stroke in the setting of thyroid storm. Cureus 2020;12:e7992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min T, Benjamin S, Cozma L. Thromboembolic complications of thyroid storm. Endocrinol Diabetes Metab Case Rep 2014;2014:130060.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papi G, Corsello SM, Pontecorvi A. Clinical concepts on thyroid emergencies. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 2014;5:102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai Y, Ren L, Liu X, Li C, Gang X, Wang G. Thyroid storm complicated by corpus callosum infarction in a young patient: A case report and literature review. Medicine (Baltimore) 2022;101:e30318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams HP Jr., Bendixen BH, Kappelle LJ, Biller J, Love BB, Gordon DL, et al. Classification of subtype of acute ischemic stroke. Definitions for use in a multicenter clinical trial. TOAST. Trial of org 10172 in acute stroke treatment. Stroke 1993;24:35-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamel H, Healey JS. Cardioembolic stroke. Circ Res 2017;120:514-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen PY, Chang WL, Hsiao CL, Lin SK. Seasonal variations in stroke and a comparison of the predictors of unfavorable outcomes among patients with acute ischemic stroke and cardioembolic stroke. Biomedicines 2024;12:223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bednarczuk T, Brix TH, Schima W, Zettinig G, Kahaly GJ. 2021 European Thyroid Association guidelines for the management of iodine-based contrast media-induced thyroid dysfunction. Eur Thyroid J 2021;10:269-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziemnicka K. The use of iodine-based contrast materials in computed tomography and the risk of thyroid disease: What should a general practitioner know? Pol Arch Intern Med 2023;133:16572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee CM, Bhan I, Alexander EK, Brunelli SM. Association between iodinated contrast media exposure and incident hyperthyroidism and hypothyroidism. Arch Intern Med 2012;172:153-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres Acosta ND, Loku Galappaththy S, Barthel B. Iodine-induced hyperthyroidism within four hours of iodide load: A case report and review. Cureus 2019;11:e5960.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erem C. Thyroid disorders and hypercoagulability. Semin Thromb Hemost 2011;37:17-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maung AC, Cheong MA, Chua YY, Gardner DS. When a storm showers the blood clots: A case of thyroid storm with systemic thromboembolism. Endocrinol Diabetes Metab Case Rep 2021;2021:EDM200118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amalia L. Correlation between hypercoagulable state and severity level of ischemic stroke with COVID-19 infection. J Blood Med 2023;14:537-42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen AL, Ryu SJ, Lin SK. Concurrent moyamoya disease and Graves&#x2019; thyrotoxicosis: Case report and literature review. Acta Neurol Taiwan 2006;15:114-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheu JJ, Kang JH, Lin HC, Lin HC. Hyperthyroidism and risk of ischemic stroke in young adults: A 5-year follow-up study. Stroke 2010;41:961-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee TG, Ha CK, Lim BH. Thyroid storm presenting as status epilepticus and stroke. Postgrad Med J 1997;73:61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada Y, Akiyama H, Yoshimoto T, Urao Y, Ryuzaki M, Handa M. Thyroid storm with multiple organ failure, disseminated intravascular coagulation, and stroke with a normal serum FT3 level. Intern Med 2012;51:2379-83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurukumbi M, Dang T, Crossley N, Esame A, Jayam-Trouth A. Unique presentation of akinetic mutism and coexisting thyroid storm relating to stroke. Case Rep Neurol Med 2014;2014:320565.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ku BD, Park KC, Yoon SS. Fatal ischemic stroke in a case of progressive moyamoya vasculopathy associated with uncontrolled thyrotoxicosis. Korean J Intern Med 2015;30:543-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Bossolo A, Gonzalez-Rivera A, Coste-Sibilia S. Cerebrovascular Accident due to Thyroid Storm: Should We Anticoagulate? Case Rep Endocrinol 2016;2016:5218985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon SK, Kim MK. Recurrent stroke in Graves&#x2019; disease associated with moyamoya disease and thyroid storm. IOSR J Dent Med Sci 2016;15:44-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jane SA, Baek YH, Park TS, Lee KA. A case of acute cerebral infarction and thyroid storm associated with moyamoya disease. Int J Thyroidol 2017;10:56-60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanabe N, Hiraoka E, Hoshino M, Deshpande GA, Sawada K, Norisue Y, et al. Progressive ischemic stroke due to thyroid storm-associated cerebral venous thrombosis. Am J Case Rep 2017;18:194-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill JH, Nam TK, Jung HK, Jang KM, Choi HH, Park YS, et al. Acute cerebral infarction combined with a thyroid storm in a patient with both moyamoya syndrome and Graves&#x2019; disease. J Cerebrovasc Endovasc Neurosurg 2022;24:160-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Idrose AM. Acute and emergency care for thyrotoxicosis and thyroid storm. Acute Med Surg 2015;2:147-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebe A, Satar S, Sari A. Thyroid storm induced by aspirin intoxication and the effect of hemodialysis: A case report. Adv Ther 2004;21:173-7.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>