<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41673745</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-7283</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>11</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC psychology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The relationship between using communication media in non-working hours and job burnout in Jeddah.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">357</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40359-026-04077-5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Utilization of communication media for work life is an inevitable aspect of most jobs. It is regarded as a two-edged sword, as it significantly affects employees&#x2019; mental well-being and efficiency, particularly outside working hours. Despite growing global concern about digital overconnectivity, limited empirical research has examined how communication media use during non-working hours contributes to job burnout, particularly in Saudi Arabia. This research aimed to determine whether using Communication Media in Non-Working Hours (CMNWH) through the lens of Technology-Assisted Supplemental Work (TASW) influences employees&#x2019; job burnout level. The burnout was determined using the Maslach Burnout Inventory (MBI), which typically measures burnout in three facets: emotional exhaustion, depersonalization, and low personal accomplishment. Data were analyzed using the Statistical Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS) on a sample of 415 employees in Jeddah. The relationship between the CMNWH and burnout was examined using the regression analysis. The findings showed significant positive correlations among TASW and three sub-scales of burnout, specifically Reduced Personal Accomplishment (<i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.986), Exhaustion (<i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.945), and Depersonalization (<i>r</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.991), at a significance level of <i>p</i> &lt; 0.001. These results validate the evidence that the lack of boundaries between work and life, resulting from continuous connectivity through digital devices, leads to burnout. The research informs about breaking organizational communication boundaries and introducing digital well-being programs.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yasin</LastName><ForeName>Hala Mohammed</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Applied Medical Science, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia. hmyassin@uj.edu.sa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mujallad</LastName><ForeName>Alaa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Applied Medical Science, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alotaibi</LastName><ForeName>Dina Saleh</ForeName><Initials>DS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Applied Medical Science, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alshehri</LastName><ForeName>Anwar Neami</ForeName><Initials>AN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Applied Medical Science, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hakami</LastName><ForeName>Eman Ahmed</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Applied Medical Science, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sagheer</LastName><ForeName>Dalia Fahad</ForeName><Initials>DF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Applied Medical Science, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Basaeed</LastName><ForeName>Lina Fahad</ForeName><Initials>LF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, College of Applied Medical Science, University of Jeddah, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2050-7283</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Communication media</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Job burnout</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Maslach Burnout Inventory (MBI)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-Working hours</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Technology-Assisted supplemental work (TASW)</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Bioethical approval was granted by the Committee of Scientific and Medical Research at the University of Jeddah, Saudi Arabia (Application no.: UJ-REC-212). The committee reviewed the proposed research project and approved its compliance with the regulations and policies of bioethics scientific research of the University of Jeddah in accordance with the principles of the National Law of Ethics of Research on Living Things by the Bureau of Experts at the Saudi Council of Ministries and the National Committee of Bioethics at King Abdulaziz City for Science and Technology. The study was conducted in accordance with the ethical principles of the Declaration of Helsinki. The intended audience is voluntarily involved and well-informed of the study problem, consequences, and purpose, which are clearly explained on the first page. The first page of the Google Form clearly explains the study purpose, participation details, and the participants&#x2019; right to withdraw at any time. It also states that by clicking &#x2018;Continue,&#x2019; participants acknowledge this information and agree to voluntarily take part in the study. Regarding the MBI tool, permission to use the Maslach Burnout Inventory was formally obtained from Mind Garden, Inc., and the instrument was utilized in accordance with their licensing requirements. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41673745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12997710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-026-04077-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40359-026-04077-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Oksa R, Kaakinen M, Savela N, Hakanen JJ, Oksanen A. Professional social media usage and work engagement among professionals in Finland before and during the COVID-19 pandemic: four-wave follow-up study. J Med Internet Res. 2021;23(6):e29036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8208471</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34048356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tatar B, Erdil O. Always on emails and employee wellbeing: the role of subjective norm of connectivity. Int J Manpow. 2025;46(2):353&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Camilleri MA, Camilleri AC. Learning from anywhere, anytime: utilitarian motivations and facilitating conditions for mobile learning. Technol Knowl Learn. 2023;28(4):1687&#x2013;705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ver&#x10d;i&#x10d; AT, &#x160;poljari&#x107; A. Managing internal communication: how the choice of channels affects internal communication satisfaction. Public Relations Rev. 2020;46(3):101926.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hejase HJ, Dirani E, Haidar A, Alawieh Z, Ahmad L, A., Sfeir N. The impact of employee Well-Being on organizational effectiveness: context of Lebanon. Int J Hum Resource Stud. 2024;14(2):15&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong GY-L, Kwok RC-W, Zhang S, Lai GC-H, Li Y, Cheung JC-F. Exploring the consequence of information communication technology-enabled work during non-working hours: a stress perspective. Inform Technol People. 2024;37(1):285&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Ham S, Kang S-K, Choi W-J, Lee W. Beyond working hours: the association between long working hours, the use of work-related communication devices outside regular working hours, and anxiety symptoms. J Occup Health. 2024;66(1):uiad004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11020288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38258934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin L, P&#xe9;nard T, Poussing N. Are employees happier when staying connected with their companies outside working hours? Social Sci Comput Rev. 2022;40(4):1035&#x2013;53.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu W, Ye Z, Zhang Z. Off-time work-related smartphone use and bedtime procrastination of public employees: a cross-cultural study. Front Psychol. 2022;13:850802.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35360589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi B-Y, Min J-Y, Ryoo S-W, Min K-B. Use of work-related communication technology outside regular working hours and work-family conflict (work interference with family and family interference with work): results from the 6th Korean working conditions survey. Annals Occup Environ Med. 2022;34:e44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9836822</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36704540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi SB, Yoon J-H, Lee W. The modified international standard classification of occupations defined by the clustering of occupational characteristics in the Korean working conditions survey. Ind Health. 2020;58(2):132&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7118061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31527354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn J, Kim N-S, Lee B-K, Park J, Kim Y. Relationship of occupational category with risk of physical and mental health problems. Saf Health Work. 2019;10(4):504&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6933206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31890333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yue CA. The paradox of using public social media for work: the influence of after-hours work communication on employee outcomes. J Bus Res. 2022;149:748&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen A, Conroy SA, Crain TL. Identifying forms of after-hours information communication technology use and their role in psychological detachment: an episodic approach. Hum Resour Manag. 2024;63(6):919&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adisa TA, Ogbonnaya C, Adekoya OD. Remote working and employee engagement: a qualitative study of British workers during the pandemic. Inform Technol People. 2023;36(5):1835&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris KJ, Harris RB, Valle M, Carlson J, Carlson DS, Zivnuska S, Wiley B. Technostress and the entitled employee: impacts on work and family. Inform Technol People. 2022;35(3):1073&#x2013;95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khalid J, Weng QD, Luqman A, Rasheed MI, Hina M. After-hours work-related technology use and individuals&#x2019; deviance: the role of other-initiated versus self-initiated interruptions. Inform Technol People. 2022;35(7):1955&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li L, Lin TT. Smartphones at work: a qualitative exploration of psychological antecedents and impacts of work-related smartphone dependency. Int J Qualitative Methods. 2019;18:1609406918822240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Ca, Tang L, Liu Z. How social media usage affects psychological and subjective well-being: testing a moderated mediation model. BMC Psychology 2023;11(1):286.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10515432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37737198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu L, Zhong Y, Sun Y, Qin G. The impact of excessive social media use at work: a usage experience&#x2013;stressor&#x2013;strain perspective. Behav Inform Technol. 2023;42(7):985&#x2013;1004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folkman S, Lazarus RS. Stress processes and depressive symptomatology. J Abnorm Psychol. 1986;95(2):107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3711433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraimer ML, Shaffer MA, Bolino MC, Charlier SD, Wurtz O. A transactional stress theory of global work demands: A challenge, hindrance, or both? J Appl Psychol. 2022;107(12):2197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35343728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ninaus K, Diehl S, Terlutter R. Employee perceptions of information and communication technologies in work life, perceived burnout, job satisfaction and the role of work-family balance. J Bus Res. 2021;136:652&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Je&#x17e;kov&#xe1; Petr&#x16f; G, Zychov&#xe1; K, Drahotov&#xe1; K, Kuralov&#xe1; K, Kvasni&#x10d;kov&#xe1; Stanislavsk&#xe1; L, Pila&#x159; L. Identifying the communication of burnout syndrome on the Twitter platform from the individual, organizational, and environmental perspective. Front Psychol. 2023;14:1236491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10621209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37928590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslach C, Leiter P. Understanding the burnout experience: recent research and its implications for psychiatry. World Psychiatry. 2016;15:103&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4911781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27265691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gon&#xe7;alves SP, Santos JVd. Smartphone use side-by-side with burnout: mediation of work&#x2013;family interaction and loneliness. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(11):6692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9180685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35682276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheng N, Yang C, Han L, Jou M. Too much overload and concerns: antecedents of social media fatigue and the mediating role of emotional exhaustion. Comput Hum Behav. 2023;139:107500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brandst&#xe4;tter V, Bernecker K. Persistence and disengagement in personal goal pursuit. Ann Rev Psychol. 2022;73(1):271&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34280324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park SK, Rhee M-K, Lee SW. The effects of job demands and resources on turnover intention: the mediating roles of emotional exhaustion and depersonalization. Work. 2021;70(1):301&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34511473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulaedzah IA. Burnout on contact center: A literature review. Interdisciplinary Social Stud. 2022;1(4):383&#x2013;402.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia CX, Li JC-m. Work-family conflict, burnout, and turnover intention among Chinese social workers: the moderating role of work support. J Social Service Res. 2022;48(1):12&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shields B, Chen C. Examining the relationship between work-life conflict and burnout. J Natl Inst Career Educ Counselling. 2021;47(1):67&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blake H, Hassard J, Singh J, Teoh K. Work-related smartphone use during off-job hours and work-life conflict: a scoping review. PLOS Digit Health. 2024;3(7):e0000554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11288435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39078844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tams S, Ahuja M, Thatcher J, Grover V. Worker stress in the age of mobile technology: the combined effects of perceived interruption overload and worker control. J Strateg Inf Syst. 2020;29(1):101595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Zoonen W, Sivunen A, Rice RE. Boundary communication: how smartphone use after hours is associated with work-life conflict and organizational identification. J Appl Communication Res. 2020;48(3):372&#x2013;92.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen TD, Merlo K, Lawrence RC, Slutsky J, Gray CE. Boundary management and work-nonwork balance while working from home. Appl Psychol. 2021;70(1):60&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page KJ, Nastasi A, Voyles E. Did you get that thing I sent you? Mediating effects of strain and work-family conflict on the telepressure and burnout relationship. Stress Health. 2021;37(5):928&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33882178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Alwis S. A conceptual model on how technology assisted supplemental work leads to work-life conflict: entanglements of ICTs with work-life experiences. Management: J Contemp Manage Issues. 2023;28(1):15&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kunz LK, Ducki A, Roswag M, Hoppe A. Daily occurrence of technology-assisted supplemental work events and their relationships with recovery experiences and emotional exhaustion. Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Arbeits- und Organisationspsychologie. 2025;69(3):105&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stokes YA. Technology tool use and work/life balance among millennial workers: a correlational study. ProQuest Grand Canyon University; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesmodel US. Cross-sectional studies&#x2013;what are they good for? Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2018;97(4):388&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29453895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Noor S, Tajik O, Golzar J. Simple random sampling. Int J Educ Lang Stud. 2022;1(2):78&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Beer LT, van der Vaart L, Escaffi-Schwarz M, De Witte H, Schaufeli WB. Maslach burnout inventory &#x2013; general survey. Eur J Psychol Assess. 2024;40(5):360&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maslach C, Jackson SE, Leiter MP. Maslach burnout inventory. In: Zalaquett CP, Wood RJ, editors. Evaluating stress: a book of resources. 3rd ed. Lanham: Scarecrow Education; 1997. p. 191&#x2013;218.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotecha K, Ukpere W, Geldenhuys M. Validating the Technology-Assisted supplemental work scale (TASW). Corp Ownersh Control. 2015;12(2):4&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field A. Discovering statistics using IBM SPSS statistics. 6th ed. London: SAGE Publications Ltd; 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piedmont, R. L. Inter-Item Correlations. In A. C. Michalos (Ed.), Encyclopedia of quality of life and well-being research. Dordrecht: Springer; 2014. pp. 3303&#x2013;3304. 10.1007/978-94-007-0753-5_1493.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yong AG, Pearce S. A beginner&#x2019;s guide to factor analysis: focusing on exploratory factor analysis. Tutorials Quant Methods Psychol. 2013;9(2):79&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahayu NI, Muktiarni M, Hidayat Y. An application of statistical testing: A guide to basic parametric statistics in educational research using SPSS. ASEAN J Sci Eng. 2024;4(3):569&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang C, Wu M, Luo Q, Xu G, Huang L, Tian H, Sun M, Liang F. Acupuncture for migraine: A systematic review and meta-regression of randomized controlled trials. Complement Ther Med. 2024;86:103076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39243985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odunayo H, Fagbemide O. The impact of remote work on organizational efficiency: lessons from Nigerian telecommunications industry. ICCCM J Social Sci Humanit. 2024;3(1):46&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KH, Chon M-G. When work and life boundaries are blurred: the effect of after-hours work communication through communication technology on employee outcomes. J Communication Manage. 2022;26(4):386&#x2013;400.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichberger C, Derks D, Zacher H. Technology-assisted supplemental work, psychological detachment, and employee well-being: A daily diary study. German J Hum Resource Manage. 2021;35(2):199&#x2013;223.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim S, Ham S, Kang SK, Choi WJ, Lee W. Beyond working hours: the association between long working hours, the use of work-related communication devices outside regular working hours, and anxiety symptoms. J Occup Health. 2024;66(1):uiad004. 10.1093/joccuh/uiad004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11020288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38258934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi W-S, Kang S-W, Choi SB. The dark side of mobile work during non-work hours: moderated mediation model of presenteeism through conservation of resources lens. Front Public Health. 2024;12:1186327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10909990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38439760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>