<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38100106</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2574-3805</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JAMA network open</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Netw Open</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Biomarker Testing in Patients With Unresectable Advanced or Recurrent Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e2347700</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e2347700</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e2347700</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.47700</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE">Biomarker testing for driver mutations is essential for selecting appropriate non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) treatment but is insufficient.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To investigate the status of biomarker testing and drug therapy for NSCLC in Japan for identifying problems in treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS">The REVEAL cohort study included retrospective data collection and prospective follow-up from 29 institutions across Japan. Of 1500 patients diagnosed with advanced or recurrent NSCLC between January 1 and March 18, 2021, 1479 were eligible. Cases recognized at the wrong clinical stage (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;12), diagnosed outside the study period (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;6), not treated according to eligibility criteria before recurrence (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;2), and with deficient consent acquisition procedure (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;1) were excluded.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES">The primary end point was the biomarker testing status. Treatment-related factors were examined.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Among the 1479 patients included in the analysis, the median age was 72 (range, 30-95) years; 1013 (68.5%) were men; 1161 (78.5%) had an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status 0 or 1; 1097 (74.2%) were current or past smokers; and 947 (64.0%) had adenocarcinoma. Biomarker status was confirmed in 1273 patients (86.1%). Multigene testing was performed in 705 cases (47.7%); single-gene testing, in 847 (57.3%); and both, in 279 (18.9%). Biomarker testing was performed for EGFR in 1245 cases (84.2%); ALK, in 1165 (78.8%); ROS1, in 1077 (72.8%); BRAF, in 803 (54.3%); and MET, in 805 (54.4%). Positivity rates among 898 adenocarcinoma cases included 305 (34.0%) for EGFR, 29 (3.2%) for ALK, 19 (2.1%) for ROS1, 11 (1.2%) for BRAF, and 14 (1.6%) for MET. Positivity rates among 375 nonadenocarcinoma cases were 14 (3.7%) for EGFR, 6 (1.6%) for ALK, 1 (0.3%) for ROS1, 3 (0.8%) for BRAF, and 8 (2.1%) for MET. Poor physical status, squamous cell carcinoma, and other comorbidities were associated with hampered multigene testing. Targeted therapy was received as first-line treatment by 263 of 278 cases (94.6%) positive for EGFR, 25 of 32 (78.1%) positive for ALK, 15 of 24 (62.5%) positive for ROS1, 9 of 12 (75.0%) positive for BRAF, and 12 of 19 (63.2%) positive for MET. Median overall survival of patients with positive findings for driver gene alteration and who received targeted therapy was 24.3 (95% CI, not reported) months; with positive findings for driver gene alteration and who did not receive targeted therapy, 15.2 (95% CI, 7.7 to not reported) months; and with negative findings for driver gene alteration, 11.0 (95% CI, 10.0-12.5) months. Multigene testing for nonadenocarcinomas and adenocarcinomas accounted for 705 (47.7%) of all NSCLC cases.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE">These findings suggest that multigene testing has not been sufficiently implemented in Japan and should be considered prospectively, even in nonadenocarcinomas, to avoid missing rare driver gene alterations.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakamoto</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respiratory Medicine and Rheumatology, Department of Multidisciplinary Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Tottori University, Yonago, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsubara</LastName><ForeName>Taichi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, Kitakyushu Municipal Medical Center, Kitakyushu, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahama</LastName><ForeName>Takayuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yokoyama</LastName><ForeName>Toshihide</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kurashiki Central Hospital, Kurashiki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakamura</LastName><ForeName>Atsushi</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, Sendai, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tokito</LastName><ForeName>Takaaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respirology, Neurology, and Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kurume University School of Medicine, Kurume, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okamoto</LastName><ForeName>Tatsuro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Hospital Organization Kyushu Cancer Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akamatsu</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Oki</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, National Hospital Organization Nagoya Medical Center, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tobino</LastName><ForeName>Kazunori</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Iizuka Hospital, Iizuka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ikeda</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kanagawa Cardiovascular and Respiratory Center, Yokohama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Hospital Organization Osaka Toneyama Medical Center, Toyonaka City, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mimura</LastName><ForeName>Chihiro</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respiratory Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Kobe, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maeno</LastName><ForeName>Ken</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Allergy and Clinical Immunology, Nagoya City University Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miura</LastName><ForeName>Satoru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Niigata Cancer Center Hospital, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harada</LastName><ForeName>Toshiyuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Respiratory Diseases, Japan Community Health Care Organization Hokkaido Hospital, Sapporo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishimura</LastName><ForeName>Kunihiro</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Xcoo Inc, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hiraoka</LastName><ForeName>Manabu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Japan Medical Affairs, Japan Oncology Business Unit, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kenmotsu</LastName><ForeName>Hirotsugu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Shizuoka Cancer Center, Nagaizumi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujimoto</LastName><ForeName>Junya</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Translational Molecular Pathology, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shimokawa</LastName><ForeName>Mototsugu</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Yamaguchi University Graduate School of Medicine, Ube, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JAMA Netw Open</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101729235</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2574-3805</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011505">Protein-Tyrosine Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.11.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D048493">Proto-Oncogene Proteins B-raf</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011518">Proto-Oncogene Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D066246">ErbB Receptors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D020794">Receptor Protein-Tyrosine Kinases</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>JAMA Netw Open. 2024 Jul 1;7(7):e2429990. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2024.29990.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">39083280</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011505" MajorTopicYN="N">Protein-Tyrosine Kinases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D048493" MajorTopicYN="N">Proto-Oncogene Proteins B-raf</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011518" MajorTopicYN="N">Proto-Oncogene Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000230" MajorTopicYN="Y">Adenocarcinoma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066246" MajorTopicYN="N">ErbB Receptors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020794" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptor Protein-Tyrosine Kinases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</b> Dr Sakamoto reported receiving grant funding from Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited during the conduct of the study and personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eli Lilly and Company, Novartis AG, Merck &amp; Co Inc, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Hisamitsu Pharmaceutical Co Inc, Janssen Global Services LLC, Amgen Inc, Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited, AstraZeneca, Kyowa Kirin Co Ltd, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Illumina Inc outside the submitted work. Dr Takahama reported receiving grant funding from Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited during the conduct of the study and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Roche Diagnostics, and MSD and grant funding from Pfizer Inc outside the submitted work. Dr Yokoyama reported grant funding from MSD, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Boehringer Ingelheim, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Delta-Fly Pharma Inc, Janssen Global Services LLC, AbbVie Inc, Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited, and Parexel International Corporation and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eli Lilly and Company, Pfizer Inc, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, MSD, Novartis AG, and Merck &amp; Co Inc outside the submitted work. Dr Nakamura reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eli Lilly and Company, Novartis AG, Thermo Fisher Scientific, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Pfizer Inc, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, and Merck &amp; Co Inc. Dr Tokito reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, MSD Oncology, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, and Boehringer Ingelheim outside the submitted work. Dr Okamoto reported receiving research funding from MSD, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eli Lilly and Company, Pfizer Inc, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis AG, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, and Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd and personal fees from AstraZeneca, MSD, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eli Lilly and Company, and Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd. Dr Akamatsu reported receiving personal fees from Amgen Inc, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eli Lilly and Company, MSD, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, Novartis AG, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Pfizer Inc, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Janssen Global Services LLC, and Sandoz Group AG and grant funding from Amgen Inc, MSD, and Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd outside the submitted work. Dr Oki reported receiving grant funding from AbbVie Inc, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, GSK plc, MSD, Parexel International Corporation, Sanofi, AstraZeneca, FUJIFILM Toyama Chemical Co Ltd, Janssen Global Services LLC, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, and Pfizer Inc and personal fees from Amco Inc, Canon Medical Systems Corporation, FUJIFILM Toyama Chemical Co Ltd, Merit Medical Systems, Olympus Corporation, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Kaneka Medix Corp, Novartis AG, and Sanofi outside the submitted work. Dr Sato reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, MSD, Novartis AG, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Pfizer Inc, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Eli Lilly and Company, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Kyowa Kirin Co Ltd, and Boehringer Ingelheim outside the submitted work. Dr Ikeda reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly and Company, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, and Pfizer Inc and grant funding from AstraZeneca and Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd outside the submitted work. Dr Mori reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, Eli Lilly and Company, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Merck &amp; Co Inc, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited, Delta-Fly Pharma Inc, MSD, and Pfizer Inc outside the submitted work. Dr Mimura reported receiving grant funding from Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited during the conduct of the study. Dr Maeno reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly and Company, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited and grant funding from Boehringer Ingelheim and Eli Lilly and Company outside the submitted work. Dr Miura reported receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Pfizer Inc, Eli Lilly and Company, Boehringer Ingelheim, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, AstraZeneca, Novartis AG, MSD, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Amgen Inc, Merck &amp; Co Inc, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited outside the submitted work. Dr Nishimura reported being the chief executive officer and founder of Xcoo Inc and receiving research funding from Medical Data Card Inc and Systems Engineering Consultants Co Ltd outside the submitted work. Dr Kenmotsu reported receiving grant funding from Novartis AG, Eli Lilly and Company, AstraZeneca, and Loxo Oncology and personal fees from Amgen Inc, AstraZeneca, Bayer AG, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited, Eli Lilly and Company, Merck &amp; Co Inc, Novartis AG, Pfizer Inc, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited during the conduct of the study and grant funding from Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd and personal fees from Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Kyowa Kirin Co Ltd, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, and Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd outside the submitted work. Dr Fujimoto reported receiving grant funding from Sakura Finetek Japan Co Ltd outside the submitted work. Dr Yamamoto reported receiving grant funding from Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Shionogi Inc, Eli Lilly and Company, Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited, Tumura, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, Asahi Kasei Pharma Corporation, AstraZeneca, Janssen Global Services LLC, Sanofi, Amgen Inc, Novartis AG, Astellas Pharma Inc, MSD, Esai Co Ltd, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, AbbVie Inc, and Tosoh Corporation and personal fees from MSD, AstraZeneca, Amgen Inc, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Otsuka Holdings Co Ltd, Guardant Health Inc, Tumura, Kyowa Kirin Co Ltd, Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, GSK plc, Sanofi, Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eli Lilly and Company, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis AG, Pfizer Inc, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Miyarisan Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Merck &amp; Co Inc, and Janssen Global Services LLC outside the submitted work. Dr Nakagawa reported grant funding from Parexel International Corporation, PRA Health Sciences, EPS Corporation, Kissei Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, EPS International Co Ltd, Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, PPD-SNBL, SymBio Pharmaceuticals Limited, IQVIA Inc, Syneos Health, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, EP-CRSU Co Ltd, Mebix Inc, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Janssen Global Services LLC, CMIC Holdings Co Ltd, Shionogi Inc, Astellas Pharma Inc, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eisai Co Ltd, AstraZeneca, Mochida Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, LabCorp-Covance, Japan Clinical Research Operations, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, GSK plc, Sanofi, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Boehringer Ingelheim, Sysmex Corporation, Medical Research Support, Eli Lilly and Company, Amgen Inc, Novartis AG, Otsuka Holdings Co Ltd, SRL Inc, Pfizer Japan Inc, Bayer Yakuhin Ltd, Pfizer Inc, and Ascent Development Services and personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Amgen Inc, Nippon Kayaku Co Ltd, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Eli Lilly and Company, MSD, Pfizer Inc, Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co Ltd, Bayer Yakuhin Ltd, CMIC ShiftZero, Life Technologies Japan Ltd, NEO Communication, Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited, Incyte, Merck &amp; Co Inc, Kyowa Kirin Co Ltd, Takeda Pharmaceutical Company Limited, 3H Clinical Trial Inc, Care Net, Medical Review Co Ltd, Medical Mobile Communications Co Ltd, Yodosha Co Ltd, Nikkei Business Publications Inc, Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC Holdings Co Ltd, Novartis AG, Taiyo Pharma Co Ltd, Bristol Myers Squibb Company, and Janssen Global Services LLC outside the submitted work; and having a patent for Daiichi Sankyo Company Limited issued. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38100106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10724778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.47700</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2812963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Soria JC, Ohe Y, Vansteenkiste J, et al. ; FLAURA Investigators . Osimertinib in untreated EGFR-mutated advanced non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(2):113-125. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1713137</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1713137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hida T, Nokihara H, Kondo M, et al. Alectinib versus crizotinib in patients with ALK-positive non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer (J-ALEX): an open-label, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2017;390(10089):29-39. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)30565-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)30565-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28501140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw AT, Ou SH, Bang YJ, et al. Crizotinib in ROS1-rearranged non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2014;371(21):1963-1971. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1406766</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1406766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4264527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25264305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Planchard D, Smit EF, Groen HJM, et al. Dabrafenib plus trametinib in patients with previously untreated BRAF<sup>V600E</sup>-mutant metastatic non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer: an open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2017;18(10):1307-1316. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(17)30679-4

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(17)30679-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28919011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paik PK, Felip E, Veillon R, et al. Tepotinib in non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer with <i>MET</i> exon 14 skipping mutations. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(10):931-943. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2004407

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2004407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8422679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32469185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drilon A, Oxnard GR, Tan DSW, et al. Efficacy of selpercatinib in RET fusion-positive non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(9):813-824. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2005653</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2005653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7506467</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32846060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skoulidis F, Li BT, Dy GK, et al. Sotorasib for lung cancers with KRAS p.G12C mutation. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(25):2371-2381. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2103695</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2103695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9116274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34096690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lassen U. Entrectinib for ROS1 fusion-positive NSCLC and NTRK fusion-positive solid tumours. Lancet Oncol. 2020;21(2):193-194. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30789-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30789-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31838008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japan Lung Cancer Society . Lung cancer treatment guidelines&#x2014;including malignant pleural mesothelioma and thymic tumors. 2022. Accessed July 1, 2023. https://www.haigan.gr.jp/guideline/2022/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakata S, Otsubo K, Yoshida H, et al. Real-world data on NGS using the Oncomine DxTT for detecting genetic alterations in non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer: WJOG13019L. Cancer Sci. 2022;113(1):221-228. doi: 10.1111/cas.15176</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cas.15176</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8748216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34704312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association . World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191-2194. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.281053</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.281053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>A project to investigate the actual status of biomarker testing in unresectable advanced or recurrent non-small cell lung cancer (REVEAL)(WJOG15421L). UMIN Identifier: UMIN000046079. April 1, 2022. Accessed July 1, 2023. https://rctportal.niph.go.jp/en/detail?trial_id=UMIN000046079</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hess LM, Krein PM, Haldane D, Han Y, Sireci AN. Biomarker testing for patients with advanced/metastatic non-squamous NSCLC in the United States of America, 2015 to 2021. JTO Clin Res Rep. 2022;3(6):100336. doi: 10.1016/j.jtocrr.2022.100336</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2022.100336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9168140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35677681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo YH, Chiu CH, Scott Kuo CH, et al. Lung cancer in Republic of China. J Thorac Oncol. 2021;16(4):519-527. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2020.10.155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2020.10.155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33781442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajadurai P, How SH, Liam CK, Sachithanandan A, Soon SY, Tho LM. Lung cancer in Malaysia. J Thorac Oncol. 2020;15(3):317-323. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2019.10.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2019.10.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32093853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reungwetwattana T, Oranratnachai S, Puataweepong P, Tangsujaritvijit V, Cherntanomwong P. Lung cancer in Thailand. J Thorac Oncol. 2020;15(11):1714-1721. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2020.04.024</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2020.04.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33148410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsudomi T, Tan D, Yang JC, et al. Expert consensus recommendations on biomarker testing in metastatic and nonmetastatic NSCLC in Asia. J Thorac Oncol. 2023;18(4):436-446. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2022.10.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2022.10.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36379356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teishikata T, Shiraishi K, Shinno Y, et al. An alert to possible false positives with a commercial assay for <i>MET</i> exon 14 skipping. J Thorac Oncol. 2021;16(12):2133-2138. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2021.07.028

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2021.07.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34419686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viola P, Maurya M, Croud J, et al. A validation study for the use of <i>ROS1</i> immunohistochemical staining in screening for <i>ROS1</i> translocations in lung cancer. J Thorac Oncol. 2016;11(7):1029-1039. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2016.03.019

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2016.03.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27179848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong JH, Yeung SF, Chan AWH, et al. <i>MET</i> amplification and exon 14 splice site mutation define unique molecular subgroups of non&#x2013;small cell lung carcinoma with poor prognosis. Clin Cancer Res. 2016;22(12):3048-3056. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-15-2061

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-15-2061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26847053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima K, Ozawa Y, Daga H, et al. Osimertinib for patients with poor performance status and EGFR T790M mutation-positive advanced non-small cell lung cancer: a phase II clinical trial. Invest New Drugs. 2020;38(6):1854-1861. doi: 10.1007/s10637-020-00943-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10637-020-00943-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32424780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Igawa S, Fukui T, Kasajima M, et al. First-line osimertinib for poor performance status patients with EGFR mutation-positive non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer: a prospective observational study. Invest New Drugs. 2022;40(2):430-437. doi: 10.1007/s10637-021-01195-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10637-021-01195-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34807331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iwama E, Goto Y, Murakami H, et al. Alectinib for patients with ALK rearrangement-positive non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer and a poor performance status (Lung Oncology Group in Kyushu 1401). J Thorac Oncol. 2017;12(7):1161-1166. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2017.02.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2017.02.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28238961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimizu J, Masago K, Saito H, et al. Biomarker testing for personalized, first-line therapy in advanced nonsquamous non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer patients in the real world setting in Japan: a retrospective, multicenter, observational study (the BRAVE study). Ther Adv Med Oncol. 2020;12:1758835920904522. doi: 10.1177/1758835920904522</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1758835920904522</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7036489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32127924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeda M, Sakai K, Terashima M, et al. Clinical application of amplicon-based next-generation sequencing to therapeutic decision making in lung cancer. Ann Oncol. 2015;26(12):2477-2482. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdv475</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdv475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26420428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>