<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38127362</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2374-2445</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JAMA oncology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Oncol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Atezolizumab and Platinum Plus Pemetrexed With or Without Bevacizumab for Metastatic Nonsquamous Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer: A Phase 3 Randomized Clinical Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>315</StartPage><EndPage>324</EndPage><MedlinePgn>315-324</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamaoncol.2023.5258</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE">The combination of an antibody to programmed cell death-1 (PD-1) or to its ligand (PD-L1) with chemotherapy is the standard first-line treatment for metastatic non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Bevacizumab is expected to enhance the efficacy not only of chemotherapy but also of PD-1/PD-L1 antibodies through blockade of vascular endothelial growth factor-mediated immunosuppression, but further data are needed to support this.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the efficacy and safety of bevacizumab administered with platinum combination therapy and atezolizumab in patients with advanced nonsquamous NSCLC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS">An open-label phase 3 randomized clinical trial was conducted at 37 hospitals in Japan. Patients with advanced nonsquamous NSCLC without genetic driver alterations or those with genetic driver alterations who had received treatment with at least 1 approved tyrosine kinase inhibitor were enrolled between January 20, 2019, and August 12, 2020.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS">Patients were randomly assigned to receive either atezolizumab plus carboplatin with pemetrexed (APP) or atezolizumab, carboplatin plus pemetrexed, and bevacizumab (APPB). After 4 cycles of induction therapy, maintenance therapy with atezolizumab plus pemetrexed or with atezolizumab, pemetrexed, and bevacizumab was administered until evidence of disease progression, development of unacceptable toxic effects, or the elapse of 2 years from the initiation of protocol treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES">The primary end point was progression-free survival (PFS) as assessed by blinded independent central review (BICR) in the intention-to-treat (ITT) population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 412 patients were enrolled (273 men [66%]; median age, 67.0 [range, 24-89] years) and randomly assigned, with 205 in the APPB group and 206 in the APP group of the ITT population after exclusion of 1 patient for good clinical practice violation. The median BICR-assessed PFS was 9.6 months with APPB vs 7.7 months with APP (stratified hazard ratio [HR], 0.86; 95% CI, 0.70-1.07; 1-sided stratified log-rank test; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.92). According to prespecified subgroup analysis of BICR-assessed PFS, an improved PFS with APPB vs APP was apparent specifically in driver oncogene-positive patients (median, 9.7 vs 5.8 months; stratified HR, 0.67; 95% CI, 0.46-0.98). Toxic effects related to bevacizumab were increased in the APPB group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE">The findings of this trial did not show superiority of APPB over APP for patients with nonsquamous NSCLC; however, this regimen showed a similar tolerability and improved survival relative to APP in patients with driver oncogenes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">Japan Registry of Clinical Trials Identifier: jRCT2080224500.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shiraishi</LastName><ForeName>Yoshimasa</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kishimoto</LastName><ForeName>Junji</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Research and Development of Next Generation Medicine, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugawara</LastName><ForeName>Shunichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, Miyagi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mizutani</LastName><ForeName>Hideaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Saitama Cancer Center, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daga</LastName><ForeName>Haruko</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Osaka City General Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azuma</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respirology, Neurology, and Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kurume University School of Medicine, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matsumoto</LastName><ForeName>Hirotaka</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hyogo Prefectural Amagasaki General Hospital, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hataji</LastName><ForeName>Osamu</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Respiratory Center, Matsusaka Municipal Hospital, Mie, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishino</LastName><ForeName>Kazumi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Osaka International Cancer Institute, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Masahide</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Hospital Organization Osaka Toneyama Medical Center, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shukuya</LastName><ForeName>Takehito</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Juntendo University Faculty of Medicine, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Saito</LastName><ForeName>Haruhiro</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Kanagawa Cancer Center, Kanagawa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tachihara</LastName><ForeName>Motoko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respiratory Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, Kobe University Graduate School of Medicine, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsuya</LastName><ForeName>Asuka</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Izumi City General Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wakuda</LastName><ForeName>Kazushige</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Shizuoka Cancer Center, Shizuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yanagitani</LastName><ForeName>Noriko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Medical Oncology, The Cancer Institute Hospital, Japanese Foundation for Cancer Research, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakamoto</LastName><ForeName>Tomohiro</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respiratory Medicine and Rheumatology, Department of Multidisciplinary Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Tottori University, Tottori, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miura</LastName><ForeName>Satoru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Niigata Cancer Center Hospital, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hata</LastName><ForeName>Akito</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Kobe Minimally Invasive Cancer Center, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okada</LastName><ForeName>Morihito</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kozuki</LastName><ForeName>Toshiyuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Hospital Organization Shikoku Cancer Center, Ehime, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harada</LastName><ForeName>Taishi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Japan Community Health Care Organization-Kyushu Hospital, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takayama</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Science, Kyoto Prefectural University of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Third Department of Internal Medicine, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Okamoto</LastName><ForeName>Isamu</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JAMA Oncol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101652861</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2374-2437</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061067">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>52CMI0WC3Y</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C000594389">atezolizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060890">B7-H1 Antigen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>2S9ZZM9Q9V</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068258">Bevacizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>BG3F62OND5</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016190">Carboplatin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>04Q9AIZ7NO</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000068437">Pemetrexed</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>49DFR088MY</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010984">Platinum</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D061026">Programmed Cell Death 1 Receptor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D042461">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061067" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal, Humanized</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="N">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060890" MajorTopicYN="N">B7-H1 Antigen</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068258" MajorTopicYN="N">Bevacizumab</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016190" MajorTopicYN="N">Carboplatin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002289" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068437" MajorTopicYN="N">Pemetrexed</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010984" MajorTopicYN="N">Platinum</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061026" MajorTopicYN="N">Programmed Cell Death 1 Receptor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D042461" MajorTopicYN="N">Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor A</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</b> Dr Shiraishi reported receiving personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Bristol-Myers Squibb, and Chugai Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Sugawara reported receiving lecture fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, MSD, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly and Company, Novartis, Kyowa Kirin, Takeda, Nippon Kayaku, Merck, Amgen, AbbVie, Otsuka, ThermoFisher Scientific, and Towa Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Daga reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca outside the submitted work. Dr Azuma reported receiving lecture fees from AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Bristol-Myers Squibb, and Chugai Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Matsumoto reported receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca KK, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Takeda, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Ono Pharmaceutical, and Taiho Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Hataji reported receiving lecture fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; lecture fees and grants from AstraZeneca, Daiichi Sankyo, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Novartis Pharma, and Eli Lilly; lecture fees from Boehringer Ingelheim, Kyowa Kirin, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bayer Yakuhin, Merck, and Nippon Kayaku; and grants from AbbVie, Bristol-Myers Squibb, and Janssen Pharmaceutical KK outside the submitted work. Dr Nishino reported receiving grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; personal fees and grants from AstraZeneca, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly Japan, Merck Biopharma, Pfizer, Janssen Pharmaceutical, and Takeda Pharmaceutical; personal fees from Roche Diagnostics, Novartis Pharmaceuticals, Bristol-Myers Squibb, and Nippon Kayaku; and grants from Ono Pharmaceutical, Merus, Taiho Pharmaceutical, MSD, AbbVie, Daiichi Sankyo, Amgen, Eisai, and Sanofi outside the submitted work Dr Mori reported receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Shukuya reported receiving grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; grants and personal fees from AstraZeneca; grants from Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, and MSD; and personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, MSD, Taiho Pharma, Daiichi Sankyo, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Nippon Kayaku, Pfizer, Takeda, and Eli Lilly and Company outside the submitted work. Dr Saito reported receiving grants and personal fees from Chugai Pharma, AstraZeneca, Ono Pharma, and Bristol-Myers Squib; and personal fees from Boehringer Ingelheim and Pfizer Pharma outside the submitted work. Dr Tachihara reported receiving grants and personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; personal fees and grants from AstraZeneca; and personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, MSD, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Nippon, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis Pharmaceuticals, and Pfizer Japan outside the submitted work. Dr Hayashi reported receiving personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical, Merck Biopharma, Daiichi Sankyo, 3H Clinical Trial, AstraZeneca, Novartis Pharma, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly Japan, Amgen, MSD, Sysmex, Pfizer Japan, Takeda Pharmaceutical, and Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim; grants from IQVIA Services Japan, Eisai, Syneos Health Clinical, EP-CRSU, EPS, Shionogi &amp; Co, Nippon Kayaku, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Takeda Pharmaceutical, GlaxoSmithKline, MSD, Sanofi, Amgen, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb, SRL Medisearch, Janssen Pharmaceutical, PRA Health Sciences, CMIC, Astellas Pharma, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan, G.K. Ascent Development Services, Labcorp Development Japan, Eisai Inc, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical, Bayer Yakuhin, and Pfizer Japan; and personal fees from Guardant Health Japan outside the submitted work. Dr Wakuda reported receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, AstraZeneca, Daiichi Sankyo, Janssen Pharmaceutical, and Takeda Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Yanagitani reported receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; personal fees from Taiho, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Novartis, Pfizer, Eli Lilly, and Bayer AG outside the submitted work. Dr Sakamoto reported receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Merck, Taiho, Hisamitsu, Janssen, Amgen, Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca, Kyowa Kirin, Takeda, and Illumina outside the submitted work. Dr Miura reported receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Eli Lilly, Boehringer-Ingelheim Japan, Ono Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Novartis, MSD, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Daiichi Sankyo, Nippon Kayaku, Amgen, Merck, and Takeda Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Hata reported receiving grants and personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; personal fees and grants from MSD, AstraZeneca, Eli Lilly, Taiho, and Boehringer Ingelheim; personal fees from Pfizer; and grants from AbbVie outside the submitted work. Dr Kozuki reported receiving grants from Eli Lilly Japan, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Ono Pharmaceutical, MSD, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Merck Biopharma, Daiichi Sankyo, Amgen, AbbVie, Sanofi, Eisai, and Labcorp Development Japan; personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical, AstraZeneca, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer Japan, Daiichi Sankyo, Bayer, AbbVie, Eli Lilly Japan, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, MSD, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Merck Biopharma, Nippon Kayaku, Novartis, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Bayer, Sawai, and Amgen outside the submitted work. Dr Sato reported grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; personal fees from AstraZeneca Honoraria, personal fees from MSD Honoraria, personal fees from Novartis Honoraria, personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical Honoraria, personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical Honoraria, personal fees from Pfizer Honoraria, personal fees from Taiho Pharmaceutical Honoraria, personal fees from Nippon Kayaku Honoraria, personal fees from Bristol-Myers Squibb Honoraria, personal fees from Eli Lilly Honoraria, personal fees from Takeda Honoraria, and personal fees from Kyowa Kirin Honoraria outside the submitted work. Dr Takayama reported receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical and Eli Lilly Lecture fee during the conduct of the study; personal fees from AstraZeneca, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Boehringer-Ingelheim, and Amgen; and grants from Taiho Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. Dr Yamamoto reported receiving grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; grants from Boehringer-Ingelheim, Taiho, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Shionogi, Eli Lilly Japan, Daiichi Sankyo, Tumura, Nippon Kayaku, Asahikasei-pharma, AstraZeneca, Janssen, Sanofi, Amgen, Novartis, Astellas, MSD, Esai, Bristol Myers Squibb, AbbVie, and Tosoh; and personal fees from MSD, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Ono Pharmaceutical, Otsuka, Guardant Health Japan, Tumura, Kyowa-Kirin, Kyorin, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Daiichi Sankyo, Taiho, Takeda, Chugai, Eli Lilly Japan, Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer-Ingelheim, Novartis, Pfizer, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Miyarisan, Merck, and Janssen outside the submitted work. Dr Nakagawa reported receiving grants from Amgen, MSD, Ono Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis Pharma, Pfizer Japan, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly Japan, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, AstraZeneca, Parexel International, PRA Health Sciences, EPS, Kissei Pharmaceutical, Taiho Pharmaceutical, PPD-SNBL SymBio Pharmaceuticals, IQVIA Services Japan, Syneos Health Clinical, Nippon Kayaku, EP-CRSU, Mebix, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Astellas Pharma, Bayer Yakuhin, Eisai, Mochida Pharmaceutical, Labcorp Development Japan (Covance Japan), Japan Clinical Research Operations, Takeda Pharmaceutical, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Sysmex, Medical Research Support, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, SRL, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan, CMIC, Shionogi &amp; Co, Kobayashi Pharmaceutical, and Ascent Development Services; and personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical, Amgen, Nippon Kayaku, AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, MSD, Pfizer Japan, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Bayer Yakuhin, CMIC ShiftZero, Life Technologies Japan, Neo Communication, Daiichi Sankyo, Incyte Biosciences Japan, Merck Biopharma, Kyowa Kirin, Takeda Pharmaceutical, 3H Clinical Trial, Care Net, Medical Review, Medical Mobile Communications, Yodosha, Nikkei Business Publications, Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC, Novartis Pharma, Taiyo Pharma, Janssen Pharmaceutical, and Bristol-Myers Squibb outside the submitted work; in addition, Dr Nakagawa had a patent for Daiichi Sankyo issued. Dr Okamoto reported receiving grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical during the conduct of the study; grants from Taiho Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Pfizer, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, MSD, Astellas, Novartis, and AbbVie; and personal fees from AstraZeneca, AbbVie, Bristol-Myers Squibb, AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, MSD, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly, Novartis, and Chugai Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>38</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38127362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10739077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2023.5258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2813227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gandhi L, Rodr&#xed;guez-Abreu D, Gadgeel S, et al. ; KEYNOTE-189 Investigators . Pembrolizumab plus chemotherapy in metastatic non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(22):2078-2092. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1801005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1801005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Socinski MA, Jotte RM, Cappuzzo F, et al. ; IMpower150 Study Group . Atezolizumab for first-line treatment of metastatic nonsquamous NSCLC. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(24):2288-2301. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1716948</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1716948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29863955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>West H, McCleod M, Hussein M, et al. Atezolizumab in combination with carboplatin plus nab-paclitaxel chemotherapy compared with chemotherapy alone as first-line treatment for metastatic non-squamous non-small-cell lung cancer (IMpower130): a multicentre, randomised, open-label, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2019;20(7):924-937. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30167-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30167-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31122901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nishio M, Barlesi F, West H, et al. Atezolizumab plus chemotherapy for first-line treatment of nonsquamous NSCLC: results from the randomized phase 3 IMpower132 trial. J Thorac Oncol. 2021;16(4):653-664. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2020.11.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2020.11.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33333328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wang Z, Fang J, et al. Efficacy and safety of sintilimab plus pemetrexed and platinum as first-line treatment for locally advanced or metastatic nonsquamous NSCLC: a randomized, double-blind, phase 3 study (Oncology pRogram by InnovENT anti-PD-1-11). J Thorac Oncol. 2020;15(10):1636-1646. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2020.07.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2020.07.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32781263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Chen G, Huang Y, et al. ; CameL Study Group . Camrelizumab plus carboplatin and pemetrexed versus chemotherapy alone in chemotherapy-naive patients with advanced non-squamous non-small-cell lung cancer (CameL): a randomised, open-label, multicentre, phase 3 trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9(3):305-314. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30365-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(20)30365-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33347829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Wang Z, Sun Y, et al. Sugemalimab versus placebo, in combination with platinum-based chemotherapy, as first-line treatment of metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer (GEMSTONE-302): interim and final analyses of a double-blind, randomised, phase 3 clinical trial. Lancet Oncol. 2022;23(2):220-233. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(21)00650-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(21)00650-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35038432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin C, Enrico D. Current and novel therapeutic strategies for optimizing immunotherapy outcomes in advanced non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer. Front Oncol. 2022;12:962947. doi: 10.3389/fonc.2022.962947</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2022.962947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9772042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36568253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandler A, Gray R, Perry MC, et al. Paclitaxel-carboplatin alone or with bevacizumab for non-small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2006;355(24):2542-2550. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa061884</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa061884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ott PA, Hodi FS, Buchbinder EI. Inhibition of immune checkpoints and vascular endothelial growth factor as combination therapy for metastatic melanoma: an overview of rationale, preclinical evidence, and initial clinical data. Front Oncol. 2015;5:202. doi: 10.3389/fonc.2015.00202</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2015.00202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4585112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26442214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen DS, Mellman I. Oncology meets immunology: the cancer-immunity cycle. Immunity. 2013;39(1):1-10. doi: 10.1016/j.immuni.2013.07.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.immuni.2013.07.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23890059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Y, Goel S, Duda DG, Fukumura D, Jain RK. Vascular normalization as an emerging strategy to enhance cancer immunotherapy. Cancer Res. 2013;73(10):2943-2948. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-12-4354</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-12-4354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3655127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23440426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckanovich RJ, Facciabene A, Kim S, et al. Endothelin B receptor mediates the endothelial barrier to T cell homing to tumors and disables immune therapy. Nat Med. 2008;14(1):28-36. doi: 10.1038/nm1699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm1699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18157142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motz GT, Santoro SP, Wang LP, et al. Tumor endothelium FasL establishes a selective immune barrier promoting tolerance in tumors. Nat Med. 2014;20(6):607-615. doi: 10.1038/nm.3541</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.3541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4060245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24793239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rini BI, Powles T, Atkins MB, et al. ; IMmotion151 Study Group . Atezolizumab plus bevacizumab versus sunitinib in patients with previously untreated metastatic renal cell carcinoma (IMmotion151): a multicentre, open-label, phase 3, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2019;393(10189):2404-2415. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30723-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30723-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31079938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finn RS, Qin S, Ikeda M, et al. ; IMbrave150 Investigators . Atezolizumab plus bevacizumab in unresectable hepatocellular carcinoma. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(20):1894-1905. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1915745</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1915745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32402160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenhauer EA, Therasse P, Bogaerts J, et al. New response evaluation criteria in solid tumours: revised RECIST guideline (version 1.1). Eur J Cancer. 2009;45(2):228-247. doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2008.10.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejca.2008.10.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19097774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE), version 5.0. US Dept of Health and Human Services, National Institutes of Health, National Cancer Institute; November 27, 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reckamp KL, Redman MW, Dragnev KH, et al. Phase II randomized study of ramucirumab and pembrolizumab versus standard of care in advanced non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer previously treated with immunotherapy&#x2013;Lung-MAP S1800A. J Clin Oncol. 2022;40(21):2295-2306. doi: 10.1200/JCO.22.00912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.22.00912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9287284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35658002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hung MS, Chen IC, Lin PY, et al. Epidermal growth factor receptor mutation enhances expression of vascular endothelial growth factor in lung cancer. Oncol Lett. 2016;12(6):4598-4604. doi: 10.3892/ol.2016.5287</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ol.2016.5287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5228119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28101216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinmuth N, Jauch A, Xu EC, et al. Correlation of <i>EGFR</i> mutations with chromosomal alterations and expression of EGFR, ErbB3 and VEGF in tumor samples of lung adenocarcinoma patients. Lung Cancer. 2008;62(2):193-201. doi: 10.1016/j.lungcan.2008.03.011

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2008.03.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18450321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nogami N, Barlesi F, Socinski MA, et al. IMpower150 final exploratory analyses for atezolizumab plus bevacizumab and chemotherapy in key NSCLC patient subgroups with <i>EGFR</i> mutations or metastases in the liver or brain. J Thorac Oncol. 2022;17(2):309-323. doi: 10.1016/j.jtho.2021.09.014

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtho.2021.09.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34626838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reck M, Mok TSK, Nishio M, et al. ; IMpower150 Study Group . Atezolizumab plus bevacizumab and chemotherapy in non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer (IMpower150): key subgroup analyses of patients with <i>EGFR</i> mutations or baseline liver metastases in a randomised, open-label phase 3 trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2019;7(5):387-401. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30084-0

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30084-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30922878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu S, Wu L, Jian H, et al. Sintilimab plus bevacizumab biosimilar IBI305 and chemotherapy for patients with EGFR-mutated non-squamous non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer who progressed on EGFR tyrosine-kinase inhibitor therapy (ORIENT-31): first interim results from a randomised, double-blind, multicentre, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2022;23(9):1167-1179. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(22)00382-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(22)00382-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35908558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satouchi M, Nosaki K, Takahashi T, et al. First-line pembrolizumab vs chemotherapy in metastatic non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer: KEYNOTE-024 Japan subset. Cancer Sci. 2021;112(12):5000-5010. doi: 10.1111/cas.15144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cas.15144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8645705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34543477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horinouchi H, Nogami N, Saka H, et al. Pembrolizumab plus pemetrexed-platinum for metastatic nonsquamous non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer: KEYNOTE-189 Japan Study. Cancer Sci. 2021;112(8):3255-3265. doi: 10.1111/cas.14980</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cas.14980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8353942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34036692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niho S, Kunitoh H, Nokihara H, et al. ; JO19907 Study Group . Randomized phase II study of first-line carboplatin-paclitaxel with or without bevacizumab in Japanese patients with advanced non-squamous non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. Lung Cancer. 2012;76(3):362-367. doi: 10.1016/j.lungcan.2011.12.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2011.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22244743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yoshioka H, Shimokawa M, Seto T, et al. Final overall survival results of WJTOG3405, a randomized phase III trial comparing gefitinib versus cisplatin with docetaxel as the first-line treatment for patients with stage IIIB/IV or postoperative recurrent <i>EGFR</i> mutation-positive non&#x2013;small-cell lung cancer. Ann Oncol. 2019;30(12):1978-1984. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdz399

</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdz399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31553438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>