<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39012406</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8253</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurology and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurol Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Safety and Effectiveness of Satralizumab in Japanese Patients with Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum Disorder: A 6-month Interim Analysis of Post-marketing Surveillance.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1361</StartPage><EndPage>1383</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1361-1383</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40120-024-00640-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Satralizumab, an anti-interleukin-6 receptor antibody, is approved in Japan for relapse prevention in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD) and is undergoing post-marketing surveillance (PMS) of clinical use. We aimed to describe the real-world safety and effectiveness of satralizumab in Japanese patients with NMOSD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is an ongoing PMS (planned completion: February 2027). This 6-month interim analysis assessed the safety and effectiveness of satralizumab in Japanese patients with NMOSD using data collected from August 2020 to July 2021.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 570 patients who participated, 523 (91.75%) were female and the mean&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;standard deviation (SD) age was 52.4&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;14.1&#xa0;years. At baseline, NMOSD expanded disability status scale mean&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;SD was 4.19&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;2.19; 490 (85.96%) patients used glucocorticoids and 277 (48.59%) patients used immunosuppressants concomitantly. Of 570 satralizumab-treated patients, 85 (14.91%) had discontinued satralizumab treatment at 6&#xa0;months. For the overall adverse drug reactions (ADRs), 76.22 (66.07-87.48) events/100 person-years occurred in 118 (20.70%) patients, and infections occurred in 28 (4.91%) patients. Serious infections occurred in 18 (3.15%) patients, with an event rate of 9.05 (5.80-13.47) events/100 person-years. Of the 24 events of serious infections, respiratory tract infections (29.17%; 7) and urinary tract infections (25.00%; 6) were the most common serious infection events. One fatal ADR (septic shock) suspected to be related to satralizumab was reported. The mean&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;SD glucocorticoid dose reduced from 12.28&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;10.17&#xa0;mg/day at the index date to 8.11&#xa0;&#xb1;&#xa0;7.30&#xa0;mg/day at 6&#xa0;months. The Kaplan-Meier cumulative relapse-free rate (95% confidence interval) was 94.59% (92.25-96.23) at 6&#xa0;months.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this study, satralizumab was found to be safe, well tolerated, and effective in patients with NMOSD in routine clinical practice. The results are consistent with those of previous clinical trials. The safety and effectiveness of satralizumab in Japanese patients with NMOSD will be analyzed over the 6-year surveillance period.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">UMIN Clinical Trials Registry, UMIN000041047.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamura</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9048-0375</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Immunology, National Institute of Neuroscience, National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry, 4 Chome-1-1 Ogawahigashicho, Kodaira, Tokyo, 187-8551, Japan. yamamura@ncnp.go.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Isobe</LastName><ForeName>Noriko</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9525-4254</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Neurological Institute, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, 812-8582, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawachi</LastName><ForeName>Izumi</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7140-8500</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Brain Research Institute, Niigata University, Chuo-ku, Niigata, 951-8585, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Education Center, Niigata University School of Medicine, Chuo-ku, Niigata, 951-8510, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nohara</LastName><ForeName>Chiyoko</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Ebara Hospital, Tokyo Metropolitan Health and Medical Treatment Corporation, Tokyo, 145-0065, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miyazaki</LastName><ForeName>Yusei</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8235-7569</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research, National Hospital Organization Hokkaido Medical Center, Sapporo, 063-0005, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomita</LastName><ForeName>Minami</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0003-3201-305X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Safety Division, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 1-1 Nihonbashi-Muromachi 2-Chome, Nihonbashi Mitsui Tower (Reception15F), Chuo-ku, Tokyo, 103-8324, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tsumuraya</LastName><ForeName>Takahiko</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0009-7261-0346</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Drug Safety Division, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 1-1 Nihonbashi-Muromachi 2-Chome, Nihonbashi Mitsui Tower (Reception15F), Chuo-ku, Tokyo, 103-8324, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamashita</LastName><ForeName>Katsuhisa</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5761-1609</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Affairs Division, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Tokyo, 103-8324, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakahara</LastName><ForeName>Jin</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5858-0998</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Keio University School of Medicine, Tokyo, 160-8582, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakashima</LastName><ForeName>Ichiro</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2612-8948</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Neurology, Tohoku Medical and Pharmaceutical University, Sendai, 983-8512, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fujihara</LastName><ForeName>Kazuo</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3096-4156</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Multiple Sclerosis Therapeutics, Fukushima Medical University School of Medicine, Fukushima, 960-1295, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Multiple Sclerosis and Neuromyelitis Optica Center, Southern TOHOKU Research Institute for Neuroscience, Koriyama, 963-8563, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Neurol Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101637818</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2193-6536</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-IL-6 receptor antibody</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Effectiveness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glucocorticoids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Post-marketing surveillance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Relapse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Satralizumab</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Takashi Yamamura served on scientific advisory boards for Chugai Pharmaceutical, Roche, Biogen Japan, Biogen MA, Novartis Pharma, and Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma; received research grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Novartis Pharma, Biogen Japan, Chiome Bioscience, Sanofi, UCB Japan, and Mebix; and received speaker honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Biogen Japan, Novartis Pharma, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Miyarisan Pharmaceutical, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Sumitomo Pharma, and Teijin Pharma. Noriko Isobe received speaker honoraria from Biogen Japan, Novartis Pharma, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, UCB Japan, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Teijin Pharma, Argenx, and Chugai Pharmaceutical and research grants from Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Novartis Pharma, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Biogen Japan, Sumitomo Pharma, CSL Behring, Eisai, Kyowa Kirin, and Japan Blood Products Organization. Izumi Kawachi received a grant from JSPS KAKENHI (grant no. 20K07899, JP23K06923) and the MHLW Research Program on Rare and Intractable Diseases, Grant/Award (JPMH 20FC1030, JPMH 23FC1009); funding for research, travel, and/or speaker honoraria from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Novartis Pharma, Biogen, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceutical, Teijin Pharma, Argenx, and Daiichi Sankyo; and is a scientific advisory board member for Chugai Pharmaceutical. Chiyoko Nohara has no competing interests to disclose. Yusei Miyazaki received funding for travel and/or speaker honoraria from Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Biogen Japan, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Novartis Pharma, Takeda Pharmaceutical, and Teijin Pharma. Minami Tomita, Takahiko Tsumuraya and Katsuhisa Yamashita are employees of Chugai Pharmaceutical. Jin Nakahara received speaker honoraria from Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Mitsubishi Tanabe, and Roche; served as a paid consultant for Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Horizon, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, and Roche; and received research grants from Chugai Pharmaceutical, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, MEXT, and MHLW. Ichiro Nakashima serves on the scientific advisory boards for Chugai Pharmaceutical, Biogen Japan, and Novartis Pharma and receives honoraria for speaking engagements with Chugai Pharmaceutical, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, Biogen Japan, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, and Novartis Pharma. Kazuo Fujihara serves as an advisor on scientific advisory boards for Biogen, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Novartis Pharma, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Roche, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, VielaBio/Horizon Therapeutics, UCB, Merck Biopharma, Japan Tobacco, and Abbvie; has received funding for travel and speaker honoraria from Biogen, Eisai, Mitsubishi Tanabe Pharma, Novartis Pharma, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Roche, Alexion Pharmaceuticals, VielaBio, Teijin Pharma, Asahi Kasei Medical, Merck, and Takeda Pharmaceutical; and has received the Grants-in-Aid for Scientific Research from the Ministry of Education, Culture, Sports, Science and Technology of Japan and the Grants-in-Aid for Scientific Research from the Ministry of Health, Welfare and Labour of Japan.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39012406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11393251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40120-024-00640-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40120-024-00640-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Holroyd KB, Manzano GS, Levy M. Update on neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Curr Opin Ophthalmol. 2020;31:462&#x2013;8. 10.1097/ICU.0000000000000703. 10.1097/ICU.0000000000000703</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ICU.0000000000000703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7771018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33009077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wingerchuk DM, Banwell B, Bennett JL, et al. International consensus diagnostic criteria for neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders. Neurology. 2015;85:177&#x2013;89. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000001729. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000001729</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001729</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4515040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26092914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paolilo RB, da Paz JA, Apostolos-Pereira SL, de Rimkus CM, Callegaro D, Sato DK. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: a review with a focus on children and adolescents. Arq Neuro-Psiquiatr. 2023;81:201&#x2013;11. 10.1055/s-0043-1761432. 10.1055/s-0043-1761432</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-1761432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10033201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36948203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miyamoto K, Fujihara K, Kira JI, et al. Nationwide epidemiological study of neuromyelitis optica in Japan. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:667&#x2013;8. 10.1136/jnnp-2017-317321. 10.1136/jnnp-2017-317321</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2017-317321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29326292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Houzen H, Kondo K, Niino M, et al. Prevalence and clinical features of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders in northern Japan. Neurology. 2017;89:1995&#x2013;2001. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000004611. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000004611</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000004611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28986408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleiter I, Traboulsee A, Palace J, et al. Long-term efficacy of satralizumab in AQP4-IgG-seropositive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder from SAkuraSky and SAkuraStar. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2023;10: e200071. 10.1212/NXI.0000000000200071. 10.1212/NXI.0000000000200071</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/NXI.0000000000200071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9756307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36724181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waliszewska-Prosol M, Chojdak-Lukasiewicz J, Budrewicz S, Pokryszko-Dragan A. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder treatment-current and future prospects. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:2801. 10.3390/ijms22062801. 10.3390/ijms22062801</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms22062801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7998461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosso M, Saxena S, Chitnis T. Targeting IL-6 receptor in the treatment of neuromyelitis optica spectrum: a review of emerging treatment options. Expert Rev Neurother. 2020;20(5):509&#x2013;16. 10.1080/14737175.2020.1757434. 10.1080/14737175.2020.1757434</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14737175.2020.1757434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32306778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamura T, Kleiter I, Fujihara K, et al. Trial of satralizumab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. N Engl J Med. 2019;381:2114&#x2013;24. 10.1056/NEJMoa1901747. 10.1056/NEJMoa1901747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1901747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31774956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traboulsee A, Greenberg BM, Bennett JL, et al. Safety and efficacy of satralizumab monotherapy in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a randomised, double-blind, multicentre, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet Neurol. 2020;19:402&#x2013;12. 10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30078-8. 10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30078-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(20)30078-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7935419</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32333898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennett JL, Greenberg B, Weinshenker BG, et al. P324: long-term efficacy and safety of satralizumab in adults with AQP4-IgG-seropositive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD): results from the roll-over, open-label study SAkuraMoon. ACTRIMS forum 2023&#x2014;poster presentations. Multiple Scler J. 2023;29(2):18&#x2013;242. 10.1177/13524585231169437. 10.1177/13524585231169437</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13524585231169437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heo YA. Satralizumab: first approval. Drugs. 2020;80:1477&#x2013;82. 10.1007/s40265-020-01380-2. 10.1007/s40265-020-01380-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-020-01380-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7522096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32797372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pharmaceuticals and Medical Devices Agency. Various related notifications (use results evaluation). Available from https://www.pmda.go.jp/review-services/inspections/devices/0008.html#gpsp_ordinance. Accessed 30 September 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japanese Law Translation. Available from https://www.japaneselawtranslation.go.jp/en/laws/view/3213/en#je_toc. Accessed 30 September 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamura T, Weinshenker B, Yeaman MR, et al. Long-term safety of satralizumab in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder (NMOSD) from SAkuraSky and SAkuraStar. Multiple Scler Relat Disord. 2022;66: 104025. 10.1016/j.msard.2022.104025. 10.1016/j.msard.2022.104025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2022.104025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36007339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aungsumart S, Youngkong S, Dejthevaporn C, et al. Efficacy and safety of monoclonal antibody therapy in patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Front Neurol. 2023;14:1166490. 10.3389/fneur.2023.1166490. 10.3389/fneur.2023.1166490</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2023.1166490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10110910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37082442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Declemy A, Chesnel C, Charlanes A, Le Breton F, Ismael SS, Amarenco G. Specificity of lower urinary tract symptoms in neuromyelitis optica in comparison with multiple sclerosis patients. Int Neurourol J. 2018;22:185&#x2013;91. 10.5213/inj.1836050.025. 10.5213/inj.1836050.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5213/inj.1836050.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6177731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30286581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koike T, Harigai M, Inokuma S, et al. Effectiveness and safety of tocilizumab: postmarketing surveillance of 7901 patients with rheumatoid arthritis in Japan. J Rheumatol. 2014;41:15&#x2013;23. 10.3899/jrheum.130466. 10.3899/jrheum.130466</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.130466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24187110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita R, Aratake Y, Nakata K, Fujii C, Kondo T. Urosepsis risk in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder patients administered satralizumab. Intern Med. 2023;62:3317&#x2013;20. 10.2169/internalmedicine.1642-23. 10.2169/internalmedicine.1642-23</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2169/internalmedicine.1642-23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10713369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37032080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mealy MA, Boscoe A, Caro J, Levy M. Assessment of patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder using the EQ-5D. Int J MS Care. 2019;21:129&#x2013;34. 10.7224/1537-2073.2017-076. 10.7224/1537-2073.2017-076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7224/1537-2073.2017-076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6552992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31191178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rice JB, White AG, Scarpati LM, Wan G, Nelson WW. Long-term systemic corticosteroid exposure: a systematic literature review. Clin Ther. 2017;39:2216&#x2013;29. 10.1016/j.clinthera.2017.09.011. 10.1016/j.clinthera.2017.09.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2017.09.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29055500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuck AE, Minder CE, Frey FJ. Risk of infectious complications in patients taking glucocorticosteroids. Rev Infect Dis. 1989;11:954&#x2013;63. 10.1093/clinids/11.6.954. 10.1093/clinids/11.6.954</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/clinids/11.6.954</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2690289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima I, Nakahara J, Yasunaga H, et al. Real-world management of patients with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder using satralizumab: results from a Japanese claims database. Multiple Scler Relat Disord. 2024;84: 105502. 10.1016/j.msard.2024.105502. 10.1016/j.msard.2024.105502</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2024.105502</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38401202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>