<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39399795</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-3643</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JTO clinical and research reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JTO Clin Res Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Final Analysis Data and Exploratory Biomarker Analysis of a Randomized Phase 2 Study of Osimertinib Plus Bevacizumab Versus Osimertinib Monotherapy for Untreated Patients With Nonsquamous NSCLC Harboring EGFR Mutations: The WJOG9717L Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100716</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100716</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100716</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2024.100716</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors have been&#xa0;the standard treatment for patients with NSCLC who have sensitive <i>EGFR</i> mutations. This study revealed final analysis survival data, biomarkers, and resistance mechanisms of osimertinib plus bevacizumab or osimertinib monotherapy in previously untreated patients with advanced <i>EGFR</i>-positive nonsquamous NSCLC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We previously reported the primary results of&#xa0;a randomized, open-label, phase 2 study comparing osimertinib plus bevacizumab with osimertinib monotherapy for this population. In this exploratory analysis using tissue and plasma samples, we evaluated gene profiles at baseline and disease progression or the last dose using targeted deep sequencing.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The median progression-free survival (PFS) by the blinded independent central reviewer was 22.1 months for the osimertinib plus bevacizumab arm and 20.2 months for the osimertinib arm (hazard ratio [HR]&#xa0;= 0.864, 95% confidence interval [CI]: 0.549-1.359). The 3-year overall survival was not different between the two arms (osimertinib plus bevacizumab: 57.1%; osimertinib monotherapy: 65.0%; HR 1.271, 95% CI: 0.727-2.223). A total of 94 patients had assessable plasma samples at baseline, and 40 had assessable pretreatment tissue samples. <i>EGFR</i> mutations (76.6%) and <i>TP53</i> mutations (44.7%) were detected in plasma samples at baseline. In patients with plasma <i>TP53</i> mutations (n&#xa0;= 42), the median PFS by blinded independent central reviewer was 19.8 months for the osimertinib plus bevacizumab arm and 20.2 months for the osimertinib arm (HR&#xa0;= 1.107, 95% CI: 0.534-2.297).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There was also no significant difference in the PFS between the two arms, even in patients with <i>TP53</i> mutations.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kenmotsu</LastName><ForeName>Hirotsugu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Shizuoka Cancer Center, Nagaizumi-cho, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakai</LastName><ForeName>Kazuko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Keita</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Center, Shizuoka Cancer Center Nagaizumi-cho, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kato</LastName><ForeName>Terufumi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Kanagawa Cancer Center, Yokohama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sugawara</LastName><ForeName>Shunichi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pulmonary Medicine, Sendai Kousei Hospital, Miyagi, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kirita</LastName><ForeName>Keisuke</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Cancer Center Hospital East, Kashiwa, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yoneshima</LastName><ForeName>Yasuto</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kyushu University, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Azuma</LastName><ForeName>Koichi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Respirology, Neurology, and Rheumatology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kurume University School of Medicine, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishino</LastName><ForeName>Kazumi</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Osaka International Cancer Institute, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teraoka</LastName><ForeName>Shunsuke</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koyama</LastName><ForeName>Ryo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Juntendo University, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Masuda</LastName><ForeName>Ken</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Hiroshima City Hiroshima Citizens Hospital, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Faculty of Medicine, Kindai University, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Toyozawa</LastName><ForeName>Ryo</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, NHO Kyushu Cancer Center, Fukuoka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miura</LastName><ForeName>Satoru</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Niigata Cancer Center Hospital, Niigata, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sato</LastName><ForeName>Yuki</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kobe City Medical Center General Hospital, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Faculty of Medicine, Kindai University, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamamoto</LastName><ForeName>Nobuyuki</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Internal Medicine III, Wakayama Medical University, Wakayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Takahashi</LastName><ForeName>Toshiaki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Thoracic Oncology, Shizuoka Cancer Center, Nagaizumi-cho, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JTO Clin Res Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101769967</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-3643</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bevacizumab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EGFR mutation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non&#x2013;small cell lung cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osimertinib</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">TP53 mutation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Dr. Kenmotsu reports receiving grants from 10.13039/501100013170Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 10.13039/100030831Novartis Pharma K.K., Eli Lilly K.K., AstraZeneca K.K., and Loxo Oncology and personal fees from Amgen Inc., AstraZeneca K.K., Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly K.K., Kyowa Hakko Kirin Co., Ltd., Merck, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Pfizer, Taiho Pharma, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Dr. Sakai reports receiving personal fees from Hitachi, Life Technologies Japan Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Yodosha Co., Ltd. Dr. Mori reports receiving personal fees from Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., and Eli Lilly Japan K.K. Dr. Kato reports receiving grants from 10.13039/100006483AbbVie, 10.13039/100002429Amgen, 10.13039/100004325AstraZeneca, 10.13039/100017239BeiGene, BluePrint, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, Haihe, Merck KGaA, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Pfizer, Regeneron, Takeda, and TurningPoint; receiving personal fees from Amgen, AstraZeneca, BeiGene, Boehringer Ingelheim, Chugai, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly, GlaxoSmithKline, Janssen, Merck KGaA, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Ono, Pfizer, Taiho, and Takeda; and having a family member who is an employee of Eli Lilly. Dr. Sugawara reports receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly and Company, Novartis, Kyowa Kirin, Yakult Honsha, Takeda, Nippon Kayaku, Merck, Amgen, AbbVie, Otsuka, Thermo Fisher Scientific, and Towa Pharmaceutical. Dr. Kirita reports receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca K.K. Dr. Azuma reports receiving personal fees from Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol Myers Squibb, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, AstraZeneca, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, and Takeda Pharmaceutical. Dr. Nishino reports receiving grants from 10.13039/501100013170Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 10.13039/100009947Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, AbbVie, Daiichi Sankyo Company, Limited, Amgen, Eisai Co., Ltd., Sanofi K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Novartis Pharmaceuticals, Pfizer, Eli Lilly Japan, Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Chugai pharmaceutical, and Merus and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Eli Lilly Japan, Roche Diagnostics, Novartis, Pfizer, Merck, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Bristol Myers Squibb, and Nippon Kayaku. Dr. Teraoka reports being an employee (January 16, 2024&#x2013;) of AstraZeneca K.K. and receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca K.K., Boehringer Ingelheim Japan Inc., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Novartis Pharma K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., and Taiho Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Dr. Hayashi reports receiving grants from AstraZeneca K.K., Astellas Pharma Inc., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Merck Serono Co., Ltd./Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., SymBio Pharmaceuticals Ltd., AbbVie Inc., inVentiv Health Japan, ICON Japan K.K., Gritsone Oncology Inc., Parexel International Corp., Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., EPS Corporation, Syneos Health, Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., A2 Healthcare Corp., Quintiles Inc./IQVIA Services Japan K.K., EP-CRSU Co., Ltd., Linical Co., Ltd., Eisai Co., Ltd., CMIC Shift Zero K.K., Kyowa Hakko Kirin Co., Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., EPS International Co., Ltd., and Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and personal fees from Amgen K.K., AstraZeneca K.K., Boehringer Ingelheim Japan Inc., Bristol Myers Squibb Co. Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co. Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Guardant Healthcare, Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Merck Biopharma Co. Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Novartis Pharmaceuticals K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Shanghai Haihe Biopharm, Taiho Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Pfizer, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. Dr. Toyozawa reports receiving grants from AbbVie, Amgen, AnHeart Therapeutics, Daiichi Sankyo, Eli Lilly Japan, Novartis Pharma, Pfizer Japan, and Takeda Pharmaceutical and personal fees from AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Eli Lilly Japan, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis Pharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer Japan, Taiho Pharmaceutical, and Takeda Pharmaceutical. Dr. Miura reports receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca KK, Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb, Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical, Co., Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical, Co., Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme KK, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan Inc., Eli Lilly Japan KK, Novartis Pharma K.K., Pfizer, Kyowa Hakko Kirin, Daiichi Sankyo, AbbVie, Nippon Kayaku, Amgen, Merck, and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Dr. Sato reports receiving personal fees from AstraZeneca, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Chugai Pharmaceutical, Ono Pharmaceutical, Pfizer, Taiho Pharmaceutical, Nippon Kayaku, Bristol Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Takeda, and Kyowa Kirin. Dr. Nakagawa reports receiving grants from AstraZeneca K.K., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Parexel International Corp., PRA HEALTHSCIENCES, EPS Corporation, Kissei Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., EPS International Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., PPD-SNBL K.K., SymBio Pharmaceuticals Limited, IQVIA Services Japan K.K., SYNEOS HEALTH CLINICAL K.K., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., EP-CRSU Co., Ltd., Mebix, Inc., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., AbbVie Inc., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., Eisai Co., Ltd., Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Covance Japan Inc., Japan Clinical Research Operations, Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., Sanofi K.K., Sysmex Corporation, Medical Research Support, Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., SRL, Inc., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., and Amgen Inc. and personal fees from Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Kyorin Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., Amgen Inc., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., CMIC ShiftZero K.K., Life Technologies Japan, Ltd., Neo Communication, Roche Diagnostics K.K., AbbVie Inc., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., Kyowa Kirin Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., 3H Clinical Trial Inc., Care Net, Inc., Medical Review Co., Ltd., Medical Mobile Communications Co., Ltd., YODOSHA Co., Ltd., Nikkei Business Publications, Inc., Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., TAIYO Pharma Co., Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb K.K., and Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. Dr. Yamamoto reports receiving grants from Boehringer Ingelheim, Taiho, Chugai, Shionogi, Eli Lilly Japan, Daiichi Sankyo, Tumura, Nippon Kayaku, Asahikasei-pharma, AstraZeneca, Janssen, Sanofi, Amgen, Novartis, Astellas, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Esai, Bristol Myers Squibb, AbbVie, and Tosoh, and personal fees from Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Ono, Otsuka, Guardant Health Japan, Tumura, Kyowa Kirin, Kyorin, GlaxoSmithKline, Sanofi, Daiichi Sankyo, Taiho, Takeda, Chugai, Eli Lilly Japan, Nippon Kayaku, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis, Pfizer, Bristol Myers Squibb, Miyarisan, Merck, and Janssen. Dr. Nishio reports receiving grants from 10.13039/100017346Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, West Japan Oncology Group, Thoracic Oncology Research Group, North East Japan Study Group, Clinical Research Support Center Kyushu, Nichirei Biosciences Inc., Eli Lilly Japan, Hitachi, Sysmex, and Otsuka Pharmaceutical and personal fees from SymBio Pharmaceuticals, Solasia Pharma, Eli Lilly Japan, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Chugai, Pfizer, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis Pharma, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Merck Biopharma, Roche Diagnostics, Yakult Honsha, Guardant Health, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, FUJIREBIO, Bristol Myers Squibb, Merck Biopharma, Janssen Pharmaceutical, Daiichi Sankyo, and Ono Pharmaceutical. Dr. Takahashi reports receiving grants from AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Amgen Inc., Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, and Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., and personal fees from AstraZeneca KK, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Boehringer Ingelheim Japan, Inc., Roche Diagnostics K.K., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Yakult Honsha Co. Ltd. All remaining authors have declared no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>16</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39399795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11470244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtocrr.2024.100716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-3643(24)00086-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lynch T.J., Bell D.W., Sordella R., et al. Activating mutations in the epidermal growth factor receptor underlying responsiveness of non-small-cell lung cancer to gefitinib. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2004;350:2129&#x2013;2139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15118073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maemondo M., Inoue A., Kobayashi K., et al. Gefitinib or chemotherapy for non-small-cell lung cancer with mutated EGFR. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2010;362:2380&#x2013;2388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20573926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitsudomi T., Morita S., Yatabe Y., et al. Gefitinib versus cisplatin plus docetaxel in patients with non-small-cell lung cancer harbouring mutations of the epidermal growth factor receptor (WJTOG3405): an open label, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2010;11:121&#x2013;128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20022809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosell R., Carcereny E., Gervais R., et al. Erlotinib versus standard chemotherapy as first-line treatment for European patients with advanced EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer (EURTAC): a multicentre, open-label, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2012;13:239&#x2013;246.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22285168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C., Wu Y.L., Chen G., et al. Erlotinib versus chemotherapy as first-line treatment for patients with advanced EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer (OPTIMAL, CTONG-0802): a multicentre, open-label, randomised, phase 3 study. Lancet Oncol. 2011;12:735&#x2013;742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21783417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sequist L.V., Yang J.C., Yamamoto N., et al. Phase III study of afatinib or cisplatin plus pemetrexed in patients with metastatic lung adenocarcinoma with EGFR mutations. J&#xa0;Clin Oncol. 2013;31:3327&#x2013;3334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23816960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y.L., Zhou C., Hu C.P., et al. Afatinib versus cisplatin plus gemcitabine for first-line treatment of Asian patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer harbouring EGFR mutations (LUX-Lung 6): an open-label, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2014;15:213&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24439929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soria J.C., Ramalingam S.S. Osimertinib in EGFR mutation-positive advanced NSCLC. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2018;378:1262&#x2013;1263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29590540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wildiers H., Guetens G., De Boeck G., et al. Effect of antivascular endothelial growth factor treatment on the intratumoral uptake of CPT-11. Br J Cancer. 2003;88:1979&#x2013;1986.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2741115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12799646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickson P.V., Hamner J.B., Sims T.L., et al. Bevacizumab-induced transient remodeling of the vasculature in neuroblastoma xenografts results in improved delivery and efficacy of systemically administered chemotherapy. Clin Cancer Res. 2007;13:3942&#x2013;3950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17606728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain R.K. A&#xa0;new target for tumor therapy. N&#xa0;Engl J Med. 2009;360:2669&#x2013;2671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4792114</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19535806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le X., Nilsson M., Goldman J., et al. Dual EGFR-VEGF pathway inhibition: a promising strategy for patients with EGFR-mutant NSCLC. J&#xa0;Thorac Oncol. 2021;16:205&#x2013;215.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33096270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seto T., Kato T., Nishio M., et al. Erlotinib alone or with bevacizumab as first-line therapy in patients with advanced non-squamous non-small-cell lung cancer harbouring EGFR mutations (JO25567): an open-label, randomised, multicentre, phase 2 study. Lancet Oncol. 2014;15:1236&#x2013;1244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25175099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto N., Seto T., Nishio M., et al. Erlotinib plus bevacizumab vs erlotinib monotherapy as first-line treatment for advanced EGFR mutation-positive non-squamous non-small-cell lung cancer: survival follow-up results of the randomized JO25567 study. Lung Cancer. 2021;151:20&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33279874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saito H., Fukuhara T., Furuya N., et al. Erlotinib plus bevacizumab versus erlotinib alone in patients with EGFR-positive advanced non-squamous non-small-cell lung cancer (NEJ026): interim analysis of an open-label, randomised, multicentre, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2019;20:625&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30975627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawashima Y., Fukuhara T., Saito H., et al. Bevacizumab plus erlotinib versus erlotinib alone in Japanese patients with advanced, metastatic, EGFR-mutant non-small-cell lung cancer (NEJ026): overall survival analysis of an open-label, randomised, multicentre, phase 3 trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2022;10:72&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenmotsu H., Wakuda K., Mori K., et al. Randomized phase 2 study of osimertinib plus bevacizumab versus osimertinib for untreated patients with nonsquamous NSCLC harboring EGFR mutations: WJOG9717L study. J&#xa0;Thorac Oncol. 2022;17:1098&#x2013;1108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35636696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun S., Schiller J.H., Gazdar A.F. Lung cancer in never smokers--a different disease. Nat Rev Cancer. 2007;7:778&#x2013;790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17882278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akamatsu H., Toi Y., Hayashi H., et al. Efficacy of osimertinib plus bevacizumab vs osimertinib in patients with EGFR T790M-mutated non-small cell lung cancer previously treated with epidermal growth factor receptor-tyrosine kinase inhibitor: West Japan Oncology Group 8715L phase 2 randomized clinical trial. JAMA Oncol. 2021;7:386&#x2013;394.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7791398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33410885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soo R.A., Han J.Y., Dafni U., et al. A&#xa0;randomised phase II study of osimertinib and bevacizumab versus osimertinib alone as second-line targeted treatment in advanced NSCLC with confirmed EGFR and acquired T790M mutations: the European Thoracic Oncology Platform (ETOP 10&#x2013;16) BOOSTER trial. Ann Oncol. 2022;33:181&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34839016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu H.A., Schoenfeld A.J., Makhnin A., et al. Effect of osimertinib and bevacizumab on progression-free survival for patients with metastatic EGFR-mutant lung cancers: a phase 1/2 single-group open-label trial. JAMA Oncol. 2020;6:1048&#x2013;1054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7256866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32463456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa K., Garon E.B., Seto T., et al. Ramucirumab plus erlotinib in patients with untreated, EGFR-mutated, advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (RELAY): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2019;20:1655&#x2013;1669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31591063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piccirillo M.C., Bonanno L., Garassino M.C.C., et al. 12070 bevacizumab&#xa0;+ erlotinib vs erlotinib alone as first-line treatment of pts with EGFR mutated advanced non squamous NSCLC: final analysis of the multicenter, randomized, phase III Beverly trial. Ann Oncol. 2021;32:S950.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dafni U., Soo R.A., Peters S., et al. Impact of smoking status on the relative efficacy of the EGFR TKI/angiogenesis inhibitor combination therapy in advanced NSCLC-a systematic review and meta-analysis. ESMO Open. 2022;7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9271510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35696746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibbons D.L., Byers L.A., Kurie J.M. Smoking, p53 mutation, and lung cancer. Mol Cancer Res. 2014;12:3&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3925633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24442106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakagawa K., Nadal E., Garon E.B., et al. RELAY subgroup analyses by EGFR Ex19del and Ex21L858R mutations for ramucirumab plus erlotinib in metastatic non-small cell lung cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2021;27:5258&#x2013;5271.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9662911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34301751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramalingam S., Cheng Y.J., Zhou C., et al. Mechanisms of acquired resistance to first-line osimertinib: preliminary data from the phase III FLAURA study. Ann Oncol. 2018;29(suppl 8)</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>