<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40865373</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-8332</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>207</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Lung cancer (Amsterdam, Netherlands)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lung Cancer</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of B7-H3 and DLL3 expression on the efficacy of PD-L1 blockade therapy in extensive-stage small cell lung cancer.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>108723</StartPage><MedlinePgn>108723</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lungcan.2025.108723</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0169-5002(25)00615-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">B7-H3 and delta-like ligand 3 (DLL3) are novel therapeutic targets in extensive-stage small cell lung cancer (ES-SCLC). We aimed to assess the impact of B7-H3 and DLL3 expression on the tumor immune microenvironment (TME) and on the therapeutic efficacy of programmed cell death-ligand 1 (PD-L1) blockade for ES-SCLC.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 146 ES-SCLC patients who received platinum-based chemotherapy either with (Chemo&#xa0;+&#xa0;ICI cohort) or without (Chemo cohort) an immune checkpoint inhibitor was analyzed. Progression-free survival (PFS) and overall survival (OS) were evaluated in each cohort according to B7-H3 or DLL3 expression status as detected by immunohistochemistry. The relation of B7-H3 or DLL3 expression to characteristics of the TME was assessed by immune-related gene expression profiling (irGEP).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In the Chemo&#xa0;+&#xa0;ICI cohort, patients with high B7-H3 expression showed a shorter PFS (median of 4.3 vs. 5.4&#xa0;months; HR of 2.11 with a 95&#xa0;%&#x2009;Cl of 1.08-4.10; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.03) and OS (median of 8.4 vs. 14.2&#xa0;months; HR of 1.83 with a 95&#xa0;%&#x2009;CI of 0.91-3.69; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.09) than those with low B7-H3 expression. In the Chemo cohort, there was no apparent difference in survival outcomes between the high and low B7-H3 expression groups. The irGEP analysis revealed that the effector function of CD8<sup>+</sup> T cells was impaired in tumors with high B7-H3 expression. No clear association was apparent between therapeutic efficacy and DLL3 expression status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">High B7-H3 expression may serve as a resistance mechanism for PD-L1 antibody therapy by promoting T cell dysfunction in ES-SCLC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kurosaki</LastName><ForeName>Takashi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kanemura</LastName><ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan. Electronic address: hiroaki.kanemura@med.kindai.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Otani</LastName><ForeName>Tomoyuki</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawanaka</LastName><ForeName>Yusuke</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan; Department of Medical Oncology, Kishiwada City Hospital, Kishiwada, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukuda</LastName><ForeName>Yasushi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kurashiki Central Hospital, Kurashiki, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kudo</LastName><ForeName>Keita</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, National Hospital Organization Osaka Minami Medical Center, Kawachinagano, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tanizaki</LastName><ForeName>Junko</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan; Department of Medical Oncology, Kishiwada City Hospital, Kishiwada, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Suzuki</LastName><ForeName>Shinichiro</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan; Department of Medical Oncology, Kishiwada City Hospital, Kishiwada, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tomida</LastName><ForeName>Shuta</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Comprehensive Genomic Medicine, Okayama University Hospital, Okayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sakai</LastName><ForeName>Kazuko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiba</LastName><ForeName>Yasutaka</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Research Center, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ito</LastName><ForeName>Akihiko</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nishio</LastName><ForeName>Kazuto</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Genome Biology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nakagawa</LastName><ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan; Cancer Center, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hayashi</LastName><ForeName>Hidetoshi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Kindai University Faculty of Medicine, Osaka-Sayama, Japan; Kindai Hospital Global Research Alliance Center. KHGRAC, Kindai University Hospital, Osaka-Sayama, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Ireland</Country><MedlineTA>Lung Cancer</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8800805</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0169-5002</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C496666">DLL3 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060887">B7 Antigens</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D008565">Membrane Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C423237">CD276 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D047908">Intracellular Signaling Peptides and Proteins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D060890">B7-H1 Antigen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000082082">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C423236">CD274 protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D014408">Biomarkers, Tumor</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008175" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060887" MajorTopicYN="Y">B7 Antigens</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055752" MajorTopicYN="Y">Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000401" MajorTopicYN="N">mortality</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008565" MajorTopicYN="Y">Membrane Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059016" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Microenvironment</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D047908" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intracellular Signaling Peptides and Proteins</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060890" MajorTopicYN="Y">B7-H1 Antigen</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000037" MajorTopicYN="N">antagonists &amp; inhibitors</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000082082" MajorTopicYN="Y">Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009367" MajorTopicYN="N">Neoplasm Staging</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014408" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers, Tumor</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">B7-H3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Delta-like ligand 3</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Small cell lung cancer</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Hiroaki Kanemura reports financial support was provided by Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. Takashi Kurosaki reports financial support was provided by The Osaka Medical Research Foundation for Intractable Diseases. Hidetoshi Hayashi reports financial support was provided by the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science. Hiroaki Kanemura reports a relationship with Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. that includes: funding grants. Hirosaki Kanemura reports a relationship with Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., and Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. that includes: speaking and lecture fees. Yasushi Fukuda reports a relationship with Novartis Pharma, and Parexel International Inc. that includes: funding grants. Yasushi Fukuda reports a relationship with AstraZeneca, Chugai Pharma, MSD, Merck Biopharma, Ono Pharmaceutical, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli Lilly, Boehringer Ingelheim, Novartis Pharma, and Takeda Pharmaceutical that includes: speaking and lecture fees. Junko Tanizaki reports a relationship with AstraZeneca K.K., AbbVie GK, Boehringer-Ingelheim Japan Inc., Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. Ltd., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Daiichi sankyo Co. Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K, MSD K.K, Nihon Medi-Physics Co. Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co. Ltd., Ono pharmaceutical Co. Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co. Ltd. K., and Takeda Pharmaceuticals that includes: speaking and lecture fees. Junko Tanizaki reports a relationship with AstraZeneca K.K., AbbVie GK, and Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. that includes: consultation or advisory fees. Shinichiro Suzuki reports a relationship with Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim that includes: funding grants. Shuta Tomida reports a relationship with Illumina, Inc that includes: speaking and lecture fees. Kazuko Sakai reports a relationship with Qiagen, Inc., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Nippon Kayaku Co.,Ltd., and Life Technologies Japan Ltd that includes: speaking and lecture fees. Kazuto Nishio reports a relationship with Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim, West Japan Oncology Group, Nichirei Biosciences Inc., Eli Lilly Japan, Hitachi, Sysmex, Otsuka Pharmaceutical, Thoracic Oncology, Research Group, Okayama University, and Japan Breast Cancer Research Group that includes: funding grants. Kazuto Nishio reports a relationship with SymBio Pharmaceuticals, ELI LILLY JAPAN, and Otsuka Pharmaceutical that includes: consultation or advisory fees. Kazuto Nishio reports a relationship with Chugai, ELI LILLY JAPAN., MSD, Novartis Pharma, AstraZeneca, Guardant Health, Janssen Pharmaceutical, DAIICHI SANKYO, Ono Pharmaceutical, Invitae Japan, Nichirei, and Maruho that includes speaking and lecture fees. Kazuhiko Nakagawa reports a relationship with IQVIA Services JAPAN K.K., SYNEOS HEALTH CLINICAL K.K., EPS Corporation., Nippon Kayaku Co.,Ltd., EPS International Co.,Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., MSD K.K., Ono Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., Amgen Inc., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., EP-CRSU Co., Ltd., Mebix, Inc., Bristol-Myers Squibb K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., Kobayashi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc, Astellas Pharma Inc., Eisai Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Labcorp Development Japan K.K. (Covance Japan Inc.), Japan Clinical Research Operations, Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., Sanofi K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co.,Ltd., SRL, Inc., Medical Reserch Support, Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Novartis Pharma K.K., CMIC CO., Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd, Shionogi &amp; Co., Ltd., PRA Health Sciences Inc., and Ascent Development Services that includes: funding grants. Kazuhiko Nakagawa reports a relationship with Eli Lilly Japan K.K., and Ono Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd. that includes: consultation or advisory fees. Kazuhiko Nakagawa reports a relationship with Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Amgen Inc., Nippon Kayaku Co., Ltd., and AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., MSD K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co., Ltd., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Incyte biosciences Japan, M3, Inc., Global Health Consulting Japan Co., Ltd., The Yomiuri Shimbun, Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., TAIYO Pharma Co., Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Life Technologies Japan Ltd., Neo Communication, Novartis Pharma K.K., Medical Mobile Communications co., Ltd, YODOSHA CO., LTD., CMIC ShiftZero K.K., Japan Clinical Research Operations, CMIC Co., Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., Otuka Pharmaceutical Factory, Inc., and Hisamitsu Pharmaceuticsl Co., Ltd. that includes: speaking and lecture fees. Hidetoshi Hayashi reports a relationship with IQVIA Services JAPAN K.K., SYNEOS HEALTH CLINICAL K.K., EPS Corporation., Nippon Kayaku Co.,Ltd., Takeda Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., MSD K.K., Amgen Inc., Taiho Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K., CMIC CO., Ltd., Pfizer R&amp;D Japan G.K., Labcorp Development Japan K.K., Kobayashi Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., Pfizer Japan Inc., AbbVie Inc., A2 Healthcare Corp., Eisai Co., Ltd., EP-CRSU CO., LTD., Shionogi &amp; Co., Ltd., Otsuka Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., GlaxoSmithKline K.K., Sanofi K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co.,Ltd., SRL Medisearch Inc., PRA Health Sciences Inc., Astellas Pharma Inc., Ascent Development Services, Eisai Inc., Bayer Yakuhin, Ltd, AstraZeneca K.K., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., Novartis Pharma K.K., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., Medpace Japan K.K., Japanese Gastric Cancer Association, Clinical Research Support Center Kyushu, Japan Clinical Cancer Research Organization, EPS International Co.,Ltd., Ono Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., Covance Japan Inc., Medical Reserch Support, Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd, Kyowa Kirin Co.,Ltd., Thoracic Oncology Research Group, West Japan Oncology Group, Comprehensive Support Project for Oncological Research of Breast Cancer, Mebix, Inc., Mochida Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd., and Japan Clinical Research Operations that includes: funding grants. Hidetoshi Hayashi reports a relationship with Ono Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., Chugai Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., Eli Lilly Japan K.K., MSD K.K., Pfizer Japan Inc., Nippon Boehringer Ingelheim Co.,Ltd., Guardant Health Japan Corp., Merck Biopharma Co., Ltd., 3H Clinical Trial Inc., Novartis Pharma K.K., Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Amgen Inc., Sysmex Corporation, Takeda Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd.,and Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K.; participation on a data safety monitoring board or advisory board for Bristol Myers Squibb Company, Chugai Pharmaceutical Co.,Ltd., AstraZeneca K.K., Janssen Pharmaceutical K.K, AbbVie Inc., Novocure K.K., and Daiichi Sankyo Co., Ltd. that includes: speaking and lecture fees. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>8</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40865373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lungcan.2025.108723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0169-5002(25)00615-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>