<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35522949</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-751X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiopulmonary rehabilitation and prevention</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevalence, Impact, and Trajectories of Sleep Disturbance in Cardiac Rehabilitation: A NARRATIVE REVIEW AND SUGGESTIONS FOR EVALUATION AND TREATMENT.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>316</StartPage><EndPage>323</EndPage><MedlinePgn>316-323</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000694</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this review was to summarize literature examining the prevalence, impact, and trajectories of sleep disturbance in cardiac rehabilitation (CR) patients and discuss how CR programs may incorporate targeted evaluation and interventions to promote sleep health.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="REVIEW METHODS">A narrative review of literature allowed for an examination of the prevalence of sleep disturbance in CR patients, the effects of sleep disturbance on CR outcomes, and trajectories of sleep disturbance in CR.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SUMMARY">Sleep disturbance is prevalent in CR patient populations and is related to clinical and functional outcomes. Sleep may be an important biobehavioral process to target in CR to improve important patient outcomes and achieve secondary prevention goals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tighe</LastName><ForeName>Caitlan A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0592-4213</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>VISN 4 Mental Illness Research, Education and Clinical Center (Dr Tighe) and Geriatric Research Education and Clinical Center (Drs Weiner and Forman), VA Pittsburgh Healthcare System, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Departments of Psychiatry (Drs Buysse and Weiner), Medicine (Drs Weiner and Forman), and Anesthesiology (Dr Weiner) and Clinical and Translational Science Institute (Dr Weiner) University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; VA Center for Integrated Healthcare, Washington, District of Columbia (Dr Beehler); and Community Health and Health Behavior, School of Public Health and Health Professions, University of Buffalo, Buffalo, New York (Dr Beehler).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buysse</LastName><ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName><Initials>DJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiner</LastName><ForeName>Debra K</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beehler</LastName><ForeName>Gregory P</ForeName><Initials>GP</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forman</LastName><ForeName>Daniel E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 AG024827</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>P50 DA046346</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG058883</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG060499</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>IK2 RX003393</GrantID><Acronym>RX</Acronym><Agency>RRD VA</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 AG047139</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013486">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, Non-P.H.S.</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013487">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Cardiopulm Rehabil Prev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101291247</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-7501</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000072038" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiac Rehabilitation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015995" MajorTopicYN="N">Prevalence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055502" MajorTopicYN="N">Secondary Prevention</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012890" MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012893" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sleep Wake Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of Interest:</b> Drs. Tighe, Beehler, Weiner, and Forman have no conflicts to report. Over the past 3 years, Dr. Buysse has served as a paid consultant to National Cancer Institute, Pear Therapeutics (which markets the Somryst&#xae; sleep app), Sleep Number, Idorsia, and Weight Watchers International. Dr. Buysse is an author of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index, Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index Addendum for PTSD (PSQI-A), Brief Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (B-PSQI), Daytime Insomnia Symptoms Scale, Pittsburgh Sleep Diary, Insomnia Symptom Questionnaire, and RU_SATED (copyrights held by University of Pittsburgh). These instruments have been licensed to commercial entities for fees. He is also co-author of the Consensus Sleep Diary (copyright held by Ryerson University), which is licensed to commercial entities for a fee.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1772819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9437109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/HCR.0000000000000694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01273116-202209000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Antman EM et al. ACC/AHA Guidelines for the Management of Patients With ST-Elevation Myocardial Infarction&#x2014;Executive Summary: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines (Writing Committee to Revise the 1999 Guidelines for the Management of Patients With Acute Myocardial Infarction). J. Am. Coll. Cardiol 2004;44:671&#x2013;719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15358045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braunwald E et al. ACC/AHA 2002 guideline update for the management of patients with unstable angina and non-ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction--summary article: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association task force on practice guidelines (Committee on the Management of Patients With Unstable Angina). J. Am. Coll. Cardiol 2002;40:1366&#x2013;1374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12383588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Committee Members et al. ACC/AHA 2002 Guideline Update for the Management of Patients With Chronic Stable Angina&#x2014;Summary Article: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines (Committee on the Management of Patients With Chronic Stable Angina). Circulation 2003;107:149&#x2013;158 (2003).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12515758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WRITING COMMITTEE MEMBERS et al. ACC/AHA 2005 Guideline Update for the Diagnosis and Management of Chronic Heart Failure in the Adult&#x2014;Summary Article: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines (Writing Committee to Update the 2001 Guidelines for the Evaluation and Management of Heart Failure): Developed in Collaboration With the American College of Chest Physicians and the International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation: Endorsed by the Heart Rhythm Society. Circulation 2005;112:1825&#x2013;1852.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16160202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balady GJ et al. Core Components of Cardiac Rehabilitation/Secondary Prevention Programs: 2007 Update: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association Exercise, Cardiac Rehabilitation, and Prevention Committee, the Council on Clinical Cardiology; the Councils on Cardiovascular Nursing, Epidemiology and Prevention, and Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Metabolism; and the American Association of Cardiovascular and Pulmonary Rehabilitation. J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 2007;27:121&#x2013;129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17558191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redeker NS, Ruggiero J &amp; Hedges C Patterns and predictors of sleep pattern disturbance after cardiac surgery. Res. Nurs. Health 2004;27:217&#x2013;224 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15264261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander M et al. The National Veteran Sleep Disorder Study: Descriptive Epidemiology and Secular Trends, 2000&#x2013;2010. Sleep 2016;39:1399&#x2013;1410 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4909622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27091538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J-Y, Zhang Y-H &amp; Qin L-Q Obstructive sleep apnea and cardiovascular risk: Meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies. Atherosclerosis 2013;229:489&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23684511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Redeker NS Sleep in Acute Care Settings: An Integrative Review. J. Nurs. Scholarsh 2000;32:31&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10819736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liao W-C, Huang C-Y, Huang T-Y &amp; Hwang S-L A Systematic Review of Sleep Patterns and Factors That Disturb Sleep After Heart Surgery. J. Nurs. Res 19, 275&#x2013;288 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ Sleep health: can we define it? Does it matter? Sleep 37, 9&#x2013;17 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3902880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24470692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hirshkowitz M et al. National Sleep Foundation&#x2019;s sleep time duration recommendations: methodology and results summary. Sleep Health 1, 40&#x2013;43 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29073412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krittanawong C et al. Association between short and long sleep durations and cardiovascular outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur. Heart J. Acute Cardiovasc. Care 8, 762&#x2013;770 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29206050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiawei Yin et al. Relationship of Sleep Duration With All-Cause Mortality and Cardiovascular Events: A Systematic Review and Dose-Response Meta-Analysis of Prospective Cohort Studies. J. Am. Heart Assoc 6, e005947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5634263</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28889101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan L, Xu W, Cai Y, Hu Y &amp; Wu C Sleep Duration and the Risk of Dementia: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis of Prospective Cohort Studies. J. Am. Med. Dir. Assoc 20, 1480&#x2013;1487.e5 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31604673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline C Sleep Quality. in Encyclopedia of Behavioral Medicine (eds. Gellman MD &amp; Turner JR) 1811&#x2013;1813 (Springer, 2013).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwok Chun Shing et al. Self-Reported Sleep Duration and Quality and Cardiovascular Disease and Mortality: A Dose-Response Meta-Analysis. J. Am. Heart Assoc 7, e008552 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6201443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30371228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Classification of Sleep Disorders. (American Academy of Sleep Medicine, 2014).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drager Luciano F, McEvoy R. Doug, Barbe Ferran, Lorenzi-Filho Geraldo, &amp; Redline Susan. Sleep Apnea and Cardiovascular Disease. Circulation 136, 1840&#x2013;1850 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5689452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29109195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil SP et al. Treatment of Adult Obstructive Sleep Apnea with Positive Airway Pressure: An American Academy of Sleep Medicine Clinical Practice Guideline. J. Clin. Sleep Med. JCSM Off. Publ. Am. Acad. Sleep Med 15, 335&#x2013;343 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6374094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30736887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu J et al. Association of Positive Airway Pressure With Cardiovascular Events and Death in Adults With Sleep Apnea: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. JAMA 318, 156&#x2013;166 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5541330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28697252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao YY et al. Effect of Continuous Positive Airway Pressure Treatment on Health-Related Quality of Life and Sleepiness in High Cardiovascular Risk Individuals With Sleep Apnea: Best Apnea Interventions for Research (BestAIR) Trial. Sleep 40, (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28419387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis EF et al. Impact of continuous positive airway pressure and oxygen on health status in patients with coronary heart disease, cardiovascular risk factors, and obstructive sleep apnea: A Heart Biomarker Evaluation in Apnea Treatment (HEARTBEAT) analysis. Am. Heart J 189, 59&#x2013;67 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5788025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28625382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofi F et al. Insomnia and risk of cardiovascular disease: a meta-analysis. Eur. J. Prev. Cardiol 21, 57&#x2013;64 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22942213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ge L et al. Insomnia and risk of mortality from all-cause, cardiovascular disease, and cancer: Systematic review and meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies. Sleep Med. Rev 48, 101215 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31630016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javaheri S &amp; Redline S Insomnia and Risk of Cardiovascular Disease. Chest 152, 435&#x2013;444 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5577359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyle SD, Morgan K &amp; Espie CA Insomnia and health-related quality of life. Sleep Med. Rev 14, 69&#x2013;82 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19962922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardle-Pinkston S, Slavish DC &amp; Taylor DJ Insomnia and cognitive performance: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med. Rev 48, 101205 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31522135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hertenstein E et al. Insomnia as a predictor of mental disorders: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med. Rev 43, 96&#x2013;105 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30537570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benz F et al. The efficacy of cognitive and behavior therapies for insomnia on daytime symptoms: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Clin. Psychol. Rev 80, 101873 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32777632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juskiene A, Podlipskyte A, Bunevicius A &amp; Varoneckas G Type D Personality and Sleep Quality in Coronary Artery Disease Patients With and Without Obstructive Sleep Apnea: Mediating Effects of Anxiety and Depression. Int. J. Behav. Med 25, 171&#x2013;182 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29327226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banack HR et al. The association between sleep disturbance, depressive symptoms, and health-related quality of life among cardiac rehabilitation participants. J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 34, 188&#x2013;194 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24681969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risom SS, Fevejle Cromhout P, Overgaard D, Hastrup Svendsen J &amp; Kikkenborg Berg S Effect of Rehabilitation on Sleep Quality After Ablation for Atrial Fibrillation: Data From a Randomized Trial. J. Cardiovasc. Nurs 33, 261&#x2013;268 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5908260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29271795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurose S et al. Association of locomotive activity with sleep latency and cognitive function of elderly patients with cardiovascular disease in the maintenance phase of cardiac rehabilitation. J. Cardiol 73, 530&#x2013;535 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30611685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horsley KJ et al. Insomnia symptoms and heart rate recovery among patients in cardiac rehabilitation. J. Behav. Med 39, 642&#x2013;651 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26944765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouleau CR et al. The Association Between Insomnia Symptoms and Mood Changes During Exercise Among Patients Enrolled in Cardiac Rehabilitation. J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 35, 409&#x2013;416 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26378493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouleau CR, Toivonen K, Aggarwal S, Arena R &amp; Campbell TS The association between insomnia symptoms and cardiovascular risk factors in patients who complete outpatient cardiac rehabilitation. Sleep Med. 32, 201&#x2013;207 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28366335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Da Costa D et al. Prevalence and Determinants of Insomnia After a Myocardial Infarction. Psychosomatics 58, 132&#x2013;140 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28104338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S &amp; Parker AT Prevalence of obstructive sleep apnea in a patient population undergoing cardiac rehabilitation. J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 31, 188&#x2013;192 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21240006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sert-Kuniyoshi FH et al. Screening for obstructive sleep apnea in early outpatient cardiac rehabilitation: feasibility and results. Sleep Med. 12, 924&#x2013;927 (2011).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21978725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung Y-Y, Loo G, Gay GMW, Tay H-Y &amp; Lee C-H Screening questionnaires for sleep-disordered breathing and six-minute walk test in patients attending cardiac rehabilitation. Int. J. Cardiol 207, 20&#x2013;22 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26784566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skobel E et al. Risk factors for, and prevalence of, sleep apnoea in cardiac rehabilitation facilities in Germany: The Reha-Sleep registry. Eur. J. Prev. Cardiol 22, 820&#x2013;830 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24879359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hupin D et al. Obstructive Sleep Apnea in Cardiac Rehabilitation Patients. J. Clin. Sleep Med. JCSM Off. Publ. Am. Acad. Sleep Med 14, 1119&#x2013;1126 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6040801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29991415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox H et al. Prevalence of Sleep-Disordered Breathing and Patient Characteristics in a Coronary Artery Disease Cohort Undergoing Cardiovascular Rehabilitation: J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 36, 421&#x2013;429 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27490427</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hargens TA, Aron A, Newsome LJ, Austin JL &amp; Shafer BM Effects of obstructive sleep apnea on hemodynamic parameters in patients entering cardiac rehabilitation. J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 35, 181&#x2013;185 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25622219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marzolini S, Sarin M, Reitav J, Mendelson M &amp; Oh P Utility of Screening for Obstructive Sleep Apnea in Cardiac Rehabilitation. J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 36, 413&#x2013;420 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27182760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Loo G et al. Sleep-disordered Breathing in Cardiac Rehabilitation: Prevalence, Predictors, and Influence on the Six-Minute Walk Test. Heart Lung Circ. 25, 584&#x2013;591 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26809462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto U et al. Six-Month Aerobic Exercise Training Ameliorates Central Sleep Apnea in Patients With Chronic Heart Failure. J. Card. Fail 13, 825&#x2013;829 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18068615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Javaheri S et al. Sleep Apnea. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol 69, 841&#x2013;858 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393905</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28209226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hupin D et al. Obstructive Sleep Apnea in Cardiac Rehabilitation Patients. J. Clin. Sleep Med 14, 1119&#x2013;1126 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6040801</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29991415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelson M et al. Long-term effects of cardiac rehabilitation on sleep apnea severity in patients with coronary artery disease. J. Clin. Sleep Med. JCSM Off. Publ. Am. Acad. Sleep Med 16, 65&#x2013;71 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31957654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendelson M et al. Effects of exercise training on sleep apnoea in patients with coronary artery disease: a randomised trial. Eur. Respir. J 48, 142&#x2013;150 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27076578</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueno LM et al. Effects of exercise training in patients with chronic heart failure and sleep apnea. Sleep 32, 637&#x2013;647 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2675899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19480231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kline CE The Bidirectional Relationship Between Exercise and Sleep: Implications for Exercise Adherence and Sleep Improvement. Am. J. Lifestyle Med 8, 375&#x2013;379 (2014).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4341978</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25729341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St-Onge M-P et al. Sleep Duration and Quality: Impact on Lifestyle Behaviors and Cardiometabolic Health: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association. Circulation 134, (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5567876</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27647451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith MT &amp; Haythornthwaite JA How do sleep disturbance and chronic pain inter-relate? Insights from the longitudinal and cognitive-behavioral clinical trials literature. Sleep Med Rev 8, 119&#x2013;32 (2004).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15033151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healthy People
2030.  | health.gov.
https://health.gov/healthypeople.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramar K et al. Sleep is essential to health: an American Academy of Sleep Medicine position statement. J. Clin. Sleep Med 17, 2115&#x2013;2119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8494094</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34170250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakral M, Von Korff M, McCurry SM, Morin CM &amp; Vitiello MV ISI-3: evaluation of a brief screening tool for insomnia. Sleep Med. 82, 104&#x2013;109 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8141095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33910159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraepelien M et al. A very brief self-report scale for measuring insomnia severity using two items from the Insomnia Severity Index - development and validation in a clinical population. Sleep Med. 81, 365&#x2013;374 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33813233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder E, Cai B, DeMuro C, Morrison MF &amp; Ball W A New Single-Item Sleep Quality Scale: Results of Psychometric Evaluation in Patients With Chronic Primary Insomnia and Depression. J. Clin. Sleep Med 14, 1849&#x2013;1857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6223557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30373688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Grande MR et al. Screening for obstructive sleep apnoea in cardiac rehabilitation: A position statement from the Australian Centre for Heart Health and the Australian Cardiovascular Health and Rehabilitation Association. Eur. J. Prev. Cardiol 23, 1466&#x2013;1475 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27271098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EHRA Scientific Committee Task Force &amp; ESC Scientific Document Group. European Heart Rhythm Association (EHRA)/European Association of Cardiovascular Prevention and Rehabilitation (EACPR) position paper on how to prevent atrial fibrillation endorsed by the Heart Rhythm Society (HRS) and Asia Pacific Heart Rhythm Society (APHRS). EP Eur. 19, 190&#x2013;225 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6279109</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28175283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeghiazarians Y et al. Obstructive Sleep Apnea and Cardiovascular Disease: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association. Circulation (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34148375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ades PA &amp; Savage PD The Treatment of Obesity in Cardiac Rehabilitation: A Review And Practical Recommendations. J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 41, 295&#x2013;301 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8522194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34461619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alessi C et al. Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Insomnia in Older Veterans Using Nonclinician Sleep Coaches: Randomized Controlled Trial. J. Am. Geriatr. Soc 64, 1830&#x2013;1838 (2016).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5351772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27550552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luik AI, Kyle SD &amp; Espie CA Digital Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (dCBT) for Insomnia: a State-of-the-Science Review. Curr. Sleep Med. Rep 3, 48&#x2013;56 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5427093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28553574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson NF, Rosen IM &amp; Chervin RD The Past Is Prologue: The Future of Sleep Medicine. J. Clin. Sleep Med 13, 127&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5181604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27998380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carden KA Sleep is essential: A new strategic plan for the American Academy of Sleep Medicine. J. Clin. Sleep Med 16, 1&#x2013;2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7052992</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31957637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarmiento KF et al. National Expansion of Sleep Telemedicine for Veterans: The TeleSleep Program. J. Clin. Sleep Med. JCSM Off. Publ. Am. Acad. Sleep Med 15, 1355&#x2013;1364 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6760390</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31538607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas RJ et al. Home-Based Cardiac Rehabilitation: A Scientific Statement From The American Association Of Cardiovascular And Pulmonary Rehabilitation, The American Heart Association, And The American College Of Cardiology. J. Cardiopulm. Rehabil. Prev 39, 208&#x2013;225 (2019).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7530797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31082934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutte-Rodin S, Broch L, Buysse D, Dorsey C &amp; Sateia M Clinical Guideline for the Evaluation and Management of Chronic Insomnia in Adults. J. Clin. Sleep Med 04, 487&#x2013;504 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2576317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18853708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adult Obstructive Sleep Apnea Task Force of the American Academy of Sleep Medicine. Clinical Guideline for the Evaluation, Management and Long-term Care of Obstructive Sleep Apnea in Adults. J. Clin. Sleep Med 05, 263&#x2013;276 (2009).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2699173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19960649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgenthaler TI et al. Practice Parameters for the Treatment of Narcolepsy and other Hypersomnias of Central Origin. 30, 16 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2276123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18246980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong JC, Dawson SC, Mundt JM &amp; Moore C Developing a cognitive behavioral therapy for hypersomnia using telehealth: a feasibility study. J. Clin. Sleep Med. JCSM Off. Publ. Am. Acad. Sleep Med 16, 2047&#x2013;2062 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7848927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32804069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgenthaler TI et al. Practice Parameters for the Clinical Evaluation and Treatment of Circadian Rhythm Sleep Disorders. Sleep 30, 1445&#x2013;1459 (2007).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2082098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18041479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auger RR et al. Clinical Practice Guideline for the Treatment of Intrinsic Circadian Rhythm Sleep-Wake Disorders: Advanced Sleep-Wake Phase Disorder (ASWPD), Delayed Sleep-Wake Phase Disorder (DSWPD), Non-24-Hour Sleep-Wake Rhythm Disorder (N24SWD), and Irregular Sleep-Wake Rhythm Disorder (ISWRD). An Update for 2015: An American Academy of Sleep Medicine Clinical Practice Guideline. J. Clin. Sleep Med 11, 1199&#x2013;1236 (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4582061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26414986</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgenthaler TI et al. Position Paper for the Treatment of Nightmare Disorder in Adults: An American Academy of Sleep Medicine Position Paper. J. Clin. Sleep Med 14, 1041&#x2013;1055 (2018).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5991964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29852917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standards of Practice Committee et al. Best Practice Guide for the Treatment of REM Sleep Behavior Disorder (RBD). J. Clin. Sleep Med 06, 85&#x2013;95 (2010).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2823283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20191945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aurora RN et al. The Treatment of Restless Legs Syndrome and Periodic Limb Movement Disorder in Adults&#x2014;An Update for 2012: Practice Parameters with an Evidence-Based Systematic Review and Meta-Analyses. SLEEP (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3397810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22851800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>