<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39319356</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-0640</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effect of a prescription digital therapeutic for chronic insomnia on post-treatment insomnia severity, depression, and anxiety symptoms: results from the real-world DREAM study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1450615</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1450615</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1450615</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpsyt.2024.1450615</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Chronic insomnia is a substantial public health burden that often presents with co-occurring depression and anxiety. Randomized clinical trials and preliminary real-world evidence have shown that digitally delivered cognitive-behavioral therapy for insomnia (dCBT-I) is associated with improvements in insomnia, but real-world evidence is needed to determine the true impact of digital CBT-I. This pragmatic study aimed to evaluate the benefits of treating chronic insomnia with a tailored prescription digital therapeutic in a real-world population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This prospective, single-arm clinical study involved adults aged 22-75 with chronic insomnia living in the US who had access to a mobile device. Participants accessed the FDA-cleared prescription digital therapeutic (PDT; Somryst<sup>&#xae;</sup>) over a 9-week intervention period. The PDT delivers cognitive-behavioral therapy for insomnia via six interactive treatment cores and daily sleep diaries used for tailoring treatment. Participants completed validated patient-reported instruments at baseline, before completing treatment cores, immediately post-intervention, and at 6-month and 1-year follow-ups. The Insomnia Severity Index [ISI], the 8-item Patient Health Questionnaire [PHQ-8], and the Generalized Anxiety Disorder-7 scale [GAD-7] were used to determine the effect of the PDT on insomnia, depression, and anxiety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">After screening, 1565 adults accessed the PDT. 58% of those who began the program completed Core 4, established as exposure to all mechanisms of action in the digital therapeutic. For those who completed assessments for all 6 cores (48.4%), the ISI was lowered from 18.8 to a mean of 9.9 (P &lt;.001). These scores continued to be lower than baseline at immediate post (11.0), 6-month (11.6), and 1-year follow-ups (12.2) (P &lt;.001). The results of the PHQ-8 and GAD-7 also show significant decreases at all measured timepoints from baseline (P &lt;.001). Of the patients that began the program, 908 (58.0%) were considered adherent and 733 (46.8%) completed all 6 cores.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Data from the DREAM study contributes to the growing body of clinical evidence of how patients are utilizing a PDT in the real world, outside of controlled settings, offering insights for clinicians who use these therapeutics in practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ClinicalTrials.gov, identifier NCT04325464.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Thorndike, Morin, Ojile, Edington, Gerwien, Ong, Wickwire, Ritterband and Riney.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thorndike</LastName><ForeName>Frances P</ForeName><Initials>FP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nox Health, Alpharetta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morin</LastName><ForeName>Charles M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Psychology and CERVO/BRAIN Research Center, Laval University, Quebec, QC, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ojile</LastName><ForeName>Joseph</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clayton Sleep Institute, St. Louis, MO, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edington</LastName><ForeName>Samantha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nox Health, Alpharetta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gerwien</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Statistical Consulting, Newington, CT, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ong</LastName><ForeName>Jason C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nox Health, Alpharetta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wickwire</LastName><ForeName>Emerson M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary, Critical Care, and Sleep Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, University of Maryland School of Medicine, Baltimore, MD, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ritterband</LastName><ForeName>Lee M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Behavioral Health &amp; Technology, Department of Psychiatry and Neurobehavioral Sciences, University of Virginia School of Medicine, Charlottesville, VA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Riney</LastName><ForeName>Heidi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nox Health, Alpharetta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04325464</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101545006</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1664-0640</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CBT-I</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insomnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescription digital therapeutic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">real-world data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sleep</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Authors FT, SE, JCO, and HR were employed by the company Nox Health. Authors CM, JO, BG, EW, and LR were consultants of Nox Health. Author JO was employed by the company Clayton Sleep Institute. FT was a former faculty member at the University of Virginia and reports having equity ownership in BeHealth Solutions, LLC, who originally licensed the Sleep Health Using the Internet (SHUTi) program from the University of Virigina. Somryst, a commercial Prescription Digital Therapeutic for insomnia, was nd Venture Group. LR reports having equity ownership in BeHealth Solutions, LLC, who originally licensed the Sleep Healthy Using the Internet (SHUTi) program from the University of Virginia. Somryst, a commercial Prescription Digital Therapeutic for insomnia, was developed based on the SHUTi program by Pear Therapeutics who subsequently sold their license to Nox Health. Nox Health has a royalty agreement with BeHealth Solutions, LLC and the UVA Licensing and Venture Group. The terms of this arrangement have been reviewed and approved by the University of Virginia in accord with its conflict of interest policy. CM has served on advisory boards for Haleon and Idorsia, has received research support from Eisai, Idorsia, and Lallemand Health, and owns equity in BeHealth Solutions. EMW&#x2019;s institution has received research funding from the AASM Foundation, Department of Defense, Merck, NIH/NIA, ResMed, the ResMed Foundation, and the Sleep Research Society Foundation. Author EMW has served as a scientific consultant to Axsome Therapeutics, DayZz, Eisai, EnsoData, Idorsia, Merck, Primasun, Purdue, and ResMed and is an equity shareholder in WellTap. The authors declare that this study received funding from Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc. The funder had the following involvement in the study: study design and collection of the data. The authors declare that this study also received funding from Nox Health, Inc. The funder had the following involvement in the study: analysis, interpretation of data, the writing of this article, and the decision to submit it for publication.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39319356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11420038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2024.1450615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bhaskar S, Hemavathy D, Prasad S. Prevalence of chronic insomnia in adult patients and its correlation with medical comorbidities. J Family Med Prim Care. (2016) 5:780&#x2013;4. doi:&#xa0; 10.4103/2249-4863.201153</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2249-4863.201153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5353813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28348990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin CM, Jarrin DC. Epidemiology of insomnia: prevalence, course, risk factors, and public health burden. Sleep Med Clin. (2022) 17:173&#x2013;91. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.jsmc.2022.03.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsmc.2022.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35659072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grandner M, Olivieri A, Ahuja A, Busser A, Freidank M, McCall W. The burden of untreated insomnia disorder in a sample of 1 million adults: a cohort study. BMC Public Health. (2023) 23:1481. doi:&#xa0; 10.1186/s12889-023-16329-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-023-16329-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10399052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37537544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Hafner M, Romanelli RJ, Yerushalmi E, Troxel WM. The societal and economic burden of insomnia in adults: An international study. Santa Monica, CA: RAND Corporation;  (2023). Available at: https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_reports/RRA2166-1.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daley M, Morin CM, LeBlanc M, Gregoire JP, Savard J. The economic burden of insomnia: direct and indirect costs for individuals with insomnia syndrome, insomnia symptoms, and good sleepers. Sleep. (2009) 32:55&#x2013;64. doi:&#xa0; 10.5665/sleep/32.1.55</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5665/sleep/32.1.55</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2625324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19189779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>An American Academy of Sleep Medicine Report . Practice parameters for the psychological and behavioral treatment of insomnia: an update. Sleep. (2006) 29:1415&#x2013;9. doi:&#xa0; 10.1093/sleep/29.11.1415</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/29.11.1415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17162987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sateia MJ, Buysse DJ, Krystal AD, Neubauer DN, Heald JL. Clinical practice guideline for the pharmacologic treatment of chronic insomnia in adults: An American Academy of sleep medicine clinical practice guideline. J Clin Sleep Med. (2017) 13:307&#x2013;49. doi:&#xa0; 10.5664/jcsm.6470</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5664/jcsm.6470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5263087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27998379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qaseem A, Kansagara D, Forciea MA, Cooke M, Denberg TD. Management of chronic insomnia disorder in adults: a clinical practice guideline from the American College of Physicians. Ann Intern Med. (2016) 165:125&#x2013;33. doi:&#xa0; 10.7326/M15-2175</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M15-2175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27136449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salisbury-Afshar E. Management of insomnia disorder in adults. Am Fam Physician. (2018) 98:319&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30216028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutte-Rodin S, Broch L, Buysse D, Dorsey C, Sateia M. Clinical guideline for the evaluation and management of chronic insomnia in adults. J Clin Sleep Med. (2008) 4:487&#x2013;504. doi:&#xa0; 10.5664/jcsm.27286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5664/jcsm.27286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2576317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18853708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riemann D, Espie CA, Altena E, Arnardottir ES, Baglioni C, Bassetti CL, et al. The European Insomnia Guideline: An update on the diagnosis and treatment of insomnia 2023. J sleep Res. (2023) 32:e14035. doi:&#xa0; 10.1111/jsr.14035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jsr.14035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38016484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edinger JD, Arnedt JT, Bertisch SM, Carney CE, Harrington JJ, Lichstein KL, et al. Behavioral and psychological treatments for chronic insomnia disorder in adults: an American Academy of Sleep Medicine clinical practice guideline. J Clin Sleep Med. (2021) 17:255&#x2013;62. doi:&#xa0; 10.5664/jcsm.8986</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5664/jcsm.8986</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33164742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin CM, Espie CA. Insomnia: A clinical guide to assessment and treatment. New York, NY, US: Kluwer Academic/Plenum Publishers; (2003).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edinger JD, Means MK. Cognitive-behavioral therapy for primary insomnia. Clin Psychol Rev. (2005) 25:539&#x2013;58. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.cpr.2005.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2005.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15951083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigeon WR. Treatment of adult insomnia with cognitive-behavioral therapy. J&#xa0;Clin Psychol. (2010) 66:1148&#x2013;60. doi:&#xa0; 10.1002/jclp.20737</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.20737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4294319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20853442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas A, Grandner M, Nowakowski S, Nesom G, Corbitt C, Perlis ML. Where are the behavioral sleep medicine providers and where are they needed? a geographic assessment. Behav Sleep Med. (2016) 14:687&#x2013;98. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/15402002.2016.1173551</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15402002.2016.1173551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5070478</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27159249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zachariae R, Lyby MS, Ritterband LM, O'Toole MS. Efficacy of internet-delivered cognitive-behavioral therapy for insomnia - a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Sleep Med Rev. (2015) 30:1&#x2013;10. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.smrv.2015.10.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2015.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26615572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyffert M, Lagisetty P, Landgraf J, Chopra V, Pfeiffer PN, Conte ML, et al. Internet-delivered cognitive behavioral therapy to treat insomnia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. (2016) 11:e0149139. doi:&#xa0; 10.1371/journal.pone.0149139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0149139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4750912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26867139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alimoradi Z, Jafari E, Brostr&#xf6;m A, Ohayon MM, Lin CY, Griffiths MD, et al. Effects of cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia (CBT-I) on quality of life: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev. (2022) 64:101646. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.smrv.2022.101646</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2022.101646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35653951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasan F, Tu YK, Yang CM, Gordon CJ, Wu D, Lee HC, et al. Comparative efficacy of digital cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Sleep Med Rev. (2022) 61:101567. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.smrv.2021.101567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.smrv.2021.101567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34902820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon L, Steinmetz L, Feige B, Benz F, Spiegelhalder K, Baumeister H. Comparative efficacy of onsite, digital, and other settings for cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Sci Rep. (2023) 13:1929. doi:&#xa0; 10.1038/s41598-023-28853-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-28853-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9894949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36732610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritterband LM, Thorndike FP, Ingersoll KS, Lord HR, Gonder-Frederick L, Frederick C, et al. Effect of a web-based cognitive behavior therapy for insomnia intervention with 1-year follow-up: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry. (2016) 74:68&#x2013;75. doi:&#xa0; 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2016.3249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2016.3249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27902836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen H, Batterham PJ, Gosling JA, Ritterband LM, Griffiths KM, Thorndike FP, et al. Effectiveness of an online insomnia program (SHUTi) for prevention of depressive episodes (the GoodNight Study): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Psychiatry. (2016) 3:333&#x2013;41. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00536-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(15)00536-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin CM. Profile of somryst prescription digital therapeutic for chronic insomnia: overview of safety and efficacy. Expert Rev Med Devices. (2020) 17:1239&#x2013;48. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/17434440.2020.1852929</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17434440.2020.1852929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33226269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorndike FP, Berry RB, Gerwien R, Braun S, Maricich YA. Protocol for Digital Real-world Evidence trial for Adults with insomnia treated via Mobile (DREAM): an open-label trial of a prescription digital therapeutic for treating patients with chronic insomnia. J Comp Eff Res. (2021) 10:569&#x2013;81. doi:&#xa0; 10.2217/cer-2021-0004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2217/cer-2021-0004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33682430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin CM, Belleville G, Belanger L, Ivers H. The Insomnia Severity Index: psychometric indicators to detect insomnia cases and evaluate treatment response. Sleep. (2011) 34:601&#x2013;8. doi:&#xa0; 10.1093/sleep/34.5.601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/34.5.601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3079939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21532953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien CH, Vallieres A, Morin CM. Validation of the Insomnia Severity Index as an outcome measure for insomnia research. Sleep Med. (2011) 2:297&#x2013;307. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/S1389-9457(00)00065-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1389-9457(00)00065-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11438246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Strine TW, Spitzer RL, Williams JBW, Berry JT, Mokdad AH. The PHQ-8 as a measure of current depression in the general population. J Aff Dis. (2009) 114:163&#x2013;73. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.jad.2008.06.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2008.06.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18752852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JBW, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. (2006) 166:1092&#x2013;7. doi:&#xa0; 10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorndike FP, Gerwien R, Edington S, Ong J, Riney H, Ritterband L, et al. Comparing adherence for a prescription digital therapeutic for insomnia across controlled and real-world settings. Sleep. (2024) 47:A191. doi: 10.1093/sleep/zsae067.0445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/sleep/zsae067.0445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebert EA, Vincent N, Lewycky S, Walsh K. Attrition and adherence in the online treatment of chronic insomnia. Behav Sleep Med. (2010) 8:141e150. doi:&#xa0; 10.1080/15402002.2010.487457</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15402002.2010.487457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20582757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yeung W, Chung K, Ho FY, Ho L. Predictors of dropout from internet-based self-help cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia. Behav Res Ther. (2015) 73:19&#x2013;24. doi:&#xa0; 10.1016/j.brat.2015.07.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2015.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26226091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>