<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41493714</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-7558</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of behavioral medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Behav Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>"Better Sleep Means I'm Better Able to Provide Care": Caregivers' Perceived Impacts of an Internet-Delivered Insomnia Intervention.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12529-025-10425-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Family caregivers frequently experience sleep challenges that impact their own health and ability to provide care for a care recipient (i.e., the person a caregiver supports). Cognitive-behavioral therapy for insomnia (CBT-I) effectively treats insomnia, but there is limited evidence regarding caregivers' perceived impacts of this intervention. The current study evaluated caregivers' experiences using Sleep Healthy Using The Internet (SHUTi), an Internet-delivered CBT-I intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">The sample comprised caregivers with insomnia who supported care recipients requiring medium- or high-intensity care for any condition, including Alzheimer's disease/dementia (21%), cancer (11%), or a mobility problem (11%). Participating caregivers who used SHUTi (n&#x2009;=&#x2009;82; age M&#x2009;=&#x2009;53.20, 85% female, 59% lived with the care recipient) provided open-ended feedback about their experience. Responses were analyzed using a rapid content analysis approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Responses revealed that caregivers perceived benefits of SHUTi to their functioning and their understanding of sleep. Caregivers described how the intervention improved their overall daytime abilities, mood, and caregiving capacity. They also shared how the intervention helped them prioritize sleep and self-care, gave them insight into their sleep, and increased their knowledge of healthy sleep.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Caregivers reported wide-ranging benefits from CBT-I beyond improved sleep. Despite the untailored nature of this intervention, several caregivers described positive impacts on their caregiving capabilities and outlook, resulting from the program helping them to improve their sleep and self-care more broadly. These results suggest that framing caregiver-focused health interventions as important to both caregivers and care recipients may increase caregivers' uptake of such resources.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perepezko</LastName><ForeName>Kate</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Miami University, Oxford, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gallagher</LastName><ForeName>Virginia</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Virginia, Charlottesville, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glazer</LastName><ForeName>Jillian</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Virginia, Charlottesville, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Donovan</LastName><ForeName>Heidi</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Virginia, Charlottesville, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mattos</LastName><ForeName>Meghan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Virginia, Charlottesville, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klinger</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buysse</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ritterband</LastName><ForeName>Lee</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Virginia, Charlottesville, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaffer</LastName><ForeName>Kelly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Virginia, Charlottesville, United States. kms8nr@uvahealth.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>HSR210255</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Behav Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9421097</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1070-5503</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Care partner</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caregivers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive-behavioral therapy for insomnia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Internet intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleep initiation and maintenance disorders</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing Interests: KP, VG, JG, HD, MM, JK, and KS have no conflicts to report. Over the past 3&#xa0;years, DB has served as a paid or unpaid consultant to Sleep Number, Idorsia, and Eisai. All consulting agreements have been for a total of less than $5000 per year from any single entity. Consulting has focused on insomnia, behavioral sleep treatments, and the measurement of sleep characteristics. DB is an author of the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index, Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index Addendum for PTSD (PSQI-A), Brief Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (B-PSQI), Daytime Insomnia Symptoms Scale, Pittsburgh Sleep Diary, Insomnia Symptom Questionnaire, and RU_SATED (copyrights held by the University of Pittsburgh). These instruments have been licensed to commercial entities for fees. He is also co-author of the Consensus Sleep Diary (copyright held by Ryerson University), which is licensed to commercial entities for a fee. LR reports having equity ownership in BeHealth Solutions, LLC, the company that was originally established to make available digital health products, including Sleep Healthy Using the Internet (SHUTi), now licensed by Nox Health. LR is a paid consultant of Nox Health, which owns the IP of Somryst, a commercial PDT for insomnia based on the SHUTi program. These companies had no role in the preparation of this manuscript. The terms of these arrangements have been reviewed and approved by the University of Virginia in accordance with its policies.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41493714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12529-025-10425-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12529-025-10425-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>AARP and National Alliance for Caregiving (2025) Caregiving in the US 2025. 24 July. Washington, DC: AARP Public Policy Institute. Available at: https://www.aarp.org/pri/topics/ltss/family-caregiving/caregiving-in-the-us-2025/ (accessed 19 September 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Academy of Sleep (2005) International classification of sleep disorders: diagnostic and coding manual. 2nd ed. Westchester, IL.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association (2013) Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders. 5th ed. Washington, DC.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ankuda CK, Maust DT, Kabeto MU, et al. Association between spousal caregiver well-being and care recipient healthcare expenditures. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2017;65(10):2220&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28836269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5762126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averill JB. Matrix analysis as a complementary analytic strategy in qualitative inquiry. Qual Health Res. 2002;12(6):855&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12109729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baglioni C, Battagliese G, Feige B, et al. Insomnia as a predictor of depression: a meta-analytic evaluation of longitudinal epidemiological studies. J Affect Disord. 2011;135(1&#x2013;3):10&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21300408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnhart WR, Ellsworth DW, Robinson AC, et al. Caregiving in the shadows: national analysis of health outcomes and intensity and duration of care among those who care for people with mental illness and for people with developmental disabilities. Disabil Health J. 2020;13(1):100837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31506219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien CH, Valli&#xe8;res A, Morin CM. Validation of the Insomnia Severity Index as an outcome measure for insomnia research. Sleep Med. 2001;2(4):297&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11438246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie L, Kyle SD, Espie CA, et al. Social interactions, emotion and sleep: a systematic review and research agenda. Sleep Med Rev. 2015;24:83&#x2013;100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25697832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birt L, Scott S, Cavers D, et al. Member checking: a tool to enhance trustworthiness or merely a nod to validation? Qual Health Res. 2016;26(13):1802&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27340178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breslau N, Roth T, Rosenthal L, et al. Sleep disturbance and psychiatric disorders: a longitudinal epidemiological study of young adults. Biol Psychiatry. 1996;39(6):411&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8679786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brewster GS, Wang D, McPhillips MV, et al. Correlates of sleep disturbance experienced by informal caregivers of persons living with dementia: a systematic review. Clin Gerontol. 2024;47(3):380&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36314643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buysse DJ, Angst J, Gamma A, et al. Prevalence, course, and comorbidity of insomnia and depression in young adults. Sleep. 2008;31(4):473&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18457234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2279748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byun E, Lerdal A, Gay CL, et al. How adult caregiving impacts sleep: a systematic review. Curr Sleep Med Rep. 2016;2(4):191&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31080704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6508862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carney S, Koetters T, Cho M, et al. Differences in sleep disturbance parameters between oncology outpatients and their family caregivers. J Clin Oncol. 2011;29(8):1001&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3068050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro CM, Lee KA, Bliwise DL, et al. Sleep patterns and sleep-related factors between caregiving and non-caregiving women. Behav Sleep Med. 2009;7(3):164&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19568966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charmes J. The unpaid care work and the labour market: an analysis of time use data based on the latest world compilation of time-use surveys. Geneva: ILO; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu Y-C, Lee Y-N, Wang P-C, et al. Family caregivers&#x2019; sleep disturbance and its associations with multilevel stressors when caring for patients with dementia. Aging Ment Health. 2014;18(1):92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24053456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen H, Batterham PJ, Gosling JA, et al. Effectiveness of an online insomnia program (SHUTi) for prevention of depressive episodes (the GoodNight Study): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Psychiatry. 2016;3(4):333&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dale J, Nanton V, Day T, et al. Uptake and use of care companion, a web-based information resource for supporting informal carers of older people: mixed methods study. JMIR Aging. 2023;6:e41185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37733406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10556998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniel LC, Schwartz LA, Mindell JA, et al. Initial validation of the sleep disturbances in pediatric cancer model. J Pediatr Psychol. 2016;41(6):588&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26994058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6281138</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Day A, Haj-Bakri S, Lubchansky S, et al. Sleep, anxiety and fatigue in family members of patients admitted to the intensive care unit: a questionnaire study. Crit Care. 2013;17(3):R91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23705988</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3706908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>del-Pino-Casado R, Priego-Cubero E, L&#xf3;pez-Mart&#xed;nez C, et al. Subjective caregiver burden and anxiety in informal caregivers: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLOS ONE Ottoboni G (ed.) 2021;16(3):e0247143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edinger JD, Arnedt JT, Bertisch SM, et al. Behavioral and psychological treatments for chronic insomnia disorder in adults: an American Academy of Sleep Medicine systematic review, meta-analysis, and GRADE assessment. J Clin Sleep Med. 2021;17(2):263&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33164741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7853211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Espie CA, Emsley R, Kyle SD. Effect of digital cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia on health, psychological well-being, and sleep-related quality of life: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiat. 2019;76(1):21&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Puerta L, Prados G, Jim&#xe9;nez-Mej&#xed;as E. Interventions that improve sleep in caregivers of adult care-recipients: a systematic review. West J Nurs Res. 2022;44(2):180&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33686882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franzen PL, Gianaros PJ, Marsland AL, et al. Cardiovascular reactivity to acute psychological stress following sleep deprivation. Psychosom Med. 2011;73(8):679&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21949422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3614084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fredman L, Gordon SA, Heeren T, et al. Positive affect is associated with fewer sleep problems in older caregivers but not noncaregivers. Gerontologist. 2014;54(4):559&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23676301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao C, Chapagain NY, Scullin MK. Sleep duration and sleep quality in caregivers of patients with dementia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open. 2019;2(8):e199891.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31441938</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6714015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garnett A, Northwood M, Ting J, et al. mHealth interventions to support caregivers of older adults: equity-focused systematic review. JMIR Aging. 2022;5(3):e33085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35616514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9308083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghosh S, Choi W, Williams A, et al. Burden on caregivers of adults with multiple chronic conditions: intersectionality of age, gender, education level, employment status, and impact on social life. Can J Aging Rev Can Vieissement. 2020;39(3):456&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibson RH, Gander PH, Jones LM. Understanding the sleep problems of people with dementia and their family caregivers. Dementia. 2014;13(3):350&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24339061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AM, Chen S. The role of sleep in interpersonal conflict: do sleepless nights mean worse fights? Soc Psychol Personal Sci. 2014;5(2):168&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AM, Mendes WB, Prather AA. The social side of sleep: elucidating the links between sleep and social processes. Curr Dir Psychol Sci. 2017;26(5):470&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29398789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5791747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AM, Carrillo B, Barnes CM. Sleep and social relationships in healthy populations: a systematic review. Sleep Med Rev. 2021;57:101428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33596514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton AB (2013) Qualitative methods in rapid turn-around health services research.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansen D, Sheehan DK, Stephenson P. Family caregiver recruitment via social media: challenges, opportunities and lessons. Int J Palliat Nurs. 2017;23(2):84&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28245165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaussent I, Dauvilliers Y, Ancelin M-L, et al. Insomnia symptoms in older adults: associated factors and gender differences. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2011;19(1):88&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20808113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3179987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keeton VF, Trask J, Whitney R, et al. Overburdened and underprepared: medical/nursing task performance among informal caregivers in the United States. J Gerontol Nurs. 2020;46(9):25&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32845344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keuppens L, Marten F, Baeyens D, et al. A pilot study of a cognitive-behavioral sleep intervention specifically for adolescents with ADHD and sleep problems: a qualitative and quantitative evaluation. Cogn Behav Pract. 2024;31(3):367&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klionsky D, Abdelmohsen K, Abe A, et al. Guidelines for the use and interpretation of assays for monitoring autophagy (3rd edition). Autophagy. 2016;12(1):1&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26799652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4835977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koerner SS, Kenyon DB, Shirai Y. Caregiving for elder relatives: which caregivers experience personal benefits/gains? Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2009;48(2):238&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18336932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyle SD, Espie CA, Morgan K. &#x201c;&#x2026; not just a minor thing, it is something major, which stops you from functioning daily&#x201d;: quality of life and daytime functioning in insomnia. Behav Sleep Med. 2010;8(3):123&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20582756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyle SD, Morgan K, Spiegelhalder K, et al. No pain, no gain: an exploratory within-subjects mixed-methods evaluation of the patient experience of sleep restriction therapy (SRT) for insomnia. Sleep Med. 2011;12(8):735&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21907616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LeBlanc M, Beaulieu-Bonneau S, M&#xe9;rette C, et al. Psychological and health-related quality of life factors associated with insomnia in a population-based sample. J Psychosom Res. 2007;63(2):157&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17662752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CT, Gonsalves CL, Gao-Kang J, et al. Resource utilization among informal caregiver of lung cancer patients undergoing treatment. Patient Exp J. 2022;9(1):103&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee D, Morgan K, Lindesay J. Effect of institutional respite care on the sleep of people with dementia and their primary caregivers. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2007;55(2):252&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17302663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leggett AN, Meyer OL, Bugajski BC, et al. Accentuate the positive: the association between informal and formal supports and caregiving gains. J Appl Gerontol. 2021;40(7):763&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32326797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu Z, Heffernan C, Tan J. Caregiver burden: a concept analysis. Int J Nurs Sci. 2020;7(4):438&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33195757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7644552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maltby KF, Sanderson CR, Lobb EA, et al. Sleep disturbances in caregivers of patients with advanced cancer: a systematic review. Palliat Support Care. 2017;15(1):125&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28095943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meltzer LJ, Moore M. Sleep disruptions in parents of children and adolescents with chronic illnesses: prevalence, causes, and consequences. J Pediatr Psychol. 2007;33(3):279&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18084038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mollica MA, Smith AW, Kent EE. Caregiving tasks and unmet supportive care needs of family caregivers: a U.S. population-based study. Patient Educ Couns. 2020;103(3):626&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31704030</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monaghan MC, Hilliard ME, Cogen FR, et al. Nighttime caregiving behaviors among parents of young children with Type 1 diabetes: associations with illness characteristics and parent functioning. Fam Syst Health. 2009;27(1):28&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19630443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery RJV and Talley RC (2013) Perspectives on caregiving across the life span: current status and future directions. In: Talley RC and Montgomery RJV (eds) Caregiving Across the Lifespan. Caregiving: Research &#x2022; Practice &#x2022; Policy. New York, NY: Springer New York, pp. 177&#x2013;182. Available at: https://link.springer.com/ https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4614-5553-0_10 (accessed 15 October 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moon H, Dilworth-Anderson P. Baby boomer caregiver and dementia caregiving: findings from the National Study of Caregiving. Age Ageing. 2015;44(2):300&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25359299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morin CM, Belleville G, B&#xe9;langer L, et al. The Insomnia Severity Index: psychometric indicators to detect insomnia cases and evaluate treatment response. Sleep. 2011;34(5):601&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21532953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3079939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison K, Winter L, Gitlin LN. Recruiting community-based dementia patients and caregivers in a nonpharmacologic randomized trial: what works and how much does it cost? J Appl Gerontol. 2016;35(7):788&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24799354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Alliance for Caregiving and AARP (2020) Caregiving in the U.S. 2020. 14 May. Washington, DC: AARP. Available at: https://www.aarp.org/ppi/info-2020/caregiving-in-the-united-states.html (accessed 24 April 2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nazem S, Barnes SM, Forster JE, et al. Efficacy of an internet-delivered intervention for improving insomnia severity and functioning in veterans: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Ment Health. 2023;10:e50516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37999953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10709797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohayon MM. Epidemiology of insomnia: what we know and what we still need to learn. Sleep Med Rev. 2002;6(2):97&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pan Y-C, Lin Y-S. Systematic review and meta-analysis of prevalence of depression among caregivers of cancer patients. Front Psychiatry. 2022;13:817936.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35633789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9133351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawl JD, Lee S-Y, Clark PC, et al. Sleep characteristics of family caregivers of individuals with a primary malignant brain tumor. Oncol Nurs Forum. 2013;40(2):171&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23448742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perepezko K, Shaffer K, Beach S, et al. (2024) Effects of caregiver sleep disturbances on relationship quality with their care recipient. The Journals of Gerontology: Series B Kelley J (ed.) 79(1): gbad137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prather AA, Puterman E, Epel ES, et al. Poor sleep quality potentiates stress-induced cytokine reactivity in postmenopausal women with high visceral abdominal adiposity. Brain Behav Immun. 2014;35:155&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24060585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pristavec T. The burden and benefits of caregiving: a latent class analysis. Gerontologist. 2019;59(6):1078&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29659788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritterband LM, Thorndike FP, Gonder-Frederick LA, et al. Efficacy of an internet-based behavioral intervention for adults with insomnia. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2009;66(7):692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19581560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3723339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritterband LM, Bailey ET, Thorndike FP, et al. Initial evaluation of an Internet intervention to improve the sleep of cancer survivors with insomnia. Psycho-Oncol. 2012;21(7):695&#x2013;705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulz R, Beach SR, Friedman EM. Caregiving factors as predictors of care recipient mortality. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2021;29(3):295&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32718853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson C, Carter P. Dementia behavioural and psychiatric symptoms: effect on caregiver&#x2019;s sleep. J Clin Nurs. 2013;22(21&#x2013;22):3042&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23445081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3797264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smekal M, Gil S, Donald M, et al. Content and quality of websites for patients with chronic kidney disease: an environmental scan. Can J Kidney Health Dis. 2019;6:2054358119863091.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31391944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6668187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xf6;rensen S, Conwell Y. Issues in dementia caregiving: effects on mental and physical health, intervention strategies, and research needs. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2011;19(6):491&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21502853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3774150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spielman AJ, Saskin P, Thorpy MJ. Treatment of chronic insomnia by restriction of time in bed. 1987;10:45&#x2013;56.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan-Bolyai S, Deatrick J, Gruppuso P, et al. Constant vigilance: mothers&#x2019; work parenting young children with type 1 diabetes. J Pediatr Nurs. 2003;18(1):21&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12610784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sunnhed R, Hesser H, Andersson G, et al. Comparing internet-delivered cognitive therapy and behavior therapy with telephone support for insomnia disorder: a randomized controlled trial. Sleep. 2020;43(2):zsz245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31608389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theng B, Tran JT, Serag H, et al. Understanding caregiver challenges: a comprehensive exploration of available resources to alleviate caregiving burdens. Cureus. 2023;15(8):e43052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37680399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10480575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorndike F, Saylor D, Bailey E, et al. Development and perceived utility and impact of an internet intervention for insomnia. E-Journal of Applied Psychology. 2008;4(2):32&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20953264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2954428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care. 2007;19(6):349&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vellone E, Biagioli V, Durante A, et al. The influence of caregiver preparedness on caregiver contributions to self-care in heart failure and the mediating role of caregiver confidence. J Cardiovasc Nurs. 2020;35(3):243&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32084078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vincent GE, Kovac K, Sprajcer M, et al. Sleep disturbances in caregivers of children with medical needs: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Health Psychol. 2021;40(4):263&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33856833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wasilewski MB, Stinson JN, Cameron JI. Web-based health interventions for family caregivers of elderly individuals: a scoping review. Int J Med Inform. 2017;103:109&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28550996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer Kelly M, Ritterband LM, You W, et al. Single-Group Trial of an Internet-Delivered Insomnia Intervention Among Higher-Intensity Family Caregivers: Rationale and Protocol for a Mixed Methods Study. JMIR Res Protoc 2022;11(1):e34792.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer KM, Ritterband LM, You W, et al. Caregivers&#x2019; Internet-Delivered Insomnia Intervention Engagement and Benefit: SHUTi-CARE Trial Primary Quantitative Analysis. Ann Behav Med 2024; kaae031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaffer KM, Perepezko K, Glazer JV, et al. Caregiver Experiences With an Internet-Delivered Insomnia Intervention: SHUTi-CARE Trial Primary Qualitative Analysis. Ann Behav Med 2024;58(10):658&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glazer JV, MacDonnell K, Frederick C, et al. Liar! Liar! Identifying eligibility fraud by applicants in digital health research. Internet Interv 2021;25:100401.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>