<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37432990</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1940-5480</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>21</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Journal of the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Acad Orthop Surg</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Disconnected: Electronic Patient-Reported Outcome Measure Collection In Orthopaedic Patients at an Urban Safety-Net Hospital.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1136</StartPage><EndPage>1142</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1136-1142</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5435/JAAOS-D-23-00132</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Collection of patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs) in orthopaedic patients at safety-net hospitals is challenging. The purpose of this study was to evaluate the success of electronic PROM (E-PROM) collection in this setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective review identified 207 consecutive orthopaedic patients undergoing 77 elective arthroplasty procedures and 130 trauma procedures. E-PROMs were collected through automated e-mails from an online patient engagement platform (PatientIQ) at 2 weeks, 6 weeks, and 3 months postoperatively. Patients with trauma received the percentage of normal Single Assessment Numerical Evaluation (SANE) and Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System-Physical Function (PROMIS-PF). Arthroplasty patients received the Hip/Knee SANE, Hip/Knee Disability and Osteoarthritis Outcome Score-Joint Replacement (HOOS Jr/KOOS Jr), PROMIS Global Physical Health (PROMIS-G-PH), and Veterans RAND 12-Item (VR-12) Health Survey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Compared with patients with trauma, arthroplasty patients were older (median difference 18.0 years; 95% confidence interval [CI] 12.0-22.0; P &lt; 0.0001), more likely to be Hispanic/Black (proportional difference 16.9%; CI 2.8-30.3%; P = 0.02), more likely to have noncommercial or no insurance (proportional difference 34.0%; CI 23.2-43.0%; P &lt; 0.001), and did not differ in Area Deprivation Index or E-PROM completion at each time point. E-PROMs were completed at 2 weeks, 6 weeks, and 3 months by 25.1% (52 of 207), 24.6% (51 of 207), and 21.7% (45 of 207) of all patients, respectively. Trauma and arthroplasty patients had a similar rate of partial E-PROM completion. Patients who completed 3-month E-PROMs were less likely to be Hispanic/Black (PD -16.4%; CI -31.0 to -0.2%; P &lt; 0.04); less likely to have noncommercial/no insurance (PD -20.0%; CI -35.5 to -4.5%; P = 0.01); and did not differ in age, sex, Area Deprivation Index, or procedure type.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION">The low collection rate of E-PROMs from orthopaedic patients at safety-net hospitals should be weighed against their costs. E-PROM collection may exacerbate disparities in PROM collection among certain patient populations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE">Diagnostic Level III.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American Academy of Orthopaedic Surgeons.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tucker</LastName><ForeName>Nicholas J</ForeName><Initials>NJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the Department of Orthopaedics (Dr. Tucker, Dr. Mauffrey, Dr. Hammerberg, Dr. Parry), Denver Health Medical Center, St. Denver, CO (Tucker, Mauffrey, Hammerberg, and Parry), and the University of Colorado School of Medicine, Denver, Colorado (Tucker, Shah, Mauffrey, Hammerberg, and Parry), Aurora, CO.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shah</LastName><ForeName>Ananya</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mauffrey</LastName><ForeName>Cyril</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammerberg</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parry</LastName><ForeName>Joshua A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8262-4065</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Acad Orthop Surg</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9417468</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1067-151X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37432990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5435/JAAOS-D-23-00132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00124635-202311010-00010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title/><Reference><Citation>Franklin PD, Lewallen D, Bozic K, Hallstrom B, Jiranek W, Ayers DC. Implementation of patient-reported outcome measures in U.S. Total joint replacement registries: Rationale, status, and plans. J Bone Joint Surg. 2014;96 (Suppl 1):104-109</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MOTION Group: Patient-reported outcomes in orthopaedics. J Bone Joint Surg 2018;100:436-442</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Makhni EC: Meaningful clinical applications of patient-reported outcome measures in orthopaedics. J Bone Joint Surg 2021;103:84-91,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parry JA, Peterson SL, Strage KE, et al.: Percent of normal: A pragmatic patient-reported outcome measure for the orthopaedic trauma clinic. J Orthopaedic Trauma 2021;35:e429-e432,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchings A, Neuburger J, Grosse Frie K, Black N, van der Meulen J: Factors associated with non-response in routine use of patient reported outcome measures after elective surgery in England. Health Qual Life Outcomes 2012;10:34,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernstein DN, Karhade AV, Bono CM, Schwab JH, Harris MB, Tobert DG: Sociodemographic factors are associated with patient-reported outcome measure completion in orthopaedic surgery: An analysis of completion rates and determinants among new patients. JB JS open access 2022;7:e22.00026.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varady NH, d'Amonville S, Chen AF: Electronic patient portal use in orthopaedic surgery is associated with disparities, improved satisfaction, and lower No-show rates. J Bone Joint Surg 2020;102:1336-1343,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizzio VA, Dekhne MS, Makhni EC: Electronic patient-reported outcome collection systems in orthopaedic clinical practice. JBJS Rev 2019;7:e2,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kind AJH, Buckingham WR: Making neighborhood-disadvantage metrics accessible - the neighborhood atlas. N Engl J Med 2018;378:2456-2458,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strage K, Parry J, Mauffrey C: Standardizing statistics and data reporting in orthopaedic research. Eur J Orthop Surg Traumatol 2021;31:1-6,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strage K, Stacey S, Mauffrey C, Parry JA: The interobserver reliability of clinical relevance in medical research. Injury 2022, Jan 19:S0020-1383(21)01061-5. doi: 10.1016/j.injury.2021.12.044. Epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.injury.2021.12.044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schober P, Boer C, Schwarte LA: Correlation coefficients: Appropriate use and interpretation. Anesth Analgesia 2018;126:1763-1768,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zelle BA, Buttacavoli FA, Shroff JB, Stirton JB: Loss of follow-up in orthopaedic trauma: Who is getting lost to follow-up?. J Orthopaedic Trauma 2015;29:510-515,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horn ME, Reinke EK, Mather RC, O'Donnell JD, George SZ: Electronic health record-integrated approach for collection of patient-reported outcome measures: A retrospective evaluation. BMC Health Serv Res 2021;21:626,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen MP, Rivard RL, Blaschke B, et al.: Capturing patient-reported outcomes: Paper versus electronic survey administration. OTA Int Open Access J Orthopaedic Trauma 2022;5:e212,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin E, Bozic KJ, Ibrahim S, O'Connor MI, Nelson CL: Does value-based care threaten joint arthroplasty access for vulnerable patient populations?: AOA critical issues. J Bone Joint Surg 2022;104:e92,</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connor CM, Ring D: Correlation of single assessment numeric evaluation (SANE) with other patient reported outcome measures (PROMs). Arch Bone Joint Surg 2019;7:303-306.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>