<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37717255</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1888</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of clinical dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chronic Prurigo Including Prurigo Nodularis: New Insights and Treatments.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>15</StartPage><EndPage>33</EndPage><MedlinePgn>15-33</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40257-023-00818-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Chronic prurigo (CPG) is a neuroinflammatory, fibrotic dermatosis that is defined by the presence of chronic pruritus (itch lasting longer than 6 weeks), scratch-associated pruriginous skin lesions and history of repeated scratching. Patients with CPG experience a significant psychological burden and a notable impairment in their quality of life. Chronic prurigo of nodular type (CNPG; synonym: prurigo nodularis) represents the most common subtype of CPG. As CNPG is representative for all CPG subtypes, we refer in this review to both CNPG and CPG. We provide an overview of the clinical characteristics and assessment of CPG, the burden of disease and the underlying pathophysiology including associated therapeutic targets. The information provided results from a PubMed search for the latest publications and a database search for current clinical trials (ClinicalTrials.gov, EU Clinical Trials Register [European Medicines Agency]; using the following terms or combinations of terms: 'chronic prurigo', 'prurigo', 'prurigo nodularis', 'pathophysiology', 'therapy', 'biologics', 'treatment'). Dupilumab is the first authorized systemic therapy by the European Medicines Agency (EMA) and the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for CNPG to date. Topical and systemic agents that are currently under investigation in clinical randomized, placebo-controlled phase II and III trials such as biologics (e.g., nemolizumab, vixarelimab/KPL-716, barzolvolimab/CDX-0159), small molecules (ruxolitinib cream, povorcitinib/INCB054707, abrocitinib) and the opioid modulator nalbuphine are highlighted. In the last past 15 years, several milestones have been reached regarding the disease understanding of CPG such as first transcriptomic analysis, first terminology, first guideline, and first therapy approval in 2022, which contributed to improved medical care of affected patients. The broad range of identified targets, current case observations and initiated trials offers the possibility of more drug approvals in the near future.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>M&#xfc;ller</LastName><ForeName>Svenja</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2118-959X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Allergy, University Hospital Bonn, Bonn, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Zeidler</LastName><ForeName>Claudia</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9485-8627</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Center for Chronic Pruritus, University Hospital M&#xfc;nster, Von-Esmarch-Str. 58, 48149, M&#xfc;nster, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>St&#xe4;nder</LastName><ForeName>Sonja</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3612-7786</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Center for Chronic Pruritus, University Hospital M&#xfc;nster, Von-Esmarch-Str. 58, 48149, M&#xfc;nster, Germany. sonja.staender@ukmuenster.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>PPRC-2020-21</GrantID><Agency>European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100895290</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1175-0561</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000911">Antibodies, Monoclonal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011536" MajorTopicYN="Y">Prurigo</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011537" MajorTopicYN="N">Pruritus</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000911" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Monoclonal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Svenja M&#xfc;ller is or was advisor, speaker or investigator for Galderma, Incyte Inc., Eli Lilly, Sanofi/Regeneron and LEO Pharma outside the submitted work. Claudia Zeidler is or was advisor, speaker or investigator for Novartis, Janssen, Pfizer, UCB, Lilly, AbbVie, Boehringer Ingelheim, Sanofi, Regeneron, Leo, Galderma, Dermasence, Beiersdorf, Unna Akademie. She was a consultant for Sanofi and Allmiral. All outside the submitted work. Sonja St&#xe4;nder is an investigator for Celldex, Clexio, Dermasence, Galderma, GSK, Incyte, Kiniksa, Novartis, Sanofi, Trevi. She is a consultant and/or member of advisory boards for AbbVie, Almirall, Beiersdorf, Benevolent, Bionorica, Cara, Celgene, Clexio, DS Biopharma, Eli Lilly, Escient, Galderma, Kiniksa, Klinge Pharma, Leo Pharma, Maruho, Menlo, P.G. Unna Academy, Pfizer, Sanofi, Symbio Research, Trevi, Vanda, Vifor, WebMD.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37717255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10796623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-023-00818-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40257-023-00818-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pereira MP, Steinke S, Zeidler C, Forner C, Riepe C, Augustin M, et al. European academy of dermatology and venereology European prurigo project: expert consensus on the definition, classification and terminology of chronic prurigo. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2018;32:1059&#x2013;1065. doi: 10.1111/jdv.14570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.14570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28857299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;nder S. How to define chronic pruritus: symptom or disease? Exp Dermatol. 2019;28:1461&#x2013;1465. doi: 10.1111/exd.13953.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exd.13953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31066940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;rmann CM, Schedel F, Plewig G, L&#xf6;ser C, St&#xe4;nder H, St&#xe4;nder S. Nihil certum: Historische Entwicklung des Begriffs Prurigo [Nihil certum: historical development of the term prurigo] Hautarzt. 2014;65(8):674&#x2013;683. doi: 10.1007/s00105-014-2752-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00105-014-2752-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25113325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misery L. Chronic prurigo. Br J Dermatol. 2022;187:464&#x2013;471. doi: 10.1111/bjd.21698.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.21698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35656799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xfc;ndel S, Pereira MP, Storck M, Osada N, Schneider G, St&#xe4;nder S, Zeidler C. Analysis of 325 patients with chronic nodular prurigo: clinics, burden of disease and course of treatment. Acta Derm Venereol. 2020;100:adv00269. 10.2340/00015555-3571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9234994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32556359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MP, Hoffmann V, Weisshaar E, Wallengren J, Halvorsen JA, Garcovich S, et al. Chronic nodular prurigo: clinical profile and burden. A European cross-sectional study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2020;34:2373&#x2013;83. 10.1111/jdv.16309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustin M, Garbe C, Hagenstr&#xf6;m K, Petersen J, Pereira MP, St&#xe4;nder S. Prevalence, incidence and presence of comorbidities in patients with prurigo and pruritus in Germany: a population-based claims data analysis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2021;35:2270&#x2013;2276. doi: 10.1111/jdv.17485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.17485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34192369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang AH, Canner JK, Khanna R, Kang S, Kwatra SG. Real-world prevalence of prurigo nodularis and burden of associated diseases. J Invest Dermatol. 2020;140:480&#x2013;483.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.jid.2019.07.697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2019.07.697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31421126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boozalis E, Tang O, Patel S, Semenov YR, Pereira MP, Stander S, et al. Ethnic differences and comorbidities of 909 prurigo nodularis patients. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2018;79:714&#x2013;719.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2018.04.047.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2018.04.047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6518410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29733939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkon N, Assen FP, Arnoldner T, Bauer WM, Medjimorec MA, Shaw LE, et al. Single-cell RNA sequencing defines disease-specific differences between chronic nodular prurigo and atopic dermatitis. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2023 doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2023.04.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2023.04.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37210042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng J, Parthasarathy V, Marani M, Bordeaux Z, Lee K, Trinh C, et al. Extracellular matrix and dermal nerve growth factor dysregulation in prurigo nodularis compared to atopic dermatitis. Front Med (Lausanne). 2022;9:1022889. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2022.1022889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.1022889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9810753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36619628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storck M, Sandmann S, Bruland P, Pereira MP, Steinke S, Riepe C, et al. Pruritus Intensity Scales across Europe: a prospective validation study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2021;35:1176&#x2013;1185. doi: 10.1111/jdv.17111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.17111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33411947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MP, Zeidler C, Nau T, Bobko S, Evers AWM, Garcovich S, et al. Position Statement: Linear prurigo is a subtype of chronic prurigo. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2019;33:263&#x2013;266. doi: 10.1111/jdv.15275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.15275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30288812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeidler C, Pereira MP, St&#xe4;nder S. Chronic prurigo: similar clinical profile and burden across clinical phenotypes. Front Med (Lausanne). 2021;8:649332. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2021.649332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2021.649332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8277241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenaut E, Halvorsen JA, Dalgard FJ, Lien L, Balieva F, Sampogna F, et al. The self-assessed psychological comorbidities of prurigo in European patients: a multicentre study in 13 countries. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2019;33:157&#x2013;162. doi: 10.1111/jdv.15145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.15145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29923228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeidler C, Pereira MP, Dugas M, Augustin M, Storck M, Weyer-Elberich V, et al. The burden in chronic prurigo: patients with chronic prurigo suffer more than patients with chronic pruritus on non-lesional skin: a comparative, retrospective, explorative statistical analysis of 4,484 patients in a real-world cohort. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2021;35:738&#x2013;743. doi: 10.1111/jdv.16929.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.16929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32924186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MP, Zeidler C, Wallengren J, Halvorsen JA, Weisshaar E, Garcovich S, et al. Chronic nodular prurigo: a European cross-sectional study of patient perspectives on therapeutic goals and satisfaction. Acta Derm Venereol. 2021;101:adv00403. 10.2340/00015555-3726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9366694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33320272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider G, Driesch G, Heuft G, Evers S, Luger TA, St&#xe4;nder S. Psychosomatic cofactors and psychiatric comorbidity in patients with chronic itch. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2006;31:762&#x2013;767. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2230.2006.02211.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2230.2006.02211.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17040260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen KM, Egeberg A, Gislason GH, Skov L, Thyssen JP. Anxiety, depression and suicide in patients with prurigo nodularis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2017;31:e106&#x2013;e107. doi: 10.1111/jdv.13827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.13827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27505149</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider G, Zeidler C, Pereira MP, St&#xe4;nder S. One third of chronic prurigo patients scratch automatically and in the absence of itch - a naturalistic study of 1142 patients. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2022;36:e297&#x2013;e300. doi: 10.1111/jdv.17777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.17777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34705294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oexle N, R&#xfc;sch N. Stigma&#x2014;risikofaktor und Konsequenz suizidalen Verhaltens: implikationen f&#xfc;r die Suizidpr&#xe4;vention. [Stigma&#x2014;risk factor and consequence of suicidal behavior: implications for suicide prevention]. Nervenarzt. 2018;89:779&#x2013;83. 10.1007/s00115-017-0450-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29147725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stumpf A, St&#xe4;nder S, Warlich B, Fritz F, Bruland P, Pfleiderer B, et al. Relations between the characteristics and psychological comorbidities of chronic pruritus differ between men and women: women are more anxious than men. Br J Dermatol. 2015;172:1323&#x2013;1328. doi: 10.1111/bjd.13492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.13492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25350351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao Y, Zhu Y, Xiao Z, Shen Y, Dai B, Tang H, Wang D. RNA sequencing reveals the transcriptome profile of the atopic prurigo nodularis with severe itching. Exp Dermatol. 2023;32:30&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1111/exd.14678.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exd.14678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36134503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calugareanu A, Specque F, Demouche S, Grolleau C, Dobos G, Merandet M, et al. Transcriptomic landscape of prurigo nodularis lesional skin CD3+ T cells using single-cell RNA-sequencing. J Invest Dermatol. 2023 doi: 10.1016/j.jid.2023.05.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2023.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37263486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutaria N, Alphonse MP, Roh YS, Choi J, Parthasarathy V, Deng J, et al. Cutaneous transcriptomics identifies fibroproliferative and neurovascular gene dysregulation in prurigo nodularis compared with psoriasis and atopic dermatitis. J Invest Dermatol. 2022;142:2537&#x2013;2540. doi: 10.1016/j.jid.2022.02.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2022.02.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9391257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35257721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsoi LC, Hacini-Rachinel F, Fogel P, Rousseau F, Xing X, Patrick MT, et al. Transcriptomic characterization of prurigo nodularis and the therapeutic response to nemolizumab. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2022;149:1329&#x2013;1339. doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2021.10.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2021.10.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8995330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34857395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agelopoulos K, Renkhold L, Wiegmann H, Dugas M, S&#xfc;er A, Zeidler C, et al. Transcriptomic, epigenomic, and neuroanatomic signatures differ in chronic prurigo, atopic dermatitis, and brachioradial pruritus. J Invest Dermatol. 2023;143:264&#x2013;272.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.jid.2022.08.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2022.08.042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto T, Nattkemper LA, Kim HS, Kursewicz CD, Fowler E, Shah SM, et al. Dermal periostin: a new player in itch of prurigo nodularis. Acta Derm Venereol. 2021;101:adv00375. 10.2340/00015555-3702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9309858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33236123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel JR, Joel MZ, Lee KK, Kambala A, Cornman H, Oladipo O, et al. Single-cell RNA sequencing reveals dysregulated fibroblast subclusters in prurigo nodularis. bioRxiv 2023. 10.1101/2023.01.29.526050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38246584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto T, Okuno S, Okuzawa M, Satoh T. Increased sensitivity to touch-evoked itch (punctate hyperknesis) in prurigo nodularis and type 2 inflammation: a cross-sectional pilot study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2023;37:e789&#x2013;e791. doi: 10.1111/jdv.18942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.18942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36734586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Chu Y, Li S, Wang Y, Zhong X, Fang H, Qiao J. Myeloid dendritic cells are increased in the lesional skin and associated with pruritus in patients with prurigo nodularis. MedComm. 2020;2023(4):e204. doi: 10.1002/mco2.204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mco2.204</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9921813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36789100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashimoto T, Nattkemper LA, Kim HS, Kursewicz CD, Fowler E, Shah SM, et al. Itch intensity in prurigo nodularis is closely related to dermal interleukin-31, oncostatin M, IL-31 receptor alpha and oncostatin M receptor beta. Exp Dermatol. 2021;30:804&#x2013;810. doi: 10.1111/exd.14279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exd.14279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33428793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parthasarathy V, Cravero K, Deng J, Sun Z, Engle SM, Auxier AN, et al. Circulating plasma IL-13 and periostin are dysregulated type 2 inflammatory biomarkers in prurigo nodularis: a cluster analysis. Front Med (Lausanne). 2022;9:1011142. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2022.1011142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.1011142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9763609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36561717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parthasarathy V, Cravero K, Xu L, Deng J, Sun Z, Engle SM, et al. The blood proteomic signature of prurigo nodularis reveals distinct inflammatory and neuropathic endotypes: a cluster analysis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2023;88:1101&#x2013;1109. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2023.01.042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2023.01.042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11212685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36806647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju T, Labib A, Nattkemper L, Engle S, Auxier A, Hahn N, et al. Serum interleukin-13 and caspase 8 are elevated in prurigo nodularis. Acta Derm Venereol. 2023;103:adv00861. 10.2340/actadv.v103.4804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10391783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36748331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaowattanapanit S, Wongjirattikarn R, Chaisuriya N, Ungarreevittaya P, Poosekeaw P, Winaikosol K, et al. Increased IL-31 expression in serum and tissue protein in prurigo nodularis. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2022;13:20406223221112561. doi: 10.1177/20406223221112561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20406223221112561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9301099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35875833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutaria N, Alphonse MP, Marani M, Parthasarathy V, Deng J, Wongvibulsin S, et al. Cluster analysis of circulating plasma biomarkers in prurigo nodularis reveals a distinct systemic inflammatory signature in African Americans. J Invest Dermatol. 2022;142:1300&#x2013;1308.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.jid.2021.10.011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2021.10.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9038640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34717952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MP, Pogatzki-Zahn E, Snels C, Vu T-H, &#xdc;&#xe7;eyler N, Loser K, et al. There is no functional small-fibre neuropathy in prurigo nodularis despite neuroanatomical alterations. Exp Dermatol. 2017;26:969&#x2013;971. doi: 10.1111/exd.13343.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/exd.13343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28370394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bobko S, Zeidler C, Osada N, Riepe C, Pfleiderer B, Pogatzki-Zahn E, et al. Intraepidermal nerve fibre density is decreased in lesional and inter-lesional prurigo nodularis and reconstitutes on healing of lesions. Acta Derm Venereol. 2016;96:404&#x2013;406. doi: 10.2340/00015555-2232.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/00015555-2232</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26338533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuhknecht B, Marziniak M, Wissel A, Phan NQ, Pappai D, Dangelmaier J, et al. Reduced intraepidermal nerve fibre density in lesional and nonlesional prurigo nodularis skin as a potential sign of subclinical cutaneous neuropathy. Br J Dermatol. 2011;165:85&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2133.2011.10306.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2133.2011.10306.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21410670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pogatzki-Zahn EM, Pereira MP, Cremer A, Zeidler C, Dreyer T, Riepe C, et al. Peripheral sensitization and loss of descending inhibition is a hallmark of chronic pruritus. J Invest Dermatol. 2020;140:203&#x2013;211.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.jid.2019.05.029.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2019.05.029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31276675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choragudi S, Yosipovitch G. Prurigo nodularis is highly linked with neural sensitization disorders of pain among hospitalized adults in the United States&#x2014;National inpatient sample 2016&#x2013;2019. Br J Dermatol. 2023 doi: 10.1093/bjd/ljad121.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjd/ljad121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37067913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pereira MP, Agelopoulos K, K&#xf6;llner J, Neufang G, Schmelz M, St&#xe4;nder S. Selective nerve fibre activation in patients with generalized chronic pruritus: hint for central sensitization? Acta Derm Venereol. 2019;99:1009&#x2013;1015. doi: 10.2340/00015555-3261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/00015555-3261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31289838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasavda C, Wan G, Szeto MD, Marani M, Sutaria N, Rajeh A, et al. A polygenic risk score for predicting racial and genetic susceptibility to prurigo nodularis. J Invest Dermatol. 2023 doi: 10.1016/j.jid.2023.04.033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2023.04.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11290854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37245863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xf6;lking J, Zeidler C, Schedel F, Osada N, Augustin M, Metze D, et al. Prurigo Activity Score (PAS): validity and reliability of a new instrument to monitor chronic prurigo. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2018;32:1754&#x2013;1760. doi: 10.1111/jdv.15040.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.15040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29729201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeidler C, Pereira MP, Augustin M, Spellman M, St&#xe4;nder S. Investigator's global assessment of chronic prurigo: a new instrument for use in clinical trials. Acta Derm Venereol. 2021;101:adv00401. 10.2340/00015555-3701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9366679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33236125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;nder S, Pereira MP, Berger T, Zeidler C, Augustin M, Bobko S, et al. IFSI-guideline on chronic prurigo including prurigo nodularis. Itch. 2020;5:e42&#x2013;e42. doi: 10.1097/itx.0000000000000042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/itx.0000000000000042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Massa MC, Connolly SM. Bullous pemphigoid with features of prurigo nodularis. Arch Dermatol. 1982;118:937&#x2013;939. doi: 10.1001/archderm.1982.01650230065032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archderm.1982.01650230065032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6753767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanumaiah B, Joseph JM. Role of dermoscopy in the diagnosis of hypertrophic lichen planus and prurigo nodularis. Indian J Dermatol. 2019;64:341&#x2013;345. doi: 10.4103/ijd.IJD_123_18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijd.IJD_123_18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6749763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31543526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller S, St&#xe4;nder S, Naatz M, Augustin M, Steinke S. Cost-effectiveness and quality of specialized and routine care in a german cohort of patients with chronic pruritus. Acta Derm Venereol. 2023;103:adv4868. 10.2340/actadv.v103.4868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10134063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37083094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich A, Chatzigeorkidis E, Zeidler C, Osada N, Furue M, Takamori K, et al. Tailoring the Cut-off values of the visual analogue scale and numeric rating scale in itch assessment. Acta Derm Venereol. 2017;97:759&#x2013;760. doi: 10.2340/00015555-2642.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/00015555-2642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28224165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay AY, Khan GK. Dermatology life quality index (DLQI)&#x2014;a simple practical measure for routine clinical use. Clin Exp Dermatol. 1994;19:210&#x2013;216. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2230.1994.tb01167.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2230.1994.tb01167.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8033378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai NS, Poindexter GB, Monthrope YM, Bendeck SE, Swerlick RA, Chen SC. A pilot quality-of-life instrument for pruritus. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2008;59:234&#x2013;244. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2008.04.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2008.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18550210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2003;1:29. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-1-29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-1-29</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC183845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12914662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labib A, Ju T, Vander Does A, Yosipovitch G. Immunotargets and therapy for prurigo nodularis. Immunotargets Ther. 2022;11:11&#x2013;21. doi: 10.2147/ITT.S316602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/ITT.S316602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9056055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35502157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yosipovitch G, Mollanazar N, St&#xe4;nder S, Kwatra SG, Kim BS, Laws E, et al. Dupilumab in patients with prurigo nodularis: two randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 trials. Nat Med. 2023;29:1180&#x2013;1190. doi: 10.1038/s41591-023-02320-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-023-02320-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10202800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37142763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wong SS, Goh CL. Double-blind, right/left comparison of calcipotriol ointment and betamethasone ointment in the treatment of prurigo nodularis. Arch Dermatol. 2000;136:807&#x2013;808. doi: 10.1001/archderm.136.6.807.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archderm.136.6.807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10871962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siepmann D, Lotts T, Blome C, Braeutigam M, Phan NQ, Butterfass-Bahloul T, et al. Evaluation of the antipruritic effects of topical pimecrolimus in non-atopic prurigo nodularis: results of a randomized, hydrocortisone-controlled, double-blind phase II trial. Dermatology. 2013;227:353&#x2013;360. doi: 10.1159/000355671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000355671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24281309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams KA, Huang AH, Belzberg M, Kwatra SG. Prurigo nodularis: pathogenesis and management. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;83:1567&#x2013;1575. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2020.04.182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.04.182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32461078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;nder HF, Elmariah S, Zeidler C, Spellman M, St&#xe4;nder S. Diagnostic and treatment algorithm for chronic nodular prurigo. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;82:460&#x2013;468. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2019.07.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2019.07.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31310842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dupilumab SM. First global approval. Drugs. 2017;77:1115&#x2013;1121. doi: 10.1007/s40265-017-0768-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-017-0768-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28547386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/dupixent.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fachler T, Maria Faitataziadou S, Molho-Pessach V. Dupilumab for pediatric prurigo nodularis: a case report. Pediatr Dermatol. 2021;38:334&#x2013;335. doi: 10.1111/pde.14464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pde.14464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33247435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang H-Y, Lian C-H. The effectiveness and safety of dupilumab in the management of refractory prurigo nodularis in 45 Chinese patients: a real-life observational study. J Dermatol. 2023 doi: 10.1111/1346-8138.16803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1346-8138.16803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37088954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giovannini M, Mori F, Oranges T, Ricci S, Barni S, Canessa C, et al. Dupilumab treatment of prurigo nodularis in an adolescent. Eur J Dermatol. 2021;31:104&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1684/ejd.2020.3947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/ejd.2020.3947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33586661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Husein-ElAhmed H, Steinhoff M. Dupilumab in prurigo nodularis: a systematic review of current evidence and analysis of predictive factors to response. J Dermatolog Treat. 2022;33:1547&#x2013;1553. doi: 10.1080/09546634.2020.1853024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09546634.2020.1853024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33200955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damsky W, King BA. JAK inhibitors in dermatology: the promise of a new drug class. 2017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6035868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28139263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisshaar E, Szepietowski JC, Bernhard JD, Hait H, Legat FJ, Nattkemper L, et al. Efficacy and safety of oral nalbuphine extended release in prurigo nodularis: results of a phase 2 randomized controlled trial with an open-label extension phase. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2022;36:453&#x2013;461. doi: 10.1111/jdv.17816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.17816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34780095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Datsi A, Steinhoff M, Ahmad F, Alam M, Buddenkotte J. Interleukin-31: The "itchy" cytokine in inflammation and therapy. Allergy. 2021;76:2982&#x2013;2997. doi: 10.1111/all.14791.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/all.14791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33629401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keam SJ. Nemolizumab: first approval. Drugs. 2022;82:1143&#x2013;1150. doi: 10.1007/s40265-022-01741-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-022-01741-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35834124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;nder S, Yosipovitch G, Legat F. et al. 436 Nemolizumab monotherapy was associated with significant improvements in prurigo activity score in adult patients with moderate-to-severie prurigo nodularis: results form a phase 3 trial (OLYMPIA 2). Br J Dermatol. Suppl. 3. 10.1093/bjd/ljad162.056.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;nder S, Yosipovitch G, Legat FJ, Lacour J-P, Paul C, Narbutt J, et al. Trial of nemolizumab in moderate-to-severe prurigo nodularis. N Engl J Med. 2020;382:706&#x2013;716. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1908316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1908316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32074418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;nder S, Yosipovitch G, Lacour J-P, Legat FJ, Paul C, Reich A, et al. Nemolizumab efficacy in prurigo nodularis: onset of action on itch and sleep disturbances. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2022;36:1820&#x2013;1825. doi: 10.1111/jdv.18377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.18377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9796585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35766128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofen H, Bissonnette R, Yosipovitch G, Silverberg JI, Tyring S, Loo WJ, et al. Efficacy and safety of vixarelimab, a human monoclonal oncostatin M receptor &#x3b2; antibody, in moderate-to-severe prurigo nodularis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase 2a study. EClinicalMedicine. 2023;57:101826. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.101826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2023.101826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9932343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36816342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams KA, Roh YS, Brown I, Sutaria N, Bakhshi P, Choi J, et al. Pathophysiology, diagnosis, and pharmacological treatment of prurigo nodularis. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2020 doi: 10.1080/17512433.2021.1852080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17512433.2021.1852080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33191806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima C, Yanagihara S, Otsuka A. Innovation in the treatment of atopic dermatitis: emerging topical and oral Janus kinase inhibitors. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34815171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMA approval cibinqo. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/cibinqo.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMA approval olumiant. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/olumiant.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMA approval rinvoq. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/rinvoq.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMA approval opzelura. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/opzelura.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papp K, Szepietowski JC, Kircik L, Toth D, Eichenfield LF, Leung DYM, et al. Efficacy and safety of ruxolitinib cream for the treatment of atopic dermatitis: results from 2 phase 3, randomized, double-blind studies. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2021;85:863&#x2013;872. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2021.04.085.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2021.04.085</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33957195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vander Does A, Yosipovitch G. Failure of dupilimab with severe prurigo nodularis that responded well to abrocitinib. Dermatitis. 2023 doi: 10.1089/derm.2022.0065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/derm.2022.0065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36847309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson EL, Sinclair R, Forman S, Wollenberg A, Aschoff R, Cork M, et al. Efficacy and safety of abrocitinib in adults and adolescents with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis (JADE MONO-1): a multicentre, double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2020;396:255&#x2013;266. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30732-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30732-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terhorst-Molawi D, Hawro T, Grekowitz E, Kiefer L, Merchant K, Alvarado D, et al. Anti-KIT antibody, barzolvolimab, reduces skin mast cells and disease activity in chronic inducible urticaria. Allergy. 2023;78:1269&#x2013;1279. doi: 10.1111/all.15585.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/all.15585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36385701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeidler C, St&#xe4;nder S. The pathogenesis of Prurigo nodularis&#x2014;'Super-Itch' in exploration. Eur J Pain. 2016;20:37&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1002/ejp.767.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejp.767</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26416433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;nder S, Weisshaar E, Mettang T, Szepietowski JC, Carstens E, Ikoma A, et al. Clinical classification of itch: a position paper of the International Forum for the Study of Itch. Acta Derm Venereol. 2007;87:291&#x2013;294. doi: 10.2340/00015555-0305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/00015555-0305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17598029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pezzolo E, Gambardella A, Guanti M, Bianchelli T, Bertoldi A, Giacchetti A, et al. Tralokinumab shows clinical improvement in patients with prurigo nodularis-like phenotype atopic dermatitis: a multicenter, prospective, open-label case series study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2023 doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2023.04.056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2023.04.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37150301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu T, Chu Y, Wang Y, Zhong X, Yang C, Bai J, et al. Successful treatment of prurigo nodularis with tofacitinib: the experience from a single center. Int J Dermatol. 2023;62:e293&#x2013;e295. doi: 10.1111/ijd.16568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijd.16568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36573437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosmarin D, Passeron T, Pandya AG, Grimes P, Harris JE, Desai SR, et al. Two phase 3, randomized, controlled trials of ruxolitinib cream for vitiligo. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:1445&#x2013;1455. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2118828.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2118828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36260792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi VY, Bhutani T, Fonacier L, Deleuran M, Shumack S, Valdez H, et al. Phase 3 efficacy and safety of abrocitinib in adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis after switching from dupilumab (JADE EXTEND). 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35439608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;nder S, Kwon P, Hirman J, Perlman AJ, Weisshaar E, Metz M, Luger TA. Serlopitant reduced pruritus in patients with prurigo nodularis in a phase 2, randomized, placebo-controlled trial. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2019;80:1395&#x2013;1402. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2019.01.052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2019.01.052</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30894279</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsianakas A, Zeidler C, Riepe C, Borowski M, Forner C, Gerss J, et al. Aprepitant in anti-histamine-refractory chronic nodular prurigo: a multicentre, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, cross-over, phase-II trial (APREPRU) Acta Derm Venereol. 2019;99:379&#x2013;385. doi: 10.2340/00015555-3120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/00015555-3120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30653242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>