<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37838256</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-6787</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>90</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Acad Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Generalized pustular psoriasis: A consensus statement from the National Psoriasis Foundation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>727</StartPage><EndPage>730</EndPage><MedlinePgn>727-730</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jaad.2023.09.080</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0190-9622(23)02969-9</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Armstrong</LastName><ForeName>April W</ForeName><Initials>AW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Department of Medicine, David Geffen School of Medicine at University of California, Los Angeles, California. Electronic address: armstrongpublication@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elston</LastName><ForeName>Carly A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elewski</LastName><ForeName>Boni E</ForeName><Initials>BE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ferris</LastName><ForeName>Laura K</ForeName><Initials>LK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gottlieb</LastName><ForeName>Alice B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lebwohl</LastName><ForeName>Mark G</ForeName><Initials>MG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Medical Board of the National Psoriasis Foundation</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016446">Consensus Statement</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Acad Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7907132</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0190-9622</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Am Acad Dermatol. 2024 Apr;90(4):705-706. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2023.07.1049.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">37839736</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011565" MajorTopicYN="Y">Psoriasis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002908" MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000208" MajorTopicYN="N">Acute Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D032921" MajorTopicYN="N">Consensus</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IL-36 inhibition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">National Psoriasis Foundation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">access</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">consensus statement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">generalized pustular psoriasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">imsidolimab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psoriasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spesolimab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest Dr Armstrong has served as a research investigator, scientific advisor, and/or speaker to AbbVie, Almirall, Arcutis, ASLAN, Beiersdorf, BI, BMS, EPI, Incyte, Leo,&#xa0;UCB, Janssen, Lilly, Nimbus, Novartis, Ortho Dermatologics, Sun, Dermavant Sciences, Dermira, Sanofi, Regeneron, Pfizer, and Modmed. Dr Elewski has served as a research investigator and/or consultant for Boehringer Ingelheim, Pfizer, Lilly, Amgen, Novartis, UCB, and BMS. Dr Ferris has received compensation as an investigator from Amgen, AbbVie, UCB, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Janssen, Nimbus, Dermavant, and Arcutis. Dr&#xa0;Gottlieb has received honoraria as an advisory board member and consultant for Amgen, AnaptypsBio, Avotres Therapeutics, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Dice Therapeutics, Eli Lilly, Janssen, Novartis, Sanofi, UCB, and Xbiotech and has received research/educational grants from AnaptypsBio, Moonlake Immunotherapeutics AG, Novartis, Bristol Myers Squibb, and UCB Pharma, (all paid to Mount Sinai School of Medicine). Dr Lebwohl is an employee of Mount Sinai which has received research funds from AbbVie, Amgen, Arcutis, Avotres, Boehringer Ingelheim, Cara therapeutics, Dermavant Sciences, Eli Lilly, Incyte, Inozyme, Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC, Ortho Dermatologics, Pfizer, Sanofi-Regeneron, and UCB, and he serves as a consultant for Almirall, AltruBio Inc, AnaptysBio, Arcutis, Inc., AstraZeneca, Avotres Therapeutics, Brickell Biotech, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Castle Biosciences, Celltrion, Corevitas, Dermavant Sciences, EPI, Evommune, Inc, Facilitation of International Dermatology Education, Forte biosciences, Foundation for Research and Education in Dermatology, Galderma, Genentech, Incyte, LEO Pharma, Meiji Seika Pharma, Mindera, Pfizer, Seanergy, Strata, Trevi, and Verrica. Dr Calabrese has served as a consultant and/or speaker to Regeneron, Sanofi and AbbVie. Dr Desai has served as a research investigator, scientific advisor, consultant, and/or speaker to AbbVie, Galderma Laboratories, Foundation for Research &amp; Education of Dermatology, Almirall, Dermavant Sciences, Ferndale Laboratories, Incyte, Gore Range Capital, AOBiome, BMS, Verrica Pharmaceuticals, UCB, Ortho Dermatologics, Scientis, EPI Health, Avita, Pfizer, Eli Lilly, LEO Pharma, L&#x2019;Oreal USA, Beiersdorf, Johnson and Johnson, VYNE Therapeutics, Revision Skincare, Candela Corporation, Amgen, Cutera, and Hyphens Pharma; he is also the founder of Illuminate Skin Care. Dr Duffin has served on the advisory board or as a consultant and/or investigator for Stiefel, Novartis, Amgen, AbbVie, Celgene, Lilly, Ortho, Pfizer, Janssen, and Boehringer Ingelheim. Dr Feldman has received compensation from AbbVie, Accordant, Advance Medical, Almirall, Alovtech, Amgen, Arcutis, Arena, Argenx, Biocon, Boehringer Ingelheim, BMS, Caremark, Celgene, Dermavant, Eli Lilly, Galderma, GlaxoSmithKline/Stiefel, Helsinn, Informa, Janssen, LEO Pharma, Menlo, Merck, Mylan, National Biological Corporation, National Psoriasis Foundation, Novan, Novartis, Pfizer, Qurient Forte, Samsung, Regeneron, Sanofi, Sun Pharmaceutical, Suncare Research, UCB, UpToDate, Valeant, and vTv Therapeutics; he is also the founder and majority owner of www.DrScore.com and the founder and part owner of Causa Research. Dr Gladman has served as a consultant for Amgen, AbbVie, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Pfizer, UCB, BMS, Galapagos, Gilead Sciences, and Janssen. Dr Glick has served as a research investigator, scientific advisor, and/or speaker to AbbVie, AstraZeneca, Amgen, Janssen, Galderma, Sun Pharma, Leo, Lilly, Novartis, Dermavant Sciences, Incyte, EPI/Novan, BMS, Nimbus, Cara Therapeutics, Dermira, Sanofi Genzyme, Regeneron, Pfizer, ChemoCentryx, Ortho Dermatologics, UCB, Brickell Biotech, CorEvitas Registry PSO, CorEvitas Registry AD, and PROSE Registry for AD. Dr Han has received compensation from Bond Avillon, Pellepharm, MC2, Athenex, and Celgene; he has served as a consultant and/or speaker to Amgen, Boehringer Ingelheim, BMS, Dermavant Sciences, Janssen, Lilly, UCB, Novartis, LEO Pharma, AbbVie, Regeneron, Sanofi Genzyme, Ortho Dermatologics, Sun Pharmaceutical, and Pfizer. Dr Hawkes has served as a consultant and/or speaker to AbbVie, Arcutis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Janssen, LearnSkin, LEO Pharma, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Pfizer, Regeneron, Sanofi Genzyme, UCB, and Visual Dx. Dr Hsu has served as a consultant for Janssen, Lilly, and Boehringer Ingelheim; she has also served as a research investigator for Regeneron. Dr Kalb has served as a research investigator and/or consultant for Johnson and Johnson, AbbVie, UCB, Galderma, Novartis, Amgen, Menlo Therapeutics, and Boehringer Inhelheim. Dr Kircik has served as a consultant/speaker/ investigator/advisory board member for Abbott Laboratories, AbbVie, Ablynx, Aclaris, Acambis, Allergan, Almirall, Amgen, Anacor Pharmaceuticals, Anaptys, Arcutis, Arena, Assos Pharma, Astellas Pharma US, Asubio, Bausch Health, Berlex Laboratories (Bayer HealthCare Pharmaceuticals), Biogen-Idec, Biolife, Biopelle, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, Breckinridge Pharma, Cassiopea, Centocor, Cellceutix, Cipher, Coherus, Colbar, Combinatrix, Connetics Corporation, Coria, Dermavant Sciences, Dermira, Dermik Laboratories, Dow Pharmaceutical Sciences, Dr. Reddy&#x2019;s Lab, Dusa, Embil Pharmaceuticals, Eli Lilly, EOS, Exeltis, Ferndale Laboratories, Foamix, Ferrer, Galderma, Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, PLC, Glenmark, Health Point, LTD, Idera, Incyte, Intendis, Innocutis, Innovail, Isdin, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Kyowa Kirin, Laboratory Skin Care, LEO Pharma, L&#x2019;Oreal, 3M, Maruho, Medical International Technologies, Merck, Medicis Pharmaceutical Corp, Merz, Nano Bio, Novartis AG, Noven Pharmaceuticals, Nucryst Pharmaceuticals Corp, Obagi, Onset, OrthoNeutrogena, PediaPharma, Pfizer, Promius, PuraCap, PharmaDerm, QLT, Quinnova, Quatrix, Regeneron, Sanofi, Serono (Merck Serono International SA), SkinMedica, Stiefel Laboratories, Sun Pharma, Taro, TolerRx, Triax, UCB, Valeant Pharmaceuticals Intl, Warner-Chilcott, XenoPort, and ZAGE. Dr Koo has served as a scientific advisor and/or speaker to AbbVie, Amgen, Eli Lilly, UCB, Ortho Dermatologics, Sun Pharmaceutical Industries, Janssen, LEO Pharma, and EpiPharm. Dr Lewitt has served as a consultant, advisor, and/or speaker to AbbVie, Lilly, Janssen, Pfizer, Galderma, UCB, Dermavant, and Ortho Dermatologics. Dr Liao has received research grant funding from AbbVie, Amgen, Janssen, LEO Pharma, Novartis, Pfizer, Regeneron, and TRex Bio. Dr Liu has received research grant funding from and/or served as a speaker or scientific advisor to AbbVie, Janssen, Lilly, Sanofi-Regeneron, Arcutis, Dermavant, Pfizer, Bristol Myers Squib, UCB, Incyte, Amgen, and Evelo. Dr Merola has served as a research investigator and/or consultant for AbbVie, Amgen, Eli Lilly, Novartis, Janssen, UCB, Sanofi, Regeneron, Biogen, Pfizer, BMS, Dermavant, and LEO Pharma. Dr Prussick has served as a speaker to AbbVie, Jenssen, Pfizer, and Amgen. Dr Reddy has served as a consultant to Novartis, AbbVie, Janssen, UCB; he has also received research grant funding from Pfizer. Dr Schwartzman has served as a consultant and/or speaker to AbbVie, Janssen, Lilly, Pfizer, UCB, Myriad, Novartis, Regeneron, Sanofi, UCB, Stelexis, Jubilant, and Teijin. Dr Soung has received speaker honoraria from AbbVie, Actelion, Amgen, Celgene, Dermira, Eli Lilly, National Psoriasis Foundation, Novartis, Ortho Dermatologics, and Regeneron; has received consulting/advisory board honoraria from Eli Lilly, LEO Pharma, and Novartis; and has received grant/research grant funding from AbbVie, Actavis, Actelion, Allergan, Boehringer Ingelheim, Cassiopea, Dr. Reddy&#x2019;s, Galderma, GSK, Janssen, Kadmon, Kyowa Kirin, LEO Pharma, Menlo, Novan, Novartis, Ortho Dermatologics, Pfizer, and UCB. Dr van Voorhees has received grants and research support from Lilly and AbbVie; she has also served as a consultant for Amgen, Boehringer Ingelheim, BMS, UCB, and Novartis. Dr Wallace has served as a research investigator for Pfizer, Target RWE, Kyowa, Amgen, Arcutis, and Argenx. Dr Weinberg has received research grant funding from and/or served as a consultant or speaker to Novartis, Lilly, Amgen, AbbVie, Sun Pharmaceutical, Janssen, and BMS. Dr Wine Lee has served as a research investigator, scientific advisor, consultant, and/or speaker to Eli Lilly, Sanofi, Regeneron, Pfizer, Trevi Therapeutics, AbbVie, Mayne Pharmaceuticals, Incyte, Castle Creek, Pyramid Bioscience, Amyrt, Krystal Biotech, Arcutis, Celgene, Target Pharma, Amgen, Novartis, UCB, Galderma, Kiniksa, Avita, Janssen, MoonLake Pharmaceuticals, and Timber Pharmaceuticals. Dr Yamauchi has served as an investigator for Amgen, Celgene, Dermira, Eli Lilly, Galderma, Janssen, LEO Pharma, MedImmune, Novartis, Pfizer, Regeneron and Sandoz; he has also served as an advisor and/or speaker to AbbVie, Amgen, Baxter, Celgene, Dermira, Eli Lilly, Galderma, Janssen, LEO Pharma, Novartis, Pfizer, and Regeneron. The other authors have no other conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calabrese</LastName><ForeName>Cassandra</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Desai</LastName><ForeName>Seemal R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duffin</LastName><ForeName>Kristina C</ForeName><Initials>KC</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Feldman</LastName><ForeName>Steven R</ForeName><Initials>SR</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gladman</LastName><ForeName>Dafna D</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glick</LastName><ForeName>Brad P</ForeName><Initials>BP</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Han</LastName><ForeName>George</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Harris</LastName><ForeName>Jason</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hawkes</LastName><ForeName>Jason E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hsu</LastName><ForeName>Sylvia</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Margaret Y</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalb</LastName><ForeName>Robert E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kircik</LastName><ForeName>Leon H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Koo</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lewitt</LastName><ForeName>G Michael</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liao</LastName><ForeName>Wilson J</ForeName><Initials>WJ</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Clive</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merola</LastName><ForeName>Joseph F</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prussick</LastName><ForeName>Ronald B</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reddy</LastName><ForeName>Soumya M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwartzman</LastName><ForeName>Sergio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Jessica N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Soung</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Voorhees</LastName><ForeName>Abby S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth B</ForeName><Initials>EB</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weinberg</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Lara Wine</ForeName><Initials>LW</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamauchi</LastName><ForeName>Paul S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37838256</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2023.09.080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0190-9622(23)02969-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>