<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40658734</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2133</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>193</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>17</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The British journal of dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Br J Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tape strips in inflammatory skin disease: a noninvasive method for molecular insights and personalized care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>839</StartPage><EndPage>846</EndPage><MedlinePgn>839-846</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/bjd/ljaf275</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Tape stripping, a skin-sampling technique that uses adhesives to collect cells from the stratum corneum, offers a minimally invasive method that provides valuable molecular insights into various skin and systemic diseases. Initially developed in the 1930s, tape stripping has evolved from a research tool into a validated method for omics research in clinical settings. In dermatology, tape strips have been validated to study chronic inflammatory skin disorders, such as atopic dermatitis, psoriasis and hidradenitis suppurativa, in addition to various cutaneous malignancies, providing insight into pathophysiology, aiding in disease differentiation, and tracking treatment response. Tape strips circumvent the pain, scarring, infection risk and follow-up requirements associated with traditional skin biopsies. Moreover, tape strips allow for higher enrolment rates for clinical trials and longitudinal studies, especially in the paediatric population where biopsies are particularly challenging. This tool has enabled researchers and clinicians to monitor disease activity and evaluate therapeutic response, especially in patients who cannot tolerate repetitive biopsies. Beyond skin conditions, tape strips are also being used to advance biomarker research in food allergy, asthma and other systemic and autoimmune diseases. They have also been used to assess epidermal and skin barrier restoration and transepidermal water loss. By facilitating data collection across diverse patient populations, tape strips are an important technological advancement towards precision medicine. As this technology continues to improve, tape stripping promises to become an asset in diagnosing and monitoring a wide range of diseases.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of British Association of Dermatologists. All rights reserved. For commercial re-use, please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service via the Permissions link on the article page on our site&#x2014;for further information please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, 1425 Madison Ave, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin D</ForeName><Initials>BD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, 1425 Madison Ave, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>Arnav</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, 1425 Madison Ave, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patel</LastName><ForeName>Dev</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, 1425 Madison Ave, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lau</LastName><ForeName>Megan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, 1425 Madison Ave, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Navrazhina</LastName><ForeName>Kristina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, 1425 Madison Ave, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>He</LastName><ForeName>Helen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, 1425 Madison Ave, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guttman-Yassky</LastName><ForeName>Emma</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, 1425 Madison Ave, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Br J Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0004041</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0007-0963</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057285" MajorTopicYN="N">Precision Medicine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D053832" MajorTopicYN="Y">Surgical Tape</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013048" MajorTopicYN="Y">Specimen Handling</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="N">instrumentation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003872" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatitis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Tape stripping is a sampling technique that uses adhesives to collect skin cells from people. Tape strips are changing how we study skin diseases. They provide a more comfortable alternative to skin biopsies. In contrast to tape stripping, skin biopsies involve cutting into the skin. This can cause pain, scarring and infection. Biopsies are especially difficult for children. This review summarizes recent evidence for using tape strips. We discuss how tape strips were originally used in skin cancer research to help identify melanoma (a type of skin cancer). Tape stripping can reduce the need for unnecessary biopsies. Subsequently, tape strips have been more broadly applied to other skin diseases. Tape strips help scientists to collect samples to examine immune activity. They can also be used to investigate skin barrier health, and other molecular changes in the skin. Tape strips are now used for conditions other than skin diseases. These include asthma and food allergies. Owing to their non-invasive nature, tape strips can enhance current research practices. The use of tape strips can allow patients who would normally not tolerate repeat biopsies to be included in clinical trials. In addition to helping diagnose diseases, tape strips have been used as tools to monitor treatment and disease outcomes. Our review article provides an overview of the use of tape strips. As technology advances, tape strips provide a fast and affordable way to collect important health data. They also help clinicians provide more personalized care for people. Overall, the use of tape strips could improve how researchers study and treat various conditions in dermatology.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2025. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of British Association of Dermatologists. All rights reserved. For commercial re-use, please contact reprints@oup.com for reprints and translation rights for reprints. All other permissions can be obtained through our RightsLink service via the Permissions link on the article page on our site&#x2014;for further information please contact journals.permissions@oup.com.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>Conflicts of interest: E.G.-Y. is an employee of Mount Sinai and has received research grants from and/or is a consultant for AbbVie, Arcutis, Almirall, Amgen, AnaptysBio, Apogee Therapeutics, Apollo Therapeutics Limited, Artax Biopharma Inc., Aslan, Astria, Bristol Meyers Squibb, Boerhinger Ingelhiem, Calliditas, Cara Therapeutics, Celldex, Centrexion Therapeutics Corporation, Concert, Connect Biopharm, Coty, DBV Technologies, Eli Lilly, Enveda Biosciences, Escient Pharmaceuticals, Inc., Fairmount Funds Management LLC, FL2022-001, Inc., Galderma, Gate Bio, Google Ventures (GV), GSK Immunology, Incyte, Inmagene, Janssen Biotech, Jasper Therapeutics, Kymera Therapeutics, Kyowa Kirin, Leo Pharma, Matchpoint Therapeutics, Merck, Nektar Therapeutics, Novartis Pharmaceuticals, NUMAB Therapeutics AG, Nuvig, OrbiMed Advisors LLC, OTSUKA, Pfizer, Pharmaxis Ltd, Pioneering Medicine VII, Inc., Proteologix US Inc, Q32Bio, RAPT, RayThera, Inc., Regeneron Pharmaceuticals, RibonTherapeutics, Inc., Rocatinlimab, SAGIMET Bioscieces, Sanofi, SATO, Schr&#xf6;dinger, Inc., Sitryx, Sun Pharma Advanced Research Company (SPARC), Takeda, Teva Branded Pharmaceutical Products R&amp;D, Inc, Trex, UCB and Ventyx Biosciences.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40658734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjd/ljaf275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">8200881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>