<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39648321</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1539-2570</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of pediatric orthopedics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Pediatr Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Who is the PROM King? Patient-reported Outcome Measures in Pediatric Musculoskeletal Oncology: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e378</StartPage><EndPage>e384</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e378-e384</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/BPO.0000000000002874</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs) are important companions to traditional, physician-reported measures. The purpose of this study was to systematically review and identify PROMs used in pediatric musculoskeletal oncology and evaluate these instruments.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A systematic literature review was conducted for studies pertaining to pediatric musculoskeletal tumors from 2010 to 2024. Two experts selected eligible papers for inclusion through a systematic approach. PROMs used in the eligible papers were cataloged, and the top 10 most frequently used instruments were evaluated with Evaluating Measures of Patient-Reported Outcomes (EMPRO), which is a standardized evaluation tool for PROs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 316 publications were included in the final analysis, reporting a total of 82 unique PROMs. Of the papers, 24% reported no PROMs, whereas 67% of the instruments were only reported once. Nine out of the 10 top PROMs scored over 50 on EMPRO, meeting the minimum acceptable criteria. Musculoskeletal Tumor Society, Toronto Extremity Salvage Score, Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder, and Hand (DASH), and Quick DASH were disease-specific instruments scoring high on EMPRO. Short Form-36, Pediatric Quality of Life Questionnaire, Quality of Life Questionnaire-30, BSI-18, and TNO AZL Child Quality Of Life met the requirements in the general instruments. Short Form-12 was the lowest-scored PROM.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results show minimal consensus on the ideal PROM in pediatric musculoskeletal oncology. We recommend using instruments that are already in widespread use instead of obscure PROMs, which defy the purpose of reporting outcomes from a patient perspective. All 4 disease-specific instruments scored highly and are already widely used, including Musculoskeletal Tumor Society, Toronto Extremity Salvage Score, DASH, and Quick DASH. However, we found no consensus on general instruments. With the development and increasing popularity of Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System, it may replace other general instruments that are proprietary, unreliable, or not developed with pediatric patients in mind.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LEVEL OF EVIDENCE" NlmCategory="METHODS">Level IV-systematic review of level II to IV studies.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baghdadi</LastName><ForeName>Soroush</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Orthopaedic Surgery, The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Van Eenenaam</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Suffix>Jr</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Orthopaedic Surgery, The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Talwar</LastName><ForeName>Divya</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Orthopaedic Surgery, The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arkader</LastName><ForeName>Alexandre</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7171-9835</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Orthopaedic Surgery, The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopedic Surgery, Perelman School of Medicine at the University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Pediatr Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8109053</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0271-6798</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071066" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Reported Outcome Measures</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001859" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bone Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019042" MajorTopicYN="Y">Muscle Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39648321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BPO.0000000000002874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01241398-202504000-00021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Garratt A, Schmidt L, Mackintosh A, et al. Quality of life measurement: bibliographic study of patient assessed health outcome measures. Brit Med J. 2002;324:1417.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leopold SS. Editorial: importance of validating the scores we use to assess patients with musculoskeletal tumors. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2019;477:669&#x2013;671.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hapsari HI, Huang M-C, Kanita MW. Evaluating self-concept measurements in adolescents: a systematic review. Children. 2023;10:399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gazendam AM, Schneider P, Bhandari M, et al. Defining minimally important differences in functional outcomes in musculoskeletal oncology. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2022;104:1659&#x2013;1666.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valderas JM, Ferrer M, Mend&#xed;vil J, et al. Development of EMPRO: a tool for the standardized assessment of patient-reported outcome measures. Value Health. 2008;11:700&#x2013;708.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukherjee AA, Kandhare AD, Bodhankar SL. Evaluation of health-related quality of life in hemolytic uraemic syndrome patients treated with eculizumab: a systematic evaluation on basis of EMPRO. Ren Fail. 2018;40:107&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt S, Ferrer M, Gonz&#xe1;lez M, et al. Evaluation of shoulder-specific patient-reported outcome measures: a systematic and standardized comparison of available evidence. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2014;23:434&#x2013;444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngwayi JRM, Obie KU, Tan J, et al. Chinese cross-culturally adapted patient-reported outcome measures (PROMs) for knee disorders: a systematic review and assessment using the Evaluating the Measurement of Patient-Reported Outcomes (EMPRO) instrument. J Orthop Surg Res. 2022;17:508.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amakoutou K, Liu RW. Current use of patient-reported outcomes in pediatric limb deformity surgery. J Pediatr Orthop B. 2021;30:399&#x2013;404.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarkis-Onofre R, Catal&#xe1;-L&#xf3;pez F, Aromataris E, et al. How to properly use the PRISMA Statement. Syst Rev. 2021;10:1&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takkouche B, Norman G. PRISMA statement. Epidemiology. 2011;22:128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baghdadi S, Yadav P, Banskota B, et al. Outcome measures in clubfoot. J Foot and Ankle Surgery (Asia Pacific). 2021;8:133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brodke DJ, Saltzman CL, Brodke DS. PROMIS for Orthopaedic Outcomes Measurement. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2016;24:744&#x2013;749.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enneking WF, Dunham W, Gebhardt MC, et al. A system for the functional evaluation of reconstructive procedures after surgical treatment of tumors of the musculoskeletal system. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1993;241:246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis AM, Wright JG, Williams JI, et al. Development of a measure of physical function for patients with bone and soft tissue sarcoma. Qual Life Res. 1996;5:508&#x2013;516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hudak PL, Amadio PC, Bombardier C, et al. Development of an upper extremity outcome measure: the DASH (disabilities of the arm, shoulder and hand) [corrected]. The Upper Extremity Collaborative Group (UECG). Am J Ind Med. 1996;29:602&#x2013;608.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beaton DE, Wright JG, Katz JN, et al; Upper Extremity Collaborative Group. Development of the QuickDASH: comparison of three item-reduction approaches. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2005;87:1038&#x2013;1046.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quatman-Yates CC, Gupta R, Paterno MV, et al. Internal consistency and validity of the QuickDASH instrument for upper extremity injuries in older children. J Pediatr Orthop. 2013;33:838&#x2013;842.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberghina F, Andreacchio A, Pavone V, et al. Review of pediatric functional outcomes measures used to evaluate surgical management in pediatric patients with an upper extremity fracture. J Pediatr Orthop B. 2022;31:260&#x2013;269.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenkinson C, Coulter A, Wright L. Short form 36 (SF36) health survey questionnaire: normative data for adults of working age. Brit Med J. 1993;306:1437&#x2013;1440.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware JE Jr, Kosinski M, Keller SD. A 12-Item Short-Form Health Survey: construction of scales and preliminary tests of reliability and validity. Med Care. 1996;34:220&#x2013;233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busija L, Osborne RH, Nilsdotter A, et al. Magnitude and meaningfulness of change in SF-36 scores in four types of orthopedic surgery. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2008;6:55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel AA, Donegan D, Albert T. The 36-item short form. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2007;15:126&#x2013;134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varni JW, Burwinkle TM, Seid M. The PedsQL as a pediatric patient-reported outcome: reliability and validity of the PedsQL Measurement Model in 25,000 children. Expert Rev Pharmacoecon Outcomes Res. 2005;5:705&#x2013;719.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>