<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34434535</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2001-6689</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of market access &amp; health policy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Mark Access Health Policy</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Cost-Effectiveness Analysis of a Prescription Digital Therapeutic for the Treatment of Opioid Use Disorder.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1966187</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1966187</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1966187</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/20016689.2021.1966187</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The lack of adequate treatment for many patients with opioid use disorder (OUD) has led to high medical costs ($90B in 2020). An analysis of the cost-effectiveness (cost-utility) of reSET-O, the first and only FDA-approved prescription digital therapeutic (PDT) for the treatment of OUD, is needed to inform value assessments and healthcare decision making. To evaluate the cost-utility of reSET-O in conjunction with treatment-as usual (TAU) compared to TAU alone. A third-party payer-perspective decision analytic model evaluated the cost-effectiveness of reSET-O +&#xa0;TAU relative to TAU (i.e., oral buprenorphine, face-to-face counseling, and contingency management [immediate rewards for negative drug tests logged]) alone over 12&#xa0;weeks. Clinical effectiveness data (retention in therapy and health state utilities) were obtained from the peer-reviewed literature, while resource utilization and cost data were obtained from a published claims data analyses. Over 12&#xa0;weeks, the addition of reSET-O to TAU resulted in a gain of 0.003 quality-adjusted life years (QALYs), and $1,014 lower costs, resulting in economic dominance vs. TAU. reSET-O +&#xa0;TAU's was economically dominant (less costly, more effective) vs. TAU alone over 12&#xa0;weeks, a result that was driven by a reduction in medical costs after initiation of reSET-O observed in a recent real-world claims analysis.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Author(s). Published by Informa UK Limited, trading as Taylor &amp; Francis Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Velez</LastName><ForeName>Fulton F</ForeName><Initials>FF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9054-5933</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pear Therapeutics, Inc, Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Malone</LastName><ForeName>Daniel C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5006-9394</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strategic Therapeutics, LLC, Oro Valley, AZ.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>J Mark Access Health Policy</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101670174</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2001-6689</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cost-effectiveness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cost-utility analysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opioid use disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescription digital therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">real-world evidence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">retention in therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34434535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20016689.2021.1966187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1966187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association (APA) . Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders (DSM-5). Arlington, VA, American Psychiatric Association;2013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudd RA, Seth P, David F, et al. Increases in Drug and Opioid-Involved Overdose Deaths - USA, 2010-2015. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2016;65(5051):1445&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28033313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) . Key substance use and mental health indicators in the USA: results from the 2018 National Survey on Drug Use and Health (HHS Publication No. PEP19-5068, NSDUH Series H-54). 2019; https://www.samhsa.gov/data/sites/default/files/cbhsq-reports/NSDUHNationalFindingsReport2018/NSDUHNationalFindingsReport2018.pdfAccessed2020 Sept
30</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Medical Association (AMA) . Issue brief: reports of increases in opioid-related overdose and other concerns during COVID pandemic. 2020. https://www.ama-assn.org/system/files/2020-09/issue-brief-increases-in-opioid-related-overdose.pdfAccessed2020 Sept
30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L-T, Zhu H, Swartz MS.. Treatment utilization among persons with opioid use disorder in the USA. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2016;169:117&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5223737</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27810654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S . Department of Health &amp; Human Services. Facing Addiction in America - The Surgeon General&#x2019;s Spotlight on Opioids. Washington, DC: HHS, September 2018..</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30860690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakeman SE, Larochelle MR, Ameli O, et al. Comparative effectiveness of different treatment pathways for opioid use disorder. JAMA Network Open. 2020;3(2):e1920622. e1920622-e1920622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11143463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32022884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubbard RL, Marsden ME, Rachal JV, et al. Drug abuse treatment: a national study of effectiveness. Chapel Hill, NC, US: University of North Carolina Press; 1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sells SB, Simpson DD. The case for drug abuse treatment effectiveness, based on the DARP research program. Br J Addict. 1980;75(2):117&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6930290</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anglin MD, Hser Y-I. Treatment of drug abuse. Crime and Justice. 1990;13: 393&#x2013;460.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ball JC, Ross A. The effectiveness of methadone maintenance treatment: patients, programs, services, and outcome. New York, NY, US: Springer-Verlag Publishing; 1991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Leon G. Psychopathology and substance abuse: what is being learned from research in therapeutic communities. J Psychoactive Drugs. 1989;21(2):177&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2668482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerstein DR, Harwood HJ, eds. Treating Drug Problems: volume 1: a Study of the Evolution, Effectiveness, and Financing of Public and Private Drug Treatment Systems. Washington DC: &#xa9; 1990 by the National Academy of Sciences; 1990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan AT, Alterman AI, Metzger DS, et al. Similarity of outcome predictors across opiate, cocaine, and alcohol treatments: role of treatment services. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1994;62(6):1141&#x2013;1158.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7860812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences Engineering and Medicine; Health and Medicine Division; Board on Health Sciences Policy; Committee on Medication-Assisted Treatment for Opioid Use Disorder . Barriers to Broader Use of Medications to Treat Opioid Use Disorder. Washington, DC: National Academies Press (US); 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences Engineering and Medicine . Medications for Opioid Use Disorder Save Lives. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press.2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30896911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy SM. The cost of opioid use disorder and the value of aversion. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2020 Dec 1;217:108382. Accessed June 25, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7737485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33183909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Premier . Opioid Overdoses Costing U.S. Hospitals an Estimated $11 Billion Annually. 2019. https://www.premierinc.com/newsroom/press-releases/opioid-overdoses-costing-u-s-hospitals-an-estimated-11-billion-annuallyAccessed2020 Jul
28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stark MJ. Dropping out of substance abuse treatment: a clinically oriented review. Clin Psychol Rev. 1992;12(1):93&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson DD. Treatment for drug abuse. Follow-up outcomes and length of time spent. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1981;38(8):875&#x2013;880.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7259424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kang SY, Kleinman PH, Woody GE, et al. Outcomes for cocaine abusers after once-a-week psychosocial therapy. Am J Psychiatry. 1991;148(5):630&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1850208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PM. Attrition revisited. American Journal of Evaluation. 1998;19(3):293&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson DD, Joe GW, Brown BS. Treatment retention and follow-up outcomes in the Drug Abuse Treatment Outcome Study (DATOS). Psychol Addict Behav. 1997;11(4):294&#x2013;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen DR, Landes RD, Jackson L, et al. Adding an Internet-delivered treatment to an efficacious treatment package for opioid dependence. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2014;82(6):964&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4244262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25090043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pear Therapeutics Inc . reSET-O - Clinician Instructions for Use. 2019. https://peartherapeutics.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/08/PEAR-MKT-025-reSET-O-Clin-Brief-Sum_Dec2019.pdfAccessed2020 Aug
17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittenberg E, Bray JW, Aden B, et al. Measuring benefits of opioid misuse treatment for economic evaluation: health-related quality of life of opioid-dependent individuals and their spouses as assessed by a sample of the US population. Addiction. 2016;111(4):675&#x2013;684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5034732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26498740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyne JM, Tripathi S, French M, et al. Longitudinal association of preference-weighted health-related quality of life measures and substance use disorder outcomes. Addiction. 2011;106(3):507&#x2013;515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3076048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21205046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sindelar JL, Olmstead TA, Peirce JM. Cost-effectiveness of prize-based contingency management in methadone maintenance treatment programs. Addiction. 2007;102(9):1463&#x2013;1471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3072844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17645428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry NM, DePhilippis D, Rash CJ, et al. Nationwide dissemination of contingency management: the veterans administration initiative. Am J Addict. 2014;23(3):205&#x2013;210.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3986725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24724876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velez FF, Colman S, Kauffman L, et al. Real-world reduction in healthcare resource utilization following treatment of opioid use disorder with reSET-O, a novel prescription digital therapeutic. In: Expert Review of Pharmacoeconomics &amp; Outcomes Research (Under Review). In review; 2020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang W, Gellings-Lowe N, Jalali A, et al. Economic Modeling of reSET-O, a Prescription Digital Therapeutic for Patients with Opioid Use Disorder. J Med Econ. 2021 Jan-Dec;24(1):61-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33267633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute for Clinical and Economic Review (ICER) . Extended-Release Opioid Agonists and Antagonist Medications for Addiction Treatment (MAT) in Patients with Opioid Use Disorder: effectiveness and Value. 2018. https://icer-review.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/ICER_Opioid_Use_Disorder_Draft_Evidence_Report_090718-1.pdfAccessed2020 Sept
23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan AT, Arndt IO, Metzger DS, et al. The effects of psychosocial services in substance abuse treatment. JAMA. 1993;269(15):1953&#x2013;1959.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8385230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsch LA, Dallery J. Advances in the psychosocial treatment of addiction: the role of technology in the delivery of evidence-based psychosocial treatment. Psychiatr Clin North Am. 2012;35(2):481&#x2013;493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3362794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22640767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pincus HA, England MJ. Improving the Quality of Psychosocial Interventions for Mental and Substance Use Disorders: a Report From the IOM. JAMA. 2015;314(12):1227&#x2013;1228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26181890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruetsch C, Tkacz J, Nadipelli VR, et al. Heterogeneity of nonadherent buprenorphine patients: subgroup characteristics and outcomes. Am J Manag Care. 2017;23(6):e172-e179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28817294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ronquest NA, Willson TM, Montejano LB, et al. Relationship between buprenorphine adherence and relapse, health care utilization and costs in privately and publicly insured patients with opioid use disorder. Subst Abuse Rehabil. 2018;9:59&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6165853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30310349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tkacz J, Volpicelli J, Un H, et al. Relationship between buprenorphine adherence and health service utilization and costs among opioid dependent patients. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2014;46(4):456&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24332511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA) . Effective Treatments for Opioid Addiction. 2016; www.drugabuse.gov/publications/effective-treatments-opioid-addiction/effective-treatments-opioid-addictionAccessed2020 Sept
20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA) . Principles of Drug Addiction Treatment: a Research-Based Guide (Third Edition). 2018. https://d14rmgtrwzf5a.cloudfront.net/sites/default/files/675-principles-of-drug-addiction-treatment-a-research-based-guide-third-edition.pdf. Accessed2020 Sept
20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones CM, McCance-Katz EF. Co-occurring substance use and mental disorders among adults with opioid use disorder. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2019;197:78&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30784952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen H, Batterham PJ, Gosling JA, et al. Effectiveness of an online insomnia program (SHUTi) for prevention of depressive episodes (the GoodNight Study): a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Psychiatry. 2016;3(4):333&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritterband LM, Thorndike FP, Ingersoll KS, et al. Effect of a Web-Based Cognitive Behavior Therapy for Insomnia Intervention With 1-Year Follow-up: a Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2017;74(1):68&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27902836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velez FF, Luderer HF, Gerwien R, et al. Evaluation of the cost-utility of a prescription digital therapeutic for the treatment of opioid use disorder. Postgrad Med. 2021;133(4):421&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33593201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Council of Economic Advisers . The underestimated cost of the opioid crisis. 2017. https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefings-statements/cea-report-underestimated-cost-opioid-crisis/</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>