<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36459399</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2291-5222</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR mHealth and uHealth</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Mhealth Uhealth</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Preliminary Use and Outcome Data of a Digital Home Exercise Program for Back, Hip, and Knee Pain: Retrospective Observational Study With a Time Series and Matched Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e38649</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e38649</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e38649</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/38649</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Musculoskeletal conditions are among the main contributors to the global burden of disease. International guidelines consider patient education and movement exercises as the preferred therapeutic option for unspecific and degenerative musculoskeletal conditions. Innovative and decentralized therapeutic means are required to provide access to and availability of such care to meet the increasing therapeutic demand for this spectrum of conditions.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This retrospective observational study of preliminary use and outcome data explores the clinical outcomes of Vivira (hereafter referred to as "program"), a smartphone-based program for unspecific and degenerative pain in the back, hip, and knee before it received regulatory approval for use in the German statutory health insurance system.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">An incomplete matched block design was employed to assess pain score changes over the intended 12-week duration of the program. Post hoc analyses were performed. In addition, a matched comparison of self-reported functional scores and adherence rates is presented.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 2517 participants met the inclusion criteria and provided sufficient data to be included in the analyses. Overall, initial self-reported pain scores decreased significantly from an average of 5.19 out of 10 (SD 1.96) to an average of 3.35 out of 10 (SD 2.38) after 12 weeks. Post hoc analyses indicate a particularly emphasized pain score reduction over the early use phases. Additionally, participants with back pain showed significant improvements in strength and mobility scores, whereas participants with hip or knee pain demonstrated significant improvements in their coordination scores. Across all pain areas and pain durations, a high yet expected attrition rate could be observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This observational study provides the first insights into the clinical outcomes of an exercise program for unspecific and degenerative back, hip, and knee pain. Furthermore, it demonstrates a potential secondary benefit of improved functionality (ie, strength, mobility, coordination). However, as this study lacks confirmatory power, further research is required to substantiate the clinical outcomes of the program assessed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">German Clinical Trials Register DRKS00021785; https://drks.de/search/en/trial/DRKS00021785.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Gisbert Wilhelm Teepe, Tobias Kowatsch, Felix Patricius Hans, Leo Benning. Originally published in JMIR mHealth and uHealth (https://mhealth.jmir.org), 02.12.2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teepe</LastName><ForeName>Gisbert Wilhelm</ForeName><Initials>GW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2264-9797</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Digital Health Interventions, ETH Z&#xfc;rich, Z&#xfc;rich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kowatsch</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5939-4145</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Digital Health Interventions, ETH Z&#xfc;rich, Z&#xfc;rich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Implementation Science in Health Care, University of Z&#xfc;rich, Z&#xfc;rich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Medicine, University of St.Gallen, St.Gallen, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hans</LastName><ForeName>Felix Patricius</ForeName><Initials>FP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7164-7624</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Emergency Center, Medical Center - University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benning</LastName><ForeName>Leo</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8429-9702</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University Emergency Center, Medical Center - University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Vivira Health Lab GmbH, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>DRKS</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>DRKS00021785</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Mhealth Uhealth</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101624439</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2291-5222</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010146" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009140" MajorTopicYN="Y">Musculoskeletal Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">back pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hip pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">home exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knee pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">musculoskeletal conditions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pain</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smartphone</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: GWT and TK are affiliated with the Center for Digital Health Interventions, a joint initiative of the Institute for Implementation Science in Health Care, University of Zurich; the Department of Management, Technology, and Economics at Swiss Federal Institute of Technology in Z&#xfc;rich; and the Institute of Technology Management and School of Medicine at the University of St Gallen, which is funded in part by the Swiss health insurer CSS. CSS is not involved in any way in this study. TK is also cofounder of Pathmate Technologies, a university spin-off company that creates and delivers digital clinical pathways. However, Pathmate Technologies was not involved in this study. LB is affiliated with Vivira Health Lab GmbH, the developer of the software examined. Vivira Health Lab GmbH did not make any financial contributions to support the analysis or the publication of this manuscript. FPH has no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36459399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9758631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/38649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v10i12e38649</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Vos T, Lim SS, Abbafati C, Abbas KM, Abbasi M, Abbasifard M, Abbasi-Kangevari M, Abbastabar H, Abd-Allah F, Abdelalim A, Abdollahi M, Abdollahpour I, Abolhassani H, Aboyans V, Abrams EM, Abreu LG, Abrigo MRM, Abu-Raddad LJ, Abushouk AI, Acebedo A, Ackerman IN, Adabi M, Adamu AA, Adebayo OM, Adekanmbi V, Adelson JD, Adetokunboh OO, Adham D, Afshari M, Afshin A, Agardh EE, Agarwal G, Agesa KM, Aghaali M, Aghamir SMK, Agrawal A, Ahmad T, Ahmadi A, Ahmadi M, Ahmadieh H, Ahmadpour E, Akalu TY, Akinyemi RO, Akinyemiju T, Akombi B, Al-Aly Z, Alam K, Alam N, Alam S, Alam T, Alanzi TM, Albertson SB, Alcalde-Rabanal JE, Alema NM, Ali M, Ali S, Alicandro G, Alijanzadeh M, Alinia C, Alipour V, Aljunid SM, Alla F, Allebeck P, Almasi-Hashiani A, Alonso J, Al-Raddadi RM, Altirkawi KA, Alvis-Guzman N, Alvis-Zakzuk NJ, Amini S, Amini-Rarani M, Aminorroaya A, Amiri F, Amit AML, Amugsi DA, Amul GGH, Anderlini D, Andrei CL, Andrei T, Anjomshoa M, Ansari F, Ansari I, Ansari-Moghaddam A, Antonio CAT, Antony CM, Antriyandarti E, Anvari D, Anwer R, Arabloo J, Arab-Zozani M, Aravkin AY, Ariani F, &#xc4;rnl&#xf6;v J, Aryal KK, Arzani A, Asadi-Aliabadi M, Asadi-Pooya AA, Asghari B, Ashbaugh C, Atnafu DD, Atre SR, Ausloos F, Ausloos M, Ayala Quintanilla BP, Ayano G, Ayanore MA, Aynalem YA, Azari S, Azarian G, Azene ZN, Babaee E, Badawi A, Bagherzadeh M, Bakhshaei MH, Bakhtiari A, Balakrishnan S, Balalla S, Balassyano S, Banach M, Banik PC, Bannick MS, Bante AB, Baraki AG, Barboza MA, Barker-Collo SL, Barthelemy CM, Barua L, Barzegar A, Basu S, Baune BT, Bayati M, Bazmandegan G, Bedi N, Beghi E, B&#xe9;jot Y, Bello AK, Bender RG, Bennett DA, Bennitt FB, Bensenor IM, Benziger CP, Berhe K, Bernabe E, Bertolacci GJ, Bhageerathy R, Bhala N, Bhandari D, Bhardwaj P, Bhattacharyya K, Bhutta ZA, Bibi S, Biehl MH, Bikbov B, Bin Sayeed MS, Biondi A, Birihane BM, Bisanzio D, Bisignano C, Biswas RK, Bohlouli S, Bohluli M, Bolla SRR, Boloor A, Boon-Dooley AS, Borges G, Borz&#xec; AM, Bourne R, Brady OJ, Brauer M, Brayne C, Breitborde NJK, Brenner H, Briant PS, Briggs AM, Briko NI, Britton GB, Bryazka D, Buchbinder R, Bumgarner BR, Busse R, Butt ZA, Caetano dos Santos FL, C&#xe1;mera LLA, Campos-Nonato IR, Car J, C&#xe1;rdenas R, Carreras G, Carrero JJ, Carvalho F, Castaldelli-Maia JM, Casta&#xf1;eda-Orjuela CA, Castelpietra G, Castle CD, Castro F, Catal&#xe1;-L&#xf3;pez F, Causey K, Cederroth CR, Cercy KM, Cerin E, Chandan JS, Chang AR, Charlson FJ, Chattu VK, Chaturvedi S, Chimed-Ochir O, Chin KL, Cho DY, Christensen H, Chu D, Chung MT, Cicuttini FM, Ciobanu LG, Cirillo M, Collins EL, Compton K, Conti S, Cortesi PA, Costa VM, Cousin E, Cowden RG, Cowie BC, Cromwell EA, Cross DH, Crowe CS, Cruz JA, Cunningham M, Dahlawi SMA, Damiani G, Dandona L, Dandona R, Darwesh AM, Daryani A, Das JK, Das Gupta R, das Neves J, D&#xe1;vila-Cervantes CA, Davletov K, De Leo D, Dean FE, DeCleene NK, Deen A, Degenhardt L, Dellavalle RP, Demeke FM, Demsie DG, Denova-Guti&#xe9;rrez E, Dereje ND, Dervenis N, Desai R, Desalew A, Dessie GA, Dharmaratne SD, Dhungana GP, Dianatinasab M, Diaz D, Dibaji Forooshani ZS, Dingels ZV, Dirac MA, Djalalinia S, Do HT, Dokova K, Dorostkar F, Doshi CP, Doshmangir L, Douiri A, Doxey MC, Driscoll TR, Dunachie SJ, Duncan BB, Duraes AR, Eagan AW, Ebrahimi Kalan M, Edvardsson D, Ehrlich JR, El Nahas N, El Sayed I, El Tantawi M, Elbarazi I, Elgendy IY, Elhabashy HR, El-Jaafary SI, Elyazar IR, Emamian MH, Emmons-Bell S, Erskine HE, Eshrati B, Eskandarieh S, Esmaeilnejad S, Esmaeilzadeh F, Esteghamati A, Estep K, Etemadi A, Etisso AE, Farahmand M, Faraj A, Fareed M, Faridnia R, Farinha CSES, Farioli A, Faro A, Faruque M, Farzadfar F, Fattahi N, Fazlzadeh M, Feigin VL, Feldman R, Fereshtehnejad S, Fernandes E, Ferrari AJ, Ferreira ML, Filip I, Fischer F, Fisher JL, Fitzgerald R, Flohr C, Flor LS, Foigt NA, Folayan MO, Force LM, Fornari C, Foroutan M, Fox JT, Freitas M, Fu W, Fukumoto T, Furtado JM, Gad MM, Gakidou E, Galles NC, Gallus S, Gamkrelidze A, Garcia-Basteiro AL, Gardner WM, Geberemariyam BS, Gebrehiwot AM, Gebremedhin KB, Gebreslassie AAAA, Gershberg Hayoon A, Gething PW, Ghadimi M, Ghadiri K, Ghafourifard M, Ghajar A, Ghamari F, Ghashghaee A, Ghiasvand H, Ghith N, Gholamian A, Gilani SA, Gill PS, Gitimoghaddam M, Giussani G, Goli S, Gomez RS, Gopalani SV, Gorini G, Gorman TM, Gottlich HC, Goudarzi H, Goulart AC, Goulart BNG, Grada A, Grivna M, Grosso G, Gubari MIM, Gugnani HC, Guimaraes ALS, Guimar&#xe3;es RA, Guled RA, Guo G, Guo Y, Gupta R, Haagsma JA, Haddock B, Hafezi-Nejad N, Hafiz A, Hagins H, Haile LM, Hall BJ, Halvaei I, Hamadeh RR, Hamagharib Abdullah K, Hamilton EB, Han C, Han H, Hankey GJ, Haro JM, Harvey JD, Hasaballah AI, Hasanzadeh A, Hashemian M, Hassanipour S, Hassankhani H, Havmoeller RJ, Hay RJ, Hay SI, Hayat K, Heidari B, Heidari G, Heidari-Soureshjani R, Hendrie D, Henrikson HJ, Henry NJ, Herteliu C, Heydarpour F, Hird TR, Hoek HW, Hole MK, Holla R, Hoogar P, Hosgood HD, Hosseinzadeh M, Hostiuc M, Hostiuc S, Househ M, Hoy DG, Hsairi M, Hsieh VC, Hu G, Huda TM, Hugo FN, Huynh CK, Hwang B, Iannucci VC, Ibitoye SE, Ikuta KS, Ilesanmi OS, Ilic IM, Ilic MD, Inbaraj LR, Ippolito H, Irvani SSN, Islam MM, Islam M, Islam SMS, Islami F, Iso H, Ivers RQ, Iwu CCD, Iyamu IO, Jaafari J, Jacobsen KH, Jadidi-Niaragh F, Jafari H, Jafarinia M, Jahagirdar D, Jahani MA, Jahanmehr N, Jakovljevic M, Jalali A, Jalilian F, James SL, Janjani H, Janodia MD, Jayatilleke AU, Jeemon P, Jenabi E, Jha RP, Jha V, Ji JS, Jia P, John O, John-Akinola YO, Johnson CO, Johnson SC, Jonas JB, Joo T, Joshi A, Jozwiak JJ, J&#xfc;risson M, Kabir A, Kabir Z, Kalani H, Kalani R, Kalankesh LR, Kalhor R, Kamiab Z, Kanchan T, Karami Matin B, Karch A, Karim MA, Karimi SE, Kassa GM, Kassebaum NJ, Katikireddi SV, Kawakami N, Kayode GA, Keddie SH, Keller C, Kereselidze M, Khafaie MA, Khalid N, Khan M. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30925-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30925-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bevan S. Economic impact of musculoskeletal disorders (MSDs) on work in Europe. Best Pract Res Clin Rheumatol. 2015 Jun;29(3):356&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1016/j.berh.2015.08.002.S1521-6942(15)00094-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.berh.2015.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26612235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCallum CA. Access to physical therapy services among medically underserved adults: a mixed-method study. Phys Ther. 2010 May;90(5):735&#x2013;47. doi: 10.2522/ptj.20090242.ptj.20090242</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2522/ptj.20090242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20338917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foster NE, Anema JR, Cherkin D, Chou R, Cohen SP, Gross DP, Ferreira PH, Fritz JM, Koes BW, Peul W, Turner JA, Maher CG, Buchbinder R, Hartvigsen J, Cherkin D, Foster NE, Maher CG, Underwood M, van Tulder M, Anema JR, Chou R, Cohen SP, Menezes Costa L, Croft P, Ferreira M, Ferreira PH, Fritz JM, Genevay S, Gross DP, Hancock MJ, Hoy D, Karppinen J, Koes BW, Kongsted A, Louw Q, &#xd6;berg B, Peul WC, Pransky G, Schoene M, Sieper J, Smeets RJ, Turner JA, Woolf A. Prevention and treatment of low back pain: evidence, challenges, and promising directions. Lancet. 2018 Jun;391(10137):2368&#x2013;2383. doi: 10.1016/s0140-6736(18)30489-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(18)30489-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29573872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayden JA, van Tulder MW, Tomlinson G. Systematic review: strategies for using exercise therapy to improve outcomes in chronic low back pain. Ann Intern Med. 2005 May 03;142(9):776&#x2013;85. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-142-9-200505030-00014.142/9/776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-142-9-200505030-00014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15867410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Gool CH, Penninx BWJH, Kempen GIJM, Rejeski WJ, Miller GD, van Eijk JTM, Pahor M, Messier SP. Effects of exercise adherence on physical function among overweight older adults with knee osteoarthritis. Arthritis Rheum. 2005 Feb 15;53(1):24&#x2013;32. doi: 10.1002/art.20902. doi: 10.1002/art.20902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.20902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15696558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf6;nninghoff A, Kramer JN, Hess AJ, Ismailova K, Teepe GW, Tudor Car L, M&#xfc;ller-Riemenschneider F, Kowatsch T. Long-term effectiveness of mHealth physical activity interventions: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Med Internet Res. 2021 Apr 30;23(4):e26699. doi: 10.2196/26699. 
 
v23i4e26699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/26699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira CB, Franco MR, Maher CG, Christine Lin C, Morelh&#xe3;o PK, Ara&#xfa;jo AC, Negr&#xe3;o Filho RF, Pinto RZ. Physical activity interventions for increasing objectively measured physical activity levels in patients with chronic musculoskeletal pain: a systematic review. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2016 Dec 28;68(12):1832&#x2013;1842. doi: 10.1002/acr.22919. doi: 10.1002/acr.22919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.22919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27111744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghadir AH, Anwer S, Iqbal A, Iqbal ZA. Test-retest reliability, validity, and minimum detectable change of visual analog, numerical rating, and verbal rating scales for measurement of osteoarthritic knee pain. J Pain Res. 2018;11:851&#x2013;856. doi: 10.2147/JPR.S158847. doi: 10.2147/JPR.S158847.jpr-11-851</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/JPR.S158847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5927184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29731662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hjermstad MJ, Fayers PM, Haugen DF, Caraceni A, Hanks GW, Loge JH, Fainsinger R, Aass N, Kaasa S, European Palliative Care Research Collaborative (EPCRC)  Studies comparing numerical rating scales, verbal rating scales, and visual analogue scales for assessment of pain intensity in adults: a systematic literature review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2011 Jun;41(6):1073&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2010.08.016. 
 
S0885-3924(11)00014-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2010.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21621130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatfield M, Mander A. The Skillings&#x2013;Mack test (Friedman test when there are missing data) Stata J. 2009 Aug 01;9(2):299&#x2013;305. doi: 10.1177/1536867x0900900208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1536867x0900900208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2761045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19829764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schellenberg KL, Lang JM, Chan KM, Burnham RS. A clinical tool for office assessment of lumbar spine stabilization endurance: prone and supine bridge maneuvers. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2007 May;86(5):380&#x2013;386. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0b013e318032156a.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0b013e318032156a</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17303961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong TK, Wu S, Nie J. Sport-specific endurance plank test for evaluation of global core muscle function. Phys Ther Sport. 2014 Feb;15(1):58&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1016/j.ptsp.2013.03.003.S1466-853X(13)00015-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ptsp.2013.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23850461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bennell K, Talbot R, Wajswelner H, Techovanich W, Kelly D, Hall A. Intra-rater and inter-rater reliability of a weight-bearing lunge measure of ankle dorsiflexion. Aust J Physiother. 1998;44(3):175&#x2013;180. doi: 10.1016/s0004-9514(14)60377-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0004-9514(14)60377-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11676731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook G, Burton L, Hoogenboom B. Pre-participation screening: the use of fundamental movements as an assessment of function - part 1. N Am J Sports Phys Ther. 2006 May;1(2):62&#x2013;72. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2953313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21522216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nugraha B, Gutenbrunner C, Barke A, Karst M, Schiller J, Sch&#xe4;fer P, Falter S, Korwisi B, Rief W, Treede R, IASP Taskforce for the Classification of Chronic Pain The IASP classification of chronic pain for ICD-11: functioning properties of chronic pain. Pain. 2019 Jan;160(1):88&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1097/j.pain.0000000000001433.00006396-201901000-00012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000001433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30586076</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da C Menezes Costa L, Maher CG, Hancock MJ, McAuley JH, Herbert RD, Costa LO. The prognosis of acute and persistent low-back pain: a meta-analysis. CMAJ. 2012 Aug 07;184(11):E613&#x2013;24. doi: 10.1503/cmaj.111271. 
 
cmaj.111271</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/cmaj.111271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3414626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22586331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Itz C, Geurts J, van Kleef M, Nelemans P. Clinical course of non-specific low back pain: a systematic review of prospective cohort studies set in primary care. Eur J Pain. 2013 Jan 28;17(1):5&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1002/j.1532-2149.2012.00170.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/j.1532-2149.2012.00170.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22641374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von der Lippe E, Krause L, Prost M, Wengler A, Leddin J, M&#xfc;ller A. Pr&#xe4;valenz von r&#xfc;cken- und nackenschmerzen in Deutschland. Ergebnisse der krankheitslast-studie BURDEN 2020. Robert Koch Institut. 2021 Mar 10;:2021. doi: 10.25646/7854.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25646/7854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumel A, Muench F, Edan S, Kane JM. Objective user engagement with mental health apps: systematic search and panel-based usage analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2019 Sep 25;21(9):e14567. doi: 10.2196/14567. 
 
v21i9e14567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6785720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31573916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleming T, Bavin L, Lucassen M, Stasiak K, Hopkins S, Merry S. Beyond the trial: systematic review of real-world uptake and engagement with digital self-help interventions for depression, low mood, or anxiety. J Med Internet Res. 2018 Jun 06;20(6):e199. doi: 10.2196/jmir.9275. 
 
v20i6e199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.9275</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6010835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29875089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansfield A, Addis M, Mahalik J. "Why won't he go to the doctor?": The psychology of men's help seeking. JOMH. 2003 May 1;2(2):93&#x2013;109. doi: 10.3149/jmh.0202.93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3149/jmh.0202.93</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jennings PA, Cameron P, Bernard S. Measuring acute pain in the prehospital setting. Emerg Med J. 2009 Aug 22;26(8):552&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1136/emj.2008.062539.26/8/552</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/emj.2008.062539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19625547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bunting J, Withers T, Heneghan N, Greaves C. Digital interventions for promoting exercise adherence in chronic musculoskeletal pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Physiotherapy. 2021 Jun;111:23&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1016/j.physio.2020.08.001.S0031-9406(20)30403-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.physio.2020.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33316865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hewitt S, Sephton R, Yeowell G. The effectiveness of digital health interventions in the management of musculoskeletal conditions: systematic literature review. J Med Internet Res. 2020 Jun 05;22(6):e15617. doi: 10.2196/15617. 
 
v22i6e15617</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/15617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32501277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toelle TR, Utpadel-Fischler DA, Haas K, Priebe JA. App-based multidisciplinary back pain treatment versus combined physiotherapy plus online education: a randomized controlled trial. NPJ Digit Med. 2019 May 3;2(1):34. doi: 10.1038/s41746-019-0109-x. doi: 10.1038/s41746-019-0109-x.109</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-019-0109-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6550294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31304380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shebib R, Bailey JF, Smittenaar P, Perez DA, Mecklenburg G, Hunter S. Randomized controlled trial of a 12-week digital care program in improving low back pain. NPJ Digit Med. 2019 Jan 7;2(1):1. doi: 10.1038/s41746-018-0076-7. doi: 10.1038/s41746-018-0076-7.76</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-018-0076-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6550254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31304351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>