<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">24394216</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2014</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1660-4601</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of environmental research and public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Environ Res Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Smoke-free laws and direct democracy initiatives on smoking bans in Germany: a systematic review and quantitative assessment.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>685</StartPage><EndPage>700</EndPage><MedlinePgn>685-700</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ijerph110100685</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Germany's 16 states regulate smoking differently within health protection principles laid down in the federal law. All state smoke-free laws in Germany have undergone at least one change since taking effect.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We systematically review federal and state laws regulating smoking, as well as petitions, popular initiatives and referenda that aimed at changing statutory smoking bans. Data generated through the systematic review were correlated with state smoking rates.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The protection from the dangers of secondhand smoke is the primary motive for smoking bans in Germany. The first smoke-free laws affecting smoking in pubs, restaurants and several other public places were introduced in 2007. In 2008, the Federal Constitutional Court of Germany ruled in a leading decision on the smoke-free laws of two states that some common smoking ban exemptions of the introduced smoke-free laws violate the basic right to freely exercise a profession and mandated revisions. All states but Bavaria and Saarland, whose smoking bans were more and less comprehensive than those judged by the constitutional court, respectively, needed to change the smoking ban exemptions to reconcile their smoke-free laws with the constitution. Direct democracy initiatives to change smoking bans were only successful in Bavaria in 2010, but a total of 15 initiatives by citizens' or interest groups attempted to influence non-smokers protection legislation through direct democratic procedures. Early ratification of a smoking ban in a federal state correlates with a higher reduction in the smoking rate from 2005 to 2009 (Spearman's &#x3c1; = 0.51, p = 0.04).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The federal government structure and direct democratic participation in smoke-free legislation in Germany has produced a diversity of local smoking bans and exemptions.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kohler</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Social Medicine, Epidemiology and Health Economics, Charit&#xe9; University Medical Center, Berlin 10117, Germany. stefan.kohler@charite.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Minkner</LastName><ForeName>Philipp</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Social Medicine, Epidemiology and Health Economics, Charit&#xe9; University Medical Center, Berlin 10117, Germany. philipp.minkner@charite.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Environ Res Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101238455</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1660-4601</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003709" MajorTopicYN="N">Democracy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006076" MajorTopicYN="N">Government</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012907" MajorTopicYN="N">Smoking</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="N">economics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000331" MajorTopicYN="Y">legislation &amp; jurisprudence</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2013</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2013</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2014</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24394216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3924468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph110100685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ijerph110100685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Keil U., Heidrich J., Wellmann J., Heuschmann P. Rote Reihe Tabakpr&#xe4;vention und Tabakkontrolle, Band 5. Deutsches Krebsforschungszentrum; Heidelberg, Germany: 2005. Passivrauchbedingte Morbidit&#xe4;t und Mortalit&#xe4;t in Deutschland (Passive Smoking Related Morbidity and Mortality in Germany) pp. 20&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller S., Kraus L., Piontek D., Pabst A. Changes in exposure to secondhand smoke and smoking behavior. Sucht. 2010;56:373&#x2013;384. doi: 10.1024/0939-5911/a000048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1024/0939-5911/a000048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraus L., Pabst A., Piontek D., M&#xfc;ller S. Kurzbericht Epidemiologischer Suchtsurvey 2009&#x2014;Tabellenband: Pr&#xe4;valenz von Tabakkonsum, Nikotinabh&#xe4;ngigkeit und Passivrauchen nach Geschlecht und Alter im Jahr 2009 (Prevalence of Tobacco Use, Nicotine Dependence and Passive Smoking by Sex and Age in 2009) Institut f&#xfc;r Therapieforschung; M&#xfc;nchen, Germany: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schenk M., Schaller K., P&#xf6;tschke-Langer M. Fakten zum Rauchen: Tabakrauch&#x2014;Ein Giftgemisch (Facts about Smoking: Tobacco Smoke&#x2014;A Toxic Mixture) Deutsches Krebsforschungszentrum; Heidelberg, Germany: 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair U., Thielmann H.W., P&#xf6;tschke-Langer M. Fakten zum Rauchen: Krebserzeugende Substanzen im Tabakrauch (Facts about Smoking: Carcinogenic Substances in Tobacco Smoke) Deutsches Krebsforschungszentrum; Heidelberg, Germany: 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control. World Health Organization; Geneva, Swizerland: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joossens L., Raw M. Progress in Tobacco Control in 30 European Countries, 2005 to 2007. Association of European Cancer Leagues; Brussels, Belgium: 2007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joossens L., Raw M. The Tobacco Control Scale 2010 in Europe. Association of European Cancer Leagues; Brussels, Belgium: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verlag C.H. Beck-online&#x2014;Die Datenbank (The Database)  [(accessed on 2 December 2013)].  Available online:
 http://beck-online.beck.de/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zur Einf&#xfc;hrung eines Rauchverbotes in Einrichtungen des Bundes und &#xf6;ffentlichen Verkehrsmitteln (Bundesnichtraucherschutzgesetz) (Law for the introduction of a smoking ban in federal facilities and public transport (Federal non-smokers protection act)) Bundesgesetzblatt. 2007;I:1595&#x2013;1597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens (Law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking) Bundesgesetzblatt. 2007;I:1595&#x2013;1597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landesnichtraucherschutzgesetz (State non-smokers protection act) Gesetzesblatt f&#xfc;r Baden-W&#xfc;rttemberg. 2007:337&#x2013;339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz der Gesundheit (Gesundheitsschutzgesetz) (Law to protect health (Health protection act)) Bayerisches Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt. 2007:919&#x2013;921.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz der Gesundheit (Gesundheitsschutzgesetz) (Law to protect health (Health protection act)) Bayerisches Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt. 2010:314&#x2013;316.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens in der &#xd6;ffentlichkeit (Nichtraucherschutzgesetz) (Law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking in public (Non-smokers protection act)) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r Berlin. 2007:578&#x2013;579.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens in der &#xd6;ffentlichkeit (Brandenburgisches Nichtrauchendenschutzgesetz) (Law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking in public (Brandenburg non-smokers protection act)) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r das Land Brandenburg. 2007;I:346&#x2013;347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bremisches Nichtraucherschutzgesetz (Bremen non-smokers protection act) Gesetzblatt der Freien Hansestadt Bremen. 2007:515&#x2013;517.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamburgisches Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens in der &#xd6;ffentlichkeit (Hamburgisches Passivraucherschutzgesetz) (Hamburgian law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking in public (Hamburgian passive-smokers protection act)) Hamburgisches Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt. 2007;I:211&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens (Hessisches Nichtraucherschutzgesetz) (Law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking (Hessian non-smokers protection act)) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r das Land Hessen. 2007;I:568&#x2013;570.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichtraucherschutzgesetz Mecklenburg-Vorpommern (Non-smokers protection act Mecklenburg-Western Pomerania) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r Mecklenburg-Vorpommern. 2007:239&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieders&#xe4;chsisches Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens (Nieders&#xe4;chsisches Nichtraucherschutzgesetz) (Lower saxony law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking (Lower saxony non-smokers protection act)) Nieders&#xe4;chsisches Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt. 2007:337&#x2013;338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zur Verbesserung des Nichtraucherschutzes in Nordrhein-Westfalen (Law to improve non-smokers protection in North Rhine-Westphalia) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r das Land Nordrhein-Westfalen. 2007:742&#x2013;743.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichtraucherschutzgesetz Rheinland-Pfalz (Non-smokers protection act Rhineland-Palatinate) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r das Land Rheinland-Pfalz. 2007:534&#x2013;536.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens (Nichtraucherschutzgesetz) (Law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking (Non-smokers protection act)) Amtsblatt des Saarlandes. 2008;I:75&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zur Wahrung des Nichtraucherschutzes im Land Sachsen-Anhalt (Nichtraucherschutzgesetz) (Law to preserve non-smokers protection in the state of Saxony-Anhalt (Non-smokers protection act)) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r das Land Sachsen-Anhalt. 2007:464&#x2013;465.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz von Nichtrauchern im Freistaat Sachsen (S&#xe4;chsisches Nichtraucherschutzgesetz) (Law on the protection of non-smokers in the free state of Saxony (Saxon non-smokers protection act)) S&#xe4;chsisches Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt. 2007:495&#x2013;496.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens (Law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r Schleswig-Holstein. 2007:485&#x2013;486.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Th&#xfc;ringer Gesetz zum Schutz vor den Gefahren des Passivrauchens (Thuringian law to protect against the dangers of passive smoking) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r den Freistaat Th&#xfc;ringen. 2007:257&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parlamentsspiegel.de&#x2014;Gemeinsames Informationssystem der Landesparlamente der Bundesrepublik Deutschland (Joint Information System of the State Parliaments of the Federal Republic of Germany)  [(accessed on 27 December 2013)].  Available online:
 http://www.parlamentsspiegel.de/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aktionsb&#xfc;ndnis Nichtrauchen e.V. Nichtraucherschutzgesetze der Einzelnen Bundesl&#xe4;nder (State Non-smokers Protection Laws)  [(accessed on 27 December 2013)].  Available online:
 http://www.abnr.de/index.php?article_id=18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bethke C. Nichtraucherschutzgesetze der Einzelnen Bundesl&#xe4;nder: Synopsen der L&#xe4;nderregelungen&#x2014;Gastst&#xe4;tten (Non-smokers Protection Laws of the Individual States: Synopses of State Regulations&#x2014;Pubs and Restaurants) Aktionsb&#xfc;ndnis Nichtrauchen e.V.; Berlin, Germany: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mach mit! Rauchfreies Saarland (Join! Smoke-free Saarland) Ministeriums f&#xfc;r Gesundheit und Verbraucherschutz; Saarbr&#xfc;cken, Germany: 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministerium f&#xfc;r Gesundheit, Emanzipation, Pflege und Alter des Landes Nordrhein-Westfalen. Fragen und Antworten zum Nichtraucherschutzgesetz Nordrhein-Westfalen (Questions and Answers Regarding the Smoke-free Law of North Rhine-Westphalia)  [(accessed on 27 December 2013)].  Available online:
 http://www.mgepa.nrw.de/gesundheit/praevention/nichtraucherschutz/fragen_und_antworten_zum_nichtraucherschutzgesetz_nordrhein-westfalen/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merk R. Geschlossene Gesellschaft! Zu den Grenzen des Nichtraucherschutzes (Private function! On the limits of non-smokers protection) Publicus. 2012;5:32&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volksbegehrensberichte 2000&#x2013;2002 (Referendum Reports 2000&#x2013;2002) Mehr Demokratie e.V.; Berlin, Germany: 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehmet F. Volksbegehrensberichte 2003&#x2013;2012 (Referendum Reports 2003&#x2013;2012) Mehr Demokratie e.V.; Berlin, Germany: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz &#xfc;ber Ordnungswidrigkeiten (Ordnungswidrigkeitengesetz) (Administrative offence act) Bundesgesetzblatt. 1987:602&#x2013;629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikrozensus&#x2014;Fragen zur Gesundheit: Rauchgewohnheiten der Bev&#xf6;lkerung 2009 (Microcensus&#x2014;Questions about Health: Smoking Habits of the Population 2009) Statistisches Bundesamt; Wiesbaden, Germany: 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deutsche Bahn. Hausordnung (Stand 06/2011) (House Rules (as of 06/2011))  [(accessed on 27 December 2013)].  Available online:
 http://www.deutschebahn.com/file/5122390/data/hausordnung.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jugendschutzgesetz (Youth protection act) Bundesgesetzblatt. 2002:2730&#x2013;2739.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verordnung &#xfc;ber Arbeitsst&#xe4;tten (Arbeitsst&#xe4;ttenverordnung) (Workplace regulations) Bundesgesetzblatt. 2004;I:2179&#x2013;2189.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichtraucherschutz in Hotellerie und Gastronomie (Non-smokers Protection in Hotels and Gastronomic Facilities) Deutscher Hotel- und Gastst&#xe4;ttenverband e.V., Bundesministerium f&#xfc;r Gesundheit und Soziale Sicherung; Berlin, Germany: 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erstes Gesetz zur &#xc4;nderung des Nichtraucherschutzgesetzes (First act to amend the non-smokers protection law) Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt f&#xfc;r Berlin. 2009;13:250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gesetz zur &#xc4;nderung des Gesundheitsschutzgesetzes (Law to change the health protection act) Bayerisches Gesetz- und Verordnungsblatt. 2009:384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rehmet F. Volksentscheid Ranking 2013 (Referendum Ranking 2013) Mehr Demokratie e.V.; Berlin, Germany: 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volksinitiative Frische Luft f&#xfc;r Berlin. Abgeordnetenhaus will Keinen Verbesserten Schutz vor Passivrauch (House of Representatives does not Want Better Protection against Passive Smoke)  [(accessed on 27 December 2013)].  Available online:
 http://www.forum-rauchfrei.de/files/Presseerklaerung_20.6.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mart&#xed;nez-S&#xe1;nchez J.M., Fern&#xe1;ndez E., Fu M., Gallus S., Mart&#xed;nez C., Sureda X., la Vecchia C., Clancy L. Smoking behaviour, involuntary smoking, attitudes towards smoke-free legislations, and tobacco control activities in the European Union. PLoS One. 2010;5 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0013881.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0013881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2975630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21079729</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mons U., Nagelhout G.E., Guignard R., McNeill A., van den Putte B., Willemsen M.C., Brenner H., P&#xf6;tschke-Langer M., Breitling L.P. Comprehensive smoke-free policies attract more support from smokers in Europe than partial policies. Eur. J. Public Health. 2012;22:S10&#x2013;S16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3269297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22294779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuband K.-H. Tabakkonsum im gesellschaftlichen Wandel. Verbreitung des Konsums und Einstellung zu Rauchverboten, D&#xfc;sseldorf 1997&#x2013;2009 (Tobacco consumption in a changing society. Extent of consumption and attitudes to smoking bans, D&#xfc;sseldorf 1997&#x2013;2009) Gesundheitswesen. in press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23564265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gleich F., Mons U., P&#xf6;tschke-Langer M. Air contamination due to smoking in German restaurants, bars, and other venues&#x2014;Before and after the implementation of a partial smoking ban. Nicotine Tob. Res. 2011;13:1155&#x2013;1160. doi: 10.1093/ntr/ntr099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntr099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3203133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21622497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anger S., Kvasnicka M., Siedler T. One last puff? Public smoking bans and smoking behavior. J. Health Econ. 2011;30:591&#x2013;601. doi: 10.1016/j.jhealeco.2011.03.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhealeco.2011.03.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21570731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuehnle D., Wunder C. The effects of smoking bans on self-assessed health: Evidence from Germany. German Institute for Economic Research; Berlin, Germany: 2013. SOEPpapers on Multidisciplinary Panel Data Research 586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26749275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagelhout G.E., Mons U., Allwright S., Guignard R., Beck F., Fong G.T., de Vries H., Willemsen M.C. Prevalence and predictors of smoking in &#x201c;smoke-free&#x201d; bars. Findings from the international tobacco control (ITC) Europe surveys. Soc. Sci. Med. 2011;72:1643&#x2013;1651. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.03.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.03.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4565519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21497973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xfc;derl J., Ludwig V. Does a smoking ban reduce smoking? Evidence from Germany. Schmollers Jahrbuch. 2011;131:419&#x2013;429. doi: 10.3790/schm.131.2.419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3790/schm.131.2.419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvasnicka M., Tauchmann H. Much ado about nothing? Smoking bans and Germany&#x2019;s hospitality industry. Appl. Econ. 2012;44:4539&#x2013;4551. doi: 10.1080/00036846.2011.591739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00036846.2011.591739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>