<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38188939</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1617-9625</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Tobacco induced diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Tob Induc Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>State of the literature discussing smoke-free policies globally: A narrative review.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.18332/tid/174781</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Despite the success of the Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC), most jurisdictions in the world do not have policies that create 100% smoke-free environments in indoor workplaces, indoor public places, public transport, or other public places. We conducted a narrative review of articles that discuss smoke-free policies and describe the state of the current literature. A search of peer-reviewed and gray literature, published between 1 January 2004 and 30 April 2022, was conducted using PubMed and EMBASE databases. We classified articles based on the location of the policy discussed (WHO region, World Bank income classification) and the environment that was being made smoke-free. Insights related to policy development and implementation, as well as compliance and enforcement, were also identified. The search identified 4469 unique citations; 134 articles met the criteria for inclusion and underwent data extraction by two independent coders. The sample included articles published in or about jurisdictions in each WHO region, in high- and low- and mediumincome countries, and articles that discussed policies regulating smoke-free indoor workplaces, indoor public places, public transport, outdoor/quasi-outdoor environments, and other (unspecified) public places. Some important insights from the literature related to smoke-free policy implementation included tobacco industry interference, the important role of civil society, and the need for effective communication, education, and leadership. Enforcement officials' awareness and training, stakeholders' attitudes and beliefs, and understanding social norms were identified as relevant determinants of effective smoke-free policies. There continue to be challenges for implementing smoke-free policies in jurisdictions throughout the globe, in high- and low- and middle-income countries. The literature includes insights to support 100% smoke-free policies in each environment that must be made smoke-free as per the FCTC.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 Teed J.A. et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teed</LastName><ForeName>Jacqueline A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of International Health, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Johns Hopkings University, Baltimore, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robichaud</LastName><ForeName>Meagan O</ForeName><Initials>MO</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Behavior and Society, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Johns Hopkings University, Baltimore, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Duren</LastName><ForeName>Michelle</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Policy and Management, Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health, Johns Hopkings University, Baltimore, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gouda</LastName><ForeName>Hebe N</ForeName><Initials>HN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tobacco Free Initiative, World Health Organization, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kennedy</LastName><ForeName>Ryan David</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Global Tobacco Control, Bloomberg School of Public Health, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>001</GrantID><Acronym>WHO_</Acronym><Agency>World Health Organization</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Greece</Country><MedlineTA>Tob Induc Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101201591</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1617-9625</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Tob Induc Dis. 2024 Jan 19;22. doi: 10.18332/tid/178467.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">38250633</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HICs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LMICs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">review</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smoke-free policy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tobacco</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have completed and submitted the ICMJE Form for Disclosure of Potential Conflicts of Interest. The authors declare that they have no competing interests, financial or otherwise, related to the current work. J.A. Teed, M.O. Robichaud, M. Duren report that since the initial planning of the work they received support from the Tobacco Free Initiative at the World Health Organization. R.D. Kennedy reports that since the initial planning of the work he received a grant from the World Health Organization, 'Systematic review to identify interventions and approaches taken by nation-states, that have been shown to strengthen the implementation of smoke-free environments'. Also, he reports that in the past 36 months he is funded by the Bloomberg Initiative to Reduce Tobacco Use, the NIH and the FDA CTP through our Center for Excellence in Regulatory Science. In the past 36 months, R.D. Kennedy reports that he gave an invited talk at Roswell Park Cancer Institute in December 2022 for which he received a small honorarium and his expenses were covered for this travel.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38188939</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10767724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/tid/174781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">TID-22-03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Tobacco. WHO; 2023. Accessed August 1, 2023. http://www.who.int/mediacentre/factsheets/fs339/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services . The Health Consequences of Involuntary Exposure to Tobacco Smoke: A Report of the Surgeon General. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Coordinating Center for Health Promotion, National Center for Chronic Disease Prevention and Health Promotion, Office on Smoking and Health; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thrasher JF, P&#xe9;rez-Hern&#xe1;ndez R, Swayampakala K, Arillo-Santill&#xe1;n E, Bottai M. Policy support, norms, and secondhand smoke exposure before and after implementation of a comprehensive smoke-free law in Mexico city. Am J Public Health. 2010;100(9):1789-1798. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2009.180950</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2009.180950</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2920995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20466952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abidin NZ, Zulkifli A, Abidin EZ, et al. Knowledge, attitude and perception of second-hand smoke and factors promoting smoking in Malaysian adolescents. Int J Tuberc Lung Dis. 2014;18(7):856-861. doi: 10.5588/ijtld.13.0906</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5588/ijtld.13.0906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24902566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control. WHO; 2003. Accessed August 1, 2023. https://iris.who.int/bitstream/handle/10665/42811/9241591013.pdf;jsessionid=91381E5AC183B3FF4CEDC181640BE853?sequence=1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, United Nations Treaty Collection . WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control. 2005. Accessed August 1, 2023. https://treaties.un.org/doc/Publication/MTDSG/Volume%20I/Chapter%20IX/IX-4.en.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control . Guidelines for implementation of Article 8. WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control; 2017. Accessed October 1, 2022. https://fctc.who.int/publications/m/item/protection-from-exposure-to-tobacco-smoke</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byron MJ, Cohen JE, Frattaroli S, Gittelsohn J, Drope JM, Jernigan DH. Implementing smoke-free policies in low- and middle-income countries: a brief review and research agenda. Tob Induc Dis. 2019;17:60. doi: 10.18332/tid/110007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/tid/110007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31582949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . WHO report on the global tobacco epidemic, 2023: protect people from tobacco smoke. WHO; 2023. Accessed August 1, 2022. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240077164</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . WHO Regional Offices. Accessed August 1, 2023. https://www.who.int/about/who-we-are/regional-offices</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The World Bank Group . World Bank Country and Lending Groups. Accessed August 1, 2023. https://datahelpdesk.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/906519-world-bank-country-and-lending-groups</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covidence systematic review software . Veritas Health Innovation. Melbourne, Australia. Accessed August 1, 2023. https://www.covidence.org.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez M, Glantz SA. Failure of policy regarding smoke-free bars in the Netherlands. Eur J Public Health. 2013;23(1):139-145. doi: 10.1093/eurpub/ckr173</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurpub/ckr173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3553585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22143826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogdanovica I, McNeill A, Murray R, Britton J. What factors influence smoking prevalence and smoke free policy enactment across the European Union Member States. PLoS One. 2011;6(8):e23889. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0023889</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0023889</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3166128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21909375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croghan I, Muggli M, Zag&#xe0; V, et al. Lessons learned on the road to a smoke-free Italy. Ann Ig. 2011;23(2):125-136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3920981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21770229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harizi C, El-Awa F, Ghedira H, Audera-Lopez C, Fakhfakh R. Implementation of the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control in Tunisia: progress and challenges. Tob Prev Cessat. 2020;6:72. doi: 10.18332/tpc/130476</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/tpc/130476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33426382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Champion D, Chapman S. Framing pub smoking bans: an analysis of Australian print news media coverage, March 1996-March 2003. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2005;59(8):679-684. doi: 10.1136/jech.2005.035915</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jech.2005.035915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1733106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16020646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ueda H, Armada F, Kashiwabara M, Yoshimi I. Street smoking bans in Japan: a hope for smoke-free cities?. Health Policy. 2011;102(1):49-55. doi: 10.1016/j.healthpol.2011.05.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.healthpol.2011.05.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21684620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada K, Mori N, Kashiwabara M, et al. Industry Speed Bumps on Local Tobacco Control in Japan? The Case of Hyogo. J Epidemiol. 2015;25(7):496-504. doi: 10.2188/jea.JE20150001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2188/jea.JE20150001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4483376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26155758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah SM, Wagner-Rizvi T, Huque R, et al. &#x2018;A contradiction between our state and the tobacco company&#x2019;: conflicts of interest and institutional constraints as barriers to implementing Article 5.3 in Bangladesh. Tob Control. 2022;31(Suppl 1):s33-s38. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2021-057142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2021-057142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bardach A, Rodr&#xed;guez MB, Ciapponi A, et al. Smoke-free air interventions in seven Latin American countries: health and financial impact to inform evidence-based policy implementation. Nicotine Tob Res. 2020;22(12):2149-2157. doi: 10.1093/ntr/ntaa133</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntaa133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry RA, Abdullah SM, Chugh A, et al. Advancing whole-of-government approaches to tobacco control: article 5.3 and the challenge of policy coordination in Bangladesh, Ethiopia, India and Uganda. Tob Control. 2022;31(Suppl 1):s46-s52. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2021-057154</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2021-057154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35149600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatta DN, Crosbie E, Bialous SA, Glantz S. Defending comprehensive tobacco control policy implementation in Nepal from tobacco industry interference (2011-2018). Nicotine Tob Res. 2020;22(12):2203-2212. doi: 10.1093/ntr/ntaa067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntaa067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7733063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32309853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhatta DN, Bialous S, Crosbie E, Glantz S. Exceeding WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) obligations: Nepal overcoming tobacco industry interference to enact a comprehensive tobacco control policy. Nicotine Tob Res. 2020;22(12):2213-2223. doi: 10.1093/ntr/ntz177</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntz177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7733065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31535694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brathwaite R, Addo J, Smeeth L, Lock K. A systematic review of tobacco smoking prevalence and description of tobacco control strategies in Sub-Saharan African countries; 2007 to 2014. PLoS One. 2015;10(7):e0132401. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0132401</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0132401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4498629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26162085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charoenca N, Mock J, Kungskulniti N, Preechawong S, Kojetin N, Hamann SL. Success counteracting tobacco company interference in Thailand: an example of FCTC implementation for low- and middle-income countries. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2012;9(4):1111-1134. doi: 10.3390/ijerph9041111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph9041111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3366603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22690186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charoenca N, Kungskulniti N, Pipattanachat V, Pitayarangsarit S, Hamann S, Mock J. The implementation activist: how one determined person with a camera has achieved enforcement of smoke-free laws throughout Thailand. Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2021;22(S2):19-34. doi: 10.31557/APJCP.2021.22.S2.19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31557/APJCP.2021.22.S2.19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34780135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar P, Barry RA, Kulkarni MM, Kamath VG, Ralston R, Collin J. Institutional tensions, corporate social responsibility and district-level governance of tobacco industry interference: analysing challenges in local implementation of Article 5.3 measures in Karnataka, India. Tob Control. 2022;31(Suppl 1):s26-s32. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2021-057113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2021-057113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9125366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35078910</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha DN, Narain JP, Kyaing NN, Rinchen S. WHO framework convention on tobacco control and its implementation in South-East Asia region. Indian J Public Health. 2011;55(3):184-191. doi: 10.4103/0019-557X.89949</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0019-557X.89949</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22089686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumwine J. Implementation of the framework convention on tobacco control in Africa: current status of legislation. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2011;8(11):4312-4331. doi: 10.3390/ijerph8114312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph8114312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3228573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22163209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yunarman S, Munandar A, Ahsan A, Akbarjono A, Kusuma D. Opportunities and challenges of tobacco control policy at district level in Indonesia: a qualitative analysis. Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2021;22(10):3055-3060. doi: 10.31557/APJCP.2021.22.10.3055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31557/APJCP.2021.22.10.3055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8858251</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34710979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sebri&#xe9; EM, Schoj V, Glantz SA. Smokefree environments in Latin America: on the road to real change?. Prev Control. 2008;3(1):21-35. doi: 10.1016/j.precon.2007.09.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.precon.2007.09.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2705163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19578527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung-Hall J, Craig L, Gravely S, Sansone N, Fong GT. Impact of the WHO FCTC over the first decade: a global evidence review prepared for the Impact Assessment Expert Group. Tob Control. 2019;28:s119&#x2013;128. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2018-054389</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2018-054389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6589489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29880598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jallow IK, Britton J, Langley T. Exploration of policy makers&#x2019; views on the implementation of the framework convention on tobacco control in the Gambia: a qualitative study. Nicotine Tob Res. 2019;21(12):1652-1659. doi: 10.1093/ntr/ntz003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntz003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6861828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30629264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajoga U, Lewis S, McNeill A, Szatkowski L. Does the introduction of comprehensive smoke-free legislation lead to a decrease in population smoking prevalence? Addict Abingdon Engl. 2011;106(7):1346&#x2013;1354. doi: 10.1111/j.1360-0443.2011.03446.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1360-0443.2011.03446.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21438944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorini G, Currie L, Spizzichino L, Galeone D, Lopez MJ. Smoke-free policy development in Italy through the legislative process of the ban 2000-2005, and press media review 1998-2008. Ann Ist Super Sanita. 2011;47(3):260-265. doi: 10.4415/ANN_11_03_04</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4415/ANN_11_03_04</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21952150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uang R, Crosbie E, Glantz SA. Smokefree implementation in Colombia: Monitoring, outside funding, and business support. Salud Publica Mex. 2017;59(2):128-136. doi: 10.21149/7884</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21149/7884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5494994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28562713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balwicki &#x141;, Stok&#x142;osa M, Balwicka-Szczyrba M, Tomczak W. Tobacco industry interference with tobacco control policies in Poland: legal aspects and industry practices. Tob Control. 2016;25(5):521-526. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2015-052582</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2015-052582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5036272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26418616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann L, Mlinari&#x107; M, M&#xef; Lard N, et al. &#x2018;[&#x2026;] the situation in the schools still remains the Achilles heel.&#x2019; Barriers to the implementation of school tobacco policies-a qualitative study from local stakeholder&#x2019;s perspective in seven European cities. Health Educ Res. 2020;35(1):32-43. doi: 10.1093/her/cyz037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/her/cyz037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31943060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martinez C. Barriers and challenges of implementing tobacco control policies in hospitals: applying the institutional analysis and development framework to the Catalan Network of Smoke-Free Hospitals. Policy Polit Nurs Pract. 2009;10(3):224-232. doi: 10.1177/1527154409346736</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1527154409346736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19900946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mele V, Compagni A. Explaining the unexpected success of the smoking ban in Italy: political strategy and transition to practice, 2000&#x2013;2005. Public Adm. 2010;88(3):819&#x2013;835. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-9299.2010.01840.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-9299.2010.01840.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20925154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donchin M, Baras M. A &#x201c;smoke-free&#x201d; hospital in Israel-a possible mission. Prev Med. 2004;39(3):589-595. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2004.02.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2004.02.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15313099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallin A, Goodin A, Rayens MK, Morris S, Hahn EJ. Smoke-free policy implementation: theoretical and practical considerations. Policy Polit Nurs Pract. 2014;15(3-4):81-92. doi: 10.1177/1527154414562301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1527154414562301</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25573743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fallin-Bennett A, Roditis M, Glantz SA. The carrot and the stick? Strategies to improve compliance with college campus tobacco policies. J Am Coll Health. 2017;65(2):122-130. doi: 10.1080/07448481.2016.1262380</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2016.1262380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27869568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung R, Mallya G, Dean LT, Rizvi A, Dignam L, Schwarz DF. Instituting a smoke-free policy for city recreation centers and playgrounds, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 2010. Prev Chronic Dis. 2013;10:E116. doi: 10.5888/pcd10.120294</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5888/pcd10.120294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3711557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23845177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson LA, Marsh L. Smoke-free policies in New Zealand public tertiary education institutions. Health Educ Res. 2015;30(2):347-358. doi: 10.1093/her/cyv004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/her/cyv004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25686846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson L, Nyamurungi KN, Gravely S, et al. Implementation of 100% smoke-free law in Uganda: a qualitative study exploring civil society&#x2019;s perspective. BMC Public Health. 2018;18(1):927. doi: 10.1186/s12889-018-5869-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-018-5869-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6064096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30055607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byron MJ, Cohen JE, Frattaroli S, Gittelsohn J, Jernigan DH. Using the theory of normative social behavior to understand compliance with a smoke-free law in a middle-income country. Health Educ Res. 2016;31(6):738-748. doi: 10.1093/her/cyw043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/her/cyw043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27923863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byron MJ, Cohen JE, Frattaroli S, Gittelsohn J, Drope JM, Jernigan DH. Implementing smoke-free policies in low- and middle-income countries: A brief review and research agenda. Tob Induc Dis. 2019;17:60. doi: 10.18332/tid/110007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/tid/110007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6770618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31582949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahyuti W, Hasairin S, Mamoribo S, Ahsan A, Kusuma D. Monitoring Compliance and Examining Challenges of a Smoke-free Policy in Jayapura, Indonesia. J Prev Med Public Health. 2019;52(6):427-432. doi: 10.3961/jpmph.19.240</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3961/jpmph.19.240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6893229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31795619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Widome R, Samet JM, Hiatt RA, et al. Science, prudence, and politics: the case of smoke-free indoor spaces. Ann Epidemiol. 2010;20(6):428-435. doi: 10.1016/j.annepidem.2010.03.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annepidem.2010.03.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20470969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garritsen HH, Rozema AD, van de Goor IAM, Kunst AE. Smoke-free sports in The Netherlands: why most sports clubs have not adopted an outdoor smoke-free policy. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021;18(5):2454. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18052454</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18052454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7967586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33801520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garritsen HH, Rozema AD, Am van de Goor I, Kunst AE. Implementation of an outdoor smoke-free policy at sports clubs: critical situations and determinants influencing implementation. Int J Drug Policy. 2021;92:103129. doi: 10.1016/j.drugpo.2021.103129</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugpo.2021.103129</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33486332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laird Y, Myers F, Reid G, McAteer J. Tobacco Control Policy in Scotland: A Qualitative Study of Expert Views on Successes, Challenges and Future Actions. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(15):2659. doi: 10.3390/ijerph16152659</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph16152659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6696046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31349618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vardavas CI, Dimitrakaki C, Schoretsaniti S, et al. The role of the non-smoker in enforcing smoke-free laws. J Public Health Policy. 2011;32(1):46-59. doi: 10.1057/jphp.2010.45</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/jphp.2010.45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21150943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heydari G. A decade after introducing MPOWER, trend analysis of implementation of the WHO FCTC in the Eastern Mediterranean Region. Lung India. 2020;37(2):120-125. doi: 10.4103/lungindia.lungindia_388_19</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/lungindia.lungindia_388_19</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7065548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32108595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heydari G, Zaatari G, Al-Lawati JA, El-Awa F, Fouad H. MPOWER, needs and challenges: trends in the implementation of the WHO FCTC in the Eastern Mediterranean Region. East Mediterr Health J. 2018;24(1):63-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29658622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farrelly MC, Chaloupka FJ, Berg CJ, et al. Taking Stock of Tobacco Control Program and Policy Science and Impact in the United States. J Addict Behav Ther. 2017;1(2):8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6124688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30198028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geiger BF, Vaid I, Beeson D, Riddle B. Implementation of school policies to prevent youth tobacco use in Alabama. J Sch Health. 2012;82(6):277-284. doi: 10.1111/j.1746-1561.2012.00698.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1746-1561.2012.00698.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22568463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halkett L, Thomson G. Getting an outdoor smokefree policy: the case of Kapiti Coast District Council. N Z Med J. 2010;123(1308):28-40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20173803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arora M, Mathur MR, Singh N. A framework to prevent and control tobacco among adolescents and children: introducing the IMPACT model. Indian J Pediatr. 2013;80 Suppl 1:S55-S62. doi: 10.1007/s12098-012-0768-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12098-012-0768-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22592283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avila-Tang E, Travers MJ, Navas-Acien A. Promoting smoke-free environments in Latin America: a comparison of methods to assess secondhand smoke exposure. Salud Publica Mex. 2010;52 Suppl 2:S138-S148. doi: 10.1590/s0036-36342010000800009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/s0036-36342010000800009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21243184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kungskulniti N, Pitayarangsarit S, Hamann SL. Stakeholder&#x2019;s assessment of the awareness and effectiveness of smoke-free law in Thailand. Int J Health Policy Manag. 2018;7(10):919-922. doi: 10.15171/ijhpm.2018.47</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15171/ijhpm.2018.47</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6186465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30316244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen LJ, Peled-Raz M. Tobacco policy in Israel: 1948-2014 and beyond. Isr J Health Policy Res. 2015;4:12. doi: 10.1186/s13584-015-0007-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13584-015-0007-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4416305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25937898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uang R, Hiilamo H, Glantz SA. Accelerated adoption of smoke-free laws after ratification of the World Health Organization Framework Convention on Tobacco Control. Am J Public Health. 2016;106(1):166-171. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2015.302872</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2015.302872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4689638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S, Campion J. Achieving smoke-free mental health services: lessons from the past decade of implementation research. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2013;10(9):4224-4244. doi: 10.3390/ijerph10094224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph10094224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3799524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24025397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant LG, Oliffe JL, Johnson JL, Bottorff JL. Health care professionals implementing a smoke-free policy at inpatient psychiatric units. Qual Health Res. 2014;24(12):1732-1744. doi: 10.1177/1049732314549026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732314549026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25216860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S, Campion J. Factors associated with success of smoke-free initiatives in Australian psychiatric inpatient units. Psychiatr Serv. 2010;61(3):300-305. doi: 10.1176/ps.2010.61.3.300</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ps.2010.61.3.300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20194408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moreland-Russell S, Carothers BJ. An examination of two policy networks involved in advancing smokefree policy initiatives. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2015;12(9):11117-11131. doi: 10.3390/ijerph120911117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph120911117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4586664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26371022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freiburghaus T, Raffing R, Ballb&#xe8; M, Gual A, T&#xf6;nnesen H. The right to smoke and the right to smoke-free surroundings: international comparison of smoke-free psychiatric clinic implementation experiences. BJPsych Open. 2021;7(3):e81. doi: 10.1192/bjo.2021.35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjo.2021.35</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8086391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33858559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao D, Wang C, Chen H, Hajek P. Making hospitals in China smoke-free: a prospective study of implementing the new standard. Nicotine Tob Res. 2013;15(12):2076-2080. doi: 10.1093/ntr/ntt098</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntt098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24014515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatterjee N, Kadam R, Patil D, Todankar P. Adherence to the Tobacco-Free School Policy in Rural India. Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2017;18(9):2367-2373. doi: 10.22034/APJCP.2017.18.9.2367</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22034/APJCP.2017.18.9.2367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5720638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28950680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawn S, Feng Y, Tsourtos G, Campion J. Mental health professionals&#x2019; perspectives on the implementation of smoke-free policies in psychiatric units across England. Int J Soc Psychiatry. 2015;61(5):465-474. doi: 10.1177/0020764014553002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0020764014553002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25298224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wynne O, Guillaumier A, Twyman L, et al. Signs, fines and compliance officers: a systematic review of strategies for enforcing smoke-free policy. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2018;15(7):1386. doi: 10.3390/ijerph15071386</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph15071386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6068603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30004425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J, Cui X, Liu H, et al. Public mobilisation in implementation of smoke-free Beijing: a social media complaint platform. Tob Control. 2019;28(6):705-711. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2018-054534</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2018-054534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30448783</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arifin MA, Nurhayani, Indar, Sirajuddin S, Susanti A, Ismaniar NI, et al. The implementation of non-smoking area policy in hospital of Islam Faisal Makassar. Eur J Mol Clin Med. 2021;8(1):1358&#x2013;1365. Accessed November 2, 2023. http://repository.unhas.ac.id/id/eprint/9996/1/The_Implementationof_Non-Smoking_Area_Policy_in_Hospital_of_Islam_Faisal_Makassar%20(1).pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan MK, Hoque HE, Ferdous J. Knowledge and attitude regarding national tobacco control law and practice of tobacco smoking among Bangladesh police. Mymensingh Med J. 2019;28(4):752-761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31599237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhary A, Thakur A, Chauhan T, et al. Creation of a smoke-free environment for children: an assessment of compliance to COTPA 2003 legislation in an urban area. Indian Pediatr. 2019;56(10):837-840. doi: 10.1007/s13312-019-1609-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13312-019-1609-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31441433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suarjana K, Astuti PAS, Artawan Eka Putra IWG, et al. Implementation of smoke-free law in Denpasar Bali: between compliance and social norms of smoking. J Public Health Res. 2020;9(3):1747. doi: 10.4081/jphr.2020.1747</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/jphr.2020.1747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7445440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x160;t&#x11b;p&#xe1;nkov&#xe1; L, Kosteleck&#xe1; L, Stejskalov&#xe1; V, Kalvachov&#xe1; M, Kr&#xe1;l&#xed;kov&#xe1; E. Hospital as a smoke-free workplace. Cent Eur J Public Health. 2020;28 Suppl:S26-S30. doi: 10.21101/cejph.a6172</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21101/cejph.a6172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basnet LB, Budhathoki SS, Adhikari B, et al. Compliance with the smoke-free public places legislation in Nepal: a cross-sectional study from Biratnagar Metropolitan City. PLoS One. 2022;17(3):e0264895. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0264895</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0264895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8906589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35263360</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gravely S, Nyamurungi KN, Kabwama SN, et al. Knowledge, opinions and compliance related to the 100% smoke-free law in hospitality venues in Kampala, Uganda: crosssectional results from the KOMPLY Project. BMJ Open. 2018;8(1):e017601. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2017-017601</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2017-017601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5780705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29306880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohan S, Mini GK, Thankappan KR. High knowledge of Framework Convention on Tobacco Control provisions among local government representatives does not translate into effective implementation: findings from Kerala, India. Public Health. 2013;127(2):178-181. doi: 10.1016/j.puhe.2012.11.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.puhe.2012.11.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23298574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller CL, Hickling JA. Phased in smoke-free workplace laws: impact in grass-roots pubs and clubs in South Australia. Health Promot J Austr. 2007;18(1):26-32. doi: 10.1071/he07026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1071/he07026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17501708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballb&#xe8; M, Nieva G, Mondon S, et al. Smoke-free policies in psychiatric services: identification of unmet needs. Tob Control. 2012;21(6):549-554. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2011-050029</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2011-050029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21933940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radwan GN, Loffredo CA, Aziz R, Abdel-Aziz N, Labib N. Implementation, barriers and challenges of smoke-free policies in hospitals in Egypt. BMC Res Notes. 2012;5:568. doi: 10.1186/1756-0500-5-568</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1756-0500-5-568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3519804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23069011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severini G, Sandoval RC, S&#xf3;&#xf1;ora G, et al. Towards a smoke-free world? South America became the first 100% smoke-free subregion in the Americas. Rev Panam Salud Publica. 2022;46:e103. doi: 10.26633/RPSP.2022.103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26633/RPSP.2022.103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9534353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36211249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asyary A, Veruswati M, Arianie CP, Ratih TSD, Hamzah A. Prevalence of smoke-free zone compliance among schools in Indonesia: a nationwide representative survey. Asian Pac J Cancer Prev. 2021;22(2):359-363. doi: 10.31557/APJCP.2021.22.2.359</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31557/APJCP.2021.22.2.359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8190355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33639648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozema AD, Mathijssen JJ, Jansen MW, van Oers JA. Schools as smoke-free zones? Barriers and facilitators to the adoption of outdoor school ground smoking bans at secondary schools. Tob Induc Dis. 2016;14:10. doi: 10.1186/s12971-016-0076-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12971-016-0076-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4812616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27030793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozema AD, Mathijssen JJP, Jansen MWJ, van Oers JAM. Sustainability of outdoor school ground smoking bans at secondary schools: a mixed-method study. Eur J Public Health. 2018;28(1):43-49. doi: 10.1093/eurpub/ckx099</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurpub/ckx099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5881753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29016786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calo WA, Krasny SE. Environmental determinants of smoking behaviors: the role of policy and environmental interventions in preventing smoking initiation and supporting cessation. Curr Cardiovasc Risk Rep. 2013;7(6):446-452. doi: 10.1007/s12170-013-0344-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12170-013-0344-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3947572</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24634706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El Amin SET. School smoking policies and health science students&#x2019; use of cigarettes, shisha, and dipping tombak in Sudan. Front Public Health. 2019;7:290. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2019.00290</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2019.00290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6804594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31681722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lock K, Adams E, Pilkington P, Duckett K, Gilmore A, Marston C. Evaluating social and behavioural impacts of English smoke-free legislation in different ethnic and age groups: implications for reducing smoking-related health inequalities. Tob Control. 2010;19(5):391-397. doi: 10.1136/tc.2009.032318</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tc.2009.032318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20679418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buettner-Schmidt K, Miller DR. An observational study of compliance with North Dakota&#x2019;s smoke-free law among retail stores that sell electronic smoking devices. Tob Control. 2017;26(4):452-454. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2015-052888</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2015-052888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27343228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards R, Thomson G, Wilson N, et al. After the smoke has cleared: evaluation of the impact of a new national smoke-free law in New Zealand. Tob Control. 2008;17(1):e2. doi: 10.1136/tc.2007.020347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tc.2007.020347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18218788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edwards R, Gifford H, Waa A, Glover M, Thomson G, Wilson N. Beneficial impacts of a national smokefree environments law on an indigenous population: a multifaceted evaluation. Int J Equity Health. 2009;8:12. doi: 10.1186/1475-9276-8-12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-9276-8-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2684098</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19405964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris KJ, Stearns JN, Kovach RG, Harrar SW. Enforcing an outdoor smoking ban on a college campus: effects of a multicomponent approach. J Am Coll Health. 2009;58(2):121-126. doi: 10.1080/07448480903221285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448480903221285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19892648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skeer M, Land ML, Cheng DM, Siegel MB. Smoking in Boston bars before and after a 100% smoke-free regulation: an assessment of early compliance. J Public Health Manag Pract. 2004;10(6):501-507. doi: 10.1097/00124784-200411000-00005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00124784-200411000-00005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15643372</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goel S, Sharma D, Gupta R, Mahajan V. Compliance with smoke-free legislation and smoking behaviour: observational field study from Punjab, India. Tob Control. 2018;27(4):407-413. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2016-053559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2016-053559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6047142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28798264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagelhout GE, Mons U, Allwright S, et al. Prevalence and predictors of smoking in &#x201c;smoke-free&#x201d; bars. Findings from the International Tobacco Control (ITC) Europe Surveys. Soc Sci Med. 2011;72(10):1643-1651. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.03.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2011.03.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4565519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21497973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou L, Niu L, Jiang H, Jiang C, Xiao S. Facilitators and barriers of smokers&#x2019; compliance with smoking bans in public places: a systematic review of quantitative and qualitative literature. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2016;13(12):1228. doi: 10.3390/ijerph13121228</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph13121228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5201369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27973436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vardavas CI, Agaku I, Patelarou E, et al. Ashtrays and signage as determinants of a smoke-free legislation&#x2019;s success. PLoS One. 2013;8(9):e72945. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0072945</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0072945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3762932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24023795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahsan H, Hoe C, Aslam F, Wright K, Cohen J, Kennedy R. Compliance with smoke-free policies at indoor and outdoor public places: an observational study in Pakistan. East Mediterr Health J. 2022;28(1):50-57. doi: 10.26719/emhj.22.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26719/emhj.22.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35165878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satterlund TD, Cassady D, Treiber J, Lemp C. Barriers to adopting and implementing local-level tobacco control policies. J Community Health. 2011;36(4):616-623. doi: 10.1007/s10900-010-9350-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10900-010-9350-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3130906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21193951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satterlund TD, Cassady D, Treiber J, Lemp C. Strategies implemented by 20 local tobacco control agencies to promote smoke-free recreation areas, California, 2004-2007. Prev Chronic Dis. 2011;8(5):A111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21843414</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satterlund TD, Lee JP, Moore RS. Changes in smoking-related norms in bars resulting from California&#x2019;s Smoke-Free Workplace Act. J Drug Educ. 2012;42(3):315-326. doi: 10.2190/DE.42.3.d</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2190/DE.42.3.d</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3671496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23705511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin H, Chang C, Liu Z, Zheng Y. Subnational smoke-free laws in China. Tob Induc Dis. 2019;17:78. doi: 10.18332/tid/112665</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/tid/112665</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6856824</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31772556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lidegaard LP, Kristiansen M, Pisinger C. Readiness for implementation of smoke-free work hours in private companies: a qualitative study of perceptions among middle managers. Tob Prev Cessat. 2021;7:38. doi: 10.18332/tpc/134800</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18332/tpc/134800</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8145195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34056145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shipley M, Allcock R. Achieving a smoke-free hospital: reported enforcement of smoke-free regulations by NHS health care staff. J Public Health (Oxf). 2008;30(1):2-7. doi: 10.1093/pubmed/fdn004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pubmed/fdn004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18292178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramachandran S, Bentley S, Casey E, Bentley JP. Prevalence of and factors associated with violations of a campus smoke-free policy: a cross-sectional survey of undergraduate students on a university campus in the USA. BMJ Open. 2020;10(3):e030504. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-030504</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-030504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7103814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvillemo P, Feltmann K, Elg&#xe1;n TH, Gripenberg J. Evaluation of the implementation of a 25-year outdoor school ground smoking ban: a qualitative interview study with implications for prevention practise. Front Public Health. 2021;9:628748. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2021.628748</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2021.628748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8046920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33869127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Satterlund TD, Lee JP, Moore RS, Antin TM. Challenges to implementing and enforcing California&#x2019;s smoke-free workplace act in bars. Drugs Abingdon Engl. 2009;16(5):422&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1080/09687630802302872</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09687630802302872</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2805235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20161559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kennedy RD, Zummach D, Filsinger S, Leatherdale ST. Reported municipal costs from outdoor smoke-free by-laws-experience from Ontario, Canada. Tob Induc Dis. 2014;12(1):4. doi: 10.1186/1617-9625-12-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1617-9625-12-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3944976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24581326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antin TM, Moore RS, Lee JP, Satterlund TD. Law in practice: obstacles to a smokefree workplace policy in bars serving Asian patrons. J Immigr Minor Health. 2010;12(2):221-227. doi: 10.1007/s10903-008-9174-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10903-008-9174-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18712482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antin TM, Moore RS, Lee JP, Satterlund TD. Law in practice: obstacles to a smokefree workplace policy in bars serving Asian patrons. J Immigr Minor Health. 2010;12(2):221-227. doi: 10.1007/s10903-008-9174-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10903-008-9174-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18712482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mlinari&#x107; M, Hoffmann L, Kunst AE, et al. Explaining mechanisms that influence smoke-free implementation at the local level: a realist review of smoking bans. Nicotine Tob Res. 2019;21(12):1609-1620. doi: 10.1093/ntr/nty206</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/nty206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30285126</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>