<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31632510</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1943-8141</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of translational research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Transl Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Vitamin D and alopecia areata: possible roles in pathogenesis and potential implications for therapy.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5285</StartPage><EndPage>5300</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5285-5300</MedlinePgn></Pagination><Abstract><AbstractText>Alopecia areata is characterized by the loss of hair on the scalp and elsewhere on the body. It affects approximately 2% of the general population. It is believed to be an autoimmune disease. However, its pathogenesis remains incompletely understood. Recent studies have revealed a substantial link between vitamin D and alopecia areata. But the underlying mechanism still yet to be deciphered. This article reviews the current literature and discusses the possible roles of vitamin D in the pathogenesis of alopecia areata in the context of (1) loss of immune privilege in hair follicle, (2) autoreactive effector T cells and mast cells, (3) nature killer group 2 member d-positive cytotoxic T cells, (4) Janus kinase/signal transducers and activators of transcriptional signaling pathway, (5) regulatory T cells, (6) immune checkpoints, and (7) oxidative stress, which are believed to play important roles in autoimmunity in AA. This paper provides new insights into research directions to elucidate the exact mechanisms of vitamin D in the pathogenesis. Calcipotriol, a vitamin D analog, has been reported to be topically used in treating alopecia areata with promising results. Combination therapy of vitamin D analogs with corticosteroids might also be used in treating alopecia areata.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>AJTR Copyright &#xa9; 2019.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Xiran</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University 222 Zhongshan Road, Dalian 116011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Xianmin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Axia Women's Health 450 Cresson BLVD. Oaks, PA 19456, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Zhiqi</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, The First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University 222 Zhongshan Road, Dalian 116011, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Transl Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101493030</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1943-8141</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alopecia areata</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calcipotriol</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vitamin D</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31632510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6789271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pratt CH, King LE Jr, Messenger AG, Christiano AM, Sundberg JP. Alopecia areata. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2017;3:17011.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5573125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28300084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strazzulla LC, Wang EHC, Avila L, Lo Sicco K, Brinster N, Christiano AM, Shapiro J. Alopecia areata: disease characteristics, clinical evaluation, and new perspectives on pathogenesis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2018;78:1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29241771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai TY, Huang YC. Vitamin D deficiency in patients with alopecia areata: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2018;78:207&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29241789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim DH, Lee JW, Kim IS, Choi SY, Lim YY, Kim HM, Kim BJ, Kim MN. Successful treatment of alopecia areata with topical calcipotriol. Ann Dermatol. 2012;24:341&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3412244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22879719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;erman AA, Solak SS, Altunay &#x130;, K&#xfc;&#xe7;&#xfc;k&#xfc;nal NA. Topical calcipotriol therapy for mild-to-moderate alopecia areata: a retrospective study. J Drugs Dermatol. 2015;14:616&#x2013;620.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26091388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narang T, Daroach M, Kumaran MS. Efficacy and safety of topical calcipotriol in management of alopecia areata: a pilot study. Dermatol Ther. 2017;30</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28133875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H, Chen W, Li D, Yin X, Zhang X, Olsen N, Zheng SG. Vitamin D and chronic diseases. Aging Dis. 2017;8:346&#x2013;353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5440113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28580189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christakos S, Dhawan P, Verstuyf A, Verlinden L, Carmeliet G. Vitamin D: metabolism, molecular mechanism of action, and pleiotropic effects. Physiol Rev. 2016;96:365&#x2013;408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4839493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26681795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim D. The role of vitamin D in thyroid diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18:E1949.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5618598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28895880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umar M, Sastry KS, Chouchane AI. Role of vitamin D beyond the skeletal function: a review of the molecular and clinical studies. Int J Mol Sci. 2018;19:E1618.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6032242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29849001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz N, Serarslan G, Gokce C. Vitamin D concentrations are decreased in patients with alopecia areata. Vitam Miner. 2012;1:105&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aksu Cerman A, Sarikaya Solak S, Kivanc Altunay I. Vitamin D deficiency in alopecia areata. Br J Dermatol. 2014;170:1299&#x2013;1304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24655364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahamid M, Abu-Elhija O, Samamra M, Mahamid A, Nseir W. Association between vitamin D levels and alopecia areata. Isr Med Assoc J. 2014;16:367&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25058999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakry OA, El Farargy SM, El Shafiee MK, Soliman A. Serum Vitamin D in patients with alopecia areata. Indian Dermatol Online J. 2016;7:371&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5038097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27730032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghafoor R, Anwar MI. Vitamin D deficiency in alopecia areata. J Coll Physicians Surg Pak. 2017;27:200&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28492146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhat YJ, Latif I, Malik R, Hassan I, Sheikh G, Lone KS, Majeed S, Sajad P. Vitamin D level in alopecia areata. Indian J Dermatol. 2017;62:407&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5527723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28794553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gade VKV, Mony A, Munisamy M, Chandrashekar L, Rajappa M. An investigation of vitamin D status in alopecia areata. Clin Exp Med. 2018;18:577&#x2013;584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29869122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>d&#x2019;Ovidio R, Vessio M, d&#x2019;Ovidio FD. Reduced level of 25-hydroxyvitamin D in chronic/relapsing Alopecia Areata. Dermatoendocrinol. 2013;5:271&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24194967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daroach M, Narang T, Saikia UN, Sachdeva N, Sendhil Kumaran M. Correlation of vitamin D and vitamin D receptor expression in patients with alopecia areata: a clinical paradigm. Int J Dermatol. 2018;57:217&#x2013;222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29243839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erpolat S, Sarifakioglu E, Ayyildiz A. 25-hydroxyvitamin D status in patients with alopecia areata. Postepy Dermatol Alergol. 2017;34:248&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5471380</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28670255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson JM, Li T, Park MK, Qureshi AA, Cho E. Estimated serum vitamin D status, vitamin D intake, and risk of incident alopecia areata among US women. Arch Dermatol Res. 2016;308:671&#x2013;676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27664090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee S, Kim BJ, Lee CH, Lee WS. Increased prevalence of vitamin D deficiency in patients with alopecia areata: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2018;32:1214&#x2013;1221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29633370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unal M, Gonulalan G. Serum vitamin D level is related to disease severity in pediatric alopecia areata. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2018;17:101&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28447433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawzi MM, Mahmoud SB, Ahmed SF, Shaker OG. Assessment of vitamin D receptors in alopecia areata and androgenetic alopecia. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2016;15:318&#x2013;323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27151518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mady LJ, Ajibade DV, Hsaio C, Teichert A, Fong C, Wang Y, Christakos S, Bikle DD. The transient role for calcium and vitamin D during the developmental hair follicle cycle. J Invest Dermatol. 2016;136:1337&#x2013;1345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020884</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26994969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SM, Pike JW. The vitamin D receptor functions as a transcription regulator in the absence of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D(3) J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2016;164:265&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4769962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26323657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang H, Nan W, Wang S, Zhang T, Si H, Yang F, Li G. Epidermal growth factor promotes proliferation and migration of follicular outer root sheath cells via Wnt/&#x3b2;-catenin signaling. Cell Physiol Biochem. 2016;39:360&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27352380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerkowicz A, Chyl-Surdacka K, Krasowska D, Chodorowska G. The role of vitamin D in non-scarring alopecia. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5751255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29215595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen Y, Daich J, Soliman I, Brathwaite E, Shoenfeld Y. Vitamin D and autoimmunity. Scand J Rheumatol. 2016;45:439&#x2013;447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27191042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paus R, Bulfone-Paus S, Bertolini M. Hair follicle immune privilege revisited: the key to alopecia areata management. J Investig Dermatol Symp Proc. 2018;19:S12&#x2013;S17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29273098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragab D, Soliman D, Samaha D, Yassin A. Vitamin D status and its modulatory effect on interferon gamma and interleukin-10 production by peripheral blood mononuclear cells in culture. Cytokine. 2016;85:5&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27269178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fawaz L, Mrad MF, Kazan JM, Sayegh S, Akika R, Khoury SJ. Comparative effect of 25(OH)D3 and 1,25(OH)2D3 on Th17 cell differentiation. Clin Immunol. 2016;166-167:59&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27041081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheikh V, Kasapoglu P, Zamani A, Basiri Z, Tahamoli-Roudsari A, Alahgholi-Hajibehzad M. Vitamin D3 inhibits the proliferation of T helper cells, downregulate CD4(+) T cell cytokines and upregulate inhibitory markers. Hum Immunol. 2018;79:439&#x2013;445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29522785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kokic V, Martinovic Kaliterna D, Radic M, Tandara L, Perkovic D. Association between vitamin D, oestradiol and interferon-gamma in female patients with inactive systemic lupus erythematosus: a cross-sectional study. J Int Med Res. 2018;46:1162&#x2013;1171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5972245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29235391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mrad MF, El Ayoubi NK, Esmerian MO, Kazan JM, Khoury SJ. Effect of vitamin D replacement on immunological biomarkers in patients with multiple sclerosis. Clin Immunol. 2017;181:9&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28536054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guo H, Cheng Y, Shapiro J, McElwee K. The role of lymphocytes in the development and treatment of alopecia areata. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2015;11:1335&#x2013;1351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5148616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26548356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanemura A, Oiso N, Nakano M, Itoi S, Kawada A, Katayama I. Alopecia areata: infiltration of Th17 cells in the dermis, particularly around hair follicles. Dermatology. 2013;226:333&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23838575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hong JW, Lee CY, Ha SM, Choi SH, Kim TH, Song KH, Kim KH. The contributory roles of Th17 lymphocyte and cytotoxic T lymphocyte at the hair bulge region as well as the hair bulb area in the chronic alopecia areata patients. Ann Dermatol. 2017;29:156&#x2013;166.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5383740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28392642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantorna MT, Snyder L, Lin YD, Yang L. Vitamin D and 1,25(OH)2D regulation of T cells. Nutrients. 2015;7:3011&#x2013;3021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4425186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25912039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schardey J, Globig AM, Janssen C, Hofmann M, Manegold P, Thimme R, Hasselblatt P. Vitamin D inhibits pro-inflammatory T cell function in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2019 [Epub ahead of print]</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31051495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penna-Martinez M, Filmann N, Bogdanou D, Shoghi F, Huenecke S, Schubert R, Herrmann E, Koehl U, Husebye ES, Badenhoop K. High-dose vitamin D in Addison&#x2019;s disease regulates T-cells and monocytes: a pilot trial. Nutrition. 2018;49:66&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29522979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tom MR, Li J, Ueno A, Fort Gasia M, Chan R, Hung DY, Chenoo S, Iacucci M, Jijon HB, Kaplan GG, Beck PL, Panaccione R, Barkema HW, Buret AG, Yajnik V, Ghosh S. Novel CD8+ T-cell subsets demonstrating plasticity in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2016;22:1596&#x2013;1608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27306067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamzaoui A, Berra&#xef;es A, Hamdi B, Kaabachi W, Ammar J, Hamzaoui K. Vitamin D reduces the differentiation and expansion of Th17 cells in young asthmatic children. Immunobiology. 2014;219:873&#x2013;879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25128460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reihani H, Rastin M, Mahmoudi M, Ghoryani M, Abdollahi N, Tabasi NS, Zamani Taghizadeh Rabe S, Sahebari M. Influence of 1 alpha, 25-dihydroxyvitamin D3 on T helper 17 cells and related cytokines in systemic lupus erythematosus. Iran J Immunol. 2015;12:82&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26119191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen HY, Luo J, Li XF, Wei DD, Liu Y. 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D(3) modulates T cell differentiation and impacts on the production of cytokines from Chinese Han patients with early rheumatoid arthritis. Immunol Res. 2019;67:48&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30357602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nodehi M, Ajami A, Izad M, Asgarian Omran H, Chahardoli R, Amouzegar A, Yekaninejad S, Hemmatabadi M, Azizi F, Esfahanian F, Mansouri F, Mazaheri Nezhad Fard R, Saboor-Yaraghi AA. Effects of vitamin D supplements on frequency of CD4(+) T-cell subsets in women with Hashimoto&#x2019;s thyroiditis: a double-blind placebo-controlled study. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2019;73:1236&#x2013;1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30696977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jin B, Sun T, Yu XH, Yang YX, Yeo AE. The effects of TLR activation on T-cell development and differentiation. Clin Dev Immunol. 2012;2012:836485.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3376488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22737174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alzolibani AA, Rasheed Z, Bin Saif G, Al-Dhubaibi MS, Al Robaee AA. Altered expression of intracellular Toll-like receptors in peripheral blood mononuclear cells from patients with alopecia areata. BBA Clin. 2016;5:134&#x2013;142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4826589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27114923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yazdanpanah E, Mahmoudi M, Sahebari M, Rezaieyazdi Z, Esmaeili SA, Tabasi N, Jaberi S, Sahebkar A, Rastin M. Vitamin D3 alters the expression of Toll-like receptors in peripheral blood mononuclear cells of patients with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Cell Biochem. 2017;118:4831&#x2013;4835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28544067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Zhao Y, Ye Y, Li S, Qi S, Yang Y, Cao H, Yang J, Zhang X. Lesional infiltration of mast cells, Langerhans cells, T cells and local cytokine profiles in alopecia areata. Arch Dermatol Res. 2015;307:319&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25638328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertolini M, Zilio F, Rossi A, Kleditzsch P, Emelianov VE, Gilhar A, Keren A, Meyer KC, Wang E, Funk W, McElwee K, Paus R. Abnormal interactions between perifollicular mast cells and CD8+ T-cells may contribute to the pathogenesis of alopecia areata. PLoS One. 2014;9:e94260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4022513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24832234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Theoharides TC. Vitamin D and atopy. Clin Ther. 2017;39:880&#x2013;883.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28454657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yip KH, Kolesnikoff N, Yu C, Hauschild N, Taing H, Biggs L, Goltzman D, Gregory PA, Anderson PH, Samuel MS, Galli SJ, Lopez AF, Grimbaldeston MA. Mechanisms of vitamin D3 metabolite repression of IgE-dependent mast cell activation. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2014;133:1356&#x2013;64. 1364.e1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4154631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24461581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ZQ, Li XX, Qiu SQ, Yu Y, Li MG, Yang LT, Li LJ, Wang S, Zheng PY, Liu ZG, Yang PC. Vitamin D contributes to mast cell stabilization. Allergy. 2017;72:1184&#x2013;1192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27998003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dai Z, Xing L, Cerise J, Wang EH, Jabbari A, de Jong A, Petukhova L, Christiano AM, Clynes R. CXCR3 blockade inhibits T cell migration into the skin and prevents development of alopecia areata. J Immunol. 2016;197:1089&#x2013;1099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5031416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27412416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito T. Recent advances in the pathogenesis of autoimmune hair loss disease alopecia areata. Clin Dev Immunol. 2013;2013:348546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3789320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24151515</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seydel S, Beilfuss A, Kahraman A, Aksoy K, Gerken G, Akkiz H, Canbay A. Vitamin D ameliorates stress ligand expression elicited by free fatty acids in the hepatic stellate cell line LX-2. Turk J Gastroenterol. 2011;22:400&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21948571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reynolds JA, Haque S, Williamson K, Ray DW, Alexander MY, Bruce IN. Vitamin D improves endothelial dysfunction and restores myeloid angiogenic cell function via reduced CXCL-10 expression in systemic lupus erythematosus. Sci Rep. 2016;6:22341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26930567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hosokawa Y, Hosokawa I, Shindo S, Ozaki K, Matsuo T. Calcitriol suppressed inflammatory reactions in IL-1&#x3b2;-stimulated human periodontal ligament cells. Inflammation. 2015;38:2252&#x2013;2258.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26156812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komolmit P, Charoensuk K, Thanapirom K, Suksawatamnuay S, Thaimai P, Chirathaworn C, Poovorawan Y. Correction of vitamin D deficiency facilitated suppression of IP-10 and DPP IV levels in patients with chronic hepatitis C: a randomised double-blinded, placebo-control trial. PLoS One. 2017;12:e0174608.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5380326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28376103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu B, Du Y, Feng Y, Wang Q, Pang W, Qi Z, Wang J, Yang D, Liu Y, Cao Y. Oral administration of vitamin D and importance in prevention of cerebral malaria. Int Immunopharmacol. 2018;64:356&#x2013;363.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30243072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley EL, Fine SC, Katipunan KK, Gooderham MJ. The use of janus kinase inhibitors in alopecia areata: a review of the literature. J Cutan Med Surg. 2019;23:289&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blume-Peytavi U, Vogt A. Translational positioning of janus kinase (JAK) inhibitors in alopecia areata. EBioMedicine. 2015;2:282&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4486199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26137570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves de Medeiros AK, Speeckaert R, Desmet E, Van Gele M, De Schepper S, Lambert J. JAK3 as an emerging target for topical treatment of inflammatory skin diseases. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0164080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5053514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27711196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xing L, Dai Z, Jabbari A, Cerise JE, Higgins CA, Gong W, de Jong A, Harel S, DeStefano GM, Rothman L, Singh P, Petukhova L, Mackay-Wiggan J, Christiano AM, Clynes R. Alopecia areata is driven by cytotoxic T lymphocytes and is reversed by JAK inhibition. Nat Med. 2014;20:1043&#x2013;1049.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4362521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25129481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang P, Zhang W, Zhang D, Wang M, Aprecio R, Ji N, Mohamed O, Li Y, Ding Y, Wang Q. 25-Hydroxyvitamin D(3) -enhanced PTPN2 positively regulates periodontal inflammation through the JAK/STAT pathway in human oral keratinocytes and a mouse model of type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Periodontal Res. 2018;53:467&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29516520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeitelhofer M, Adzemovic MZ, Gomez-Cabrero D, Bergman P, Hochmeister S, N&#x2019;diaye M, Paulson A, Ruhrmann S, Almgren M, Tegn&#xe9;r JN, Ekstr&#xf6;m TJ, Guerreiro-Cacais AO, Jagodic M. Functional genomics analysis of vitamin D effects on CD4+ T cells in vivo in experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2017;114:E1678&#x2013;E1687.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5338504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speiser JJ, Mondo D, Mehta V, Marcial SA, Kini A, Hutchens KA. Regulatory T-cells in alopecia areata. J Cutan Pathol. 2019;46:653&#x2013;658.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30989699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbari A, Petukhova L, Cabral RM, Clynes R, Christiano AM. Genetic basis of alopecia areata: a roadmap for translational research. Dermatol Clin. 2013;31:109&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4362526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23159180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han YM, Sheng YY, Xu F, Qi SS, Liu XJ, Hu RM, Miao Y, Huang GQ, Yang QP. Imbalance of T-helper 17 and regulatory T cells in patients with alopecia areata. J Dermatol. 2015;42:981&#x2013;988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26077574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Q, Qin S, Zhang J, Zhon L, Pen Z, Xing T. 1,25(OH)(2)D(3) induces regulatory T cell differentiation by influencing the VDR/PLC-&#x3b3;1/TGF-&#x3b2;1/pathway. Mol Immunol. 2017;91:156&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28926770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vijayendra Chary A, Hemalatha R, Seshacharyulu M, Vasudeva Murali M, Jayaprakash D, Dinesh Kumar B. Vitamin D deficiency in pregnant women impairs regulatory T cell function. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2015;147:48&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25448751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattozzi C, Paolino G, Salvi M, Macaluso L, Luci C, Morrone S, Calvieri S, Richetta AG. Peripheral blood regulatory T cell measurements correlate with serum vitamin D level in patients with psoriasis. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2016;20:1675&#x2013;1679.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27212156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorman S, Geldenhuys S, Judge M, Weeden CE, Waithman J, Hart PH. Dietary vitamin D increases percentages and function of regulatory T cells in the skin-draining lymph nodes and suppresses dermal inflammation. J Immunol Res. 2016;2016:1426503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5031886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27672666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prietl B, Treiber G, Mader JK, Hoeller E, Wolf M, Pilz S, Graninger WB, Obermayer-Pietsch BM, Pieber TR. High-dose cholecalciferol supplementation significantly increases peripheral CD4+ Tregs in healthy adults without negatively affecting the frequency of other immune cells. Eur J Nutr. 2014;53:751&#x2013;759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23999998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miko E, Meggyes M, Doba K, Barakonyi A, Szereday L. Immune checkpoint molecules in reproductive immunology. Front Immunol. 2019;10:846.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6482223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31057559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbo A, Belum VR, Sibaud V, Oudard S, Postow MA, Hsieh JJ, Motzer RJ, Busam KJ, Lacouture ME. Immune-related alopecia (areata and universalis) in cancer patients receiving immune checkpoint inhibitors. Br J Dermatol. 2017;176:1649&#x2013;1652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5459625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27943234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petukhova L, Duvic M, Hordinsky M, Norris D, Price V, Shimomura Y, Kim H, Singh P, Lee A, Chen WV, Meyer KC, Paus R, Jahoda CA, Amos CI, Gregersen PK, Christiano AM. Genome-wide association study in alopecia areata implicates both innate and adaptive immunity. Nature. 2010;466:113&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2921172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20596022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>John KK, Brockschmidt FF, Redler S, Herold C, Hanneken S, Eigelshoven S, Giehl KA, De Weert J, Lutz G, Kruse R, Wolff H, Blaumeiser B, B&#xf6;hm M, Becker T, N&#xf6;then MM, Betz RC. Genetic variants in CTLA4 are strongly associated with alopecia areata. J Invest Dermatol. 2011;131:1169&#x2013;1172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21346773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Megiorni F, Mora B, Maxia C, Gerardi M, Pizzuti A, Rossi A. Cytotoxic T-lymphocyte antigen 4 (CTLA4) +49AG and CT60 gene polymorphisms in Alopecia Areata: a case-control association study in the Italian population. Arch Dermatol Res. 2013;305:665&#x2013;670.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23567921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffery LE, Qureshi OS, Gardner D, Hou TZ, Briggs Z, Soskic B, Baker J, Raza K, Sansom DM. Vitamin D antagonises the suppressive effect of inflammatory cytokines on CTLA-4 expression and regulatory function. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0131539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26134669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kickler K, Ni Choileain S, Williams A, Richards A, Astier AL. Calcitriol modulates the CD46 pathway in T cells. PLoS One. 2012;7:e48486.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3483209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23144765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Belle TL, Vanherwegen AS, Feyaerts D, De Clercq P, Verstuyf A, Korf H, Gysemans C, Mathieu C. 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D3 and its analog TX527 promote a stable regulatory T cell phenotype in T cells from type 1 diabetes patients. PLoS One. 2014;9:e109194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4184870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25279717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidry J, Brown M, Medina T. PD-1 inhibitor induced alopecia areata. Dermatol Online J. 2018;24</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30677804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimitrov V, Bouttier M, Boukhaled G, Salehi-Tabar R, Avramescu RG, Memari B, Hasaj B, Lukacs GL, Krawczyk CM, White JH. Hormonal vitamin D up-regulate tissue-specific PD-L1 and PD-L2 surface glycoprotein expression in humans but not mice. J Biol Chem. 2017;292:20657&#x2013;20668.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5733602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29061851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bak NF, Bendix M, Hald S, Reinert L, Magnusson MK, Agnholt J. High-dose vitamin D(3) supplementation decreases the number of colonic CD103(+) dendritic cells in healthy subjects. Eur J Nutr. 2018;57:2607&#x2013;2619.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28913556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendix M, Greisen S, Dige A, Hvas CL, Bak N, J&#xf8;rgensen SP, Dahlerup JF, Deleuran B, Agnholt J. Vitamin D increases programmed death receptor-1 expression in Crohn&#x2019;s disease. Oncotarget. 2017;8:24177&#x2013;24186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5421837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28412753</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanherwegen AS, Cook DP, Ferreira GB, Gysemans C, Mathieu C. Vitamin D-modulated dendritic cells delay lethal graft-versus-host disease through induction of regulatory T cells. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2019;188:103&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30605776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simakou T, Butcher JP, Reid S, Henriquez FL. Alopecia areata: a multifactorial autoimmune condition. J Autoimmun. 2019;98:74&#x2013;85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prie BE, Voiculescu VM, Ionescu-Bozdog OB, Petrutescu B, Iosif L, Gaman LE, Clatici VG, Stoian I, Giurcaneanu C. Oxidative stress and alopecia areata. J Med Life. 2015;8:43&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4564047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26361510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siddique YH, Ara G, Afzal M. Estimation of lipid peroxidation induced by hydrogen peroxide in cultured human lymphocytes. Dose Response. 2012;10:1&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3299524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22423225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qui&#xf1;onez-Flores CM, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ch&#xe1;vez SA, Del R&#xed;o N&#xe1;jera D, Pacheco-Tena C. Oxidative stress relevance in the pathogenesis of the rheumatoid arthritis: a systematic review. Biomed Res Int. 2016;2016:6097417.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4906181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27340664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakry OA, Elshazly RM, Shoeib MA, Gooda A. Oxidative stress in alopecia areata: a case-control study. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2014;15:57&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23839259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haslam IS, Jadkauskaite L, Szab&#xf3; IL, Staege S, Hesebeck-Brinckmann J, Jenkins G, Bhogal RK, Lim FL, Farjo N, Farjo B, B&#xed;r&#xf3; T, Sch&#xe4;fer M, Paus R. Oxidative damage control in a human (mini-) organ: Nrf2 activation protects against oxidative stress-induced hair growth inhibition. J Invest Dermatol. 2017;137:295&#x2013;304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27702566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afshari L, Amani R, Soltani F, Haghighizadeh MH, Afsharmanesh MR. The relation between serum Vitamin D levels and body antioxidant status in ischemic stroke patients: a case-control study. Adv Biomed Res. 2015;4:213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4627183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26605242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sepehrmanesh Z, Kolahdooz F, Abedi F, Mazroii N, Assarian A, Asemi Z, Esmaillzadeh A. Vitamin D supplementation affects the beck depression inventory, insulin resistance, and biomarkers of oxidative stress in patients with major depressive disorder: a randomized, controlled clinical trial. J Nutr. 2016;146:243&#x2013;248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26609167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharifi N, Amani R, Hajiani E, Cheraghian B. Does vitamin D improve liver enzymes, oxidative stress, and inflammatory biomarkers in adults with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease? A randomized clinical trial. Endocrine. 2014;47:70&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24968737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghaderi A, Banafshe HR, Motmaen M, Rasouli-Azad M, Bahmani F, Asemi Z. Clinical trial of the effects of vitamin D supplementation on psychological symptoms and metabolic profiles in maintenance methadone treatment patients. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 2017;79:84&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28642082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razzaghi R, Pourbagheri H, Momen-Heravi M, Bahmani F, Shadi J, Soleimani Z, Asemi Z. The effects of vitamin D supplementation on wound healing and metabolic status in patients with diabetic foot ulcer: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Diabetes Complications. 2017;31:766&#x2013;772.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27363929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mansournia MA, Ostadmohammadi V, Doosti-Irani A, Ghayour-Mobarhan M, Ferns G, Akbari H, Ghaderi A, Talari HR, Asemi Z. The effects of vitamin D supplementation on biomarkers of inflammation and oxidative stress in diabetic patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Horm Metab Res. 2018;50:429&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29883970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbari M, Ostadmohammadi V, Lankarani KB, Tabrizi R, Kolahdooz F, Heydari ST, Kavari SH, Mirhosseini N, Mafi A, Dastorani M, Asemi Z. The effects of vitamin D supplementation on biomarkers of inflammation and oxidative stress among women with polycystic ovary syndrome: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Horm Metab Res. 2018;50:271&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29475212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sepidarkish M, Farsi F, Akbari-Fakhrabadi M, Namazi N, Almasi-Hashiani A, Maleki Hagiagha A, Heshmati J. The effect of vitamin D supplementation on oxidative stress parameters: a systematic review and meta-analysis of clinical trials. Pharmacol Res. 2019;139:141&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30447293</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berridge MJ. Vitamin D, reactive oxygen species and calcium signalling in ageing and disease. Philos Trans R Soc Lond B Biol Sci. 2016;371:20150434.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4938033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27377727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jadkauskaite L, Coulombe PA, Sch&#xe4;fer M, Dinkova-Kostova AT, Paus R, Haslam IS. Oxidative stress management in the hair follicle: could targeting NRF2 counter age-related hair disorders and beyond? Bioessays. 2017;39</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28685843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teixeira TM, da Costa DC, Resende AC, Soulage CO, Bezerra FF, Daleprane JB. Activation of Nrf2-antioxidant signaling by 1,25-dihydroxycholecalciferol prevents leptin-induced oxidative stress and inflammation in human endothelial cells. J Nutr. 2017;147:506&#x2013;513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28250190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen L, Yang R, Qiao W, Zhang W, Chen J, Mao L, Goltzman D, Miao D. 1,25-Dihydroxyvitamin D exerts an antiaging role by activation of Nrf2-antioxidant signaling and inactivation of p16/p53-senescence signaling. Aging Cell. 2019;18:e12951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6516172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30907059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dankers W, Colin EM, van Hamburg JP, Lubberts E. Vitamin D in autoimmunity: molecular mechanisms and therapeutic potential. Front Immunol. 2017;7:697.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5247472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28163705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubertret L, Wallach D, Souteyrand P, Perussel M, Kalis B, Meynadier J, Chevrant-Breton J, Beylot C, Bazex JA, Jurgensen HJ. Efficacy and safety of calcipotriol (MC 903) ointment in psoriasis vulgaris. A randomized, double-blind, right/left comparative, vehicle-controlled study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1992;27:983&#x2013;988.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1479106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berth-Jones J, Hutchinson PE. Alopecia totalis does not respond to the vitamin-D analogue calcipotriol. J Dermatol Treat. 1991;1:293&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Segaert S, Shear NH, Chiricozzi A, Tha&#xe7;i D, Carrascosa JM, Young H, Descamps V. Optimizing anti-inflammatory and immunomodulatory effects of corticosteroid and vitamin D analogue fixed-dose combination therapy. Dermatol Ther (Heidelb) 2017;7:265&#x2013;279.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5574747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28785924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rork JF, Rashighi M, Harris JE. Understanding autoimmunity of vitiligo and alopecia areata. Curr Opin Pediatr. 2016;28:463&#x2013;469.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4957563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27191524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibrahim ZA, Hassan GF, Elgendy HY, Al-Shenawy HA. Evaluation of the efficacy of transdermal drug delivery of calcipotriol plus betamethasone versus tacrolimus in the treatment of vitiligo. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2019;18:581&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30009490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumaran MS, Kaur I, Kumar B. Effect of topical calcipotriol, betamethasone dipropionate and their combination in the treatment of localized vitiligo. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2006;20:269&#x2013;273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16503885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>