<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">32056210</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1750-3841</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>85</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of food science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Food Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The role of smart packaging system in food supply chain.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>517</StartPage><EndPage>525</EndPage><MedlinePgn>517-525</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1750-3841.15046</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Food supply chain is a rapidly growing integrated sector and covers all the aspects from farm to fork, including manufacturing, packaging, distribution, storing, as well as further processing or cooking for consumption. Along this chain, smart packaging could impact the quality, safety, and sustainability of food. Packaging systems have evolved to be smarter with integration of emerging electronics and wireless communication and cloud data solutions. Although there are many factors causing the loss and waste issues for foods throughout the whole supply chain of food and there have been several articles showing the recent advances and breakthroughs in developing smart packaging systems, this review integrates these conceptual frameworks and technological applications and focuses on how innovative smart packaging solutions are beneficial to the overall quality and safety of food supply by enhancing product traceability and reducing the amount of food loss and waste. We start by introducing the concept of the management for the integrated food supply chain, which is critical in tactical and operational components that can enhance product traceability within the entire chain. Then we highlight the impact of smart packaging in reducing food loss and waste. We summarize the basic information of the common printing techniques for smart packaging system (sensor and indicator). Then, we discuss the potential challenges in the manufacturing and deployment of smart packaging systems, as well as their cost-related drawbacks and further steps in food supply chain.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Institute of Food Technologists&#xae;.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Shoue</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Packaging, Michigan State Univ., East Lansing, MI, 48824, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Soft Machines &amp; Electronics, School of Packaging, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Michigan State Univ., East Lansing, MI, 48824, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brahma</LastName><ForeName>Sandrayee</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2159-7411</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dept. of Food Science &amp; Technology, Univ. of Nebraska-Lincoln, Lincoln, NE, 68588, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mackay</LastName><ForeName>Jonathon</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Management, Operations and Marketing, Univ. of Wollongong, Wollongong, NSW, 2522, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cao</LastName><ForeName>Changyong</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Laboratory for Soft Machines &amp; Electronics, School of Packaging, Department of Mechanical Engineering, Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Michigan State Univ., East Lansing, MI, 48824, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aliakbarian</LastName><ForeName>Bahar</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Packaging, Michigan State Univ., East Lansing, MI, 48824, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Axia Inst., Dept. of Supply Chain Management, Michigan State Univ., Midland, MI, 48640, U.S.A.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>#RG100358-17P10</GrantID><Agency>Michigan State University</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><Agency>Axia Institute</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Food Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0014052</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0022-1147</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003132" MajorTopicYN="N">Commerce</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004581" MajorTopicYN="N">Electronics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018857" MajorTopicYN="N">Food Packaging</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="N">economics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000295" MajorTopicYN="N">instrumentation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005523" MajorTopicYN="Y">Food Supply</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000191" MajorTopicYN="N">economics</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flexible electronics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">food safety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">food waste</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">printing technologies</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">smart packaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">supply chain management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sustainability</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32056210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1750-3841.15046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Abad, E., Zampolli, S., Marco, S., Scorzoni, A., Mazzolai, B., Juarros, A., &#x2026; Gomez, J. (2007). Flexible tag microlab development: Gas sensors integration in RFID flexible tags for food logistic. Sensors and Actuators B: Chemical, 127, 2-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahumada, O., &amp; Villabos, J. R. (2009). Application of planning models in the agri-food supply chain: A review. European Journal of Operational Research, 196, 1-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akkerman, R., Farahani, P., &amp; Grunow, M. (2010). Quality, safety and sustainability in food distribution: A review of quantitative operations management approaches and challenges. Or Spectrum, 32, 863-904.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alamar, M., del, C., Falag&#xe1;n, N., Aktas, E., &amp; Terry, L. A. (2018). Minimising food waste: A call for multidisciplinary research. Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture, 98(1), 8-11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliakbarian, B. (2019). Smart packaging: Challenges and opportunities in the supply chain. CSCMP's Supply Chain Quarterly, Quarter 1, 2019 issue, 34-38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliakbarian, B., Bagnasco, L., Perego, P., Leardi, R., &amp; Casale, M. (2016). Uv-vis spectroscopy for monitoring yogurt stability during storage time. Analytical Methods, 8(30), 5962-5969.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliakbarian, B., Casazza, A. A., &amp; Perego, P. (2011). Valorization of olive oil solid waste using high pressure-high temperature reactor. Food Chemistry, 128(3), 704-710.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliakbarian, B., Casale, M., Paini, M., Casazza, A. A., Lanteri, S., &amp; Perego, P. (2015). Production of a novel fermented milk fortied with natural antioxidants and its analysis by NIR spectroscopy. LWT-Food Science and Technology, 62(1), 376-383.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliakbarian, B., Fathi, A., Perego, P., &amp; Dehghani, F. (2012). Extraction of antioxidants from winery wastes using subcritical water. Journal of Supercritical Fluids, 65, 18-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliakbarian, B., Paini, M., Adami, R., Perego, P., &amp; Reverchon, E. (2017). Use of Supercritical Assisted Atomization to produce nanoparticles from olive pomace extract. Innovative Food Science and Emerging Technologies, 40, 2-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aliakbarian, B., Sampaio, F. C., de Faria, J. T., Pitangui, C. G., Lovaglio, F., Casazza, A. A., &#x2026; Perego, P. (2018). Optimization of spray drying microencapsulation of olive pomace polyphenols using Response Surface Methodology and Artificial Neural Network. LWT-Food Science and Technology, 93, 220-228.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amorim, P., G&#xfc;nther, H. O., &amp; Almada-Lobo, B. (2012). Multi-objective integrated production and distribution planning of perishable products. International Journal of Production Economics, 138, 89-101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aruoma, O. I. (2006). The impact of food regulation on the food supply chain. Toxicology, 221, 119-127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arvanitoyannis, I. S., &amp; Stratakos, A. C. (2012). Application of modified atmosphere packaging and active/smart technologies to red meat and poultry: A review. Food and Bioprocess Technology, 5, 1423-1446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badia-Melis, R., Mc Carthy, U., Ruiz-Garcia, L., Garcia-Hierro, J., &amp; Villalba, J. R. (2018). New trends in cold chain monitoring applications-a review. Food Control, 86, 170-182.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahadur, K., Haque, I., Legwegoh, A. F., &amp; Fraser, E. D. (2016). Strategies to reduce food loss in the global South. Sustainability, 8(7), 595.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bibi, F., Guillaume, C., Gontard, N., &amp; Sorli, B. (2017). A review: Rfid technology having sensing aptitudes for food industry and their contribution to tracking and monitoring of food products. Trends in Food Science &amp; Technology, 62, 91-103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blackburin, J., &amp; Scudder, G. (2009). Supply chain strategies for perishable products: The case of fresh produce. Production and Operations Management, 18, 129-137.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broad Leib, E. M., Gunders, D., Ferro, J., Nielsen, A., Nosek, G., &amp; Qu, J. (2013). The dating game: How confusing date labels lead to food waste in America, Natural Resources Defense Council Report.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosona, T., &amp; Gebresenbet, G. (2013). Food traceability as an integral part of logistics management in food and agricultural supply chain. Food Control, 33, 32-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvert, P. (2001). Inkjet printing for materials and devices. Chemistry of Materials, 13(10), 3299-3305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao, C., Andrews, J. B., &amp; Franklin, A. D. (2017). Completely printed, flexible, stable, and hysteresis-free carbon nanotube thin-film transistors via aerosol jet printing. Advanced Electronic Materials, 3(5), 1700057.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter, C. R., Rogers, D. S., &amp; Choi, T. Y. (2015). Toward the theory of the supply chain. Journal of Supply Chain Management, 51, 89-97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casazza, A. A., Aliakbarian, B., Lagazzo, A., Garbarino, G., Carnasciali, M. M., Perego, P., &amp; Busca, G. (2016). Pyrolysis of grape marc before and after the recovery of polyphenol fraction. Fuel Processing Technology, 153, 121-128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casazza, A. A., Aliakbarian, B., Mantegna, S., Cravotto, G., &amp; Perego, P. (2010). Extraction of phenolics from Vitis vinifera wastes using non-conventional techniques. Journal of Food Engineering, 100(1), 50-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaturvedi, A., &amp; Mart&#xed;nez-De-Alb&#xe9;niz, V. (2016). Safety stock, excess capacity or diversification: Trade-offs under supply and demand uncertainty. Production &amp; Operations Management, 25, 77-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chu, Y., Qian, C., Chahal, P., &amp; Cao, C. (2018). Printed Diodes: Materials processing, fabrication and applications. Advanced Science, 6(6). https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.201801653</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dainelli, D., Gontard, N., Spyropoulos, D., Zondervan-van den Beuken, E., &amp; Tobback, P. (2008). Active and intelligent food packaging: Legal aspects and safety concerns. Trends in Food Science &amp; Technology, 19, S103-S112.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Gans, B. J., Duineveld, P. C., &amp; Schubert, U. S. (2004). Inkjet printing of polymers: State of the art and future developments. Advanced Materials, 16(3), 203-213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demoustier, S., Minoux, E., Le Baillif, M., Charles, M., &amp; Ziaei, A. (2008). Review of two microwave applications of carbon nanotubes: Nano-antennas and nano-switches. Comptes Rendus Physique, 9(1), 53-66.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devin, B., &amp; Richards, C. (2018). Food waste, power, and corporate social responsibility in the Australian food supply chain. Journal of Business Ethics, 150(1), 199-210.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duncan, T. V. (2011). Applications of nanotechnology in food packaging and food safety: Barrier materials, antimicrobials and sensors. Journal of Colloid and Interface Science, 363(1), 1-24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Esser, B., Schnorr, J. M., &amp; Swager, T. M. (2012). Selective detection of ethylene gas using carbon nanotube-based devices: utility in determination of fruit ripeness. Angewandte Chemie International Edition, 51(23), 5752-5756.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang, Z., Zhao, Y., Warner, R. D., &amp; Johnson, S. K. (2017). Active and intelligent packaging in meat industry. Trends Food Scientific Technology, 61, 60-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO). (2011). Food loss and food waste. Retrieved from http://www.fao.org/food-loss-and-food-waste/en/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiddes, L. K., &amp; Yan, N. (2013). Rfid tags for wireless electrochemical detection of volatile chemicals. Sensors and Actuators B: Chemical, 186, 817-823.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fiksel, J. (2015). Resilient by Design: Creating businesses that adapt and flourish in a changing world. From risk to resilience (pp. 19-34). Berlin, Germany: Island Press/Center for Resource Economics, Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn, B. B., Huo, B., &amp; Zhao, X. (2010). The impact of supply chain integration on performance: A contingency and configuration approach. Journal of Operations Management, 28, 58-71.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flynn, B. B., Koufteros, X., &amp; Lu, G. (2016). On theory in supply chain uncertainty and its implications for supply chain integration. Journal of Supply Chain Management, 52, 3-27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foscaches, C. A. L., Sproesser, R. L., Quevedo-Silva, F., &amp; de Lima-Filho, D. (2012). Log&#xed;stica de frutas, legumes e verduras (FLV): Um estudo sobre embalagem, armazenamento e transporte em pequenas cidades brasileiras. Informa&#xe7;&#xf5;es Econ&#xf4;micas, 42, 37-46.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuertes, G., Soto, I., Carrasco, R., Vargas, M., Sabattin, J., &amp; Lagos, C. (2016). Intelligent packaging systems: sensors and nanosensors to monitor food quality and safety. Journal of Sensors, 2016, 1-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gills, R., Sharma, J. P. &amp; Bhardwaj, T. (2015). Achieving zero hunger through zero wastage: An overview of present scenario and future reflections. Indian Journal of Agricultural Science, 85(9), 1127&#x2212;1133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#xf6;bel, C., Nina, L., Antonia, B., Petra, T., &amp; Guido, R. (2015). Cutting food waste through cooperation along the food supply chain. Sustainability, 7(2), 1429-1445.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Govindan, K., Jafarian, A., Khodaverdi, R., &amp; Devika, K. (2014). Two-echelon multiple-vehicle location-routing problem with time windows for optimization of sustainable supply chain network of perishable food. International Journal of Production Economics, 152, 9-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grau, G., Cen, J., Kang, H., Kitsomboonloha, R., Scheideler, W. J., &amp; Subramanian, V. (2016). Gravure-printed electronics: Recent progress in tooling development, understanding of printing physics, and realization of printed devices. Flexible and Printed Electronics, 1(2), 023002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffin, M., Sobal, J., &amp; Lyson, T. (2009). An analysis of a community food waste stream. Agriculture and Human Values, 26(1-2), 67-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunders, D. (2012). Wasted: How America is losing up to 40 percent of its food from farm to fork to landfill. Natural Resources Defense Council Issue Paper.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustavsson, J., Cederberg, C., Sonesson, U., van Otterdijk, R., &amp; Meybeck, A. (2011). Global food losses and food waste, Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations. Rome, Italy: FAO.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall, K. D., Guo, J., Dore, M., &amp; Chow, C. C. (2009). The progressive increase of food waste in America and its environmental impact. PLoS ONE, 4(11), 9-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han, J. W., Ruiz-Garcia, L., Qian, J. P., &amp; Yang, X. T. (2018). Food packaging: A comprehensive review and future trends. Comprehensive Reviews in Food Science and Food Safety, 17(4), 860-877.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heller, M. C., Selke, S. E. M., &amp; Keoleian, G. A. (2018). Mapping the influence of food waste in food packaging environmental performance assessments. Journal of Industrial Ecology, 00(0), 1-16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>HLPE (2014). Food Losses and Waste in the Context of Sustainable Food Systems. A report by the High Level Panel of Experts on Food Security and Nutrition of the Committee on World Food Security, Rome.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrytsenko, O., Hrytsenko, D., Shvalagin, V., Grodziuk, G., &amp; Kompanets, M. (2018). The use of carbon nanoparticles for inkjet-printed functional labels for smart packaging. Journal of Nanomaterials, 2018, 1-10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hrytsenko, O., Shvalagin, V., Grodziuk, G., &amp; Granchak, V. (2017). Influence of parameters of screen printing on photoluminescence properties of nanophotonic labels for smart packaging. Journal of Nanotechnology, 2017, 1-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ivanov, D., Sokolov, B., &amp; Dolgui, A. (2014). The Ripple effect in supply chains: Trade-off &#x2018;efficiency-flexibility-resilience&#x2019; in disruption management. International Journal of Production Research, 52(7), 2154-2172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janjarasskul, T., &amp; Suppakul, P. (2018). Active and intelligent packaging: The indication of quality and safety. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition, 58(5), 808-831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaradat, R., Adams, F., Abutabenjeh, S., &amp; Keating, C. (2017). The complementary perspective of system of systems in collaboration, integration, and logistics: A value-chain based paradigm of supply chain management. Systems, 5(4), 50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jedermann, R., Behrens, C., Westphal, D., &amp; Lang, W. (2006). Applying autonomous sensor systems in logistics-Combining sensor networks, RFIDs and software agents. Sensors and Actuators A: Physical, 132(1), 370-375.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang, X., Valdeperez, D., Nazarenus, M., Wang, Z., Stellacci, F., Parak, W. J., &amp; del Pino, P. (2014). Future perspectives towards the use of nanomaterials for smart food packaging and quality control. Particle &amp; Particle Systems Characterization, 32(4), 408-416.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung, M., Kim, J., Koo, H., Lee, W., Subramanian, V., &amp; Cho, G. (2014). Roll-to-roll gravure with nanomaterials for printing smart packaging. Journal of Nanoscience and Nanotechnology, 14(2), 1303-1317.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xfc;ttner, U., &amp; Maklan, S. (2011). Supply chain resilience in the global financial crisis: An empirical study. Supply Chain Management: An International Journal, 16(4), 246-259.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaipia, R., Dukovska-Popovska, I., &amp; Loikkanen, L. (2013). Creating sustainable fresh food supply chains through waste reduction. International Journal of Physical Distribution &amp; Logistics Management, 43(3), 262-276.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamalahmadi, M., &amp; Parast, M. M. (2016). A review of the literature on the principles of enterprise and supply chain resilience: Major findings and directions for future research. International Journal of Production Economics, 171, 116-133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kantor, L. S., Lipton, K., Manchester, A., &amp; Oliveira, V. (1997). Estimating and addressing America's food losses. Food Review, 1264(202), 2-12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelepourist, T., Pramatari, K., &amp; Doukidis, G. (2007). RFID-enabled traceability in the food supply chain. Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems, 107, 183-200.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerry, J., &amp; Butler, P. (2008). Smart packaging technologies for fast moving consumer goods. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerry, J. P., O'grady, M. N., &amp; Hogan, S. A. (2006). Past, current and potential utilization of active and intelligent packaging systems for meat and muscle-based products: A review. Meat science, 74, 113-130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan, S., Lorenzelli, L., &amp; Dahiya, R. S. (2015). Technologies for printing sensors and electronics over large flexible substrates: A review. IEEE Sensors Journal, 15(6), 3164-3185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, K., Kim, E., &amp; Lee, S. J. (2012). New enzymatic time-temperature integrator (TTI) that uses laccase. Journal of Food Engineering, 113(1), 118-123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim, Y., Jung, B., Lee, H., Kim, H., Lee, K., &amp; Park, H. (2009). Capacitive humidity sensor design based on anodic aluminum oxide. Sensors and Actuators B: Chemical, 141(2), 441-446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraft, T. M., Berger, P. R., &amp; Lupo, D. (2017). Printed and organic diodes: Devices, circuits and applications. Flexible and Printed Electronics, 2(3), 033001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulchan, R., Boonsupthip, W., Jinkarn, T., &amp; Suppakul, P. (2016). Developing a novel colorimetric indicator for monitoring rancidity reaction and estimating the accelerated shelf life of oxygen-sensitive dairy products. International Food Research Journal, 23, 1092-1099.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, P., Reinitz, H. W., Simunovic, J., Sandeep, K. P., &amp; Franzon, P. D. (2009). Overview of RFID technology and its applications in the food industry. Journal of Food Science, 74, R101-R106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumari, L., Narsaiah, K., Grewal, M. K., &amp; Anurag, R. K. (2015). Application of RFID in agri-food sector. Trends in Food Science &amp; Technology, 43(2), 144-161.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kummu, M., de Moel, H., Porkka, M., Siebert, S., Varis, O., &amp; Ward, P. J. (2012). Lost food wasted resources: Global food supply chain losses and their impacts on freshwater, cropland, and fertiliser use. Science of the Total Environment, 438, 477-489.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuswandi, B., Wicaksono, Y., Jayus Abdullah, A., &amp; Heng, L. Y., Ahmad, M. (2011). Smart packaging: Sensors for monitoring of food quality and safety. Sensing and Instrumentation for Food Quality and Safety, 5(3), 137-146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert, D. M., Cooper, M. C., &amp; Pagh, J. D. (1998). Supply chain management: Implementation issues and research opportunities. International Journal of Logistics Management, 9, 1-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, H. L., Padmanabhan, V., &amp; Whang, S. (1997). The bullwhip effect in supply chains. MIT Sloan Management Review, 38, 93-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leenen, M. A., Arning, V., Thiem, H., Steiger, J., &amp; Anselmann, R. (2009). Printable electronics: Flexibility for the future. Physica Status Solidi (a), 206(4), 588-597.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leuschner, R., Rogers, D. S., &amp; Charvet, F. F. (2013). A meta-analysis of supply chain integration and firm performance. Journal of Supply Chain Management, 49, 34-57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levin, S. A. (1998). Ecosystems and the biosphere as complex adaptive systems. Ecosystems, 1(5), 431-436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liljestrand, K. (2017). Logistics solutions for reducing food waste. International Journal of Physical Distribution &amp; Logistics Management, 47(4), 318-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipinski, B., Hanson, C., &amp; Lomax, J. (2013). Reducing food loss and waste. Creating a Sustainable Food Future, Working Paper, World Resources Institute (June 2013), 1-40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopez-Rubio, A., Almenar, E., Hernandez-Munoz, P., Lagaron, J. M., Catala, R., &amp; Gavara, R. (2004). Overview of active polymer-based packaging technologies for food applications. Food Reviews International, 20(4), 357-387.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopresto, C. G., Petrillo, F., Casazza, A. A., Aliakbarian, B., Perego, P., &amp; Calabr&#xf2;, V. (2014). A nonconventional method to extract d-limonene from waste lemon peels and comparison with traditional soxhlet extraction. Separation and Purification Technology, 137, 13-20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe, T. J., &amp; Preckel, P. V. (2004). Decision technologies for agribusiness problems: A brief review of selected literature and a call for research. Manufacturing &amp; Service Operations Management, 6, 201-208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majid, I., Nayik, G. A., Dar, S. M., &amp; Nanda, V. (2018). Novel food packaging technologies: Innovations and future prospective. Journal of the Saudi Society of Agricultural Sciences, 17, 454-462.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maksud, M. I., Yusof, M. S., &amp; Abdul Jamil, M. M. (2012). Study on finite element analysis of fine solid lines by flexographic printing in printed antennas for RFID transponder. International Journal of Integrated Engineering, 4(3), 35-39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mason-Jones, R., Naylor, B., &amp; Towill, D. R. (2000). Lean, agile or leagile? Matching your supply chain to the marketplace. International Journal of Production Research, 38(17), 4061-4070.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McFarlane, D., &amp; Sheffi, Y. (2003). The impact of automatic identification on supply chain operations. International Journal of Logistics Management, 14, 1-17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mena, C., Adenso-Diaz, B., &amp; Yurt, O. (2011). The causes of food waste in the supplier-retailer interface: Evidences from the UK and Spain. Resources, Conservation and Recycling, 55(6), 648-658.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mentzer, J. T., Dewitt, W., Keebler, J. S., Min, S., Nix, N. W., Smith, C. D., &amp; Zacharia, Z. G. (2001). Defining supply chain management. Journal of Business Logistics, 22, 1-25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mik&#x1e67;-Krajnik, M., Yoon, Y. J., Ukuku, D. O., &amp; Yuk, H. G. (2016). Identification and quantification of volatile chemical spoilage indexes associated with bacterial growth dynamics in aerobically stored chicken. Journal of Food Science, 81(8), M2006-M2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monereo, O., Boix, M., Claramunt, S., Prades, J. D., Cornet, A., Cirera, A., &#x2026; Merino, C. (2011). Advanced performances in gas sensors: Stretchable, flexible, wireless, wearable. Procedia Engineering, 25, 1425-1428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mourad, M. (2016). Recycling, recovering and preventing &#x201c;food waste&#x201d;: Competing solutions for food systems sustainability in the United States and France. Journal of Cleaner Production, 126, 461-477.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muller, P., &amp; Schmid, M. (2019). Intelligent packaging in the food sector: A brief overview. Foods, 8, 16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naylor, J. B., Mohamed, M. N., &amp; Danny, B. (1999). Leagility: Integrating the lean and agile manufacturing paradigms in the total supply chain. International Journal of Production Economics, 62(1), 107-118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neethirajan, S., &amp; Jayas, D. S. (2011). Nanotechnology for the food and bioprocessing industries. Food and Bioprocess Technology, 4(1), 39-47.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neff, R. A., Kanter, R., &amp; Vandevijvere, S. (2015). Reducing food loss and waste while improving the public's health. Health Affairs, 34(11), 1821-1829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nomikos, S., Politis, A., Renieri, D., Tsigonias, M. K., &amp; Kakizis, N. K. (2014). Printed technologies for intelligent packaging applications and their impact on printed electronics market. China Instrumentation Journal, 1(1), 1-4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Occhiuzzi, C., Rida, A., Marrocco, G., &amp; Tentzeris, M. (2011). Rd passive gas sensor integrating carbon nanotubes. IEEE Transactions on Microwave Theory and Techniques, 59(10), 2674-2684.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olsmats, C., &amp; Wallteg, B. (2009). Packaging is the answer to World hunger. Vienna, Australia: World Packaging Organization (WPO) and International Packaging Press Organization (IPPO).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onses, M. S., Sutanto, E., Ferreira, P. M., Alleyne, A. G., &amp; Rogers, J. A. (2015). Mechanisms, capabilities, and applications of high-resolution electrohydrodynamic jet printing. Small, 11(34), 4237-4266.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ordonez, J. A., De Pablo, B., Perez de Castro, B., Asensio, M. A., &amp; Sanz, B. (1991). Selected chemical and microbiological changes in refrigerated pork stored in carbon dioxide and oxygen enriched atmospheres. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry, 39(4), 668-672.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pacquit, A., Frisby, J., Diamond, D., Lau, K. T., Farrell, A., Quilty, B., &amp; Diamond, D. (2007). Development of a smart packaging for the monitoring of fish spoilage. Food Chemistry, 102(2), 466-470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pardo, D. A., Jabbour, G. E., &amp; Peyghambarian, N. (2000). Application of screen printing in the fabrication of organic light-emitting devices. Advanced Materials, 12(17), 1249-1252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parfitt, J., Barthel, M., &amp; Macnaughton, S. (2010). Food waste within food supply chains: Quantification and potential for change to 2050. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 365(1554), 3065-3081.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pham, T. P. T., Kaushik, R., Parshetti, G. K., Mahmood, R., &amp; Balasubramanian, R. (2015). Food waste-to-energy conversion technologies: Current status and future directions. Waste Management (New York, N.Y.), 38, 399-408.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potyrailo, R. A., Mouquin, H., &amp; Morris, W. G. (2008). Position-independent chemical quantitation with passive 13.56-MHz radio frequency identification (RFID) sensors. Talanta, 75(3), 624-628.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potyrailo, R. A., Nagraj, N., Tang, Z., Mondello, F. J., Surman, C., &amp; Morris, W. (2012). Battery-free radio frequency identification (RFID) sensors for food quality and safety. Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry, 60(35), 8535-8543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poyatos-Racionero, E., Ros-Lis, J. V., Vivancos, J. L., &amp; Mart&#xed;nez-M&#xe1;&#xf1;ez, R. (2018). Recent advances on intelligent packaging as tools to reduce food waste. Journal of Cleaner Production, 172, 3398-3409.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pradeep, P., Junho, J., &amp; Sanghoon, K. (2012). Carbon dioxide sensors for intelligent food packaging applications. Food Control, 25, 328-333.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prasad, P., &amp; Kochhar, A. (2014). Active packaging in food industry: A review. Journal of Environmental Science, Toxicology and Food Technology, 8, 1-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rokugawa, H., &amp; Fujikawa, H. (2015). Evaluation of a new Maillard reaction type time-temperature integrator at various temperatures. Food Control, 57, 355-361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sample, A. P., Yeager, D. J., Powledge, P. S., Mamishev, A. V., &amp; Smith, J. R. (2008). Design of an RFID-based battery-free programmable sensing platform. IEEE Transactions on Instrumentation and Measurements, 57(11), 2608-2615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sannita, E., Aliakbarian, B., Casazza, A. A., Perego, P., &amp; Busca, G. (2012). Medium-temperature conversion of biomass and wastes into liquid products: A review. Renewable &amp; Sustainable Energy Reviews, 16(8), 6455-6475.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt, G., &amp; Wilhelm, W. E. (2000). Strategic, tactical and operational decisions in multi-national logistics networks: A review and discussion of modelling issues. International Journal of Production Research, 38, 1501-1523.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secor, E. B., Prabhumirashi, P. L., Puntambekar, K., Geier, M. L., &amp; Hersam, M. C. (2013). Inkjet printing of high conductivity, flexible graphene patterns. Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters, 4(8), 1347-1351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Semple, J., Georgiadou, D. G., Wyatt-Moon, G., Gelinck, G., &amp; Anthopoulos, T. D. (2017). Flexible diodes for radio frequency (RF) electronics: A materials perspective. Semiconductor Science and Technology, 32(12), 1-45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafiee-Jood, M., &amp; Cai, X. (2016). Reducing food loss and waste to enhance food security and environmental sustainability. Environmental Science and Technology, 50(16), 8432-8443.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheffi, Y., &amp; Rice JR, J. B. (2005). A supply chain view of the resilient entreprise. MIT Sloan Management Review, 47, 41-48.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, M., Haverinen, H. M., Dhagat, P., &amp; Jabbour, G. E. (2010). Inkjet printing-Process and its applications. Advanced Materials, 22(6), 673-685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohail, M., Sun, D.-W., &amp; Zhu, Z. (2018). Recent developments in intelligent packaging for enhancing food quality and safety. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition, 58, 2650-2662.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song, J. W., Kim, J., Yoon, Y. H., Choi, B. S., Kim, J. H., &amp; Han, C. S. (2008). Inkjet printing of single-walled carbon nanotubes and electrical characterization of the line pattern. Nanotechnology, 19(9), 1-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stauffer, D. (2003). Risk: The weak link in your supply chain. Harvard Management Update, 8, 3-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens, G. C. (1989). Integrating the supply chain. International Journal of Physical Distribution &amp; Materials Management, 19, 3-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tentzeris, M. M. (2008). Novel paper-based inkjet-printed antennas and wireless sensor modules. In 2008 IEEE International Conference on Microwaves, Communications, Antennas and Electronic Systems (pp. 1-8).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ThinFilm. (2013). Thinfilm Builds First Stand-Alone Sensor System in Printed Electronics. Retrieved from http://www.thinfilm.no/news/stand-alone-system/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tortorich, R. P., &amp; Choi, J. W. (2013). Inkjet printing of carbon nanotubes. Nanomaterials, 3(3), 453-468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations (UN). (2018a). Goal 2: End hunger, achieve food security and improved nutrition and promote sustainable agriculture. Retrieved from https://unstats.un.org/sdgs/report/2016/goal-02/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>United Nations (UN). (2018b). Sustainable Development Goals (SDG): 17 goals to transform our world. Retrieved from https://www.un.org/sustainabledevelopment/sustainable-development-goals/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Vorst, J. G. A. J., Tromp, S. O., &amp; Zee, D. J. V. D. (2009). Simulation modelling for food supply chain redesign; integrated decision making on product quality, sustainability and logistics. International Journal of Production Research, 47, 6611-6631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vander Vaart, T., &amp; Van Donk, D. P. (2008). A critical review of survey-based research in supply chain integration. International Journal of Production Economics, 111, 42-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderroost, M., Ragaert, P., Devlieghere, F., &amp; De Meulenaer, B. (2014). Intelligent food packaging: The next generation. Trends in Food Science &amp; Technology, 39(1), 47-62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verghese, K., Helen, L., Simon, L., &amp; Hel&#xe9;n, W. (2015). Packaging's role in minimizing food loss and waste across the supply chain. Packaging Technology and Science, 28(7), 603-620.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilari&#xf1;o, M. V., Franco, C., &amp; Quarrington, C. (2017). Food loss and waste reduction as an integral part of a circular economy. Frontiers in Environmental Science, 5(21), 1-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, X., &amp; Li, D. (2012). A dynamic product quality evaluation-based pricing model for perishable food supply chains. Omega, 40, 906-917.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waste &amp; Resources Action Program (WRAP). (2011). Consumer insight: Date labels and storage guidance. Retrieved from http://www.wrap.org.uk/content/consumer-insight-date-labels-and-storage-guidance</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Resource Institute. (2018). Food loss &amp; waste protocol addressing the challenges of quantifying food loss and waste. Retrieved from https://www.wri.org/our-work/project/food-loss-waste-protocol</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wunderlich, S. M., &amp; Martinez, N. M. (2018). Conserving natural resources through food loss reduction: Production &amp; consumption stages of the food supply chain. International Soil and Water Conservation Research, 6(4), 331-339.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyser, Y., Adams, M., Avella, M., Carlander, D., Garcia, L., Pieper, G., &#x2026; Weiss, J. (2016). Outlook and challenges of nanotechnologies for food packaging. Packaging Technology and Science, 29(12), 615-648.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xerox. (2015). Xerox launches printed memory products to combat counterfeiting. Retrieved from https://www.news.xerox.com/news/Xerox-Launches-Printed-Memory-to-Combat-Counterfeiting</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue, L., Liu, G., Parfitt, J., Liu, X., Van Herpen, E., Stenmarck, &#xc5;., &amp; Cheng, S. (2017). Missing food, missing data? A critical review of global food losses and food waste data. Environmental Science &amp; Technology, 51(12), 6618-6633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zou, Y., Wan, H., Zhang, X., Ha, D., &amp; Wang, P. (2015). Electronic nose and electronic tongue. Bioinspired smell and taste sensors. In Beijing and Springer Science Business Media Dordrecht. Beijing, China: Science Press.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>