<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39739902</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-4632</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>64</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International journal of dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int J Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Segmental vitiligo: autoimmune pathogenesis, neuronal mechanisms, and somatic mosaicism.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>490</StartPage><EndPage>498</EndPage><MedlinePgn>490-498</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ijd.17627</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Vitiligo is a common depigmentation disorder classified into nonsegmental vitiligo (NSV) and segmental vitiligo (SV). SV accounts for 5-27.9% of patients with vitiligo. The primary pathogenesis of NSV involves the autoimmune-mediated destruction of melanocytes. Recently, an autoimmune pathogenesis of SV was identified. High levels of melanocyte antigen-specific CD8+ T&#xa0;cells are found in early SV lesional skin infiltrating around melanocytes along the basal layer. Mixed vitiligo suggests an overlap in pathogenesis between SV and NSV. In active SV, serum innate immune cytokines, and CD8+ T&#xa0;cell cytokines are increased. Oxidative stress in SV may activate autoimmune responses. SV pathogenesis is associated with a local cytotoxic response targeting epidermal melanocytes. Theories have been put forward to explain the segmental pattern in SV. The previous basis of the neurogenic theory that SV results from dermatomes is no longer accepted. However, there are still research reports supporting this theory. Evaluating the distribution pattern of SV lesions has provided clues to the mosaicism detection of suspected melanocytic defects at the site of SV lesions, supporting this theory. Evidence points to a cytotoxic response targeting mosaic melanocytes. Understanding SV's autoimmune pathogenesis prompts a reevaluation of immunosuppressive medical treatments for SV. The excellent results of autologous melanocyte transplantation in SV lesions compared with the moderate to limited results in patients with NSV support the mosaicism theory.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 the International Society of Dermatology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Xiran</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6860-4263</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meng</LastName><ForeName>Xianmin</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Laboratory Medicine, Axia Women's Health, Oaks, PA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lin</LastName><ForeName>Jingrong</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University, Dalian, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Int J Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0243704</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0011-9059</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014820" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vitiligo</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Melanocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000637" MajorTopicYN="N">transplantation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009030" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mosaicism</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015551" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmunity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001327" MajorTopicYN="Y">Autoimmune Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018414" MajorTopicYN="N">CD8-Positive T-Lymphocytes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018384" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxidative Stress</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune pathogenesis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurogenic theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">segmental vitiligo</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">somatic mosaicism</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39739902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijd.17627</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Bergqvist C, Ezzedine K. Vitiligo: a review. Dermatology. 2020;236:571&#x2013;592. https://doi.org/10.1159/000506103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzedine K, Lim HW, Suzuki T, Katayama I, Hamzavi I, Lan CC, et&#xa0;al. Revised classification/nomenclature of vitiligo and related issues: the vitiligo global issues consensus conference. Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2012;25:E1&#x2013;E13. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1755&#x2010;148X.2012.00997.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Geel N, Speeckaert R. Segmental vitiligo. Dermatol Clin. 2017;35:145&#x2013;150. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.det.2016.11.005</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khaitan BK, Kathuria S, Ramam M. A descriptive study to characterize segmental vitiligo. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2012;78:715&#x2013;721. https://doi.org/10.4103/0378&#x2010;6323.102362</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Geel NA, Mollet IG, De Schepper S, Tjin EP, Vermaelen K, Clark RA, et&#xa0;al. First histopathological and immunophenotypic analysis of early dynamic events in a patient with segmental vitiligo associated with halo nevi. Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2010;23:375&#x2013;384. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1755&#x2010;148X.2010.00703.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J, Kang HY, Kim KH, Park CJ, Oh SH, Lee SC, et&#xa0;al. Involvement of T&#xa0;cells in early evolving segmental vitiligo. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2016;41:671&#x2013;674. https://doi.org/10.1111/ced.12852</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oiso N, Suzuki T, Fukai K, Katayama I, Kawada A. Non&#x2010;segmental vitiligo and autoimmune mechanism. Dermatol Res Pract. 2011;2011:518090. https://doi.org/10.1155/2011/518090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creus L, Sanchez&#x2010;Rega&#xf1;a M, Salleras M, Chaussade V, Umbert P. Syndrome de Parry&#x2010;Romberg associ&#xe9; &#xe0; un vitiligo segmentaire homolat&#xe9;ral [Parry&#x2010;Romberg syndrome associated with homolateral segmental vitiligo]. Ann Dermatol Venereol. 1994;121:710&#x2013;711. French.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonifati C, Impara G, Morrone A, Pietrangeli A, Carducci M. Simultaneous occurrence of linear scleroderma and homolateral segmental vitiligo. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2006;20:63&#x2013;65. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468&#x2010;3083.2005.01336.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen C, Kobayashi TT. What is your diagnosis? Segmental&#xa0;vitiligo and en coup de sabre. Cutis. 2010;85(230):237&#x2013;238.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janowska M, Podolec K, Lipko&#x2010;Godlewska S, Wojas&#x2010;Pelc A. Coexistence of Parry&#x2010;Romberg syndrome with homolateral segmental vitiligo. Postepy Dermatol Alergol. 2013;30:409&#x2013;411. https://doi.org/10.5114/pdia.2013.39441</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav P, Garg T, Chander R, Nangia A. Segmental vitiligo with segmental morphea: An autoimmune link? Indian Dermatol Online J. 2014;5:S23&#x2013;S25. https://doi.org/10.4103/2229&#x2010;5178.144517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Shin D, Oh SH. A case of segmental vitiligo with generalized morphea stabilized by antimalarial medication. Ann Dermatol. 2016;28:249&#x2013;250. https://doi.org/10.5021/ad.2016.28.2.249</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dev T, Bhari N, Sethuraman G. Co&#x2010;localization of segmental vitiligo and morphea: a feature of &#x2018;twin&#x2010;spotting&#x2019; type of cutaneous mosaicism? Pediatr Dermatol. 2017;34:S124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Park HS, Cho S, Yoon HS. Concurrence of circumscribed morphea and segmental vitiligo: a case report. Ann Dermatol. 2018;30:708&#x2013;711. https://doi.org/10.5021/ad.2018.30.6.708</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ubaldo HDC, Castro CCS. Coexistence of segmental vitiligo, scleroderma en coup de sabre and cleft lip on the same hemiface: association with mosaicism? An Bras Dermatol. 2019;94:248&#x2013;250. https://doi.org/10.1590/abd1806&#x2010;4841.20198110</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapagain P, Agrawal S. Co&#x2010;occurrence of progressive hemifacial atrophy due to morphea with homolateral segmental vitiligo: a case report. Clin Case Rep. 2021;9:e04458. https://doi.org/10.1002/ccr3.4458</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magri F, Miraglia E, Soda G, Giustini S. Concomitant segmental vitiligo and segmental morphea in an 8&#x2010;year&#x2010;old boy. Indian J Dermatol. 2021;66:318&#x2013;319. https://doi.org/10.4103/ijd.IJD_247_20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Filoni A, Bonamonte D. Parry&#x2010;Romberg Syndrome and contralateral segmental vitiligo: clues for cutaneous mosaicism? Ital J Dermatol Venerol. 2022;157.204&#x2013;205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dsouza D, Kumar P, Reddy H. Co&#x2010;occurrence of linear scleroderma en coup de sabre and segmental vitiligo on the face. BMJ Case Rep. 2022;15:e250056. https://doi.org/10.1136/bcr&#x2010;2022&#x2010;250056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahle J, Rohr B, Shah SD. The co&#x2010;occurrence of segmental vitiligo and linear morphea in a pediatric patient and a review of the literature. Pediatr Dermatol. 2023;40:507&#x2013;510. https://doi.org/10.1111/pde.15180</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendiratta V, Verma D, Lakhani R. Linear morphea with lipoatrophy associated with segmental vitiligo in a 13&#x2010;year&#x2010;old girl&#x2014;a continuum of spectrum of autoimmunity. Indian Dermatol Online J. 2023;14:879&#x2013;881. https://doi.org/10.4103/idoj.idoj_644_22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezzedine K, Gauthier Y, L&#xe9;aut&#xe9;&#x2010;Labr&#xe8;ze C, Marquez S, Bouchtnei S, Jouary T, et&#xa0;al. Segmental vitiligo associated with generalized vitiligo (mixed vitiligo): a retrospective case series of 19 patients. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2011;65:965&#x2013;971. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2010.08.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Park S, Park MY, Almurayshid A, Oh SH. Mixed vitiligo that progressed from segmental inflammatory vitiligo, clinically mimicking lichen striatus. J Dermatol. 2019;46:e478&#x2013;e480. https://doi.org/10.1111/1346&#x2010;8138.15069</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar S, Vinay K, Choudhary R, Thakur V, Bishnoi A, Kumaran MS, et&#xa0;al. Clinicodemographic features of mixed vitiligo: a case&#x2010;control study. Int J Dermatol. 2022;61:982&#x2013;987. https://doi.org/10.1111/ijd.16090</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allam M, Riad H. Concise review of recent studies in vitiligo. Qatar Med J. 2013;2013:1&#x2013;19. https://doi.org/10.5339/qmj.2013.10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Wijngaard R, Wankowicz&#x2010;Kalinska A, Le Poole C, Tigges B, Westerhof W, Das P. Local immune response in skin of generalized vitiligo patients. Destruction of melanocytes is associated with the prominent presence of CLA+ T&#xa0;cells at the perilesional site. Lab Invest. 2000;80:1299&#x2013;1309. https://doi.org/10.1038/labinvest.3780138</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van den Boorn JG, Konijnenberg D, Dellemijn TA, van der Veen JP, Bos JD, Melief CJ, et&#xa0;al. Autoimmune destruction of skin melanocytes by perilesional T&#xa0;cells from vitiligo patients. J Invest Dermatol. 2009;9:2220&#x2013;2232. https://doi.org/10.1038/jid.2009.32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu J, Zhou M, Wan Y, Xu A. CD8+ T&#xa0;cells from vitiligo perilesional margins induce autologous melanocyte apoptosis. Mol Med Rep. 2013;7:237&#x2013;241. https://doi.org/10.3892/mmr.2012.1117</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee NR, Chung HC, Hong H, Lee JW, Ahn SK. Spontaneous involution of congenital melanocytic nevus with halo phenomenon. Am J Dermatopathol. 2015;37:e137&#x2013;e139. https://doi.org/10.1097/DAD.0000000000000311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attili VR, Attili SK. Segmental and generalized vitiligo: both forms demonstrate inflammatory histopathological features and clinical mosaicism. Indian J Dermatol. 2013;58:433&#x2013;438. https://doi.org/10.4103/0019&#x2010;5154.119949</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang WL, Ko CH. The role of oxidative stress in vitiligo: an update on its pathogenesis and therapeutic implications. Cells. 2023;12:936. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells12060936</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shajil EM, Begum R. Antioxidant status of segmental and non&#x2010;segmental vitiligo. Pigment Cell Res. 2006;19:179&#x2013;180. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0749.2006.00299.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delmas V, Larue L. Molecular and cellular basis of depigmentation in vitiligo patients. Exp Dermatol. 2019;28:662&#x2013;666. https://doi.org/10.1111/exd.13858</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schallreuter KU, Salem MA, Holtz S, Panske A. Basic evidence for epidermal H2O2/ONOO(&#x2212;)&#x2010;mediated oxidation/nitration in segmental vitiligo is supported by re&#x2010;pigmentation of skin and eyelashes after reduction of epidermal H2O2 with topical NB&#x2010;UVB&#x2010;activated pseudocatalase PC&#x2010;KUS. FASEB J. 2013;27:3113&#x2013;3122. https://doi.org/10.1096/fj.12&#x2010;226779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanwar S, Thakur V, Bhatia A, Parsad D. Catecholamines' accumulation and their disturbed metabolism at perilesional site: a possible cause of vitiligo progression. Arch Dermatol Res. 2023;315:173&#x2013;180. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00403&#x2010;022&#x2010;02333&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li D, Zhou T, She Q, Nie X, Liu Z, Pan R, et&#xa0;al. Circulating Exosomal miR&#x2010;493&#x2010;3p affects melanocyte survival and function by regulating epidermal dopamine concentration in segmental vitiligo. J Invest Dermatol. 2022;142:3262&#x2013;3273.e11. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jid.2022.05.1086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#x105;dziela M, Kutwin M, Karp P, Wo&#x17a;niacka A. Role of cytokines and chemokines in vitiligo and their therapeutic implications. J Clin Med. 2024;13:4919. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13164919</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu X, Jiang M, Zhang C, Qiao Z, Liu W, Le Y, et&#xa0;al. New insights into segmental vitiligo: a clinical and immunological comparison with non&#x2010;segmental vitiligo. Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2022;35:220&#x2013;228. https://doi.org/10.1111/pcmr.13022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maloy KJ, Powrie F. Regulatory T&#xa0;cells in the control of immune pathology. Nat Immunol. 2001;2:816&#x2013;822. https://doi.org/10.1038/ni0901&#x2010;816</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin M, Zhang BX, Shen N, Dong XJ, Zhang C, Qi XY, et&#xa0;al. Regulatory T&#xa0;cells from active non&#x2010;segmental vitiligo exhibit&#xa0;lower suppressive ability on CD8+CLA+ T&#xa0;cells. Eur J Dermatol. 2014;24:676&#x2013;682. https://doi.org/10.1684/ejd.2014.2436</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klarquist J, Denman CJ, Hernandez C, Wainwright DA, Strickland FM, Overbeck A, et&#xa0;al. Reduced skin homing by functional Treg in vitiligo. Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2010;23:276&#x2013;286. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1755&#x2010;148X.2010.00688.x Epub 2010 Feb 19. Erratum in: Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2010 Jun;23(3):477. Wainwright, Derek J [corrected to Wainwright, Derek A].</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willemsen M, Post NF, van Uden NOP, Narayan VS, Chielie S, Kemp EH, et&#xa0;al. Immunophenotypic analysis reveals differences in circulating immune cells in the peripheral blood of patients with segmental and non&#x2010;segmental vitiligo. J Invest Dermatol. 2022;142:76&#x2013;883.e3. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jid.2021.05.022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho JJ, Lorentsen KJ, Avram D. Models of regulatory T&#xa0;cell alterations and systemic autoimmunity. In: Soboloff J, Kappes DJ, editors. Signaling mechanisms regulating T&#xa0;cell diversity and function. Boca Raton, FL: CRC Press/Taylor &amp; Francis; 2018 Chapter 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin Y, Wu X, Yang Y, Wu Y, Xiang L, Zhang C. The multifaceted role of autophagy in skin autoimmune disorders: a guardian or culprit? Front Immunol. 2024;15:1343987. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2024.1343987</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao Z, Wang X, Xiang L, Zhang C. Dysfunction of autophagy: a possible mechanism involved in the pathogenesis of vitiligo by breaking the redox balance of melanocytes. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2016;2016:3401570. https://doi.org/10.1155/2016/3401570</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang P, Li Y, Nie H, Zhang X, Shao Q, Hou X, et&#xa0;al. The changes of gene expression profiling between segmental vitiligo, generalized vitiligo and healthy individual. J Dermatol Sci. 2016;84:40&#x2013;49. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jdermsci.2016.07.006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speeckaert R, Lambert J, Bulat V, Belpaire A, Speeckaert M, van Geel N. Autoimmunity in segmental vitiligo. Front Immunol. 2020;27(11):568447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Geel N, De Lille S, Vandenhaute S, Gauthier Y, Mollet I, Brochez L, et&#xa0;al. Different phenotypes of segmental vitiligo based on a clinical observational study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2011;25:673&#x2013;678. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1468&#x2010;3083.2010.03847.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Kornmehl H, Milgraum S. Segmental vitiligo following encephalitis. Pediatr Dermatol. 2010;27:624&#x2013;625. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1525&#x2010;1470.2010.01319.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CS, Yu HS, Chang HR, Yu CL, Yu CL, Wu BN. Cutaneous blood flow and adrenoceptor response increase in segmental&#x2010;type vitiligo lesions. J Dermatol Sci. 2000;23:53&#x2013;62. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0923&#x2010;1811(99)00090&#x2010;0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Happle R. Mosaicism in human skin. Understanding the patterns and mechanisms. Arch Dermatol. 1993;129:1460&#x2013;1470.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheraghlou S, Lim Y, Choate KA. Mosaicism in genodermatoses. Clin Dermatol. 2020;38:408&#x2013;420. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clindermatol.2020.03.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz EL, Harris JE. Translational research in vitiligo. Front Immunol. 2021;12:624517. https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2021.624517 Translational Research in Vitiligo.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigues M, Ezzedine K, Hamzavi I, Pandya AG, Harris JE; Vitiligo Working Group. New discoveries in the pathogenesis and classification of vitiligo. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;77:1&#x2013;13. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2016.10.048</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Geel N, Speeckaert R, Melsens E, Toelle SP, Speeckaert M, De Schepper S, et&#xa0;al. The distribution pattern of segmental vitiligo: clues for somatic mosaicism. Br J Dermatol. 2013;168(1):56&#x2013;64. https://doi.org/10.1111/bjd.12013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Passeron T, Malmqvst VEA, Bzioueche H, Marchetti S, Rocchi S, Tulic MK. Increased activation of innate immunity and pro&#x2010;apoptotic CXCR3B in normal&#x2010;appearing skin on the lesional site of patients with segmental vitiligo. J Invest Dermatol. 2022;142:480&#x2013;483.e2. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jid.2021.07.157</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Zhu G, Yang Y, Jian Z, Guo S, Dai W, et&#xa0;al. Oxidative stress drives CD8+ T&#x2010;cell skin trafficking in patients with vitiligo through CXCL16 upregulation by activating the unfolded protein response in keratinocytes. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2017;140:177&#x2013;189.e9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaci.2016.10.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosenson JA, Flood K, Klarquist J, Eby JM, Koshoffer A, Boissy RE, et&#xa0;al. Preferential secretion of inducible HSP70 by vitiligo melanocytes under stress. Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2014;27:209&#x2013;220. https://doi.org/10.1111/pcmr.12208</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaseghi H, Houshmand M, Jadali Z. Increased levels of mitochondrial DNA copy number in patients with vitiligo. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2017;42:749&#x2013;754. https://doi.org/10.1111/ced.13185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speeckaert R, Caelenberg EV, Belpaire A, Speeckaert MM, Geel NV. Vitiligo: from pathogenesis to treatment. J Clin Med. 2024;13:5225. https://doi.org/10.3390/jcm13175225</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, Wolf P. How it works: the immunology underlying phototherapy. Dermatol Clin. 2020;38(1):37&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.det.2019.08.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lotti TM, Menchini G, Andreassi L. UV&#x2010;B radiation microphototherapy. An elective treatment for segmental vitiligo. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 1999;13(2):102&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Do JE, Shin JY, Kim DY, Hann SK, Oh SH. The effect of 308nm excimer laser on segmental vitiligo: a retrospective study of 80 patients with segmental vitiligo. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2011;27(3):147&#x2013;151. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600&#x2010;0781.2011.00587.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majid I, Imran S. Excimer light therapy in childhood segmental vitiligo: early treatment gives better results. Dermatol Ther. 2020;33(3):e13408. https://doi.org/10.1111/dth.13408</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shim WH, Suh SW, Jwa SW, Song M, Kim HS, Ko HC, et&#xa0;al. A pilot study of 1% pimecrolimus cream for the treatment of childhood segmental vitiligo. Ann Dermatol. 2013;25:168&#x2013;172. https://doi.org/10.5021/ad.2013.25.2.168</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu LY, Strassner JP, Refat MA, Harris JE, King BA. Re&#x2010;pigmentation in vitiligo using the Janus kinase inhibitor tofacitinib may require concomitant light exposure. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;77:675&#x2013;682.e1. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2017.05.043</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olamiju B, Craiglow BG. Tofacitinib cream plus narrowband ultraviolet B phototherapy for segmental vitiligo in a child. Pediatr Dermatol. 2020;37:754&#x2013;755. https://doi.org/10.1111/pde.14159</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Park SW, Lee DY, Lee JH, Yang JM. The effectiveness of early treatment in segmental vitiligo: retrospective study according to disease duration. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2013;29:103&#x2013;105. https://doi.org/10.1111/phpp.12029</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bae JM, Yoo HJ, Kim H, Lee JH, Kim GM. Combination therapy with 308&#x2010;nm excimer laser, topical tacrolimus, and short&#x2010;term systemic corticosteroids for segmental vitiligo: a retrospective study of 159 patients. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2015;73:76&#x2013;82. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2015.04.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S, Sakhiya J, Deshpande P, Sakhiya D, Inamadar AC. Safety and efficacy of the combination of 308&#x2010;nm monochromatic excimer light and topical 0.1% tacrolimus ointment in segmental vitiligo: an open&#x2010;label study. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2020;13:E69&#x2013;E75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>He M, Bao N, Qi RQ, Wu Y, Liu M. A randomized, prospective pilot study for comparison of a triple combination of 2940&#x2009;nm Er:YAG Laser and triamcinolone acetonide solution with either 308&#x2009;nm excimer laser or 0.1% tacrolimus in treatment of stable segmental vitiligo. Dermatol Ther. 2022;35:e15875. https://doi.org/10.1111/dth.15875</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>lsson MJ, Juhlin L. Long&#x2010;term follow&#x2010;up of leucoderma patients treated with transplants of autologous cultured melanocytes, ultrathin epidermal sheets and basal cell layer suspension. Br J Dermatol. 2002;147:893&#x2013;904. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365&#x2010;2133.2002.04837.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S, Kumar B. Epidermal grafting in vitiligo: influence of age, site of lesion, and type of disease on outcome. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2003;49:99&#x2013;104. https://doi.org/10.1067/mjd.2003.415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mulekar SV. Melanocyte&#x2010;keratinocyte cell transplantation for stable vitiligo. Int J Dermatol. 2003;42:132&#x2013;136. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1365&#x2010;4362.2003.01628.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Geel N, Wallaeys E, Goh BK, De Mil M, Lambert J. Long&#x2010;term results of noncultured epidermal cellular grafting in vitiligo, halo naevi, piebaldism and naevus depigmentosus. Br J Dermatol. 2010;163:1186&#x2013;1193. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365&#x2010;2133.2010.10014.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsuzaki K, Kumagai N. Treatment of vitiligo with autologous&#xa0;cultured keratinocytes in 27 cases. Eur J Plast Surg.&#xa0;2013;36:651&#x2013;656. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00238&#x2010;013&#x2010;0875&#x2010;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gan EY, Kong YL, Tan WD, Thng ST, Goh BK. Twelve&#x2010;month and sixty&#x2010;month outcomes of noncultured cellular grafting for vitiligo. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2016;75:564&#x2013;571. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2016.04.007</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos MG, Ramos DG, Ramos CG. Evaluation of treatment response to autologous transplantation of noncultured melanocyte/keratinocyte cell suspension in patients with stable vitiligo. An Bras Dermatol. 2017;92:312&#x2013;318. https://doi.org/10.1590/abd1806&#x2010;4841.20175700</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silpa&#x2010;Archa N, Griffith JL, Huggins RH, et&#xa0;al. Long&#x2010;term follow&#x2010;up of patients undergoing autologous noncultured melanocyte&#x2010;keratinocyte transplantation for vitiligo and other leukodermas. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;77:318&#x2013;327. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaad.2017.01.056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang D, Wei X, Hong W, Fu L, Qian G, Xu AE. A retrospective study of long term follow&#x2010;up of 2283 vitiligo patients treated by autologous, non&#x2010;cultured melanocyte&#x2010;keratinocyte transplantation. Aging (Albany NY). 2021;13:5415&#x2013;5425. https://doi.org/10.18632/aging.202472</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CS, Hu SC, Lan CC, Chen GS, Chuo WH, Yu HS. Low&#x2010;energy helium&#x2010;neon laser therapy induces re&#x2010;pigmentation and improves the abnormalities of cutaneous microcirculation&#xa0;in segmental&#x2010;type vitiligo lesions. Kaohsiung J Med Sci. 2008;24:180&#x2013;189. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1607&#x2010;551X(08)70115&#x2010;3</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>