<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38582907</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2042-7670</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>194</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Veterinary record</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Vet Rec</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Outcome of surgical correction of medial patellar luxation in dogs weighing less than 10 kg.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e3994</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e3994</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/vetr.3994</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Various&#xa0;trochleoplasty techniques, including trochlear wedge recession (TWR) and trochlear block recession (TBR), are used to treat dogs with medial patellar luxation (MPL). However, the objective outcomes of these surgical procedures&#xa0;are underreported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Medical records were obtained for dogs weighing less than 10&#xa0;kg that underwent either TWR or TBR and tibial tuberosity transposition to address grade I-III MPL. Long-term (at least 1 year after the last procedure) follow-up included orthopaedic and radiographic examinations, such as osteoarthritis score (OAS), ground reaction force (GRF) analysis and canine brief pain inventory (CBPI).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Overall, 20 dogs (26 stifles) were followed up in the long term. Minor postoperative complications, medial patellar reluxation (MPR) and intermittent lameness occurred in 46.15%, 19.23% and 15% of the dogs, respectively. MPR occurred only in TWR-treated stifles, while mean OAS increased in all groups. Using the CBPI, the owners perceived an excellent or very good outcome&#xa0;in 95% of dogs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="LIMITATIONS">The limitations of the study include its retrospective observational nature, a lack of randomisation and a small sample size.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Surgical treatment resulted in a favourable outcome. GRF analysis could detect subtle differences in weight bearing in dogs treated for MPL, which might not be apparent clinically. There might be a higher risk for reluxation for TWR. However, a larger-scale prospective study would be required to find which treatment is superior.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Veterinary Record published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Veterinary Association.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vodnarek</LastName><ForeName>Jakub</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8043-8189</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Small Animal Surgery, Department of Companion Animals and Horses, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schneider</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tierklinik V&#xf6;cklabruck, V&#xf6;cklabruck, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Diagnostic Imaging, Department of Companion Animals and Horses, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bockstahler</LastName><ForeName>Barbara</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Physical Rehabilitation, Department of Companion Animals and Horses, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schnabl-Feichter</LastName><ForeName>Eva</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Small Animal Surgery, Department of Companion Animals and Horses, University of Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Clinical Unit of Small Animal Surgery of VetmedUni Vienna</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078323">Observational Study, Veterinary</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Vet Rec</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0031164</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0042-4900</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004285" MajorTopicYN="N">Dogs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004283" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dog Diseases</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010003" MajorTopicYN="Y">Osteoarthritis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010329" MajorTopicYN="N">Patella</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D031222" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patellar Dislocation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000662" MajorTopicYN="N">veterinary</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013264" MajorTopicYN="N">Stifle</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38582907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/vetr.3994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>O'Neill DG, Meeson RL, Sheridan A, Church DB, Brodbelt DC. The epidemiology of patellar luxation in dogs attending primary&#x2010;care veterinary practices in England. Canine Genet Epidemiol. 2016;3:4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deangelis M. Patellar luxation in dogs. Vet Clin North Am. 1971;1:403&#x2013;415.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hulse DA. Pathophysiology and management of medial patellar luxation in the dog. Vet Med Small Anim Clin. 1981;76:43&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam MR, Ji JR, Kim MS, Kim NS. Biomarkers for identifying the early phases of osteoarthritis secondary to medial patellar luxation in dogs. J Vet Sci. 2011;12:273&#x2013;280.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Putnam RW. Patellar luxation in the dog. University of Guelph; 1968.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowaleski MP, Boudrieau RJ, Pozzi A. Stifle joint. In: Johnston SA, Tobias KM, editors. Veterinary surgery: small animal. 2nd ed. Elsevier; 2018. p. 1071&#x2013;1168.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton L, Farrell M, Mielke B, Solano M, Silva S, Calvo I. The natural history of canine occult grade II medial patellar luxation: an observational study. J Small Anim Pract. 2020;61:241&#x2013;246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arthurs GI, Langley&#x2010;Hobbs SJ. Complications associated with corrective surgery for patellar luxation in 109 dogs. Vet Surg. 2006;35:559&#x2013;566.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujii K, Watanabe T, Kobayashi T, Hayashi K. Medial ridge elevation wedge trochleoplasty for medial patellar luxation: a clinical study in 5 dogs. Vet Surg. 2013;42:721&#x2013;726.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillick M, Linn K. Rotating dome trochleoplasty: an experimental technique for correction of patellar luxation using a feline model. Vet Comp Orthop Traumatol. 2007;20:180&#x2013;184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katayama M, Ogaya H, Shunsuke S, Uzuka Y. Kite shield&#x2010;shaped wedge recession for treatment of medial patellar luxation in seven small&#x2010;breed dogs. Vet Surg. 2016;45:66&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson AL, Probst CW, Decamp CE, Rosenstein DS, Hauptman JG, Weaver BT, et&#xa0;al. Comparison of trochlear block recession and trochlear wedge recession for canine patellar luxation using a cadaver model. Vet Surg. 2001;30:140&#x2013;150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digiovanni LC, Roush JK, Berke K. Preoperative and postoperative stance analysis in dogs with patellar luxation confirms lameness improvement after surgery. Am J Vet Res. 2023;84:1&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown DC, Boston RC, Coyne JC, Farrar JT. Ability of the canine brief pain inventory to detect response to treatment in dogs with osteoarthritis. J Am Vet Med Assoc. 2008;233:1278&#x2013;1283.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook JL, Evans R, Conzemius MG, Lascelles BDX, McIlwraith CW, Pozzi A, et&#xa0;al. Proposed definitions and criteria for reporting time frame, outcome, and complications for clinical orthopedic studies in veterinary medicine. Vet Surg. 2010;39:905&#x2013;908.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roy RG, Wallace LJ, Johnston GR, Wickstrom SL. A retrospective evaluation of stifle osteoarthritis in dogs with bilateral medial patellar luxation and unilateral surgical repair. Vet Surg. 1992;21:475&#x2013;479.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarz N, Tichy A, Peham C, Bockstahler B. Vertical force distribution in the paws of sound Labrador retrievers during walking. Vet J. 2017;221:16&#x2013;22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanchon L, Grandjean D. Accuracy of asymmetry indices of ground reaction forces for diagnosis of hind limb lameness in dogs. Am J Vet Res. 2007;68:1089&#x2013;1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wessely M, Br&#xfc;hschwein A, Schnabl&#x2010;Feichter E. Evaluation of intra&#x2010; and inter&#x2010;observer measurement variability of a radiographic stifle osteoarthritis scoring system in dogs. Vet Comp Orthop Traumatol. 2017;30:377&#x2013;384.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slocum B, Devine T. Trochlear recession for correction of luxating patella in the dog. J Am Vet Med Assoc. 1985;186:365&#x2013;369.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Talcott KW, Goring RL, de Haan JJ. Rectangular recession trochleoplasty for treatment of patellar luxation in dogs and cats. Vet Comp Orthop Traumatol. 2000;13:39&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singleton WB. The diagnosis and surgical treatment of some abnormal stifle conditions in the dog. Vet Rec. 1957;69:1387&#x2013;1394.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linney WR, Hammer DL, Shott S. Surgical treatment of medial patellar luxation without femoral trochlear groove deepening procedures in dogs: 91 cases (1998&#x2013;2009). J Am Vet Med Assoc. 2011;238:1168&#x2013;1172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangdee C, Theyse LFH, Techakumphu M, Soontornvipart K, Hazewinkel HAW. Evaluation of surgical treatment of medial patellar luxation in Pomeranian dogs. Vet Comp Orthop Traumatol. 2013;26:435&#x2013;439.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crossley KM, Callaghan MJ, Linschoten RV. Patellofemoral pain. Br J Sports Med. 2016;50:247&#x2013;250.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yasukawa S, Edamura K, Tanegashima K, Seki M, Teshima K, Asano K, et&#xa0;al. Evaluation of bone deformities of the femur, tibia, and patella in Toy Poodles with medial patellar luxation using computed tomography. Vet Comp Orthop Traumatol. 2016;29:29&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam MR, Lee HB, Kim MS, Kim NS. Surgical model of osteoarthritis secondary to medial patellar luxation in dogs. Vet Med. 2011;56:123&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Zee JH. Lesions in canine stifle joints due to trochleoplasties as treatment for medial patellar luxation. J S Afr Vet Assoc. 2015;86:1245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mankin HJ. The response of articular cartilage to mechanical injury. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1982;64:460&#x2013;466.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2bc;Driscoll SW. The healing and regeneration of articular cartilage. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1998;80:1795&#x2013;1812.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daems R, Janssens LA, B&#xe9;osier YM. Grossly apparent cartilage erosion of the patellar articular surface in dogs with congenital medial patellar luxation. Vet Comp Orthop Traumatol. 2009;22:222&#x2013;224.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaiser D, G&#xf6;tschi T, Bachmann E, Snedeker JG, Tscholl PM, Fucentese SF. Deepening trochleoplasty may dramatically increase retropatellar contact pressures&#x2014;a pilot study establishing a finite element model. J Exp Orthop. 2022;9:76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallegos J, Unis M, Roush JK, Agulian L. Postoperative complications and short&#x2010;term outcome following single&#x2010;session bilateral corrective surgery for medial patellar luxation in dogs weighing &lt;15 kg: 50 cases (2009&#x2013;2014). Vet Surg. 2016;45:887&#x2013;892.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rant&#xe9;n K. Complications and the quality of life after surgical correction of medial patellar luxation in dogs [Masters' thesis]. Uppsala: Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences; 2018 [cited 2023 Sep 19]. Available from: http://stud.epsilon.slu.se</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cashmore RG, Havlicek M, Perkins NR, James DR, Fearnside SM, Marchevsky AM, et&#xa0;al. Major complications and risk factors associated with surgical correction of congenital medial patellar luxation in 124 dogs. Vet Comp Orthop Traumatol. 2014;27:263&#x2013;270.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>