<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39953296</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2191-219X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>14</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>EJNMMI research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>EJNMMI Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Quantification in respiratory-gated PET acquisition: can data-driven methods replace device-based systems?-a comparative and retrospective study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>9</StartPage><MedlinePgn>9</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13550-025-01195-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Device-based respiratory gating improves diagnostic and quantification accuracy in positron emission tomography (PET), but requires additional time to setup the device and the failure rate can be significant. Our aim was to internally validate the quantification performance of data-driven respiratory-gated PET imaging against the gold standard, the device-based method, in clinical oncological practice. We retrospectively analysed [18F]FDG PET/CT scans of patients from our centre with at least one measurable [18F]FDG-avid malignant lesion. All PET/CT acquisitions were performed on a Siemens Biograph 64 Vision 600 system with respiratory gating by belt and also by adding the data-driven gating with OncoFreeze AI&#x2122;. We recorded the SUVmax and SUVpeak for up to a maximum of 5 lesions per patient. We computed the mean absolute bias between the two gating methods and the 95% confidence intervals (CI) at the cohort level and in subgroups.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 692 consecutive patients screened for inclusion, 196 patients were analysed, from whom 536 lesions were measured. The mean absolute biases in the SUVmax and SUVpeak of lesions in the whole cohort were 3.8% (CI 3.4-4.2) and 2.1% (CI 1.9-2.4), respectively. At patient-level, 21% of them had at least one lesion with a SUVmax bias above 10%, while for SUVpeak this proportion was 5%. In the subgroup analysis by PERCIST criteria, only 2% of patients had significant bias in the SUVmax, and 0.5% in SUVpeak. There was no clinically significant effect of lesion size or anatomical site on SUV measurements between the two respiratory gating methods.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Quantitative comparison of data-driven and device-based respiratory-gated PET scans revealed negligible differences, proving that data-driven respiratory gating is a reliable and accurate alternative to the device-based gating method in routine [18F]FDG-PET/CT oncological evaluation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agrigoroaie</LastName><ForeName>Laurentiu</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8831-9133</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Imaging Departement, Gustave Roussy, 94805, Villejuif, France. laurentiu.agrigoroaie@gustaveroussy.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anizan</LastName><ForeName>Nadege</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Imaging Departement, Gustave Roussy, 94805, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Physics Department, Gustave Roussy, 94805, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garcia</LastName><ForeName>Camilo</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Imaging Departement, Gustave Roussy, 94805, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balleyguier</LastName><ForeName>Corinne</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Imaging Departement, Gustave Roussy, 94805, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inserm, Molecular Radiotherapy and Therapeutical Innovation, Paris-Saclay University, Gustave Roussy, 94800, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Henry</LastName><ForeName>Th&#xe9;ophraste</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Imaging Departement, Gustave Roussy, 94805, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Inserm, Molecular Radiotherapy and Therapeutical Innovation, Paris-Saclay University, Gustave Roussy, 94800, Villejuif, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>EJNMMI Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101560946</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2191-219X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gated PET</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oncological imaging</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quantitative accuracy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory gating</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Study approval was obtained from the local ethics committee, IRB no 2024&#x2013;408. Consent for participation was waived in according to French law. Informed consent A waiver of informed consent was granted for this study according to French law regulation (MR-004). Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>27</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39953296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11828764</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13550-025-01195-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13550-025-01195-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Guerra L, De Ponti E, Elisei F, Bettinardi V, Landoni C, Picchio M, et al. Respiratory gated PET/CT in a European multicentre retrospective study: added diagnostic value in detection and characterization of lung lesions. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2012;39:1381&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-012-2148-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22588628</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crivellaro C, De Ponti E, Elisei F, Morzenti S, Picchio M, Bettinardi V, et al. Added diagnostic value of respiratory-gated 4D 18F-FDG PET/CT in the detection of liver lesions: a multicenter study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2018;45:102&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-017-3795-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28825125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker MD, Morgan AJ, Bradley KM, McGowan DR. Data-driven respiratory gating outperforms device-based gating for clinical 18F-FDG PET/CT. J Nucl Med Off Publ Soc Nucl Med. 2020;61:1678&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7116324</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32245898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesner AL, Chung JH, Lind KE, Kwak JJ, Lynch D, Burckhardt D, et al. Validation of software gating: a practical technology for respiratory motion correction in PET. Radiology. 2016;281:239&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2016152105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27027335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robin P, Bourhis D, Bernard B, Abgral R, Querellou S, Le Duc-Pennec A, et al. Feasibility of systematic respiratory-gated acquisition in unselected patients referred for 18F-fluorodeoxyglucose positron emission tomography/computed tomography. Front Med. 2018;5:36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2018.00036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5826069</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29516001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan C, Jin X, Fung EK, Naganawa M, Mulnix T, Carson RE, et al. Event-by-event respiratory motion correction for PET with 3D internal-1D external motion correlation. Med Phys. 2013;40: 112507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1118/1.4826165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24320466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walker MD, Morgan AJ, Bradley KM, McGowan DR. Evaluation of data-driven respiratory gating waveforms for clinical PET imaging. EJNMMI Res. 2019;9:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13550-018-0470-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6318161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30607651</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;ther F, Vehren T, Sch&#xe4;fers KP, Sch&#xe4;fers M. Impact of data-driven respiratory gating in clinical PET. Radiology. 2016;281:229&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2016152067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27092660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;ther F, Jones J, Seifert R, Stegger L, Schleyer P, Sch&#xe4;fers M. Clinical evaluation of a data-driven respiratory gating algorithm for whole-body PET with continuous bed motion. J Nucl Med Off Publ Soc Nucl Med. 2020;61:1520&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32060218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier JG, Wu CC, Betancourt Cuellar SL, Truong MT, Erasmus JR, Einstein S, et al. Evaluation of a novel elastic respiratory motion correction algorithm on quantification and image quality in abdomino-thoracic PET/CT. J Nucl Med Off Publ Soc Nucl Med. 2018;60:279&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30115689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercieca S, Belderbos J, Van Loon J, Gilhuijs K, Julyan P, Van Herk M. Comparison of SUVmax and SUVpeak based segmentation to determine primary lung tumour volume on FDG PET-CT correlated with pathology data. Radiother Oncol. 2018;129:227&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2018.06.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29983260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dias AH, Schleyer P, Vendelbo MH, Hjorthaug K, Gormsen LC, Munk OL. Clinical feasibility and impact of data-driven respiratory motion compensation studied in 200 whole-body 18F-FDG PET/CT scans. EJNMMI Res. 2022;12:16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13550-022-00887-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8960547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35347465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wahl RL, Jacene H, Kasamon Y, Lodge MA. From RECIST to PERCIST: evolving considerations for PET response criteria in solid tumors. J Nucl Med Off Publ Soc Nucl Med. 2009;50(Suppl 1):122S-S150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2755245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinahan PE, Perlman ES, Sunderland JJ, Subramaniam R, Wollenweber SD, Turkington TG, et al. The QIBA profile for FDG PET/CT as an imaging biomarker measuring response to cancer therapy. Radiology. 2020;294:647&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2019191882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7053216</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31909700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seppenwoolde Y, Shirato H, Kitamura K, Shimizu S, Van Herk M, Lebesque JV, et al. Precise and real-time measurement of 3D tumor motion in lung due to breathing and heartbeat, measured during radiotherapy. Int J Radiat Oncol. 2002;53:822&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0360-3016(02)02803-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12095547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Negoro Y, Nagata Y, Aoki T, Mizowaki T, Araki N, Takayama K, et al. The effectiveness of an immobilization device in conformal radiotherapy for lung tumor: reduction of respiratory tumor movement and evaluation of the daily setup accuracy. Int J Radiat Oncol. 2001;50:889&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0360-3016(01)01516-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11429216</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Diessen JNA, La Fontaine M, van den Heuvel MM, van Werkhoven E, Walraven I, Vogel WV, et al. Local and regional treatment response by 18FDG-PET-CT-scans 4 weeks after concurrent hypofractionated chemoradiotherapy in locally advanced NSCLC. Radiother Oncol. 2020;143:30&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radonc.2019.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31767474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yap ML, Sun A, Higgins J, Clarke K, Marshall A, Becker N, et al. Adaptive dose escalation using serial four-dimensional positron emission tomography/computed tomography scans during radiotherapy for locally advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Clin Oncol. 2016;28:e199-205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clon.2016.08.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27637725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didierlaurent D, Ribes S, Batatia H, Jaudet C, Dierickx LO, Zerdoud S, et al. The retrospective binning method improves the consistency of phase binning in respiratory-gated PET/CT. Phys Med Biol. 2012;57:7829&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/0031-9155/57/23/7829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23135238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaalep A, Sera T, Oyen W, Krause BJ, Chiti A, Liu Y, et al. EANM/EARL FDG-PET/CT accreditation&#x2014;summary results from the first 200 accredited imaging systems. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2018;45:412&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00259-017-3853-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5787222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29192365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>