<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40272705</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8210</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Dermatology and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dermatol Ther (Heidelb)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of Dermatology Life Quality Index Scores in Adults and Adolescents with Alopecia Areata.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1543</StartPage><EndPage>1553</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1543-1553</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13555-025-01417-y</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study assessed Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI) scores of patients with alopecia areata (AA) and compared scores between adults and adolescents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a retrospective chart review in France, Germany, Spain, and the UK. Patients with &#x2265;&#x2009;50% scalp hair loss (SHL) due to AA and a DLQI score recorded at their index date (first date of &#x2265;&#x2009;50% SHL) were included. The DLQI (scale 0-30; higher scores indicate greater impact) assesses the impact of AA on health-related quality of life (QOL). Multivariable linear regression was used to examine the effect of age on DLQI score, adjusting for covariates. Modified Poisson regression analysis was used to estimate relative risks (RRs) between age groups and DLQI categories (none&#xa0;to&#xa0;moderate effect, very large effect, and extremely large effect), adjusting for covariates, including baseline Severity of Alopecia Tool (SALT) score.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Overall, 335 patients were included (249 adults, 86 adolescents). At index, adults had a higher mean (SD) SALT score than adolescents (63.7 [15.5] vs 60.4 [12.8]), whereas mean (SD) DLQI scores were higher in adolescents than adults (22.1 [5.3] vs 18.2 [7.5]). Most patients (84%) had DLQI scores indicating a very large or extremely large impact on their lives; this was more pronounced in adolescents than adults (98% vs 80%). In the multilinear model, adolescents had significantly higher DLQI scores than adults (&#x3b2;&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.51; P&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001), indicating a 3.51-point increase in DLQI score associated with being an adolescent. The RR (95%&#xa0;CI) of a DLQI score indicating a very large effect (1.28 [1.07-1.53]) or extremely large effect (1.40 [1.21-1.61]) relative to no or moderate effect was significantly higher for adolescents vs adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrates that, at the time of experiencing&#x2009;&#x2265;&#x2009;50% SHL due to AA, both adults and adolescents reported significant impacts on their QOL, with a higher impact on adolescents.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanson</LastName><ForeName>Kent A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7201-3324</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pfizer Inc., 235 East 42nd St, New York, NY, 10017, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Va&#xf1;&#xf3;-Galv&#xe1;n</LastName><ForeName>Sergio</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2773-7494</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Trichology Unit, Ram&#xf3;n y Cajal University Hospital and Trichology and Hair Transplant Unit, Pedro Ja&#xe9;n Group Clinic, University of Alcal&#xe1;, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Messenger</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1424-8069</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Sheffield, Sheffield, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tran</LastName><ForeName>Helen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0007-6053-6703</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pfizer Inc., 235 East 42nd St, New York, NY, 10017, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Napatalung</LastName><ForeName>Lynne</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-6158-8076</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pfizer Inc., 235 East 42nd St, New York, NY, 10017, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>Keith L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0044-7107</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RTI Health Solutions, Research Triangle Park, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Esterberg</LastName><ForeName>Lizzi</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>RTI Health Solutions, Research Triangle Park, NC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Law</LastName><ForeName>Ernest H</ForeName><Initials>EH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6111-8008</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pfizer Inc., 235 East 42nd St, New York, NY, 10017, USA. ernest.law@pfizer.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Dermatol Ther (Heidelb)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590450</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adults</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alopecia areata</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dermatology Life Quality Index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hair loss</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of interest: This study was funded by Pfizer Inc. Ernest H. Law, Helen Tran, and Lynne Napatalung report employment with and stock ownership in Pfizer Inc. Kent A. Hanson served as a paid consultant to Pfizer during the period in which the work for this manuscript was conducted; the author is no longer affiliated with the company. Keith L. Davis and Lizzi Esterberg report employment with RTI Health Solutions, which received contract research funding from Pfizer Inc. for the conduct of this study. Andrew Messenger and Sergio Va&#xf1;&#xf3;-Galv&#xe1;n report consultancy fees from Pfizer Inc. in relation to the conduct of this study. Ethical approval: The study was subjected to ethics review and approval (or exemption, as applicable) based on local, country-specific requirements. In the UK, based on the National Health Service&#x2019;s Health Research Authority (HRA) online decision tool, the study was classified as a service evaluation or clinical/non-financial audit; thus, the study was exempt from research ethics committee review (HRA decision tool certificate of exemption available upon request). In France, based on the retrospective, non-interventional study design in which only fully anonymized data were collected and retained, the study required only attestation of compliance with MR-004 (research methodology 004) to the Commission Nationale Informatique and Libert&#xe9;s. In Germany, the study underwent independent ethics committee (IEC) review (with subsequent approval) with the Ethikkommission der Bayerischen Landes&#xe4;rztekammer, in addition to notification of study conduct to the Ethikkommission der Bayerischen Landes&#xe4;rztekammer. In Spain, IEC review (and subsequent approval) was obtained from Hospital Universitario La Paz, with competent authority notification to Agencia Espa&#xf1;ola de Medicamentos y Productos Sanitarios.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40272705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12092309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13555-025-01417-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13555-025-01417-y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lee HH, Gwillim E, Patel KR, et al. Epidemiology of alopecia areata, ophiasis, totalis, and universalis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;82(3):675&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2019.08.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31437543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harries M, Macbeth AE, Holmes S, et al. The epidemiology of alopecia areata: a population-based cohort study in UK primary care. Br J Dermatol. 2022;186(2):257&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.20628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9298423</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34227101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benigno M, Anastassopoulos KP, Mostaghimi A, et al. A large cross-sectional survey study of the prevalence of alopecia areata in the United States. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2020;13:259&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CCID.S245649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7131990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32280257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard MA, Corgibet F, Beylot-Barry M, et al. Sex- and age-adjusted prevalence estimates of five chronic inflammatory skin diseases in France: results of the &#xab;&#x202f;OBJECTIFS PEAU&#x202f;&#xbb; study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2018;32(11):1967&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.14959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29569785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darwin E, Hirt PA, Fertig R, Doliner B, Delcanto G, Jimenez JJ. Alopecia areata: review of epidemiology, clinical features, pathogenesis, and new treatment options. Int J Trichology. 2018;10(2):51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/ijt.ijt_99_17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5939003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29769777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhalifah A, Alsantali A, Wang E, McElwee KJ, Shapiro J. Alopecia areata update: Part I. Clinical picture, histopathology, and pathogenesis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2010;62(2):177&#x2013;88 (quiz 89&#x2013;90).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2009.10.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20115945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cranwell WC, Lai VW, Photiou L, et al. Treatment of alopecia areata: an Australian expert consensus statement. Austral J Dermatol. 2019;60(2):163&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajd.12941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30411329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King BA, Mesinkovska NA, Craiglow B, et al. Development of the alopecia areata scale for clinical use: results of an academic-industry collaborative effort. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2022;86(2):359&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2021.08.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34474079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mesinkovska N, Craiglow B, Ball SG, et al. The invisible impact of a visible disease: psychosocial impact of alopecia areata. Dermatol Ther (Heidelb). 2023;13(7):1503&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13555-023-00941-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10307747</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37289409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aldhouse NVJ, Kitchen H, Knight S, et al. &#x201c;&#x2018;You lose your hair, what&#x2019;s the big deal?&#x2019; I was so embarrassed, I was so self-conscious, I was so depressed:&#x201d; a qualitative interview study to understand the psychosocial burden of alopecia areata. J Patient Rep Outcomes. 2020;4(1):76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41687-020-00240-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32914253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen T, Yang JS, Castelo-Soccio L. Bullying and quality of life in pediatric alopecia areata. Skin Append Disord. 2017;3(3):115&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000466704</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5582476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28879186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King B, Ohyama M, Kwon O, et al. Two phase&#xa0;3 trials of baricitinib for alopecia areata. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(18):1687&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2110343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35334197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senna M, King B, Mesinkovska A, Mostaghimi A, Hamilton C, Cassella J. Efficacy of the oral JAK1/JAK2 inhibitor deuruxolitinib in adult patients with moderate to severe alopecia areata: pooled results from the multinational double-blind, placebo-controlled THRIVE-AA1 and THRIVE-AA2 phase&#xa0;3 trials. Presented at: AAD Annual Meeting; March 8&#x2013;12, 2024; San Diego, CA. Abstract 51840. 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>King B, Zhang X, Harcha WG, et al. Efficacy and safety of ritlecitinib in adults and adolescents with alopecia areata: a randomised, double-blind, multicentre, phase&#xa0;2b&#x2013;3 trial. Lancet. 2023;401(10387):1518&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(23)00222-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37062298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finlay AY, Khan GK. Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI)&#x2014;a simple practical measure for routine clinical use. Clin Exp Dermatol. 1994;19(3):210&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2230.1994.tb01167.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8033378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vyas J, Johns JR, Abdelrazik Y, et al. The Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI) used as the benchmark in validation of 101 quality-of-life instruments: a&#xa0;systematic review. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2025;39(3):631&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11851266</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39269008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rencz F, Gul&#xe1;csi L, P&#xe9;ntek M, Wikonk&#xe1;l N, Baji P, Brodszky V. Alopecia areata and health-related quality of life: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Dermatol. 2016;175(3):561&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.14497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26914830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis KL, Messenger A, Va&#xf1;&#xf3; Galv&#xe1;n S, et al. Real-world assessment of disease characteristics and clinical outcomes in alopecia areata in a global noninterventional observational cohort (ADAAGIO). SKIN J Cutan Med. 2024;8(2):s395&#x2013;s395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25251/skin.8.supp.395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hongbo Y, Thomas CL, Harrison MA, Salek MS, Finlay AY. Translating the science of quality of life into practice: what do dermatology life quality index scores mean? J Invest Dermatol. 2005;125(4):659&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0022-202X.2005.23621.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16185263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, King B, Craiglow B. Alopecia areata is associated with impaired health-related quality of life: a survey of affected adults and children and their families. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2018;79(3):556&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2018.01.048</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29425723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>V&#xe9;lez-Mu&#xf1;iz RDC, Peralta-Pedrero ML, Jurado-Santa Cruz F, Morales-S&#xe1;nchez MA. Psychological profile and quality of life of patients with alopecia areata. Skin Append Disord. 2019;5(5):293&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000497166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6751425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31559253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ito T, Kamei K, Yuasa A, et al. Health-related quality of life in patients with alopecia areata: results of a Japanese survey with norm-based comparisons. J Dermatol. 2022;49(6):584&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1346-8138.16364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9314875</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35342979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>