<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40588648</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1942</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Drug safety</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Drug Saf</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Characteristics of Drug-RElated Hospitalizations for Nursing HOme Residents: Cross-Sectional RENHO Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1047</StartPage><EndPage>1061</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1047-1061</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40264-025-01556-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Nursing home residents with advancing age are often exposed to polypharmacy, a well-known risk factor for adverse drug reactions (ADRs), which increases the risk of hospitalization. Therefore, we assessed the characteristics of and factors associated with ADR-related emergency department (ED) admissions among nursing home residents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We carried out a cross-sectional study using the Toulouse University Hospital discharge database to identify nursing home residents ED admissions from 1 April, 2019 to 31 March, 2020. Information was updated for 2 years after inclusion (re-admissions). Emergency department medical files were analyzed to identify factors associated with these admissions (including demographics, functional dependency level, comorbidities, body mass index, ED admission in the previous 12 previous months, and number of drugs).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We identified 1514 patients (corresponding to 2024 ED admissions), 409 of whom (27.0%) were admitted at least once for an ADR. Thirty-six nursing home residents were re-admitted in 2020 and/or 2021 for ADRs, half of whom were for the same ADR. The most frequent ADRs were falls (114, 24.3%), hemorrhagic events (106, 22.6%), and constipation (47, 10.0%) involving benzodiazepines and Z-drugs (170, 16.0%), antidepressants (125, 11.9%), antithrombotic drugs (110, 10.3%), and opioids (82, 7.7%). About 12% of ADRs were assessed as avoidable. Factors significantly associated with ADR-related ED admissions were the number of drugs (odds ratio 1.09; 95% confidence interval 1.05-1.13), previous ED admissions (odds ratio 3.47; 95% confidence interval 2.46-4.90), and overweight (odds ratio 1.54; confidence interval 1.15-2.06).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Drug-induced iatrogenic disease could lead to ED admission for nursing home residents in approximately one-quarter of cases, 12% of which were assessed as avoidable. A previous history of ED admission and polypharmacy remain key associated factors. The awareness-raising campaigns for health professionals should be strengthened to prevent avoidable drug-induced ADRs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Lopez</LastName><ForeName>Alice</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Alfarano</LastName><ForeName>Chiara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lepetit</LastName><ForeName>Marianne</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Methological and Statistical Supporting Center MeDataS, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Clinical Investigation Centre 1436, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chebane</LastName><ForeName>Leila</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Redjimi</LastName><ForeName>Nassima</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Couret</LastName><ForeName>Ana&#xef;s</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Methological and Statistical Supporting Center MeDataS, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Clinical Investigation Centre 1436, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fabre</LastName><ForeName>Didier</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Information, Toulouse University Hospital (CHU Toulouse), Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gardette</LastName><ForeName>Virginie</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Methological and Statistical Supporting Center MeDataS, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Clinical Investigation Centre 1436, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berda&#xef;</LastName><ForeName>Driss</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Pharmacology, Bordeaux University Hospital, Bordeaux, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lapeyre-Mestre</LastName><ForeName>Maryse</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Methological and Statistical Supporting Center MeDataS, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Clinical Investigation Centre 1436, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bagheri</LastName><ForeName>Haleh</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9585-9341</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical and Clinical Pharmacology, Methological and Statistical Supporting Center MeDataS, Regional Pharmacovigilance Centre of Toulouse, Clinical Investigation Centre 1436, Toulouse University Hospital, Toulouse, France. haleh.bagheri@univ-tlse3.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Drug Saf</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9002928</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0114-5916</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009735" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nursing Homes</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064420" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drug-Related Side Effects and Adverse Reactions</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hospitalization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000369" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged, 80 and over</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D019338" MajorTopicYN="N">Polypharmacy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004636" MajorTopicYN="Y">Emergency Service, Hospital</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="N">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Funding: This study was funded by Appel d&#x2019;Offre Epiphare 2023. Conflicts of interest/competing interests: No commercial organizations had any role in the writing of this paper for publication. Alice Lopez, Chiara Alfarano, Marianne Lepetit, Leila Chebane, Nassima Redjimi, Ana&#xef;s Couret, Didier Fabre, Virginie Gardette, Driss Berda&#xef;, Maryse Lapeyre-Mestre, and Haleh Bagheri have no conflicts of interest that are directly relevant to the content of this article. Ethics approval: Strict confidentiality was ensured at all times during data collection, storage, and analysis. All methods were carried out in accordance with relevant guidelines and regulations. According to the French Ethics and Regulatory law (public health code), retrospective/prospective studies based on the exploitation of usual care data do not have to be submitted to an ethics committee, but they must be declared or covered by the reference methodology of the French National Commission on Informatics and Liberties&#xa0;(CNIL). A collection and computer processing of personal and medical data was implemented to analyze the results of the research. Toulouse University Hospital signed a commitment of compliance to the reference methodology MR-004 of CNIL. After evaluation and validation by the data protection officer and according to the General Data Protection Regulation, this study completing all the criteria, it is registered in the register of data study of the Toulouse University Hospital (RnIPH 2022-192) and covered by the MR-004 (CNIL number: 2206723 v 0). This study was approved by Toulouse University Hospital who confirms that ethics requirements were totally respected in the above report. According to French law on ethics, clinical trials covered by reference methodology MR-004, patients were informed that their codified data will be used for the study; written consent is not required. Consent to participate: Not applicable. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Availability of data and material: Data sharing is not applicable to this article as the datasets used are based on anonymized data that are protected by agreements with the French Data Protection Commission (CNIL). Code availability: R version 4.4.1 (2024-06-14 ucrt), ""Race for Your Life" Copyright 2024, The R Foundation for Statistical Computing Platform: x86_64-w64-mingw32/x64. Authors&#x2019; contributions: AL and CA contributed to the data collection, analysis of patient records and medications, analysis and interpretation of data, drafting of the manuscript, and critical revision. ML contributed to the data base adjustments, statistical analysis of data, and manuscript revision. LC contributed to database entry and optimization. NR contributed to the acquisition of data (arranging), database entry, and patient record archiving. DF contributed to the acquisition of data (arranging and obtaining) and patient records. VG and DB contributed to critical revision of the manuscript. ML contributed to the conception, design, and methodology, statistical analysis and interpretation of the data, and critical revision of the manuscript. HB contributed to the conception, design and methodology, data collection and analysis supervision, writing manuscript and critical revision, and team coordination. All authors read and approved the final version.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40588648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12334531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40264-025-01556-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40264-025-01556-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ageing. https://www.unfpa.org/ageing. Accessed 20 May 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Des r&#xe9;sidents de plus en plus &#xe2;g&#xe9;s et d&#xe9;pendants dans les &#xe9;tablissement d&#x2019;h&#xe9;bergement pour personnes &#xe2;g&#xe9;es.pdf. https://drees.solidarites-sante.gouv.fr/sites/default/files/2022-07/er1237.pdf. Accessed 16 Feb 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann F, Boeschen D, D&#xf6;rks M, et al. Renal insufficiency and medication in nursing home residents: a cross-sectional study (IMREN). Dtsch Arztebl Int. 2016;113:92&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4782265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26931625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AL, Franklin M, Bradshaw L, et al. Health status of UK care home residents: a cohort study. Age Ageing. 2014;43:97&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3861334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23864424</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwyer LL, Han B, Woodwell DA, et al. Polypharmacy in nursing home residents in the United States: results of the 2004 National Nursing Home Survey. Am J Geriatr Pharmacother. 2010;8:63&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20226393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fassmer AM, Hoffmann F. Acute health care services use among nursing home residents in Germany: a comparative analysis of out-of-hours medical care, emergency department visits and acute hospital admissions. Aging Clin Exp Res. 2019;32:1359&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31428997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haerdtlein A, Debold E, Rottenkolber M, et al. Which adverse events and which drugs are implicated in drug-related hospital admissions: a systematic review and metaanalysis. J Clin Med. 2023;12:1320.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9963366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36835854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ouslander JG, Lamb G, Perloe M, et al. Potentially avoidable hospitalizations of nursing home residents: frequency, causes, and costs. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2010;58:627&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20398146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kada O, Janig H, Likar R, et al. Reducing avoidable hospital transfers from nursing homes in Austria: project outline and baseline results. Gerontol Geriatr Med. 2017;3:2333721417696671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5433662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28540338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lemoyne SE, Herbots HH, De Blick D, et al. Appropriateness of transferring nursing home residents to emergency departments: a systematic review. BMC Geriatr. 2019;19:17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6341611</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30665362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renom-Guiteras A, Uhrenfeldt L, Meyer G, et al. Assessment tools for determining appropriateness of admission to acute care of persons transferred from long-term care facilities: a systematic review. BMC Geriatr. 2014;14:80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4094601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24952409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah BM, Hajjar ER. Polypharmacy, adverse drug reactions, and geriatric syndromes. Clin Geriatr Med. 2012;28:173&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22500537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen JK, Fouts MM, Kotabe SE, et al. Polypharmacy as a risk factor for adverse drug reactions in geriatric nursing home residents. Am J Geriatr Pharmacother. 2006;4:36&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16730619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies EC, Green CF, Mottram DR, et al. Emergency re-ad-missions to hospital due to adverse drug reactions within 1 year of the index admission. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2010;70:749&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2997315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21039769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hauviller L, Eyvrard F, Garnault V, et al. Hospital re-admission associated with adverse drug reactions in patients over the age of 65 years. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2016;72:631&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26884320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parameswaran Nair N, Chalmers L, Bereznicki BJ, et al. Repeat adverse drug reaction-related hospital admissions in elderly Australians: a retrospective study at the Royal Hobart Hospital. Drugs Aging. 2017;34:777&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28952130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lombardi F, Paoletti L, Carrieri B, et al. Underprescription of medications in older adults: causes, consequences and solutions: a narrative reveiw. Eur Geriatr Med. 2021;12:453&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33709336</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wauters M, Elseviers M, Vaes B, et al. Too many, too few, or too unsafe? Impact of inappropriate prescribing on mortality, and hospitalization in a cohort of community-dwelling oldest old. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2016;82:1382&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5061799</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27426227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonville-B&#xe9;ra AP, Saissi H, Bensouda-Grimaldi L, et al. Avoidability of adverse drug eeactions spontaneously reported to French regional drug monitoring. Drug Saf. 2009;32:429&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19419237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu Esba LC, Al Mardawi G, Aljasser AI, et al. Adverse drug reactions spontaneously reported at a tertiary care hospital and preventable measures implemented. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2021;46:460&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8247361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33285001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO. International statistical classification of diseases and related health problems, 10th revision. http://apps.who.int/classifications/icd10/browse/2010/en. Accessed 14 May 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlson ME, Carrozzino D, Guidi J, et al. Charlson Comorbidity Index: a critical review of clinimetric properties. Psychother Psychosom. 2022;91:8&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34991091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutton V. Evaluer la d&#xe9;pendance &#xe0; l&#x2019;aide de groupes iso-ressources (GIR): une tentative en France avec la grille aggir. Gerontol Soc. 2001;24:111&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norwegian Institute of Public Health. Anatomical therapeutic chemical structure and principles. https://www.whocc.no/atc/structure_and_principles. Accessed 10 June 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Coordinating Council for Medication Error Reporting and Prevention (NCCMERP). What is medication error? https://www.nccmerp.org/about-medication-errors. Accessed 10 June 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meid AD, Lampert A, Burnett A, et al. The impact of pharmaceutical care interventions for medication underuse in older people: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2015;80:768&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4594715</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25868941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medical Dictionary for Regulatory Activities (MedDRA). https://www.meddra.org/. Accessed 10 June 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang M, Holman CDJ, Price SD, et al. Comorbidity and repeat admission to hospital for adverse drug reactions in older adults: retrospective cohort study. BMJ. 2009;338:2752.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2615549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19129307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper JW. Adverse drug reaction-related hospitalizations of nursing facility patients: a 4-year study. South Med J. 1999;92:485&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10342894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayani N, Oya N, Kitaoka R, et al. Epidemiology of adverse drug events and medication errors in four nursing homes in Japan: the Japan Adverse Drug Events (JADE) Study. BMJ Qual Saf. 2022;31:878&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9685701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35450935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou S, Jia B, Kong J, et al. Drug-induced fall risk in older patients: a pharmacovigilance study in FDA adverse event reporting system database. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:1044744. 10.3389/fphar.2022.1044744.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.1044744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9746618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36523498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watanabe JH. Medication use, falls, and fall-related worry in older adults in the United States. Consult Pharm. 2016;31:385&#x2013;93. 10.4140/TCP.n.2016.385.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4140/TCP.n.2016.385</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27412315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oya N, Ayani N, Kuwahara A, et al. Over half of falls were associated with psychotropic medication use in four nursing homes in Japan: a retrospective cohort study. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19:3123. 10.3390/ijerph19053123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph19053123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8910089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35270813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cox CA, van Jaarsveld HJ, Houterman S, et al. Psychotropic drug prescription and the risk of falls in nursing home residents. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2016;17:1089&#x2013;93. 10.1016/j.jamda.2016.07.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2016.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27650670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima T, Akishita M, Nakamura T, et al. Association of polypharmacy with fall risk among geriatric outpatients. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2011;11:438&#x2013;44. 10.1111/j.1447-0594.2011.00703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1447-0594.2011.00703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21545384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly K, Bracchi R, Hewitt J, Routledge PA, Carter B. Benzodiazepines, Z-drugs and the risk of hip fracture: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. 2017;12: e0174730. 10.1371/journal.pone.0174730.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0174730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28448593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapeyre-Mestre M. A review of adverse outcomes associated with psychoactive drug use in nursing home residents with dementia. Drugs Aging. 2016;33:865&#x2013;88. 10.1007/s40266-016-0414-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40266-016-0414-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27812994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couret A, Gallini A, Poncet M, et al. Benzodiazepine dispensing to persons with dementia in France, 2011&#x2013;2016: a nationwide study. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2020;21:830&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.jamda.2020.02.019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2020.02.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32299715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller-Lissner S, Bassotti G, Coffin B, et al. Opioid-induced constipation and bowel dysfunction: a clinical guideline. Pain Med. 2017;18:1837&#x2013;63. 10.1093/pm/pnw255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pm/pnw255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5914368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28034973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Every-Palmer S, Newtones-Howes G, Clarke MJ. Treatment for antipsychotic-related constipation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;1:CD011128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6465073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28116777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurwitz JH, Field TS, Avorn J, et al. Incidence and preventability of adverse drug events in nursing homes. Am J Med. 2000;109:87&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10967148</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Field TS, Gurwitz JH, Avorn J, et al. Risk factors for adverse drug events among nursing home residents. Arch Intern Med. 2001;161:1629&#x2013;34. 10.1001/archinte.161.13.1629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.161.13.1629</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11434795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau DT, Kasper JD, Potter DE, Lyles A, Bennett RG. Hospitalization and death associated with potentially inappropriate medication prescriptions among elderly nursing home residents. Arch Intern Med. 2005;165:68&#x2013;74. 10.1001/archinte.165.1.68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.165.1.68</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15642877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chae HW, Zhao J, Ah YM, et al. Potentially inappropriate medication use as predictors of hospitalization for residents in nursing home. BMC Geriatr. 2023;23:467. 10.1186/s12877-023-04165-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12877-023-04165-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10394923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37532993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moulis F, Moulis G, Balardy L, et al. Exposure to atropinic drugs and frailty status. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2015;16:253&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25548029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picker D, Heard K, Bailey TC, Martin NR, LaRossa GN, Kollef MH. The number of discharge medications predicts thirty-day hospital readmission: a cohort study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015;15:282. 10.1186/s12913-015-0950-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-015-0950-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4512093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26202163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deschodt M, Devriendt E, Sabbe M, et al. Characteristics of older adults admitted to the emergency department (ED) and their risk factors for ED admission based on comprehensive geriatric assessment: a prospective cohort study. BMC Geriatr. 2015;15:54. 10.1186/s12877-015-0055-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4417280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25928799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visade F, Babykina G, Lamer A, et al. Importance of previous hospital stays on the risk of hospital re-admission in older adults: a real life analysis of the PAERPA study population. Age Ageing. 2021;50:141&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32687169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lani&#xe8;ce I, Couturier P, Dram&#xe9; M, et al. Incidence and main factors associated with early unplanned hospital readmission among French medical inpatients aged 75 and over admitted through emergency units. Age Ageing. 2008;37:416&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18487268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kojima G. Frailty as a predictor of hospitalisation among community-dwelling older people: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Epidemiol Community Health. 2016;70:722&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26933121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang SY, Shamliyan TA, Talley KM, Ramakrishnan R, Kane RL. Not just specific diseases: systematic review of the association of geriatric syndromes with hospitalization or nursing home admission. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2013;57:16&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23578847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park S, Kim AJ, Ah YM, et al. Prevalence and predictors of medication-related emergency department visit in older adults: a multicenter study linking national claim database and hospital medical records. Front Pharmacol. 2022;13:1009485. 10.3389/fphar.2022.1009485. (<b>eCollection 2022</b>).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.1009485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9614024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36313329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olivier P, Bertrand L, Tubery M, Lauque D, Montastruc JL, Lapeyre-Mestre M. Hospitalizations because of adverse drug reactions in elderly patients admitted through the emergency department: a prospective survey. Drugs Aging. 2009;26:475&#x2013;82. 10.2165/00002512-200926060-00004. (<b>PMID: 19591522</b>).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00002512-200926060-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19591522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hohl CM, Kuramoto L, Yu E, Rogula B, et al. Evaluating adverse drug event reporting in administrative data from emergency departments: a validation study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2013;13:473. 10.1186/1472-6963-13-473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6963-13-473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3842633</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24219303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>