<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40615900</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1472-6955</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>05</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC nursing</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Nurs</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Nursing students'knowledge and effectiveness of teaching in infection prevention and control.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>850</StartPage><MedlinePgn>850</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">850</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12912-025-03316-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In order to prevent healthcare-associated infections, infection prevention and control (IPC) is taught to nursing students in France as soon as they enter the nursing training institutes. The primary objective of this study was to assess the knowledge of standard precautions and hand hygiene of French nursing students before and after training. Secondary objectives were to measure factors predicting success on knowledge tests, and to investigate the effectiveness of the different teaching techniques used.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A quantitative study using online self-administered questionnaires was performed between September 1, 2022 and March 7, 2023 in French nursing training institutes. Three self-administered questionnaires were administered: the first to IPC trainers on their teaching methods, and the next two to nursing students on their knowledge and socio-demographic characteristics, with one questionnaire before and one after IPC training.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Fifty-nine nursing training institutes took part in the study. Before and after IPC training, 3,739 and 2,378 nursing students participated, respectively. At the start of training, the mean score on the knowledge test was 35.67 out of 50 ([35.53-35.77] sd&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.76), i.e. a moderate level of knowledge. After IPC training, the mean score on the knowledge test was 37.55 out of 50 ([37.40-37.68] sd&#x2009;=&#x2009;3.48), i.e. a good level of knowledge. Students with a Nursing Auxiliary Diploma (NAD) scored significantly better than no NAD students, both before (p&#x2c2;0.001) and after (p&#x2c2;0.001) IPC training. The teaching techniques used were varied and combined, but only practice audits significantly improved students' knowledge after training (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.050).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nursing students' knowledge of IPC before training is heterogeneous and moderate. After training, knowledge had improved little but significantly. Only auditing was effective to improve students' level of knowledge of IPC. Audits should be included in the IPC training program.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohammedi</LastName><ForeName>Stephanie Bouget</ForeName><Initials>SB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0005-6731-1588</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>French Red Cross Competence Auvergne-Rh&#xf4;ne-Alpes, Valence, 26000, France. stephanie.bouget-mohammedi@croix-rouge.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Univ. Grenoble Alpes, CNRS, UMR 5525, VetAgro Sup, Grenoble INP, CHU Grenoble Alpes, TIMC, Grenoble, 38000, France. stephanie.bouget-mohammedi@croix-rouge.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Croix-Rouge Comp&#xe9;tence, 76 chemin de Ronde, Valence, 26000, France. stephanie.bouget-mohammedi@croix-rouge.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gillois</LastName><ForeName>Pierre</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Univ. Grenoble Alpes, CNRS, UMR 5525, VetAgro Sup, Grenoble INP, CHU Grenoble Alpes, TIMC, Grenoble, 38000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Public Health, Grenoble Alpes University Hospital, Grenoble, 38000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHU Grenoble Alpes, Boulevard Chantourne, La Tronche, 38700, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Landelle</LastName><ForeName>Caroline</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Univ. Grenoble Alpes, CNRS, UMR 5525, VetAgro Sup, Grenoble INP, CHU Grenoble Alpes, TIMC, Grenoble, 38000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Infection Control Unit, Grenoble Alpes University Hospital, Grenoble, 38000, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHU Grenoble Alpes, Boulevard Chantourne, La Tronche, 38700, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Nurs</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088683</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6955</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hand hygiene</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infection prevention and control</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nursing education</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Standard precautions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Teaching</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Research was conducted in compliance with the Helsinki Declaration. The clinical research direction of Grenoble Alps University Hospital in France classified the survey as a RNIPH (Research Not Involving the Human Person) according to the French research methodology (MR-004). Only informed consent to participate was obtained from all of the participants. Consent for publication: Not available. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40615900</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12228198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12912-025-03316-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12912-025-03316-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>WHO. WHO guidelines on hand hygiene in health care: a summary. 2009 [cited 2024 Aug 21]; Available from: https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241597906</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alison D, Lydecker PA, Osei L, Pineles JK, Johnson J, Meisel OC, Stine L, Magder AP, Gurses. Joan hebden, Cagla oruc, Lona mody, Kara Jacobs slifka, nimalie D stone, Mary-Claire roghmann. Targeted gown and glove use to prevent Staphylococcus aureus acquisition in community-based nursing homes: A pilot study. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2021;42(4):448&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/ice.2020.1219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33077004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mast ST, Woolwine JD, Gerberding JL. Efficacy of gloves in reducing blood volumes transferred during simulated needlestick injury. J Infect Dis. 1993;168(6):1589&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/168.6.1589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8245553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pittet D, Hugonnet S, Harbarth S, Mourouga P, Sauvan V, Touveneau S, et al. Effectiveness of a hospital-wide programme to improve compliance with hand hygiene. Infect Control Programme Lancet Lond Engl. 2000;356(9238):1307&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11073019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouget Mohammedi S, Landelle C. Review of literature: knowledge and practice of standard precautions by nursing student and teaching techniques used in training. Am J Infect Control. 2023;51(5):574&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajic.2022.08.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36075296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouget Mohammedi SB, Dinh C, Landelle C. Educational methods used to teach infection prevention and control in nurse training: Survey of French training institutes [Internet]. In Review; 2023 May [cited 2023 May 20]. Available from: https://www.researchsquare.com/article/rs-2934066/v1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pangandaman, et al. Innovative classroom pedagogy in nursing education: A systematic review| Semantic Scholar [Internet]. 2020 [cited 2021 Jul 5]. Available from: https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/INNOVATIVE-CLASSROOM-PEDAGOGY-IN-NURSING-EDUCATION%3A-Pangandaman-Boloron/efc1def4fef3b05e68ad5f62ef4a0a2d63a39898</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xd6;zbay &#xd6;, &#xc7;&#x131;nar S. Effectiveness of flipped classroom teaching models in nursing education: A systematic review. Nurse Educ Today. 2021;102:104922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2021.104922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33940481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan ZM. Improving knowledge and compliance with infection control standard precautions among undergraduate nursing students in Jordan. Am J Infect Control. 2018;46(3):297&#x2013;302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajic.2017.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7115283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29102051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappes Ramirez MS. Influence of undergraduate nursing student teaching methods on learning standard precautions and transmission-based precautions: experimental research. Nurse Educ Today. 2018;61:101&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2017.11.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29195210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim E, Kim SS, Kim S. Effects of infection control education for nursing students using standardized patients vs. peer role-play. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020;18(1).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7794753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33375222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu KS, Lee SSJ, Chen JK, Chen YS, Tsai HC, Chen YJ, et al. Identifying heterogeneity in the Hawthorne effect on hand hygiene observation: a cohort study of overtly and covertly observed results. BMC Infect Dis. 2018;18(1):369.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-018-3292-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30081843</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter EJ, Mancino D, Hessels AJ, Kelly AM, Larson EL. Reported hours of infection education received positively associated with student nurses&#x2019; ability to comply with infection prevention practices: results from a nationwide survey. Nurse Educ Today. 2017;53:19&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2017.02.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28365555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kra O, Aoussi E, Ehui I, Ouattara B, Bissagn&#xe9;n&#xe9; E. Nursing students&#x2019; attitudes, knowledge and practices regarding nosocomial infections in Abidjan (Ivory Coast). M&#xe9;decine Mal Infect. 2009;39:S77&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0399-077X(09)74517-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhumaid S, Al Mutair A, Al Alawi Z, Alsuliman M, Ahmed GY, Rabaan AA, et al. Knowledge of infection prevention and control among healthcare workers and factors influencing compliance: a systematic review. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2021;10(1):86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13756-021-00957-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dicko-Traore F, Gire C, Brevaut Malaty V, Busutill M, Monnier AS, Brunel V. Evaluation of hand hygiene knowledge and practices in the neonatology and intensive care unit of the infantile medicine and neonatology department of the North hospital, Marseille. J P&#xe9;diatrie Pu&#xe9;riculture. 2011;24(4):172&#x2013;7. 17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpp.2011.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider J, Moromisato D, Zemetra B, Rizzi-Wagner L, Rivero N, Mason W, et al. Hand hygiene adherence is influenced by the behavior of role models. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2009;10(3):360&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PCC.0b013e3181a32f16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19325501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Decree of July 3. 2023 amending the decree of July 31, 2009 relating to the dipl&#xf4;me d&#x2019;Etat d&#x2019;infirmier. [Internet]. Available from: https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/jorf/id/JORFTEXT000047784162</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gould D, Drey N. Student nurses&#x2019; experiences of infection prevention and control during clinical placements. Am J Infect Control. 2013;41(9):760&#x2013;3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajic.2013.01.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23993761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sundal JS, Aune AG, Storvig E, Aasland JK, Fjeldsaeter KL, Torjuul K. The hand hygiene compliance of student nurses during clinical placements. J Clin Nurs. 2017;26(23&#x2013;24):4646&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.13811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28329415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>AL-Mugheed K, Bayraktar N, Al-Bsheish M, AlSyouf A, Aldhmadi BK, Jarrar M et al. H Luo editor 2022 Effectiveness of game-based virtual reality phone application and online education on knowledge, attitude and compliance of standard precautions among nursing students. PLoS ONE 17 11 e0275130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0275130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9632768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36327261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Min A, Min H, Kim S. Effectiveness of serious games in nurse education: A systematic review. Nurse Educ Today. 2022;108:105178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2021.105178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34717098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shorey S, Ng ED. The use of virtual reality simulation among nursing students and registered nurses: A systematic review. Nurse Educ Today. 2021;98:104662.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2020.104662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33203545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salmon S, Wang XB, Seetoh T, Lee SY, Fisher DA. A novel approach to improve hand hygiene compliance of student nurses. Antimicrob Resist Infect Control. 2013;2(1):16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2047-2994-2-16</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3679881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23721611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Research S, Evaluation and, Department S. Three times as many female nursing students will drop out in the first year in 2021 as in 2011, [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Apr 15]. Available from: https://drees.solidarites-sante.gouv.fr/publications-communique-de-presse/etudes-et-resultats/les-etudiantes-en-formation-dinfirmiere-sont#:~:text=En%202021%2C%2010%20%25%20des%20%C3%A9tudiantes,en%20troisi%C3%A8me%20ann%C3%A9e%20en%202021</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>