<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41026200</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-5195</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>49</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>International orthopaedics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Int Orthop</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Over ten year follow-up results of a prospective and consecutive series of primary total knee arthroplasty with a multimodular total knee prosthesis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>2635</StartPage><EndPage>2643</EndPage><MedlinePgn>2635-2643</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00264-025-06634-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSED">High survival rates up to ten years have been reported for total knee replacements (TKR). Publications beyond ten years have more diverse conclusions. To study the long-term survival and clinical results of a multi-modular TKR, we examined a series of 120 cases with a minimum ten-years follow-up.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This is a prospective multicentric observational study operated for arthritis by five senior surgeons. No control group has been included. Different femoral components (posterior stabilized (PS) or cruciate retaining (PC) versions), different tibial baseplates, both in cemented or cementless versions, were associated with an PS, PC or rotating version (PR) polyethylene insert and a patellar resurfacing or a partial inlay polyethylene component. In some cases the patella was not implanted. At ten years 38 patients were deceased (31.7 %) and 25 patients were lost to follow-up (20.8 %). 57 patients were reviewed at ten years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The Kaplan Meier cumulative survival rate of the TKR, by considering revision for any reason as endpoint, at ten years is at 92.6% (CI: 86.2-96.1).They were two infections (1.7%) and eight other revisions for different reasons (6.7 %). Secondary IKS scores were statistically improved. Functional score was 79.4 points (p&lt;0.001) and knee score was 89.2 (p&lt;0.001). Minimal clinically important difference (MCID) were obtained in most of patients. Satisfaction of the patients was obtained in 93.75 % in a correspondence questionnaire.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">At ten year follow-up, this multi-modular TKR provides very good implant survival rates and clinical score with a high patient satisfaction.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwartz</LastName><ForeName>Claude</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>, Colmar, France. schwartzop@aol.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mainard</LastName><ForeName>Didier</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Lorraine, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vastel</LastName><ForeName>Laurent</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Raymond Poincar&#xe9; University Hospital, Garches, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hummer</LastName><ForeName>Jacques</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Lorraine, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hummer</LastName><ForeName>Nicolas</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Lorraine, Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Int Orthop</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7705431</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0341-2695</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Int Orthop. 2026 Mar;50(3):705-706. doi: 10.1007/s00264-026-06754-x.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41689591</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long term follow-up</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multi-modular total knee replacement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Total knee replacement</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval: This is a non-interventional observational research study not involving the human person (RNIPH), the information and non-opposition of patients, and the processing of personal data has been operated in accordance with the Data Protection Act No. 2018&#x2013;493 of May 3, 2018, and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), applying the reference methodology MR-004. The local Research Ethics Committee has confirmed that no ethical approval is required. Consent for publication: I would also like to declare that the contents of this manuscript have not been copyrighted or published previously and the contents of this manuscript are original and have not been published elsewhere nor are they currently under consideration for publication elsewhere. I do hereby declare that I have read carefully the submission guidelines available on the website of &#x201c;International Orthopaedics.&#x201d; Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41026200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12594733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00264-025-06634-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00264-025-06634-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Bourne RB, Chesworth BM, Davis AM, Mahomed NN, Charron KDJ (2010) Patient satisfaction after total knee arthroplasty: who is satisfied and who is not? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2010;468(1):57&#x2013;63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YH, Park JW, Kim JS (2014) Clinical outcomes of total knee arthroplasty with posterior- stabilized prosthesis: minimum 5-year follow-up. Clin Orthop Relat Res 2014 Jan 472(1):135&#x2013;144</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carr AJ, Robertson O, Graves S et al (2012) Knee replacement. Lancet 2012;379(9823):1331&#x2013;40</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell SM, Shelton TJ, Hull ML (2018) Ten-year survivorship of kinematically aligned total knee arthroplasty using manual instruments. JAMA Surg. 2018;153(5):431&#x2013;437</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton DF, Lane JV, Gaston P, Patton JT, MacDonald D, Simpson AHRW (2013) What determines patient satisfaction with surgery? A prospective cohort study of 4709 patients following total joint replacement. BMJ Open. 2013;3(4):e002525</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pabinger C, Berghold A, Boehler N, Labek G (2013) Revision rates after knee replacement: cumulative results from worldwide clinical studies versus joint registers. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2013;21(2):263&#x2013;268</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price AJ, Alvand A, Troelsen A et al (2018) Knee replacement. Lancet. 2018;6(10158):1672&#x2013;1682</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jenny JY, Boeri C, Ricciardi JE et al (2014) Analyse de survie de la proth&#xe8;se totale de genou &#xe0; un recul minimum de dix ans: &#xe9;tude multicentrique nationale portant sur 846 cas. Rev Chir Orthop Traumatol. 2014;100(6):593&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YH, Park JW, Kim JS (2023) Long-term clinical results of alumina ceramic medial pivot total knee arthroplasty: a 10-year follow-up study. Arthroplasty. 2023;5(1):6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mont MA, Alexander NE, Krackow KA, Hungerford DS (2015) Long-term results of cruciate-retaining total knee arthroplasty in patients with rheumatoid arthritis: a minimum 15-year review. J Arthroplasty. 2015;30(6):1082&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berend ME, Ritter MA, Meding JB, Faris PM, Keating EM, Redelman R (2001) The Genesis total knee prosthesis: a 10-year follow-up study. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2001;(388):117&#x2013;25</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han HS, Kang SB, Yoon KS (2012) Long-term results of hybrid total knee arthroplasty: minimum 10-years follow-up. Clin Orthop Surg. 2012;4(3):176&#x2013;81</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranawat CS, Luessenhop CP, Rodriguez JA (1993) The long-term results of total condylar knee arthroplasty. A 15-year survivorship study. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1993;(286):94&#x2013;102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Joint Registry. 20th Annual Report 2023. London: NJR (2023) [cited 2025 May 6]. Available from: https://www.njrreports.org.uk/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beard DJ, Harris K, Dawson J et al (2015) Meaningful changes for the Oxford hip and knee scores after joint replacement surgery. J Clin Epidemiol. 2015;68(1):73&#x2013;79</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizaur-Utrilla A, Gonzalez-Parre&#xf1;o S, Martinez-Mendez D, Miralles-Mu&#xf1;oz FA, et Lopez- Prats FA (2020). &#xab; Minimal Clinically Important Differences and Substantial Clinical Benefit for Knee Society Scores &#xbb;. Knee Surgery, Sports Traumatology, Arthroscopy 2020;28(5):1473&#x2013;78</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayhew D, Mendonca V, Murthy BVS (2019) A review of ASA physical status &#x2013; historical perspectives and modern developments. Anaesthesia 2019;74:373&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insall JN, Dorr LD, Scott RD, Scott WN (1989) Rationale of the Knee Society Clinical Rating System. Clin Orthop Relat Res.1989;(248):13&#x2013;14</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ergin M, Budin M, &#xc7;ilo&#x11f;lu O, Forero F, Gehrke T, &#xc7;&#x131;tak M (2025) Factors contributing to instability after primary total knee arthroplasty: a twenty five Year retrospective cohort study. Int Orthop. 2025;26. 10.1007/s00264-025-06620-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soundarrajan D, Kumar KM, Singh R, Rajasekaran RB, Palanisami D, Natesan R, Rajasekaran S (2025) Imageless robotic-assisted total knee arthroplasty allows intra- articular correction of severe extra-articular deformities using functional alignment and desired under-correction. Int Orthop. 2025;49(8):1869&#x2013;1878. 10.1007/s00264-025-06563-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obada B, Iliescu MG, Costea DO, Petcu L, Popescu AI (2025) Comparative study of outcomes with total knee arthroplasty: medial pivot prosthesis vs posterior stabilized implant. Prospective randomized control. Int Orthop. 2025;49(3):629&#x2013;639. 10.1007/s00264-025-06420-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angst F, Aeschlimann A, Stucki G (2002) Smallest detectable and minimal clinically important differences of rehabilitation intervention with their implications for required sample sizes. Osteoarthritis Cartilage. 2002;10(5):394&#x2013;404</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins NJ, Misra D, Felson DT et al (2011) Measures of knee function: WOMAC, KOOS, OKS. Arthritis Care Res 2011;63(S11):S208&#x2013;28</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizaur-Utrilla A, Miralles-Mu&#xf1;oz FA, L&#xf3;pez-Prats FA (2020) Validation of the minimal clinically important difference in function and pain in patients undergoing TKA. Knee. 2020;27(5):1391&#x2013;1397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argenson JN, Boisgard S, Parratte S, Descamps S, Bercovy M, Bonnevialle P et al (2013) Survival analysis of total knee arthroplasty at a minimum 10 years&#x2019; follow-up: A multicentre French nationwide study including 846 cases. Orthop Traumatol Surg Res, 2013;99:385&#x2013;390</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura S, Kobayashi M, Ito H, Nakamura K, Ueo T, Nakamura T (2010) The Bi- Surface total knee arthroplasty: minimum 10-year follow-up study. Knee. 2010;17(4):274&#x2013;278</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans JT, Walker RW, Evans JP, Blom AW, Sayers A, Whitehouse MR (2019) How long does a knee replacement last? A systematic review and meta-analysis of case series and national registry reports with more than 15 years of follow-up. Lancet. 2019;393(10172):655&#x2013;663</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdeen AR, &#x2219; Collen SR, &#x2219; Vince KG (2010) Fifteen-year to 19-year follow-up of the Insall- Burstein-1 total knee arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty. 2010;25:173&#x2013;178</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>