<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">42168888</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2334</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC infectious diseases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Infect Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Concurrent pulmonary, hepatic and cerebral pneumocystosis: case report and review of the literature.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12879-026-13363-x</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Pneumocystosis is a common opportunistic fungal infection primarily affecting immunocompromised individuals. While pulmonary involvement represents the most frequent presentation, extra pulmonary dissemination remains rare.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION" NlmCategory="METHODS">We report herein an exceptional case of disseminated pneumocystosis in a patient living with HIV who presented with multiple symptoms including cough, dyspnea and generalized anasarca. Imaging tests showed pleural effusion with bilateral pulmonary parenchymal consolidations, marked splenomegaly with intra-parenchymal nodules, homogeneous hepatomegaly, and multiple cerebral lesions. Pneumocystis jirovecii was detected using qPCR in induced sputum and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid. Despite the initiation of appropriate treatment, the clinical course was progressive leading to the death of the patient. Gomori methenamine silver staining identified P. jirovecii asci in a liver biopsy performed one day before the patient died. qPCR assays performed retrospectively in cerebrospinal fluid, serum, and in paraffin-embedded hepatic tissue, were positive. The same multilocus genotype with a mutation in the dhps gene was identified in bronchoalveolar lavage fluid, serum, and liver biopsy specimens suggesting a disseminated infection due to a single strain of P. jirovecii.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This case highlights a rare and fatal presentation of disseminated pneumocystosis with the evidence of a single strain responsible for concurrent pulmonary, hepatic and blood involvement in a patient with advanced HIV-infection. It demonstrates the interest of P. jirovecii qPCR assays in organ and serum specimens to confirm histopathological and mycological diagnosis of this clinical presentation of the infection.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chouaieb</LastName><ForeName>Hamed</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Parasitology-Mycology Department, Avicenne Hospital, AP-HP, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Sousse, Faculty of Medicine of Sousse, Sousse, Tunisia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>M&#xe9;cha&#xef;</LastName><ForeName>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Infectious and Tropical Diseases, Avicenne Hospital, AP-HP, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INSERM UMR 1137, IAME, Sorbonne Paris Nord University, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziol</LastName><ForeName>Marianne</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service d'anatomie pathologique et Centre de Ressources Biologiques (BB-0033-00027) AP-HP, Sorbonne Paris Nord University, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Behnam</LastName><ForeName>Jean-Fran&#xe7;ois</ForeName><Initials>JF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Parasitology-Mycology Department, Avicenne Hospital, AP-HP, Bobigny, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nevez</LastName><ForeName>Gilles</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHU de Brest, Laboratoire de Parasitologie-Mycologie, Brest, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Brest, Universit&#xe9; d'Angers, Infections Respiratoires Fongiques, Brest, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gal</LastName><ForeName>Solene Le</ForeName><Initials>SL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHU de Brest, Laboratoire de Parasitologie-Mycologie, Brest, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Brest, Universit&#xe9; d'Angers, Infections Respiratoires Fongiques, Brest, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brun</LastName><ForeName>Sophie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Parasitology-Mycology Department, Avicenne Hospital, AP-HP, Bobigny, France. sophie.brun@aphp.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INSERM UMR 1137, IAME, Sorbonne Paris Nord University, Bobigny, France. sophie.brun@aphp.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Infect Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968551</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2334</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disseminated pneumocystosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Extrapulmonary pneumocystosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genotyping</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">QPCR</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: Not applicable Consent for publication: In accordance with the French reference methodology MR-004, applicable to the retrospective use of health-related data, data and samples from a participant who died before or during the study may be used, provided that he did not express a written refusal during his lifetime. In our case, after being informed of the possible subsequent use of his data, the patient did not express any opposition during his entire hospital stay. In addition, written informed consent for publication was obtained from next of kin Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">42168888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-026-13363-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12879-026-13363-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>