<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40366322</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2772-3747</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JACC. Asia</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JACC Asia</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of Nonadherence to Any Antiplatelet Therapy After PCI With Drug-Eluting Stents on Critical Outcomes.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>758</StartPage><EndPage>768</EndPage><MedlinePgn>758-768</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jacasi.2025.03.008</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2772-3747(25)00196-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Lifelong antiplatelet therapy after percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI) with drug-eluting stents (DES) is strongly recommended. However, the extent and temporal variation in the risk of nonadherence to this recommendation remain unclear.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to investigate how nonadherence to any antiplatelet therapy after PCI affects critical cardiac events and whether this effect varies over time.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This cohort study analyzed Japanese nationwide insurance claims and health checkup records of working-age patients who underwent PCI with DES between April 2016 and March 2022. Nonadherence was defined as prescription coverage of antiplatelet therapy &lt;50% within preceding 90 days. Landmark-time survival analysis with propensity-score matching was conducted every 5 days from 90th to 1,095th days after PCI. The primary outcome was a composite of all-cause death, myocardial infarction, or cardiopulmonary arrest. Results were synthesized to assess temporal variation in the risk magnitude.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among 40,902 patients (mean age, 58.3 &#xb1; 8.3 years; 5.5% women [2,240 of 40,902], median [IQR] follow-up: 653 days [Q1-Q3: 235-1,233 days]), nonadherence was observed in 1.18% (421 of 35,582) at 90 days and 4.70% (579 of 12,312) at 1,095 days after PCI. Critical cardiac events were more frequent in nonadherent patients (HR: 2.50 [95% CI: 1.92-3.26]; P &lt; 0.001), with no significant temporal variation across landmark times.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Nonadherence to any antiplatelet therapy after PCI was associated with a more than 2-fold increase in critical cardiac events, irrespective of post-PCI timing throughout 3 years. These findings emphasize the need for sustained efforts by health care providers and patients to maintain drug adherence over a prolonged period.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mori</LastName><ForeName>Yuichiro</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Health Sciences, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friede</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Statistics, University Medical Center G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany; DZHK (German Center for Cardiovascular Research), partner site Lower Saxony, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hattori</LastName><ForeName>Satoshi</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Statistics, Graduate School of Medicine and Integrated Frontier Research for Medical Science Division, Institute for Open and Transdisciplinary Research Initiatives (OTRI), The University of Osaka, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yamaji</LastName><ForeName>Kyohei</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fukuma</LastName><ForeName>Shingo</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Health Sciences, Kyoto University Graduate School of Medicine, Kyoto, Japan; Department of Epidemiology Infectious Disease Control and Prevention, Hiroshima University Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima, Japan. Electronic address: fukuma.shingo.3m@kyoto-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JACC Asia</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918452380106676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2772-3747</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antiplatelet therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug-eluting stent(s)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding Support and Author Disclosures The research is funded by the research grant from Japan Health Insurance Association (20JHIA04). Dr Friede reports payments to institution from Abbott, grants from Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG), Federal Joint Committee (G-BA) and European Commission; consulting fees (including data monitoring committees) from Actimed, Aslan, Bayer, BiosensWebster, BMS, CSLBehring, Daiichi-Sankyo, eCovery, Enanta, Fresenius Kabi, Galapagos, IQVIA, Novartis, PPD, Pfizer, RECARDIO, Recordati, Relaxera, Roche, Viatris, CSL Vifor, VICO Therapeutics. All other authors have reported that they have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40366322</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12287742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacasi.2025.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2772-3747(25)00196-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Waldo S.W., Gokhale M., O&#x2019;Donnell C.I., et al. Temporal trends in coronary angiography and percutaneous coronary intervention: insights from the VA clinical assessment, reporting, and tracking program. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2018;11:879&#x2013;888.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29747919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmis A., Vardas P., Townsend N., et al. European Society of Cardiology: cardiovascular disease statistics 2021. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:716&#x2013;799.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35016208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawton J.S., Tamis-Holland J.E., Bangalore S., et al. 2021 ACC/AHA/SCAI guideline for coronary artery revascularization: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Joint Committee on Clinical Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2022;79:e21&#x2013;e129.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34895950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knuuti J., Wijns W., Saraste A., et al. 2019 ESC guidelines for the diagnosis and management of chronic coronary syndromes: the Task Force for the Diagnosis and Management of Chronic Coronary Syndromes of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) Eur Heart J. 2019;41:407&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura M., Kimura K., Kimura T., et al. JCS 2020 guideline focused update on antithrombotic therapy in patients with coronary artery disease. Circ J. 2020;84:831&#x2013;865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32173684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valgimigli M., Bueno H., Byrne R.A., et al. 2017 ESC focused update on dual antiplatelet therapy in coronary artery disease developed in collaboration with EACTS: the Task Force for Dual Antiplatelet Therapy in Coronary Artery Disease of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) and of the European Association for Cardio-Thoracic Surgery (EACTS) Eur Heart J. 2018;39:213&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28886622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peasah S.K., Mager D., Munshi K.D., et al. Real-world use and outcomes of oral antiplatelets among patients with acute coronary syndrome: a retrospective cohort study. Drugs Real World Outcomes. 2022;9:121&#x2013;127.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8844330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34780040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristensen A.M.D., Pareek M., Kragholm K.H., McEvoy J.W., Torp-Pedersen C., Prescott E.B. Long-term aspirin adherence following myocardial infarction and risk of cardiovascular events. Eur Heart J. Qual Care Clin Outcomes. 2024;10(7):612&#x2013;622. doi: 10.1093/ehjqcco/qcae009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ehjqcco/qcae009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38305132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho P.M., O&#x2019;Donnell C.I., McCreight M., et al. Multifaceted intervention to improve P2Y12 inhibitor adherence after percutaneous coronary intervention: a stepped wedge trial. J Am Heart Assoc. 2022;11</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9333389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35766258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth G.A., Morden N.E., Zhou W., Malenka D.J., Skinner J. Clopidogrel use and early outcomes among older patients receiving a drug-eluting coronary artery stent. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2012;5:103&#x2013;112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3261311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22147885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigen R., Maddox T.M., O&#x2019;Donnell C.I., et al. Hospital variation in premature clopidogrel discontinuation after drug-eluting stent placement in the Veterans Affairs (VA) Healthcare System. J Am Heart Assoc. 2016;5 doi: 10.1161/JAHA.114.001376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.114.001376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4889159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27151513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikegami N., Yoo B.-K., Hashimoto H., et al. Japanese universal health coverage: evolution, achievements, and challenges. Lancet. 2011;378:1106&#x2013;1115.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21885107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xfc;scher T.F., Steffel J., Eberli F.R., et al. Drug-eluting stent and coronary thrombosis:biological mechanisms and clinical implications. Circulation. 2007;115:1051&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17325255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taniwaki M., Radu M.D., Zaugg S., et al. Mechanisms of very late drug-eluting stent thrombosis assessed by optical coherence tomography. Circulation. 2016;133:650&#x2013;660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26762519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Houwelingen H.C., Putter H. CRC Press, Taylor and Francis Group; 2011. Dynamic Prediction in Clinical Survival Analysis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E., Altman D.G., Egger M., et al. Strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. BMJ. 2007;335:806&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2034723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17947786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health and Global Policy Institute  3.1 Japan&#x2019;s Health Insurance System. Japan Health Policy NOW. January 14, 2022 https://japanhpn.org/en/section-3-1/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fukuma S., Iizuka T., Ikenoue T., Tsugawa Y. Association of the national health guidance intervention for obesity and cardiovascular risks with health outcomes among Japanese men. JAMA Intern Med. 2020;180:1630&#x2013;1637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7536624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33031512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mori Y., Matsushita K., Inoue K., Fukuma S. Patterns and predictors of adherence to follow-up health guidance invitations in a general health check-up program in Japan: a cohort study with an employer-sponsored insurer database. PLoS One. 2023;18</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10212164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37228080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Japanese Ministry of Health Labour and Welfare  Annual report on the implementation of general health check-up program by Japan Health Insurance Association. 2020 (Japanese). https://www.mhlw.go.jp/content/12400000/001017830.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen L., Wettermark B., Steinke D., Potteg&#xe5;rd A. Core concepts in pharmacoepidemiology: measures of drug utilization based on individual-level drug dispensing data. Pharmacoepidemiol Drug Saf. 2022;31:1015&#x2013;1026.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9545237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35819240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awtry E.H., Loscalzo J. Aspirin. Circulation. 2000;101:1206&#x2013;1218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10715270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hansson E.C., Malm C.J., Hesse C., et al. Platelet function recovery after ticagrelor withdrawal in patients awaiting urgent coronary surgery. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2017;51:633&#x2013;637.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28007881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber A.A., Braun M., Hohlfeld T., Schwippert B., Tsch&#xf6;pe D., Schr&#xf6;r K. Recovery of platelet function after discontinuation of clopidogrel treatment in healthy volunteers. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2001;52:333&#x2013;336.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2014541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11560568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inker L.A., Eneanya N.D., Coresh J., et al. New creatinine- and cystatin C-based equations to estimate GFR without race. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:1737&#x2013;1749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8822996</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34554658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang F., Ishwaran H. Random Forest missing data algorithms. Stat Anal Data Min. 2017;10:363&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5796790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29403567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ono Y., Taneda Y., Takeshima T., Iwasaki K., Yasui A. Validity of claims diagnosis codes for cardiovascular diseases in diabetes patients in Japanese administrative database. Clin Epidemiol. 2020;12:367&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7152547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32308492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fontein D.B.Y., Klinten Grand M., Nortier J.W.R., et al. Dynamic prediction in breast cancer: proving feasibility in clinical practice using the TEAM trial. Ann Oncol. 2015;26:1254&#x2013;1262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25862439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koo T.K., Li M.Y. A guideline of selecting and reporting intraclass correlation coefficients for reliability research. J Chiropr Med. 2016;15:155&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4913118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27330520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baber U., Mehran R., Giustino G., et al. Coronary thrombosis and major bleeding after PCI with drug-eluting stents: risk scores from PARIS. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2016;67:2224&#x2013;2234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27079334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shi X., Miao W., Tchetgen E.T. A selective review of negative control methods in epidemiology. Curr Epidemiol Rep. 2020;7:190&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8118596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33996381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simonsson M., Alfredsson J., Szummer K., Jernberg T., Ueda P. Association of ischemic and bleeding events with mortality among patients in sweden with recent acute myocardial infarction receiving antithrombotic therapy. JAMA Netw Open. 2022;5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9425148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36036452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yokoyama S., Tanaka Y., Nakagita K., Hosomi K., Takada M. Bleeding risk of warfarin and direct oral anticoagulants in younger population: a historical cohort study using a Japanese claims database. Int J Med Sci. 2018;15:1686&#x2013;1693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6299405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30588192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mullen L., Meah M.N., Elamin A., et al. Risk of major bleeding with potent antiplatelet agents after an acute coronary event: a comparison of ticagrelor and clopidogrel in 5116 consecutive patients in clinical practice. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8174168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33834845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y., Zhu Z., Gao C. Polypill Strategy in Secondary Cardiovascular Prevention. N Engl J Med. 2022;387:2197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36477041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park D.-W., Park S.-W., Park K.-H., et al. Frequency of and risk factors for stent thrombosis after drug-eluting stent implantation during long-term follow-up. Am J Cardiol. 2006;98:352&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16860022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tada T., Byrne R.A., Simunovic I., et al. Risk of stent thrombosis among bare-metal stents, first-generation drug-eluting stents, and second-generation drug-eluting stents. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2013;6:1267&#x2013;1274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24355117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawayama Y., Sasaki K., Taninobu N., et al. The effect of intravascular imaging-guided percutaneous coronary intervention on coronary artery perforation. JACC Asia. 2024;5(1):46&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/j.jacasi.2024.09.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacasi.2024.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11775771</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39886189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chau K.H., Kirtane A.J., Easterwood R.M., et al. Stent thrombosis risk over time on the basis of clinical presentation and platelet reactivity: analysis from ADAPT-DES. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2021;14:417&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33516690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frossard M., Fuchs I., Leitner J.M., et al. Platelet function predicts myocardial damage in patients with acute myocardial infarction. Circulation. 2004;110:1392&#x2013;1397.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15313953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iqbal J., Zhang Y.-J., Holmes D.R., et al. Optimal medical therapy improves clinical outcomes in patients undergoing revascularization with percutaneous coronary intervention or coronary artery bypass grafting: insights from the Synergy Between Percutaneous Coronary Intervention with TAXUS and Cardiac Surgery (SYNTAX) trial at the 5-year follow-up. Circulation. 2015;131:1269&#x2013;1277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25847979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie J.X., Gunzburger E.C., Kaun L., et al. Medical therapy utilization and long-term outcomes following percutaneous coronary intervention. Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes. 2019;12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31665896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sawayama Y., Takashima N., Harada A., et al. Incidence and in-hospital mortality of acute myocardial infarction: a report from a population-based registry in Japan. J Atheroscler Thromb. 2023;30:1407&#x2013;1419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10564630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36596530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>