<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34532213</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2189-8448</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Physical therapy research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Phys Ther Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Self-rated Changes of Health Status during Stay-at-home Orders among Older Adults Using the Long-term Care Insurance System of Japan: A Cross-sectional Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>170</StartPage><EndPage>175</EndPage><MedlinePgn>170-175</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1298/ptr.E10089</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To reveal self-rated changes of health status during stay-at-home orders among older adults and to verify whether decrease in frequency of going outdoors during these orders was related to self-rated changes in health status.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">A self-completed questionnaire for older adults was provided in 2 dayservice facilities and a nursing station. We operationally defined health status with 4 domains (motor function, oral and swallowing function, depression, and social networks) and designed the questionnaire to determine self-rated changes in health status using factor analysis. After factor analysis, regression analyses were conducted. Dependent variable was each factor score (self-rated changes of health status), and independent variable was decrease in frequency of going outdoors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Approximately 80% of participants answered that their health status had "worsened" in motor function (75.0%-87.2%). Moreover, more than 70% of participants answered "worsened" in "Feeling energy" and "Getting together and speaking with friends" (72.3% and 75.7%, respectively). Regression analyses demonstrated that, after adjusting for covariates, the decrease in frequency of going outdoors was related to self-rated changes of motor function and friend network.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">During stay-at-home orders, older adults felt deterioration in their motor function, in feeling energy, and in their friend network, especially people who had decreased their frequency of going outdoors felt more deterioration in their motor function and in their friend network.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>2021, JAPANESE PHYSICAL THERAPY ASSOCIATION.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ono</LastName><ForeName>Takazumi</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Tokyo Metropolitan University, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehappy Co., Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kashima</LastName><ForeName>Mieko</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rehappy Co., Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Asakawa</LastName><ForeName>Yasuyoshi</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, Tokyo Metropolitan University, Japan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Japan</Country><MedlineTA>Phys Ther Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101700769</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2189-8448</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frequency of going outdoors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-rated health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stay-at-home orders</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34532213</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8419481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1298/ptr.E10089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Fujita K, Fujiwara Y, <i>et al.</i>: The frequency of going outdoors, and physical, psychological and social functioning among community-dwelling older adults. Nippon Koshu Eisei Zasshi (Japanese journal of Public Health). 2004; 51: 168-180 (in Japanese).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15114840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen-Mansfield J, Shmotkin D, <i>et al.</i>: Homebound older persons: prevalence, characteristics, and longitudinal predictors. Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2012; 54: 55-60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3174334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21420181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimada H, Ishizaki T, <i>et al.</i>: How often and how far do frail elderly people need to go outdoors to maintain functional capacity? Arch Gerontol Geriatr. 2010; 50: 140-146.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19356806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada K, Lee S, <i>et al.</i>: Going outdoors and cognitive function among community-dwelling older adults: Moderating role of physical function. Geriatr Gelontol Int. 2016; 16: 65-73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25597479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen-Mansfield J, Shmotkin D, <i>et al.</i>: The effect of homebound status on older persons. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2010; 2358-2362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21087220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinoshita K, Satake S, <i>et al.</i>: A homebound status is related to a reduction of meal intake in older outpatients, independent depressive mood and their physical function. Nippon Ronen Igakkai Zasshi (Japanese journal of Geriatrics). 2019; 56: 188-197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31092785</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harada K, Masumoto K, <i>et al.</i>: Frequency of going outdoors and health-related qualiry of life among older adults: Examining the moderating role of living alone and employment status. Geriatr Gelontol Int. 2018; 18: 640-647.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29218820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fujita K, Fujiwara Y, <i>et al.</i>: Frequency of Going Outdoors as a Good Predictor for Incident Disability of Physical Function as well as Disability Recovery in Community-Dwelling Older Adults in Rural Japan. J Epidemiol. 2006; 16: 261-270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7683695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17085876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs JM, Cohen A, <i>et al.</i>: Going Outdoors Daily Predicts Long-Term Functional and Health Benefits Among Ambulatory Older People. J Aging Health. 2008; 20: 259-272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18332184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kono A, Kai I, <i>et al.</i>: Frequency of Going Outdoors: A Predictor of Functional and Psychosocial Change Among Ambulatory Frail Elders Living at Home. J Gerontol A Bio Sci Med Sci. 2004; 59: 275-280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15031313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caputo EL and Reichert FF: Studies of Physical Activity and COVID-19 During the Pandemic: A Scoping Review. J Phys Act Health. 2020; 17: 1275-1284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33152693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamada M, Kimura Y, <i>et al.</i>: Effect of the COVID-19 Epidemic on Physical Activity in Community-Dwelling Older Adults in Japan: A Cross-Sectional Online Survey. J Nutr Health Aging. 2020; 24: 948-950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7597428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33155619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stanton R, To QG, <i>et al.</i>: Depression, Anxiety and Stress during COVID-19: Associations with Changes in Physical Activity, Sleep, Tobacco and Alcohol Use in Australian Adults. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020 Jun 7; 17: 4065. 10.3390/ijerph17114065. PMID 32517294; PMCID PMC7312903.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7312903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32517294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieh C, Budimir S, <i>et al.</i>: The effect of age, gender, income, work, and physical activity on mental health during coronavirus disease (COVID-19) lockdown in Austria. J Psychosom Res. 2020 Sep; 136: 110186. 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2020.110186. Epub 2020 Jul 3. Erratum in J Psychosom Res. 2020 Dec;139 110278. PMID 32682159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7832650</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32682159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lima-Costa MF, Cesar CC, <i>et al.</i>: Self-rated Health Compared With Objectively Measured Health Status as a Tool for Mortality Risk Screening in Older Adults: 10-Year Follow-up of the Bambu&#xed; Cohort Study of Aging. Am J Epidemiol. 2012; 175: 228-235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22193172</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsutsui T and Muramatsu N: Care-Needs Certification in the Long-Term Care Insurance System of Japan. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005; 53: 522-527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15743300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohkuma R, Fujishima I, <i>et al.</i>: Development of a questionnaire to screen dysphagia. Nippon Sessyoku Enge Riha Gakkai Zasshi (Japanese journal of Dysphagia Rehabilitation). 2002; 6: 3-8 (in Japanese).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sugishita K, Sugishita M, <i>et al.</i>: A validity and Reliability Study of the Japanese Version of the Geriatric Depression Scale 15 (GDS-15-J). Clin Gerontol. 2017; 40: 233-240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28452641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lubben J, Blozik E, <i>et al.</i>: Performance of an Abbreviated Version of the Lubben Social Network Scale Among Three European Community-Dwelling Older Adult Populations. Gerontologist. 2006; 46: 503-513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16921004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Japanese ministry of health, labor and welfare [Internet]: statistical report of long-term care insurance system in May 2020. [cited 2020 Sep. 1]; Available from: https://www.mhlw.go.jp/topics/kaigo/osirase/jigyo/m20/2005.html.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>