<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35295621</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2673-253X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Acceptance of E-Mental Health Services for Different Application Purposes Among Psychotherapists in Clinical Training in Germany and Switzerland: Secondary Analysis of a Cross-Sectional Survey.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>840869</StartPage><MedlinePgn>840869</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">840869</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fdgth.2022.840869</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Despite solid evidence supporting the efficacy of electronic mental health (EMH) services, their acceptance among psychotherapists is limited and uptake rates remain low. However, the acceptance of different EMH services has yet barely been examined in future generations of psychotherapists in a differentiated manner. The aims of this study were (1) to elaborate the intention to use various EMH services for different application purposes and (2) to determine predictors of EMH service acceptance among psychotherapists in clinical training (PiT).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our paper is based on a secondary data analysis of a cross-sectional survey. Respondents were recruited via recognized educational institutions for psychotherapy within Germany and the German-speaking part of Switzerland between June and July of 2020. The survey contained items on the intention to use different EMH services (i.e., guided and unguided programs, virtual reality, psychotherapy by telephone and videoconference) for various application purposes (i.e., prevention, treatment addition, treatment substitute, aftercare). Potential predictors of EMH service acceptance (e.g., barriers and advantages) were examined based on an extension of the Unified Theory of Acceptance and Use of Technology (UTAUT).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Most of the <i>n</i> = 216 respondents were female (88.4%) and located in Germany (72.2%). General acceptance of EMH was moderate (<i>M</i> = 3.4, <i>SD</i> = 1.12, range 1-5), while acceptance of psychotherapy via videoconference was highest (<i>M</i> = 3.7, <i>SD</i> = 1.15) and acceptance of unguided programs was lowest (<i>M</i> = 2.55, <i>SD</i> = 1.14). There was an interaction effect of EMH service and application purpose (&#x3b7;<sup>2</sup> = 0.21). Barriers and advantages both had a uniform influence on EMH service acceptance (Pr &gt; 0.999), while impersonality, legal concerns, concerns about therapeutic alliance, simplified information provision, simplified contact maintenance, time flexibility, and geographic flexibility were significant predictors (all <i>p</i> &lt; 0.05). Results showed that the extended UTAUT model was the best fitting model to predict EMH service acceptance (Pr &gt; 0.999).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The intention to use different EMH services varied between application purposes among PiT. To increase acceptance of EMH services and reduce misconceptions, we identified predictors that should be addressed in future acceptance-facilitating interventions when educating PiT.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 Braun, Dr&#xfc;ge, Hennemann, Nitsch, Staeck and Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braun</LastName><ForeName>Pia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Institute for Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dr&#xfc;ge</LastName><ForeName>Marie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology/Psychotherapy Research, Institute of Psychology, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hennemann</LastName><ForeName>Severin</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Psychotherapy and Experimental Psychopathology, Institute of Psychology, University of Mainz, Mainz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nitsch</LastName><ForeName>Felix Jan</ForeName><Initials>FJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Marketing Area, INSEAD, Fontainebleau, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Paris Brain Institute (ICM), INSERM U 1127, CNRS UMR 7225, Sorbonne Universit&#xe9;, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Staeck</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology/Psychotherapy Research, Institute of Psychology, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Institute for Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101771889</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2673-253X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acceptance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eMental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychotherapists</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">telemedicine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">unified theory of acceptance and use of technology</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>PB received payments from the Heinrich Heine University Dusseldorf for a lecture about electronic mental health services. PB also works for the Rehappy GmbH, which developed a digital health application for the rehabilitation of stroke patients. SH received payments from psychotherapy training institutes in the context of electronic mental health topics. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35295621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8918841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2022.840869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Shah SMA, Mohammad D, Qureshi MFH, Abbas MZ, Aleem S. Prevalence, psychological responses and associated correlates of depression, anxiety and stress in a global population, during the Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) pandemic. Community Ment Health J. (2021) 57:101&#x2013;10. 10.1007/s10597-020-00728-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10597-020-00728-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7590908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33108569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racine N, McArthur BA, Cooke JE, Eirich R, Zhu J, Madigan S. Global prevalence of depressive and anxiety symptoms in children and adolescents during COVID-19: a meta-analysis. JAMA Pediatr. (2021) 175:1142&#x2013;50. 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2021.2482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2021.2482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8353576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34369987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bareeqa SB, Ahmed SI, Samar SS, Yasin W, Zehra S, Monese GM, et al. Prevalence of depression, anxiety and stress in china during COVID-19 pandemic: A systematic review with meta-analysis. Int J Psychiatry Med. (2021) 56:210&#x2013;27. 10.1177/0091217420978005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0091217420978005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bueno-Notivol J, Gracia-Garc&#xed;a P, Olaya B, Lasheras I, L&#xf3;pez-Ant&#xf3;n R, Santab&#xe1;rbara J. Prevalence of depression during the COVID-19 outbreak: A meta-analysis of community-based studies. Int J Clin Health Psychol. (2021) 21:100196. 10.1016/j.ijchp.2020.07.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijchp.2020.07.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7458054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32904715</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dar KA, Iqbal N, Mushtaq A. Intolerance of uncertainty, depression, and anxiety: Examining the indirect and moderating effects of worry. Asian J Psychiatr. (2017) 29:129&#x2013;33. 10.1016/j.ajp.2017.04.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajp.2017.04.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29061409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holt-Lunstad J, Smith TB, Baker M, Harris T, Stephenson D. Loneliness and social isolation as risk factors for mortality: a meta-analytic review. Perspect Psychol Sci. (2015) 10:227&#x2013;37. 10.1177/1745691614568352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1745691614568352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25910392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakpour A, Griffiths MD. The fear of COVID-19 and its role in preventive behaviors. J Concurr Dis. (2020) 2:58&#x2013;63. 10.54127/WCIC8036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.54127/WCIC8036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . Factsheet May 2020: Vulnerable populations during COVID-19 response. (2020). Available online at: https://www.euro.who.int/__data/assets/pdf_file/0003/446340/Factsheet-May-2020-Vulnerable-populations-during-COVID-19-response-eng.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippi P, Baumeister H, Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Ebert DD, Hennemann S, Kott L, et al. Acceptance towards digital health interventions - model validation and further development of the Unified Theory Of Acceptance And Use Of Technology. Internet Interv. (2021) 26:100459. 10.1016/j.invent.2021.100459</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2021.100459</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8463857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34603973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G. Internet interventions: past, present and future. Internet Interv. (2018) 12:181&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.invent.2018.03.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2018.03.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Cuijpers P, Mu&#xf1;oz RF, Baumeister H. Prevention of mental health disorders using internet- and mobile-based interventions: a narrative review and recommendations for future research. Front Psychiatry. (2017) 8:116. 10.3389/fpsyt.2017.00116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2017.00116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5554359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J, Ebert DD, Lehr D, Berking M, Baumeister H. Internetbasierte kognitiv-behaviorale Behandlungs-ans&#xe4;tze: State of the Art und Einsatzm&#xf6;glichkeiten in der Rehabilitation. Rehabilitation (Stuttg). [2013] 52:155&#x2013;63. 10.1055/s-0033-1343491</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0033-1343491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23761204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#x103;s&#x103;relu CR, Andersson G, Bergman Nordgren L, Dobrean A. Internet-delivered transdiagnostic and tailored cognitive behavioral therapy for anxiety and depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Cogn Behav Ther. (2017) 46:1&#x2013;28. 10.1080/16506073.2016.1231219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2016.1231219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27712544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simblett S, Birch J, Matcham F, Yaguez L, Morris R. A systematic review and meta-analysis of e-mental health interventions to treat symptoms of posttraumatic stress. JMIR Ment Health. (2017) 4:e14. 10.2196/mental.5558</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mental.5558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5451639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28526672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayo-Wilson E, Montgomery P. Media-delivered cognitive behavioural therapy and behavioural therapy (self-help) for anxiety disorders in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. (2013) (9):CD005330. 10.1002/14651858.CD005330.pub4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD005330.pub4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11694413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24018460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moshe I, Terhorst Y, Philippi P, Domhardt M, Cuijpers P, Cristea I, et al. Digital interventions for the treatment of depression: a meta-analytic review. Psychological Bulletin. (2021). Available online at: 10.1037/bul0000334</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/bul0000334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34898233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews G, Bell C, Boyce P, Gale C, Lampe L, Marwat O, et al. Royal Australian and New Zealand College of Psychiatrists clinical practice guidelines for the treatment of panic disorder, social anxiety disorder and generalised anxiety disorder. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. (2018) 52:1109&#x2013;72. 10.1177/0004867418799453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0004867418799453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Titov N. Advantages and limitations of Internet-based interventions for common mental disorders. World Psychiatry. (2014) 13:4&#x2013;11. 10.1002/wps.20083</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3918007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24497236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, van Daele T, Nordgreen T, Karekla M, Compare A, Brugnera A, et al. Internet- and mobile-based psychological interventions: applications, efficacy, and potential for improving mental health. Eur Psychol. (2018) 23:167&#x2013;87. 10.1027/1016-9040/a000318</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1027/1016-9040/a000318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feijt MA, Kort YA de, Bongers IM, IJsselsteijn WA. Perceived drivers and barriers to the adoption of eMental health by psychologists: the construction of the levels of adoption of eMental health model. J Med Internet Res. (2018) 20:e153. 10.2196/jmir.9485</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.9485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29691215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlhausen F, Zinner M, Bieske L, Ehlers JP, Boehme P, Fehring L. Physicians' attitudes toward prescribable mhealth apps and implications for adoption in germany: mixed methods study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. (2021) 9:e33012. 10.2196/33012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/33012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34817385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carlbring P, Andersson G, Cuijpers P, Riper H, Hedman-Lagerl&#xf6;f E. Internet-based vs. face-to-face cognitive behavior therapy for psychiatric and somatic disorders: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis. Cogn Behav Ther. (2018) 47:1&#x2013;18. 10.1080/16506073.2017.1401115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2017.1401115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29215315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E, Riper H, Twisk J, Hoogendoorn A, Kleiboer A, Mira A, et al. Efficacy of self-guided internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy in the treatment of depressive symptoms: a meta-analysis of individual participant data. JAMA Psychiatry. (2017) 74:351&#x2013;9. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0044</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28241179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips EA, Gordeev VS, Schrey&#xf6;gg J. Effectiveness of occupational e-mental health interventions: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Scand J Work Environ Health. (2019) 45:560&#x2013;76. 10.5271/sjweh.3839</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5271/sjweh.3839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31184758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Harrer M, K&#xe4;hlke F, Fritsche L, Salewski C, Ebert DD. Public attitudes toward guided internet-based therapies: web-based survey study. JMIR Ment Health. [2018] 5:e10735. 10.2196/10735</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5974457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dockweiler C, Kupitz A, Hornberg C. Akzeptanz onlinebasierter Therapieangebote bei Patientinnen und Patienten mit leichten bis mittelgradigen depressiven St&#xf6;rungen. Gesundheitswesen. (2018) 80:1013&#x2013;22. 10.1055/s-0043-119287</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-119287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29126341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebel W, Lukies R, Kerst A, Stricker J, Zielasek J, Diekmann S, et al. Upscaling e-mental health in Europe: a six-country qualitative analysis and policy recommendations from the eMEN project. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. (2021) 271:1005&#x2013;16. 10.1007/s00406-020-01133-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-020-01133-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32393997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Venkatesh V, Morris MG, Davis GB. User acceptance of information technology: toward a unified view. MIS Quarterly. (2003) 27:425. 10.2307/30036540</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/30036540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Seifferth H, Lin J, Nowoczin L, L&#xfc;king M, Ebert DD. Impact of an acceptance facilitating intervention on patients' acceptance of internet-based pain interventions: a randomized controlled trial. Clin J Pain. (2015) 31:528&#x2013;35. 10.1097/AJP.0000000000000118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AJP.0000000000000118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24866854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Berking M, Cuijpers P, Lehr D, P&#xf6;rtner M, Baumeister H. Increasing the acceptance of internet-based mental health interventions in primary care patients with depressive symptoms. A randomized controlled trial. J Affect Disord. (2015) 176:9&#x2013;17. 10.1016/j.jad.2015.01.056</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2015.01.056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25682378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Hennemann S, Fritsche L, Dr&#xfc;ge M, Breil B. Determinant factors of public acceptance of stress management apps: survey study. JMIR Ment Health. (2019) 6:e15373. 10.2196/15373</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/15373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6873149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31697243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Terhorst Y, Gr&#xe4;ssle C, Freudenstein M, N&#xfc;bling R, Ebert DD. Impact of an acceptance facilitating intervention on psychotherapists' acceptance of blended therapy. PLoS ONE. (2020) 15:e0236995. 10.1371/journal.pone.0236995</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0236995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7423074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32785245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennemann S, Beutel ME, Zwerenz R. Ready for eHealth? Health professionals' acceptance and adoption of ehealth interventions in inpatient routine care. J Health Commun. (2017) 22:274&#x2013;84. 10.1080/10810730.2017.1284286</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10810730.2017.1284286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28248626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blut M, Chong AYL, Tsiga Z, Venkatesh V. Meta-analysis of the Unified Theory Of Acceptance And Use of Technology (UTAUT): challenging its validity and charting a research agenda in the red ocean. J Associat Inf Syst. (2021) 1&#x2013;128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donovan CL, Poole C, Boyes N, Redgate J, March S. Australian mental health worker attitudes towards cCBT: What is the role of knowledge? Are there differences? Can we change them? Internet Interv. (2015) 2:372&#x2013;81. 10.1016/j.invent.2015.09.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2015.09.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norman CD, Skinner HA. eHealth Literacy: essential skills for consumer health in a networked world. J Med Internet Res. (2006) 8:e9. 10.2196/jmir.8.2.e9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.8.2.e9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1550701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16867972</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer G, Gronewold N, Alvarez S, Bruns B, Hilbel T, Schultz J-H. Acceptance and expectations of medical experts, students, and patients toward electronic mental health apps: cross-sectional quantitative and qualitative survey study. JMIR Ment Health. (2019) 6:e14018. 10.2196/14018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31763990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerlinger G, Mangiapane N, Sander J. Digitale Gesundheitsanwendungen (DiGA) in der &#xe4;rztlichen und psychotherapeutischen Versorgung. Chancen und Herausforderungen aus Sicht der Leistungserbringer Bundesgesundheitsblatt Gesundheitsforschung Gesundheitsschutz. [2021] 64:1213&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s00103-021-03408-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00103-021-03408-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34550412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennemann S, Beutel ME, Zwerenz R. Morbus Google&#x201c;vs. e-Health: Qualitative Untersuchung zur Akzeptanz und Implementierung von Online-Nachsorge in der station&#xe4;ren Rehabilitation. Rehabilitation (Stuttg). (2018) 57:14&#x2013;23. 10.1055/s-0043-102150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0043-102150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28591900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Meyer B, Lutz W, Hautzinger M, Sp&#xe4;th C, et al. Attitudes towards internet interventions among psychotherapists and individuals with mild to moderate depression symptoms. Cogn Ther Res. (2017) 41:745&#x2013;56. 10.1007/s10608-017-9850-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10608-017-9850-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiweis B, Pobiruchin M, Strotbaum V, Suleder J, Wiesner M, Bergh B. Barriers and facilitators to the implementation of ehealth services: systematic literature analysis. J Med Internet Res. (2019) 21:e14197. 10.2196/14197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6898891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31755869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titzler I, Saruhanjan K, Berking M, Riper H, Ebert DD. Barriers and facilitators for the implementation of blended psychotherapy for depression: A qualitative pilot study of therapists' perspective. Internet Interv. (2018) 12:150&#x2013;64. 10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Witte NAJ, Carlbring P, Etzelmueller A, Nordgreen T, Karekla M, Haddouk L, et al. Online consultations in mental healthcare during the COVID-19 outbreak: An international survey study on professionals' motivations and perceived barriers. Internet Interv. (2021) 25:100405. 10.1016/j.invent.2021.100405</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2021.100405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8350604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34401365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichenberg C, Ott R. Klinisch-psychologische intervention im Internet. Psychotherapeut. (2012) 57:58&#x2013;69. 10.1007/s00278-011-0832-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00278-011-0832-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Fritsche L, Bierhals C, Salewski C. Improving attitudes toward e-mental health services in the general population <i>via</i> psychoeducational information material: A randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. (2018) 12:141&#x2013;9. 10.1016/j.invent.2017.12.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2017.12.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musiat P, Tarrier N. Collateral outcomes in e-mental health: a systematic review of the evidence for added benefits of computerized cognitive behavior therapy interventions for mental health. Psychol Med. (2014) 44:3137&#x2013;50. 10.1017/S0033291714000245</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291714000245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25065947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riper H, Andersson G, Christensen H, Cuijpers P, Lange A, Eysenbach G. Theme issue on e-mental health: a growing field in internet research. J Med Internet Res. (2010) 12:e74. 10.2196/jmir.1713</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3057318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21169177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xe4;mer R, K&#xf6;hler S. Evaluation of the online-based self-help programme &#x201c;Selfapy&#x201d; in patients with unipolar depression: study protocol for a randomized, blinded parallel group dismantling study. Trials. (2021) 22:264. 10.1186/s13063-021-05218-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-021-05218-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8034195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Urech A, Krieger T, Stolz T, Schulz A, Vincent A, et al. Effects of a transdiagnostic unguided Internet intervention ('velibra') for anxiety disorders in primary care: results of a randomized controlled trial. Psychol Med. (2017) 47:67&#x2013;80. 10.1017/S0033291716002270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291716002270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27655039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Krieger T, Sude K, Meyer B, Maercker A. Evaluating an e-mental health program (&#x201c;deprexis&#x201d;) as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: Results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J Affect Disord. (2018) 227:455&#x2013;62. 10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundesinstitut, f&#xfc;r Arzneimittel und Medizinprodukte. 1. Bekanntmachung zu den digitalen Gesundheitsanwendungen (DiGA) vom 06.10.2020 . Available online at: URL: https://diga.bfarm.de/thc-bfarm/assets/documents/201006_BfArM_Bekanntmachung-DiGA-1.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Carlbring P, Holmstr&#xf6;m A, Sparthan E, Furmark T, Nilsson-Ihrfelt E, et al. Internet-based self-help with therapist feedback and in vivo group exposure for social phobia: a randomized controlled trial. J Consult Clin Psychol. [2006] 74:677&#x2013;86. 10.1037/0022-006X.74.4.677</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-006X.74.4.677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16881775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olthuis JV, Watt MC, Bailey K, Hayden JA, Stewart SH. Therapist-supported Internet cognitive behavioural therapy for anxiety disorders in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. (2016) 3:CD011565. 10.1002/14651858.CD011565.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011565.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7077612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26968204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guille C, Zhao Z, Krystal J, Nichols B, Brady K, Sen S. Web-based cognitive behavioral therapy intervention for the prevention of suicidal ideation in medical interns: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry. (2015) 72:1192&#x2013;8. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.1880</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.1880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4866804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26535958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyffert M, Lagisetty P, Landgraf J, Chopra V, Pfeiffer PN, Conte ML, et al. Internet-delivered cognitive behavioral therapy to treat insomnia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS ONE. (2016) 11:e0149139. 10.1371/journal.pone.0149139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0149139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4750912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26867139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter L, Silberzahn T. editors. eHealth Monitor 2021: Deutschlands Weg in die digitale Gesundheitsversorgung - Status quo und Perspektiven. Medizinisch Wissenschaftliche Verlagsgesellschaft. (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pfeiffer V, Sojer R. Digital trends survey 2021. Schweiz &#xc4;rzteztg. (2021). 10.4414/saez.2021.20144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4414/saez.2021.20144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weightman M. Digital psychotherapy as an effective and timely treatment option for depression and anxiety disorders: Implications for rural and remote practice. J Int Med Res. (2020) 48:300060520928686. 10.1177/0300060520928686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0300060520928686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7294488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32527170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiauzzi E, Clayton A, Huh-Yoo J. Videoconferencing-based telemental health: important questions for the COVID-19 era from clinical and patient-centered perspectives. JMIR Ment Health. (2020) 7:e24021. 10.2196/24021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/24021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7725495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33180739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humer E, Pieh C, Kuska M, Barke A, Doering BK, Gossmann K, et al. Provision of Psychotherapy during the COVID-19 Pandemic among Czech, German and Slovak Psychotherapists. Int J Environ Res Public Health. (2020) 17. 10.3390/ijerph17134811</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17134811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7370023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32635422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humer E, Stippl P, Pieh C, Pryss R, Probst T. Experiences of psychotherapists with remote psychotherapy during the COVID-19 pandemic: cross-sectional web-based survey study. J Med Internet Res. (2020) 22:e20246. 10.2196/20246</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/20246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7704121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman D, Reeve S, Robinson A, Ehlers A, Clark D, Spanlang B, et al. Virtual reality in the assessment, understanding, and treatment of mental health disorders. Psychol Med. (2017) 47:2393&#x2013;400. 10.1017/S003329171700040X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S003329171700040X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5964457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28325167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rizzo A', Shilling R. Clinical Virtual Reality tools to advance the prevention, assessment, and treatment of PTSD. Eur J Psychotraumatol. (2017) 8:1414560. 10.1080/20008198.2017.1414560</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/20008198.2017.1414560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5774399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valmaggia LR, Latif L, Kempton MJ, Rus-Calafell M. Virtual reality in the psychological treatment for mental health problems: An systematic review of recent evidence. Psychiatry Res. (2016) 236:189&#x2013;95. 10.1016/j.psychres.2016.01.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2016.01.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26795129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson PL, Price M, Edwards SM, Obasaju MA, Schmertz SK, Zimand E, et al. Virtual reality exposure therapy for social anxiety disorder: a randomized controlled trial. J Consult Clin Psychol. (2013) 81:751&#x2013;60. 10.1037/a0033559</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0033559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23796315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pelissolo A, Zaoui M, Aguayo G, Yao SN, Roche S, Ecochard R, et al. Virtual reality exposure therapy versus cognitive behavior therapy for panic disorder with agoraphobia: A randomized comparison study. J Cybertherapy Rehabilitat. (2012) 5:35&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Difede J, Cukor J, Wyka K, Olden M, Hoffman H, Lee FS, et al. D-cycloserine augmentation of exposure therapy for post-traumatic stress disorder: a pilot randomized clinical trial. Neuropsychopharmacology. (2014) 39:1052&#x2013;8. 10.1038/npp.2013.317</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/npp.2013.317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3957110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24217129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moessner M, Bauer S. E-Mental-Health und internetbasierte Psychotherapie. Psychotherapeut. (2017) 62:251&#x2013;66. 10.1007/s00278-017-0198-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00278-017-0198-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elfeddali I, Bolman C, Vries H de. Situational and affective risk situations of relapse and the quality of implementation intentions in an e-health smoking relapse prevention programme. Subst Use Misuse. (2013) 48:635&#x2013;44. 10.3109/10826084.2013.800113</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10826084.2013.800113</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23750773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennemann S, Beutel ME, Zwerenz R. Drivers and barriers to acceptance of web-based aftercare of patients in inpatient routine care: a cross-sectional survey. J Med Internet Res. (2016) 18:e337. 10.2196/jmir.6003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5219589</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28011445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendelin N, Hesser H, Dahl J, Carlbring P, Nelson KZ, Andersson G. Experiences of guided Internet-based cognitive-behavioural treatment for depression: a qualitative study. BMC Psychiatry. (2011) 11:107. 10.1186/1471-244X-11-107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-11-107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3142491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21718523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas Berger. Internetbasierte Interventionen bei psychischen St&#xf6;rungen. In: Kurt Hahlweg, Martin Hautzinger, J&#xfc;rgen Margraf, Winfried Rief. editor. Fortschritte der Psychotherapie. Hogrefe Verlag: G&#xf6;ttingen. (2015).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wells M, Mitchell KJ, Finkelhor D, Becker-Blease KA. Online mental health treatment: concerns and considerations. Cyberpsychol Behav. (2007) 10:453&#x2013;9. 10.1089/cpb.2006.9933</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cpb.2006.9933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17594270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Finch WH, Bolin JE, Kelley K. Multilevel modeling using R. Boca Raton: Taylor &amp; Francis Group. (2019). 10.1201/9781351062268</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1201/9781351062268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagenmakers E-J, Farrell S. AIC model selection using Akaike weights. Psychon Bull Rev. (2004) 11:192&#x2013;6. 10.3758/BF03206482</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BF03206482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15117008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann L, D&#xf6;nisch A. Apps auf Rezept kosten Kassen zweistelligen Millionenbetrag: Seit zw&#xf6;lf Monaten k&#xf6;nnen &#xc4;rzte Apps auf Rezept verschreiben. Eine Umfrage von Handelsblatt Inside zeigt, dass rund 45.000 Apps verschrieben wurden. (2021). Available online at: https://www.handelsblatt.com/inside/digital_health/jahresbilanz-apps-auf-rezept-kosten-kassen-zweistelligen-millionenbetrag/27684116.html?ticket=ST-723945-hFzRrXFMoMBPJvqErmwL-ap3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xe1;fr&#xe1;di L, Nakamoto K, Csabai M, Papp-Zipernovszky O, Schulz PJ. An empirical test of the Health Empowerment Model: Does patient empowerment moderate the effect of health literacy on health status? Patient Educ Couns. (2018) 101:511&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.pec.2017.09.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pec.2017.09.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28899712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kobelt A, Nickel L, Grosch EV, Lamprecht F, K&#xfc;nsebeck H-W. Inanspruchnahme psychosomatischer Nachsorge nach station&#xe4;rer Rehabilitation. Psychother Psychosom Med Psychol. (2004) 54:58&#x2013;64. 10.1055/s-2003-812612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2003-812612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14872392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;pke K-H. Aufwerten, ausbauen und systematisieren &#x2013; Eine Analyse von Situation, Reformbedarf und innovativen Projekten zur Nachsorge in der Rehabilitation der Rentenversicherung. Rehabilitation (Stuttg). (2005) 44:344&#x2013;52. 10.1055/s-2005-915247</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2005-915247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16320178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibold M, Mittag O, Kulick B, M&#xfc;ller E, Opitz U, J&#xe4;ckel WH. Pr&#xe4;diktoren der Teilnahme an einer Nachsorge nach ambulanter Rehabilitation bei erwerbst&#xe4;tigen Rehabilitanden mit chronischen R&#xfc;ckenschmerzen1. Rehabilitation (Stuttg). (2011) 50:363&#x2013;71. 10.1055/s-0031-1271815</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0031-1271815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21647850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryhill MB, Halli-Tierney A, Culmer N, Williams N, Betancourt A, King M, et al. Videoconferencing psychological therapy and anxiety: a systematic review. Fam Pract. (2019) 36:53&#x2013;63. 10.1093/fampra/cmy072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/fampra/cmy072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30188992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drago A, Winding TN, Antypa N. Videoconferencing in psychiatry, a meta-analysis of assessment and treatment. Eur Psychiatry. (2016) 36:29&#x2013;37. 10.1016/j.eurpsy.2016.03.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eurpsy.2016.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27311105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips EA, Himmler SF, Schrey&#xf6;gg J. Preferences for e-Mental health interventions in germany: a discrete choice experiment. Value Health. (2021) 24:421&#x2013;30. 10.1016/j.jval.2020.09.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2020.09.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33641777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster R, Pokorny R, Berger T, Topooco N, Laireiter A-R. The advantages and disadvantages of online and blended therapy: survey study amongst licensed psychotherapists in Austria. J Med Internet Res. (2018) 20:e11007. 10.2196/11007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smoktunowicz E, Barak A, Andersson G, Banos RM, Berger T, Botella C, et al. Consensus statement on the problem of terminology in psychological interventions using the internet or digital components. Internet Interv. (2020) 21:100331. 10.1016/j.invent.2020.100331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2020.100331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32577404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sander J, Bolinski F, Diekmann S, Gaebel W, G&#xfc;nther K, Hauth I, et al. Online therapy: an added value for inpatient routine care? Perspectives from mental health care professionals. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. (2021). 10.1007/s00406-021-01251-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-021-01251-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7961170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33725165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ammenwerth E. Technology Acceptance Models in Health Informatics: TAM and UTAUT. Stud Health Technol Inform. (2019) 263:64&#x2212;71. 10.3233/SHTI190111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/SHTI190111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31411153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perle JG, Langsam LC, Randel A, Lutchman S, Levine AB, Odland AP, et al. Attitudes toward psychological telehealth: current and future clinical psychologists' opinions of internet-based interventions. J Clin Psychol. (2013) 69:100&#x2013;13. 10.1002/jclp.21912</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.21912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22975897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abd-Alrazaq A, Hassan A, Abuelezz I, Ahmed A, Alzubaidi MS, Shah U, et al. Overview of technologies implemented during the first wave of the covid-19 pandemic: scoping review. J Med Internet Res. (2021) 23:e29136. 10.2196/29136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/29136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34406962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sorkin DH, Janio EA, Eikey EV, Schneider M, Davis K, Schueller SM, et al. Rise in use of digital mental health tools and technologies in the United States during the COVID-19 pandemic: survey study. J Med Internet Res. (2021) 23:e26994. 10.2196/26994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/26994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8054774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33822737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheeran P, Webb TL. The Intention-Behavior Gap. Soc Personal Psychol Compass. (2016) 10:503&#x2013;18. 10.1111/spc3.12265</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/spc3.12265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumel A, Muench F, Edan S, Kane JM. Objective user engagement with mental health apps: systematic search and panel-based usage analysis. J Med Internet Res. (2019) 21:e14567. 10.2196/14567</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6785720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31573916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin J, Faust B, Ebert DD, Kr&#xe4;mer L, Baumeister H. A web-based acceptance-facilitating intervention for identifying patients' acceptance, uptake, and adherence of internet- and mobile-based pain interventions: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. (2018) 20:e244. 10.2196/jmir.9925</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.9925</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6123541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30131313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein B, Cook S. Preferences for e-mental health services amongst an online Australian sample? EJAP. (2010) 6. 10.7790/ejap.v6i1.184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7790/ejap.v6i1.184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuso S, Nitsch M, Zeiler M, Simek M, Adamcik T, Dey M, et al. Stakeholders' views on online interventions to prevent common mental health disorders in adults implemented into existing healthcare systems in Europe. Eur J Public Health. (2021) 31:i55&#x2013;i63. 10.1093/eurpub/ckab043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurpub/ckab043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8495679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34240157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Daele T, Karekla M, Kassianos AP, Compare A, Haddouk L, Salgado J1, et al. Recommendations for policy and practice of telepsychotherapy and e-mental health in Europe and beyond. J Psychother Integr. (2020) 30:160&#x2013;73. 10.1037/int0000218</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/int0000218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dockweiler C, Kupitz A, Palmdorf S, Hornberg C. Onlinetherapie bei depressiven St&#xf6;rungen: Eine Akzeptanzanalyse aus der Perspektive der Behandelnden. Nervenarzt. (2020) 91:243&#x2013;51. 10.1007/s00115-019-0730-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00115-019-0730-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31165209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radi&#x107; M, Donner I, Waack M, Brinkmann C, Stein L, Radi&#x107; D. Digitale Gesundheitsanwendungen: Die Akzeptanz steigern. (2021). Available online at: https://www.aerzteblatt.de/archiv/217790/Digitale-Gesundheitsanwendungen-Die-Akzeptanz-steigern</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soucy JN, Owens VAM, Hadjistavropoulos HD, Dirkse DA, Dear BF. Educating patients about Internet-delivered cognitive behaviour therapy: Perceptions among treatment seekers and non-treatment seekers before and after viewing an educational video. Internet Interv. (2016) 6:57&#x2013;63. 10.1016/j.invent.2016.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2016.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigerland S, Lj&#xf3;tsson B, Bergdahl Gustafsson F, Hagert S, Thulin U, Andersson G, et al. Attitudes towards the use of computerized cognitive behavior therapy (cCBT) with children and adolescents: A survey among Swedish mental health professionals. Internet Interv. (2014) 1:111&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.invent.2014.06.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2014.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wangberg SC, Gammon D, Spitznogle K. In the eyes of the beholder: exploring psychologists' attitudes towards and use of e-therapy in Norway. Cyberpsychol Behav. (2007) 10:418&#x2013;23. 10.1089/cpb.2006.9937</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cpb.2006.9937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17594266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>