<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37256006</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2055-2076</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating information needs and preferences regarding digital mental health services among medical and psychology students in Germany: A qualitative study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>20552076231173568</StartPage><MedlinePgn>20552076231173568</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">20552076231173568</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/20552076231173568</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Since 2020, physicians and psychotherapists in Germany can prescribe digital mental health services (dMHSs). However, even future healthcare professionals (HCPs), such as medical and psychology students, remain reluctant to use dMHSs, although they are a risk group for mental health issues themselves. Reasons include scepticism and lacking awareness of dMHSs, which can be addressed by acceptance-facilitating interventions (AFIs) such as information strategies. To date, though, little is known about their information needs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Semi-structured interviews with <i>n</i> = 21 students were conducted between August and September 2021. Students of legal age studying psychology or medicine at a German university could participate. Interview recordings were transcribed verbatim and content-analyzed according to Mayring, using deductive and inductive coding.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Most students reported having little experience with dMHSs. Digital health has barely been raised in their study, even though it was perceived as crucial for personal needs as well as in preparation for their work as HCPs. Students favoured receiving information on and recommendations for dMHSs from their university via, e.g. social media or seminars. Among others, information about data safety, scientific evidence base and application scope were preferred. Additionally, information on costs as well as user reviews seemed to be essential components of information strategies because students were concerned that high costs or low usability would hinder uptake.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The results give first insights on how future HCPs would like to be informed on dMHSs. Future research should focus on systematic variations of AFIs' components mimicking real-world decision scenarios to increase the adoption of dMHSs.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Braun</LastName><ForeName>Pia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2179-4842</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, Dusseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">9170</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schwientek</LastName><ForeName>Ann-Kathrin</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, Dusseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">9170</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University Hospital rechts der Isar, School of Medicine, Technical University of Munich, Munchen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Angerer</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, Dusseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">9170</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guthardt</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, Dusseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">9170</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Icks</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for Health Services Research and Health Economics, Centre for Health and Society, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, Dusseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">9170</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Loerbroks</LastName><ForeName>Adrian</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, Dusseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">9170</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5755-9225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Medical Faculty, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, Dusseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">9170</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101690863</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2055-2076</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health literacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychology students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">technology acceptance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: During data collection and analysis, PB has worked for the Rehappy GmbH, which developed a medical app for the rehabilitation of stroke patients. All other authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37256006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10226173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20552076231173568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_20552076231173568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thom J, Bretschneider J, Kraus N, et al. Versorgungsepidemiologie psychischer St&#xf6;rungen Warum sinken die Pr&#xe4;valenzen trotz vermehrter Versorgungsangebote nicht ab? Bundesgesundheitsblatt Gesundheitsforschung Gesundheitsschutz 2019; 62: 128&#x2013;139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DGPPN. Basisdaten Psychische Erkrankungen, Januar 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari AJ, et al. Global, regional, and national burden of 12 mental disorders in 204 countries and territories, 1990&#x2013;2019: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2019. The Lancet Psychiatry 2022; 9: 137&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8776563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35026139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah SMA, Mohammad D, Qureshi MFH, et al. Prevalence, psychological responses and associated correlates of depression, anxiety and stress in a global population, during the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic. Community Ment Health J 2021; 57: 101&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7590908</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33108569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Racine N, McArthur BA, Cooke JE, et al. Global prevalence of depressive and anxiety symptoms in children and adolescents during COVID-19: a meta-analysis. JAMA Pediatr 2021; 175: 1142&#x2013;1150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8353576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34369987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Cuijpers P, Mu&#xf1;oz RF, et al. Prevention of mental health disorders using internet- and Mobile-based interventions: a narrative review and recommendations for future research. Front Psychiatry 2017; 8: 116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5554359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torous J, J&#xe4;n Myrick K, Rauseo-Ricupero N, et al. Digital mental health and COVID-19: using technology today to accelerate the curve on access and quality tomorrow. JMIR Ment Health 2020; 7: e18848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7101061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32213476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerlinger G, Mangiapane N, Sander J. Digitale Gesundheitsanwendungen (DiGA) in der &#xe4;rztlichen und psychotherapeutischen Versorgung. Chancen und Herausforderungen aus Sicht der Leistungserbringer. Bundesgesundheitsblatt Gesundheitsforschung Gesundheitsschutz 2021; 64: 1213&#x2013;1219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34550412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saleem M, K&#xfc;hne L, de Santis KK, et al. Understanding engagement strategies in digital interventions for mental health promotion: scoping review. JMIR Ment Health 2021; 8: e30000.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8726056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34931995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>D&#xfc;lsen P, Bendig E, K&#xfc;chler A-M, et al. Digital interventions in adult mental healthcare settings: recent evidence and future directions. Curr Opin Psychiatry 2020; 33: 422&#x2013;431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32427592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippe TJ, Sikder N, Jackson A, et al. Digital health interventions for delivery of mental health care: systematic and comprehensive meta-review. JMIR Ment Health 2022; 9: e35159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9109782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35551058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riper H, Andersson G, Christensen H, et al. Theme issue on e-mental health: a growing field in internet research. J Med Internet Res 2010; 12: e74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3057318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21169177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Titov N. Advantages and limitations of internet-based interventions for common mental disorders. World Psychiatry 2014; 13: 4&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3918007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24497236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen H, Hickie IB. Using e-health applications to deliver new mental health services. Med J Aust 2010; 192: S53&#x2013;S56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20528711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoemaker EZ, Hilty DM. e-Mental health improves access to care, facilitates early intervention, and provides evidence-based treatments at a distance. In: Mucic D, Hilty DM. (eds) e-Mental health. Cham: Springer International Publishing, 2016, pp.43&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, van Daele T, Nordgreen T, et al. Internet- and mobile-based psychological interventions: applications, efficacy, and potential for improving mental health. Eur Psychol 2018; 23: 167&#x2013;187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun P, Dr&#xfc;ge M, Hennemann S, et al. Acceptance of E-mental health services for different application purposes among psychotherapists in clinical training in Germany and Switzerland: secondary analysis of a cross-sectional survey. Front Digit Health 2022; 4: 840869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8918841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35295621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feijt MA, de Kort YA, Bongers IM, et al. Perceived drivers and barriers to the adoption of eMental health by psychologists: the construction of the levels of adoption of eMental health model. J Med Internet Res 2018; 20: e153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5941096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29691215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whaibeh E, Mahmoud H, Naal H. Telemental health in the context of a pandemic: the COVID-19 experience. Curr Treat Options Psychiatry 2020; 7: 198&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7114953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32292687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>German Federal Ministry of
Health. 
<i>Draft bill of the German Federal Ministry of Health on digital
healthcare law (German, Referentenentwurf des Bundesministeriums f&#xfc;r
Gesundheit, Entwurf eines Gesetzes f&#xfc;r eine bessere Versorgung durch
Digitalisierung und Innovation) (Digitale Versorgung-Gesetz &#x2013; DVG):
DVG</i>
, 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>German Federal Institute for Drugs
and Medical Devices. DiGA &#x2013; Digitale
Gesundheitsanwendungen: Rechtliche Grundlagen: Digitale-Versorgung-Gesetz
(DVG) und Digitale Gesundheitsanwendungen-Verordnung (DiGAV),
https://www.bfarm.de/DE/Medizinprodukte/Aufgaben/DiGA/_node.html
(accessed 5 June 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann L, Rybicki B. Gesundheits-Apps werden zum Exportschlager:
Deutschland hat die App auf Rezept, die von der Kasse erstattet wird, vor
&#xfc;ber einem Jahr eingef&#xfc;hrt. Andere L&#xe4;nder wollen die
Innovation nun adaptieren, https://www.handelsblatt.com/inside/digital_health/innovation-gesundheits-apps-werden-zum-exportschlager-/27809340.html
(2021, accessed 5 June
2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harith S, Backhaus I, Mohbin N, et al. Effectiveness of digital mental health interventions for university students: an umbrella review. PeerJ 2022; 10: e13111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8977068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollis C, Falconer CJ, Martin JL, et al. Annual Research Review: digital health interventions for children and young people with mental health problems&#x2014;a systematic and meta-review. J Child Psychol Psychiatry 2017; 58: 474&#x2013;503.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27943285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies EB, Morriss R, Glazebrook C. Computer-delivered and web-based interventions to improve depression, anxiety, and psychological well-being of university students: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Internet Res 2014; 16: e130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4051748</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24836465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattie EG, Adkins EC, Winquist N, et al. Digital mental health interventions for depression, anxiety, and enhancement of psychological well-being among college students. Systematic review. J Med Internet Res 2019; 21: e12869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6681642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31333198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrer M, Adam SH, Baumeister H, et al. Internet interventions for mental health in university students: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Methods Psychiatr Res 2019; 28: e1759.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6877279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30585363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebel W, Gro&#xdf;imlinghaus I, Kerst A, et al. European Psychiatric Association (EPA) guidance on the quality of eMental health interventions in the treatment of psychotic disorders. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 2016; 266: 125&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26874958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xe4;mer R, K&#xf6;hler S. Evaluation of the online-based self-help programme &#x201c;Selfapy&#x201d; in patients with unipolar depression: study protocol for a randomized, blinded parallel group dismantling study. Trials 2021; 22: 264.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8034195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33836810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Urech A, Krieger T, et al. Effects of a transdiagnostic unguided Internet intervention (&#x2018;velibra&#x2019;) for anxiety disorders in primary care: results of a randomized controlled trial. Psychol Med 2017; 47: 67&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27655039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Krieger T, Sude K, et al. Evaluating an e-mental health program (&#x201c;deprexis&#x201d;) as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J Affect Disord 2018; 227: 455&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richter L, Silberzahn T.(eds). eHealth Monitor 2021: Deutschlands Weg in die digitale Gesundheitsversorgung&#x2014;Status quo und Perspektiven. Berlin: Medizinisch Wissenschaftliche Verlagsgesellschaft, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaebel W, Lukies R, Kerst A, et al. Upscaling e-mental health in Europe: a six-country qualitative analysis and policy recommendations from the eMEN project. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 2021; 271: 1005&#x2013;1016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32393997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Mortier P, Kaehlke F, et al. Barriers of mental health treatment utilization among first-year college students: first cross-national results from the WHO World Mental Health International College Student Initiative. Int J Methods Psychiatr Res 2019; 28: e1782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6522323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31069905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahlhausen F, Zinner M, Bieske L, et al. Physicians&#x2019; attitudes toward prescribable mHealth apps and implications for adoption in Germany: mixed methods study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth 2021; 9: e33012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8663495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34817385</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer G, Gronewold N, Alvarez S, et al. Acceptance and expectations of medical experts, students, and patients toward electronic mental health apps: cross-sectional quantitative and qualitative survey study. JMIR Ment Health 2019; 6: e14018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6902133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31763990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiweis B, Pobiruchin M, Strotbaum V, et al. Barriers and facilitators to the implementation of eHealth services: systematic literature analysis. J Med Internet Res 2019; 21: e14197.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6898891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31755869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hennemann S, Beutel ME, Zwerenz R. Ready for eHealth? Health professionals&#x2019; acceptance and adoption of eHealth interventions in inpatient routine care. J Health Commun 2017; 22: 274&#x2013;284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28248626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatdula N, Costa CB, Rasc&#xf3;n MS, et al. College students&#x2019; perceptions of telemental health to address their mental health needs. J Am Coll Health 2022: 1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35271419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dockweiler C, Kupitz A, Palmdorf S, et al. Onlinetherapie bei depressiven st&#xf6;rungen eine akzeptanzanalyse aus der perspektive der behandelnden. Nervenarzt 2020; 91: 243&#x2013;251.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31165209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radi&#x107; M, Donner I, Waack M, et al. Digitale Gesundheitsanwendungen:
Die Akzeptanz steigern, https://www.aerzteblatt.de/archiv/217790/Digitale-Gesundheitsanwendungen-Die-Akzeptanz-steigern
(2021, accessed 13 December
2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leigh S, Ashall-Payne L. The role of health-care providers in mHealth adoption. The Lancet Digital Health 2019; 1: e58&#x2013;e59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33323231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacchi S, Licinio J. Resilience and psychological distress in psychology and medical students. Acad Psychiatry 2017; 41: 185&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27060093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peluso DL, Carleton RN, Asmundson GJG. Depression symptoms in Canadian psychology graduate students: do research productivity, funding, and the academic advisory relationship play a role? Can J Behav Sci/Revue canadienne des sciences du comportement 2011; 43: 119&#x2013;127.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rotenstein LS, Ramos MA, Torre M, et al. Prevalence of depression, depressive symptoms, and suicidal ideation among medical students: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA 2016; 316: 2214&#x2013;2236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5613659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27923088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hankir AK, Northall A, Zaman R. Stigma and mental health challenges in medical students. BMJ Case Rep 2014; 2014: 1&#x2013;5. DOI: 10.1136/bcr-2014-205226</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bcr-2014-205226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4158203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25183806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyrbye LN, Eacker A, Durning SJ, et al. The impact of stigma and personal experiences on the help-seeking behaviors of medical students with burnout. Acad Med 2015; 90: 961&#x2013;969.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25650824</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwenk TL, Davis L, Wimsatt LA. Depression, stigma, and suicidal ideation in medical students. JAMA 2010; 304: 1181&#x2013;1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20841531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woof VG, Hames C, Speer S, et al. A qualitative exploration of the unique barriers, challenges and experiences encountered by undergraduate psychology students with mental health problems. Stud Higher Educ 2021; 46: 750&#x2013;762.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fletcher I, Castle M, Scarpa A, et al. An exploration of medical student attitudes towards disclosure of mental illness. Med Educ Online 2020; 25: 1727713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7034470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32054420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Berking M, Cuijpers P, et al. Increasing the acceptance of internet-based mental health interventions in primary care patients with depressive symptoms. A randomized controlled trial. J Affect Disord 2015; 176: 9&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25682378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Terhorst Y, Grssle C, et al. Impact of an acceptance facilitating intervention on psychotherapists&#x2019; acceptance of blended therapy. PLoS One 2020; 15: e0236995.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7423074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32785245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Harrer M, K&#xe4;hlke F, et al. Public attitudes toward guided internet-based therapies: web-based survey study. JMIR Ment Health 2018; 5: e10735.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5974457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Fritsche L, Bierhals C, et al. Improving attitudes toward e-mental health services in the general population via psychoeducational information material: a randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv 2018; 12: 141&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soucy JN, Owens VAM, Hadjistavropoulos HD, et al. Educating patients about internet-delivered cognitive behaviour therapy: perceptions among treatment seekers and non-treatment seekers before and after viewing an educational video. Internet Interv 2016; 6: 57&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Seifferth H, Lin J, et al. Impact of an acceptance facilitating intervention on Patients&#x2019; acceptance of internet-based pain interventions: a randomized controlled trial. Clin J Pain 2015; 31: 528&#x2013;535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24866854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Nowoczin L, Lin J, et al. Impact of an acceptance facilitating intervention on diabetes patients&#x2019; acceptance of internet-based interventions for depression: a randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2014; 105: 30&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24862240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linardon J, Anderson C, Chapneviss T, et al. Effects of an acceptance-facilitating intervention on acceptance and usage of digital interventions for binge eating. Psychiatr Serv 2022: appips202100616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers EM. Diffusion of preventive innovations. Addict Behav 2002; 27: 989&#x2013;993.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12369480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Franke M, K&#xe4;hlke F, et al. Increasing intentions to use mental health services among university students. Results of a pilot randomized controlled trial within the World Health Organization&#x2019;s world mental health international college student initiative. Int J Methods Psychiatr Res 2019; 28: e1754.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6877244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30456814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hein HJ, Glombiewski JA, Rief W, et al. Effects of a video intervention on physicians&#x2019; acceptance of pain apps: a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open 2022; 12: e060020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9039411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dederichs M, Weber J, Pischke CR, et al. Exploring medical students&#x2019; views on digital mental health interventions: a qualitative study. Internet Interv 2021; 25: 100398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34026567</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips EA, Himmler SF, Schrey&#xf6;gg J. Preferences for e-mental health interventions in Germany: a discrete choice experiment. Value Health 2021; 24: 421&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33641777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Healey BJ, Griffiths KM, Bennett K. The effect of programme testimonials on registrations for an online cognitive behaviour therapy intervention: a randomised trial. Digit Health 2017; 3: 2055207617729937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6001272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29942614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winterbottom A, Bekker HL, Conner M, et al. Does narrative information bias individual&#x2019;s decision making? A systematic review. Soc Sci Med 2008; 67: 2079&#x2013;2088.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18951673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bekker HL, Winterbottom AE, Butow P, et al. Do personal stories make patient decision aids more effective? A critical review of theory and evidence. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak 2013; 13: S9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4044102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24625283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Fritsche L, Wopperer J, et al. Investigating the persuasive effects of testimonials on the acceptance of digital stress management trainings among university students and underlying mechanisms: a randomized controlled trial. Front Psychol 2021; 12: 738950.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8549694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34721212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Harrer M, Dederichs M, et al. Exploring the influence of testimonial source on attitudes towards e-mental health interventions among university students: four-group randomized controlled trial. PLoS One 2021; 16: e0252012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8153476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34038455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie J, Lewis J, McNaughton Nicholls C, et al. (eds). Qualitative research practice: a guide for social science students and researchers. 2nd ed.London: Sage Publications Ltd, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwientek A-K, Braun P, Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, et al. Formative qualitative research on the development of a discrete choice experiment on e-Mental-Health information preferences and needs among prospect healthcare providers, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wildauer M, Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J. Untersuchung der Wirksamkeit von
psychoedukativem Informationsmaterial zur F&#xf6;rderung der Akzeptanz von
Gesundheits-Apps und E-Mental-Health-Angeboten zur Stressbew&#xe4;ltigung im
Fernstudium. Fachzeitschrift f&#xfc;r Onlineberatung
und 2018; 14:
38&#x2013;58. www.e-beratungsjournal.net (ISSN 1816&#x2013;7632)
(2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden A, Nanayakkara S, Skinner J, et al. What do Australian health consumers believe about commercial advertisements and testimonials? A survey on health service advertising. BMC Public Health 2021; 21: 74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7791787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33413201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham CE, Deal K, Rimas H, et al. Modeling the information preferences of parents of children with mental health problems: a discrete choice conjoint experiment. J Abnorm Child Psychol 2008; 36: 1123&#x2013;1138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18481167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham CE, Walker JR, Eastwood JD, et al. Modeling mental health information preferences during the early adult years: a discrete choice conjoint experiment. J Health Commun 2014; 19: 413&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3996536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24266450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cunningham CE, Zipursky RB, Christensen BK, et al. Modeling the mental health service utilization decisions of university undergraduates: a discrete choice conjoint experiment. J Am Coll Health 2017; 65: 389&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28511031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenzner T, Menold N. Frageformulierung, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayring P. Qualitative Inhaltsanalyse: Grundlagen und Techniken. 12., aktualisierte und &#xfc;berarbeitete Auflage. Weinheim, Basel: Beltz, 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dederichs M, Weber J, Muth T, et al. Students&#x2019; perspectives on interventions to reduce stress in medical school: a qualitative study. PLoS One 2020; 15: e0240587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7561099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33057431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heinrichs K, Herm&#xfc;lheim V, Pilz Gonz&#xe1;lez L, et al. When in doubt &#x2026; career indecision, mental wellbeing, and consultation-seeking behaviour&#x2014;a qualitative interview study among students and counsellors. Int J Environ Res Public Health 2021: 18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8656489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34886330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber J, Skodda S, Muth T, et al. Stressors and resources related to academic studies and improvements suggested by medical students: a qualitative study. BMC Med Educ 2019; 19: 312.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6701044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31429744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care 2007; 19: 349&#x2013;357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollin IL, Craig BM, Coast J, et al. Reporting formative qualitative research to support the development of quantitative preference study protocols and corresponding survey instruments: guidelines for authors and reviewers. Patient 2020; 13: 121&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31840215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayring P.Qualitative content analysis: theoretical foundation, basic procedures and software solution. Austria: Beltz Klagenfurt, 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerst A, Zielasek J, Gaebel W. Smartphone applications for depression: a systematic literature review and a survey of health care professionals&#x2019; attitudes towards their use in clinical practice. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci 2020; 270: 139&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30607530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundesinstitut f&#xfc;r Arzneimittel und
Medizinprodukte. 1. Bekanntmachung zu den digitalen
Gesundheitsanwendungen (DiGA) vom 06.10.2020, https://diga.bfarm.de/thc-bfarm/assets/documents/201006_BfArM_Bekanntmachung-DiGA-1.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Hennemann S, K&#xfc;ck C, et al. Exploring user-related drivers of the early acceptance of certified digital stress prevention programs in Germany. Health Serv Insights 2020; 13: 1178632920911061.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7074489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32206013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bundesinstitut f&#xfc;r Arzneimittel und
Medizinprodukte. DiGA-Verzeichnis, https://diga.bfarm.de/de/verzeichnis?category=%5B%2277%22%5D
(2022, accessed 20 December
2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiessling C, Schubert B, Scheffner D, et al. First year medical students&#x2019; perceptions of stress and support: a comparison between reformed and traditional track curricula. Med Educ 2004; 38: 504&#x2013;509.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15107084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dyrbye LN, Thomas MR, Shanafelt TD. Medical student distress: causes, consequences, and proposed solutions. Mayo Clin Proc 2005; 80: 1613&#x2013;1622.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16342655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guthrie EA, Black D, Shaw CM, et al. Embarking upon a medical career: psychological morbidity in first year medical students. Med Educ 1995; 29: 337&#x2013;341.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8699970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torous J, Nicholas J, Larsen ME, et al. Clinical review of user engagement with mental health smartphone apps: evidence, theory and improvements. Evid Based Ment Health 2018; 21: 116&#x2013;119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10270395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29871870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regehr C, Glancy D, Pitts A. Interventions to reduce stress in university students: a review and meta-analysis. J Affect Disord 2013; 148: 1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23246209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao H, Carney DM, Youn SJ, et al. Are we in crisis? National mental health and treatment trends in college counseling centers. Psychol Serv 2017; 14: 407&#x2013;415.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29120199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu CH, Stevens C, Wong SHM, et al. The prevalence and predictors of mental health diagnoses and suicide among U.S. college students: implications for addressing disparities in service use. Depress Anxiety 2019; 36: 8&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6628691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30188598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guckian J, Utukuri M, Asif A, et al. Social media in undergraduate medical education: a systematic review. Med Educ 2021; 55: 1227&#x2013;1241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33988867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dusek G, Yurova Y, Ruppel C. Using social media and targeted snowball sampling to survey a hard-to-reach population: a case study. IJDS 2015; 10: 279&#x2013;299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendes-Santos C, Nunes F, Weiderpass E, et al. Understanding mental health professionals&#x2019; perspectives and practices regarding the implementation of digital mental health: qualitative study. JMIR Form Res 2022; 6: e32558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9044148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35412459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charit&#xe9;&#x2014;Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin
Berlin. Nationaler Kompetenzbasierter Lernzielkatalog
Medizin: Version 2.0, https://nklm.de/
(2022, accessed 26 June 2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen ME, Huckvale K, Nicholas J, et al. Using science to sell apps: evaluation of mental health app store quality claims. NPJ Digit Med 2019; 2: 18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6550255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31304366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan G, Marley I, Still M, et al. Use of mental-health services by Australian medical students: a cross-sectional survey. Australas Psychiatry 2017; 25: 407&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28675041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schueller SM, Washburn JJ, Price M. Exploring mental health providers&#x2019; interest in using web and mobile-based tools in their practices. Internet Interv 2016; 4: 145&#x2013;151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5231655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28090438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen F, Sheer VC, Li R. Impact of narratives on persuasion in health communication: a meta-analysis. J Advert 2015; 44: 105&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinyard LJ, Kreuter MW. Using narrative communication as a tool for health behavior change: a conceptual, theoretical, and empirical overview. Health Educ Behav 2007; 34: 777&#x2013;792.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17200094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auerbach RP, Alonso J, Axinn WG, et al. Mental disorders among college students in the World Health Organization World Mental Health Surveys. Psychol Med 2016; 46: 2955&#x2013;2970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5129654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27484622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>