<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38156702</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>18</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-6844</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>38</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Neurorehabilitation and neural repair</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Neurorehabil Neural Repair</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Mechanisms of Post-Stroke Fatigue: A Follow-Up From the Third Stroke Recovery and Rehabilitation Roundtable.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>52</StartPage><EndPage>61</EndPage><MedlinePgn>52-61</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/15459683231219266</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Post-stroke fatigue (PSF) is a significant and highly prevalent symptom, whose mechanisms are poorly understood. The third Stroke Recovery and Rehabilitation Roundtable paper on PSF focussed primarily on defining and measuring PSF while mechanisms were briefly discussed. This companion paper to the main paper is aimed at elaborating possible mechanisms of PSF.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This paper reviews the available evidence that potentially explains the pathophysiology of PSF and draws parallels from fatigue literature in other conditions. We start by proposing a case for phenotyping PSF based on structural, functional, and behavioral characteristics of PSF. This is followed by discussion of a potentially significant role of early inflammation in the development of fatigue, specifically the impact of low-grade inflammation and its long-term systemic effects resulting in PSF. Of the many neurotransmitter systems in the brain, the dopaminergic systems have the most evidence for a role in PSF, along with a role in sensorimotor processing. Sensorimotor neural network dynamics are compromised as highlighted by evidence from both neurostimulation and neuromodulation studies. The double-edged sword effect of exercise on PSF provides further insight into how PSF might emerge and the importance of carefully titrating interventional paradigms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The paper concludes by synthesizing the presented evidence into a unifying model of fatigue which distinguishes between factors that pre-dispose, precipitate, and perpetuate PSF. This framework will help guide new research into the biological mechanisms of PSF which is a necessary prerequisite for developing treatments to mitigate the debilitating effects of post-stroke fatigue.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kuppuswamy</LastName><ForeName>Annapoorna</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4288-0814</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Queen Square Institute of Neurology, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Leeds, Leeds, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Billinger</LastName><ForeName>Sandra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Kansas Medical Center, University of Kansas Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, Fairway, KS, MO, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Coupland</LastName><ForeName>Kirsten G</ForeName><Initials>KG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Biomedical Sciences and Pharmacy, College of Health, Medicine and Wellbeing, University of Newcastle, Australia Heart and Stroke Program, Hunter Medical Research Institute, Newcastle, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>English</LastName><ForeName>Coralie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5910-7927</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, College of Health, Medicine and Wellbeing, University of Newcastle, Australia Heart and Stroke Program, Hunter Medical Research Institute, Newcastle, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kutlubaev</LastName><ForeName>Mansur A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Bashkir State Medical University, Ufa, Russia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moseley</LastName><ForeName>Lorimer</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IIMPACT in Health, University of South Australia, Adelaide, SA, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pittman</LastName><ForeName>Quentin J</ForeName><Initials>QJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Pharmacology, Hotchkiss Brain Institute, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simpson</LastName><ForeName>Dawn B</ForeName><Initials>DB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health Sciences, College of Health, Medicine and Wellbeing, University of Newcastle, Australia Heart and Stroke Program, Hunter Medical Research Institute, Newcastle, NSW, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sutherland</LastName><ForeName>Brad A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tasmanian School of Medicine, College of Health and Medicine, University of Tasmania, Hobart, TS, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Connie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Inflammatory Diseases, Department of Medicine, School of Clinical Sciences at Monash Health, Monash University, Clayton, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Corbett</LastName><ForeName>Dale</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0217-4576</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, University of Ottawa Brain and Mind Institute, University of Ottawa, Ottawa, ON, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>202346/Z/16/Z</GrantID><Acronym>WT_</Acronym><Agency>Wellcome Trust</Agency><Country>United Kingdom</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Neurorehabil Neural Repair</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100892086</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1545-9683</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005500" MajorTopicYN="N">Follow-Up Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020521" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005221" MajorTopicYN="N">Fatigue</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071939" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stroke Rehabilitation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dopamine</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mechanisms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neural networks</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-stroke fatigue</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting InterestsThe author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>48</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38156702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10798014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15459683231219266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>English CK, Simpson DB, Billinger S, et al. EXPRESS: a roadmap for research in post-stroke fatigue: consensus-based core recommendations from the third Stroke Recovery and Rehabilitation Roundtable. Int J Stroke. Published online October 12, 2023. doi: 10.1177/17474930231189135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17474930231189135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10811972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37424273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjeverud A, &#xd8;stlie K, Schanke A-K, Gay C, Thoresen M, Lerdal A. Trajectories of fatigue among stroke patients from the acute phase to 18 months post-injury: a latent class analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0231709.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7159233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choi-Kwon S, Choi J, Kwon SU, Kang D-W, Kim JS. Fluoxetine is not effective in the treatment of post-stroke fatigue: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2007;23:103-108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17124389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eriksson G, Larsson I, Guidetti S, Johansson U. Handling fatigue in everyday activities at five years after stroke: a long and demanding process. Scand J Occup Ther. 2023;30(2):228-238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35758254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ablewhite J, Nouri F, Whisker A, et al. How do stroke survivors and their caregivers manage post-stroke fatigue? A qualitative study. Clin Rehabil. 2022;36(10):1400-1410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9420885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35770809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>English C, Simpson D, Billinger S, et al. A roadmap towards major breakthroughs in post-stroke fatigue: consensus-based core recommendations from the third Stroke Recovery and Rehabilitation Roundtable. Int J Stroke. Published online October 12, 2023. doi: 10.1177/17474930231189135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17474930231189135</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delva M, Lytvynenko N, Delva I. Factors associated with the time-based phenomenology of post-stroke fatigue over the first year after stroke occurrence. Georgian Med News. 2018;279:92-97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30035728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubacher M, Calabrese P, Bassetti C, Carota A, St&#xf6;cklin M, Penner I-K. Assessment of post-stroke fatigue: the fatigue scale for motor and cognitive functions. Eur. Neurol. 2012;67:377-384.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22614741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schow T, Teasdale TW, Quas KJ, Rasmussen MA. Problems with balance and binocular visual dysfunction are associated with post-stroke fatigue. Top Stroke Rehabil. 2017;24:41-49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson B, R&#xf6;nnb&#xe4;ck L. Mental fatigue and cognitive impairment after an almost neurological recovered stroke. ISRN Psychiatry. 2012;2012:686425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3658493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23738208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutai H, Furukawa T, Houri A, Suzuki A, Hanihara T. Factors associated with multidimensional aspect of post-stroke fatigue in acute stroke period. Asian J Psychiatr. 2017;26:1-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28483068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bivard A, Lillicrap T, Krishnamurthy V, et al. MIDAS (modafinil in debilitating fatigue after stroke): a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, cross-over trial. Stroke. 2017;48:1293-1298.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5404401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28404841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Visser MM, Mar&#xe9;chal B, Goodin P, et al. Predicting modafinil-treatment response in poststroke fatigue using brain morphometry and functional connectivity. Stroke. 2019;50:602-609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30777001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Doncker W, Ondobaka S, Kuppuswamy A. Effect of transcranial direct current stimulation on post-stroke fatigue. J Neurol. 2021;268(8):2831-2842</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8289762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33598767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulrichsen KM, Kolsk&#xe5;r KK, Richard G, et al. No add-on effect of tDCS on fatigue and depression in chronic stroke patients: a randomized sham-controlled trial combining tDCS with computerized cognitive training. Brain Behav. 2022;12:e2643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9304833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35666655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zedlitz AMEE, Rietveld TCM, Geurts AC, Fasotti L. Cognitive and graded activity training can alleviate persistent fatigue after stroke: a randomized, controlled trial. Stroke. 2012;43:1046-1051.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22308241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Ponchel A, Bombois S, Bordet R, H&#xe9;non H.
Factors associated with poststroke fatigue: a systematic review. Stroke Res Treat. 2015;2015:e347920. Accessed February 9, 2021. https://www.hindawi.com/journals/srt/2015/347920/</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4458555</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26101691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appelros P. Prevalence and predictors of pain and fatigue after stroke: a population-based study. Int J Rehabil Res. 2006;29:329-333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17106351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naess H, Lunde L, Brogger J, Waje-Andreassen U. Fatigue among stroke patients on long-term follow-up. The Bergen stroke study. J. Neurol. Sci. 2012;312:138-141.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gyawali P, Hinwood M, Chow WZ, et al. Exploring the relationship between fatigue and circulating levels of the pro-inflammatory biomarkers interleukin-6 and C-reactive protein in the chronic stage of stroke recovery: a cross-sectional study. Brain Behav Immun Health. 2020;9:100157.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34589899</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roseborough AD, Zhu Y, Zhao L, Laviolette SR, Pasternak SH, Whitehead SN. Fibrinogen primes the microglial NLRP3 inflammasome and propagates pro-inflammatory signaling via extracellular vesicles: implications for blood-brain barrier dysfunction. Neurobiol Dis. 2023;177:106001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36646389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ermine CM, Nithianantharajah J, O&#x2019;Brien K, et al. Hemispheric cortical atrophy and chronic microglial activation following mild focal ischemic stroke in adult male rats. J Neurosci Res. 2021;99:3222-3237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34651338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormstad H, Aass HCD, Amthor K-F, Lund-S&#xf8;rensen N, Sandvik L. Serum levels of cytokines, glucose, and hemoglobin as possible predictors of poststroke depression, and association with poststroke fatigue. Int. J. Neurosci. 2012;122:682-690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22812657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ormstad H, Aass HCD, Amthor K-F, Lund-S&#xf8;rensen N, Sandvik L. Serum cytokine and glucose levels as predictors of poststroke fatigue in acute ischemic stroke patients. J. Neurol. 2011;258:670-676.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3065647</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21365457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klinedinst NJ, Schuh R, Kittner SJ, et al. Post-stroke fatigue as an indicator of underlying bioenergetics alterations. J Bioenerg Biomembr. 2019;51:165-174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617735</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X, Wang B, Wang X, Tian M, Wang X, Zhang Y. Elevated plasma high-sensitivity C-reactive protein at admission predicts the occurrence of post-stroke fatigue at 6 months after ischaemic stroke. Eur J Neurol. 2020;27:2022-2030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32633437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKechnie F, Lewis S, Mead G. A pilot observational study of the association between fatigue after stroke and C-reactive protein. J R Coll Physicians Edinb. 2010;40:9-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21125032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon S, Jin C, Cho S-Y, et al. Analysis of factors affecting post-stroke fatigue: an observational, cross-sectional, retrospective chart review study. Healthcare. 2021;9:1586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8621383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34828631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lacourt TE, Vichaya EG, Chiu GS, Dantzer R, Heijnen CJ. The high costs of low-grade inflammation: persistent fatigue as a consequence of reduced cellular-energy availability and non-adaptive energy expenditure. Front Behav Neurosci. 2018;12:78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5932180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29755330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witcher KG, Bray CE, Chunchai T, et al. Traumatic brain injury causes chronic cortical inflammation and neuronal dysfunction mediated by Microglia. J Neurosci. 2021;41:1597-1616.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7896020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33452227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bray CE, Witcher KG, Adekunle-Adegbite D, et al. Chronic cortical inflammation, cognitive impairment, and immune reactivity associated with diffuse brain injury are ameliorated by forced turnover of microglia. J Neurosci. 2022;42:4215-4228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9121837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35440489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wen H, Weymann KB, Wood L, Wang QM. Inflammatory signaling in post-stroke fatigue and depression. Eur Neurol. 2018;80:138-148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30448848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grossberg AJ, Zhu X, Leinninger GM, et al. Inflammation-induced lethargy is mediated by suppression of orexin neuron activity. J Neurosci. 2011;31:11376-11386.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3155688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21813697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Booij HA, Gaykema WDC, Kuijpers KAJ, Pouwels MJM, den Hertog HM. Pituitary dysfunction and association with fatigue in stroke and other acute brain injury. Endocr Connect. 2018;7:R223-R237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6000755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29748174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker K, Kohen R, Lee R, et al. Poststroke fatigue: hints to a biological mechanism. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2015;24:618-621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4359660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25542762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao C, Fedirko V, Beitler J, et al. The role of the gut microbiome in cancer-related fatigue: pilot study on epigenetic mechanisms. Support Care Cancer. 2021;29:3173-3182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8055716</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33078326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Pasokh A, Farzipour M, Mahmoudi J, Sadigh-Eteghad S.
The effect of fecal microbiota transplantation on stroke outcomes: a systematic review. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2022;31(11):106727. Accessed May 9, 2023. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36162378/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36162378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaskill PJ, Khoshbouei H. Dopamine and norepinephrine are embracing their immune side and so should we. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2022;77:102626.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10481402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36058009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobryakova E, Genova HM, DeLuca J, Wylie GR. The dopamine imbalance hypothesis of fatigue in multiple sclerosis and other neurological disorders. Front Neurol. 2015;6:52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4357260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25814977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker M, Repantis D, Dresler M, K&#xfc;hn S. Cognitive enhancement: effects of methylphenidate, modafinil, and caffeine on latent memory and resting state functional connectivity in healthy adults. Hum Brain Mapp. 2022;43:4225-4238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9435011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35670369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blockmans D, Persoons P, Van Houdenhove B, Bobbaers H. Does methylphenidate reduce the symptoms of chronic fatigue syndrome? Am J Med. 2006;119:167.e23-30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16443425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr CW, Drake J, Milch RA, et al. Effects of methylphenidate on fatigue and depression: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2012;43:68-77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22208450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofmans L, Papadopetraki D, van den Bosch R, et al. Methylphenidate boosts choices of mental labor over leisure depending on striatal dopamine synthesis capacity. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2020;45:2170-2179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7784967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32919405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poulsen MB, Damgaard B, Zerahn B, Overgaard K, Rasmussen RS. Modafinil may alleviate poststroke fatigue: a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blinded trial. Stroke. 2015;46:3470-3477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26534969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sommer CJ, Sch&#xe4;bitz W-R. Fostering poststroke recovery: towards combination treatments. Stroke. 2017;48:1112-1119.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28265015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy TH, Corbett D. Plasticity during stroke recovery: from synapse to behaviour. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2009;10:861-872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19888284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Doncker W, Dantzer R, Ormstad H, Kuppuswamy A. Mechanisms of poststroke fatigue. J. Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2018;89:287-293.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28939684</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S, Cheng S, Zhang Z, Wang C, Wang A, Zhu W. Related risk factors associated with post-stroke fatigue: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurol Sci. 2021;42(4):1463-1471.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32813167</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Gu M, Xiao L, et al. Association of lesion location and fatigue symptoms after ischemic stroke: a VLSM study. Front Aging Neurosci. 2022;14:902604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9277067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35847675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulrichsen KM, Kolsk&#xe5;r KK, Richard G, et al. Structural brain disconnectivity mapping of post-stroke fatigue. Neuroimage Clin. 2021;30:102635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8044723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33799271</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonkhoff AK, Xu T, Nelson A, et al. Reclassifying stroke lesion anatomy. Cortex. 2021;145:1-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8650827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34673291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuppuswamy A. The neurobiology of pathological fatigue: new models, new questions. Neuroscientist. 2022;28:238-253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9136477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33446049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuppuswamy A. The fatigue conundrum. Brain. 2017;140:2240-2245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28899013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuppuswamy A, Clark EV, Turner IF, Rothwell JC, Ward NS. Post-stroke fatigue: a deficit in corticomotor excitability? Brain. 2015;138:136-148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25367024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Wu C-H, Doncker WD, Croce P, Bertoli M, Tecchio F, Kuppuswamy A.
Electroencephalography-derived functional connectivity in sensorimotor networks in Stroke and Multiple Sclerosis Fatigue. bioRxiv
2022:2022.03.16.484592. Accessed March 20, 2022. https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2022.03.16.484592v1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2022.03.16.484592v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Doncker W, Brown KE, Kuppuswamy A. Influence of post-stroke fatigue on reaction times and corticospinal excitability during movement preparation. Clin Neurophysiol. 2021;132:191-199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7810236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ondobaka S, De Doncker W, Ward N, Kuppuswamy A. Neural effective connectivity explains subjective fatigue in stroke. Brain. 2022;145:285-294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8967104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34791073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Doncker WD, Kuppuswamy A.
The cocktail party effect in post-stroke fatigue: an EEG study. bioRxiv
2022:2022.03.17.484808. Accessed March 20, 2022. https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2022.03.17.484808v1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2022.03.17.484808v1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulrichsen KM, Alnaes D, Kolsk&#xe5;r KK, et al. Dissecting the cognitive phenotype of post-stroke fatigue using computerized assessment and computational modeling of sustained attention. Eur J Neurosci. 2020;52:3828-3845.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32530498</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cotter G, Salah Khlif M, Bird L, E Howard M, Brodtmann A, Egorova-Brumley N. Post-stroke fatigue is associated with resting state posterior hypoactivity and prefrontal hyperactivity. Int J Stroke. 2021. Published online September 27, 2021. doi: 10.1177/17474930211048323</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17474930211048323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34569876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vecchio F, Miraglia F, Porcaro C, et al. Electroencephalography-derived sensory and motor network topology in multiple sclerosis fatigue. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2017;31:56-64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27370602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manjaly Z-M, Harrison NA, Critchley HD, et al. Pathophysiological and cognitive mechanisms of fatigue in multiple sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2019;90:642-651.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6581095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30683707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clancy U, Gilmartin D, Jochems ACC, Knox L, Doubal FN, Wardlaw JM. Neuropsychiatric symptoms associated with cerebral small vessel disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Psychiatry. 2021;8:225-236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33539776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong X-L, Sun X, Sun W-M, et al. A randomized controlled trial to explore the efficacy and safety of transcranial direct current stimulation on patients with post-stroke fatigue. Medicine. 2021;100:e27504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8519229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34731132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Tecchio F, Cancelli A, Cottone C, et al. Brain plasticity effects of neuromodulation against multiple sclerosis fatigue. Front. Neurol. 2015;6:141. Accessed October 20, 2020. https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fneur.2015.00141/full
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2015.00141/full</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4490242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26191036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tecchio F, Cancelli A, Cottone C, et al. Multiple sclerosis fatigue relief by bilateral somatosensory cortex neuromodulation. J Neurol. 2014;261:1552-1558.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24854634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernhardt J, Dewey H, Thrift A, Donnan G. Inactive and alone: physical activity within the first 14 days of acute stroke unit care. Stroke. 2004;35:1005-1009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14988574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>English C, Healy GN, Coates A, Lewis L, Olds T, Bernhardt J. Sitting and activity time in people with stroke. Phys Ther. 2016;96:193-201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26112254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ploughman M, Austin MW, Glynn L, Corbett D. The effects of poststroke aerobic exercise on neuroplasticity: a systematic review of animal and clinical studies. Transl Stroke Res. 2015;6:13-28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25023134</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billinger SA, Arena R, Bernhardt J, et al. Physical activity and exercise recommendations for stroke survivors: a statement for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2014;45:2532-2553.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24846875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kip E, Parr-Brownlie LC. Healthy lifestyles and wellbeing reduce neuroinflammation and prevent neurodegenerative and psychiatric disorders. Front Neurosci. 2023;17:1092537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9975355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36875655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tai D, Falck RS, Davis JC, Vint Z, Liu-Ambrose T. Can exercise training promote better sleep and reduced fatigue in people with chronic stroke? A systematic review. J Sleep Res. 2022;31:e13675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35762096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regan EW, Handlery R, Liuzzo DM, et al. The Neurological Exercise Training (NExT) program: a pilot study of a community exercise program for survivors of stroke. Disabil Health J.2019;12:528-532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6581575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30967342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paul L, Wyke S, Brewster S, et al. Increasing physical activity in stroke survivors using STARFISH, an interactive mobile phone application: a pilot study. Top Stroke Rehabil. 2016;23:170-177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27077973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razazian N, Kazeminia M, Moayedi H, et al. The impact of physical exercise on the fatigue symptoms in patients with multiple sclerosis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Neurol. 2020;20:93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32169035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taul-Madsen L, Connolly L, Dennett R, Freeman J, Dalgas U, Hvid LG. Is aerobic or resistance training the most effective exercise modality for improving lower extremity physical function and perceived fatigue in people with multiple sclerosis? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2021;102:2032-2048.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33901439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larun L, Brurberg KG, Odgaard-Jensen J, Price JR. Exercise therapy for chronic fatigue syndrome. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;4:CD003200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6419524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28444695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiensch AE, Mijwel S, Bargiela D, Wengstr&#xf6;m Y, May AM, Rundqvist H. Inflammation mediates exercise effects on fatigue in patients with breast cancer. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2021;53:496-504.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7886356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32910094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bilek F, Cetisli-Korkmaz N, Ercan Z, Deniz G, Demir CF. Aerobic exercise increases irisin serum levels and improves depression and fatigue in patients with relapsing remitting multiple sclerosis: a randomized controlled trial. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2022;61:103742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35349884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeffers MS, Karthikeyan S, Gomez-Smith M, et al. Does stroke rehabilitation really matter? Part B: an algorithm for prescribing an effective intensity of rehabilitation. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2018;32:73-83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29334831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayward KS, Churilov L, Dalton EJ, et al. Advancing stroke recovery through improved articulation of nonpharmacological intervention dose. Stroke. 2021;52:761-769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33430635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dromerick AW, Geed S, Barth J, et al. Critical period after stroke study (cPASS): a phase II clinical trial testing an optimal time for motor recovery after stroke in humans. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2021;118:e2026676118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8488696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34544853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gubert C, Hannan AJ. Exercise mimetics: harnessing the therapeutic effects of physical activity. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2021;20:862-879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34103713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Sleight AG, Crowder SL, Skarbinski J, et al. A new approach to understanding cancer-related fatigue: leveraging the 3P model to facilitate risk prediction and clinical care. Cancers. 2022;14:1982. Accessed May 9, 2023. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35454890/
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9027717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35454890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cumming TB, Yeo AB, Marquez J, et al. Investigating post-stroke fatigue: an individual participant data meta-analysis. J Psychosom Res. 2018;113:107-112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30190042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>