<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35333189</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2561-326X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>6</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR formative research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Form Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Patient- and Provider-Reported Experiences of a Mobile Novel Digital Therapeutic in People With Opioid Use Disorder (reSET-O): Feasibility and Acceptability Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e33073</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e33073</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e33073</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/33073</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Medications for the treatment of opioid use disorder, such as buprenorphine, are effective and essential for addressing the opioid epidemic. However, high dropout rates from medication remain a challenge. Behavioral treatment with contingency management and cognitive behavioral counseling has shown promise for improving the outcomes of buprenorphine treatment but is complicated to deliver. The delivery of behavioral treatment through technology-based platforms has the potential to make it more feasible for widespread dissemination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">reSET-O is a prescription digital therapeutic and a commercial adaptation of the Therapeutic Education System, an internet-based program with a Community Reinforcement Approach to cognitive behavioral therapy. It delivers cognitive behavioral therapy modules and contingency management rewards upon completion of modules and negative urine drug screens. This pilot study aims to assess the feasibility and acceptability of reSET-O in a community-based opioid treatment program with a Hub and Spoke model of care as part of a larger strategy to maintain individuals in treatment. Objective and qualitative results, as well as acceptability and likeability of reSET-O, were obtained from 15 individuals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">English-speaking individuals aged &#x2265;18 years with a diagnosis of current opioid use disorder were recruited after being on buprenorphine for at least 1 week of treatment. Two 12-week prescriptions for reSET-O were written for the 24-week study. Patient reports of drug use and likeability scales of reSET-O were conducted at weeks 4, 8, 12, and 24 of the study. Qualitative interviews were also conducted. A total of 4 providers were recruited and provided feedback on the acceptability and feasibility of reSET-O.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Of the 15 participants who participated in this pilot study, 7 (47%) completed 24 weeks, and 8 (53%) were unable to complete because of dropout after enrollment, attrition in treatment, or incarceration. An average of US $96 in contingency management rewards were earned by participants for the completion of modules for the duration of the pilot study. Participants' subjective feedback revealed that reSET-O was easy to use, enjoyable, and helped provide a safe space to admit recurring substance use.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">reSET-O was well accepted based on patient and provider feedback in this pilot study; however, adherence and retention in treatment remain areas for improvement. Randomized control trials are needed to assess whether retention of community-based buprenorphine treatment is enhanced through the use of technology-based behavioral interventions such as reSET-O.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Sarah Kawasaki, Sara Mills-Huffnagle, Nicole Aydinoglo, Halley Maxin, Edward Nunes. Originally published in JMIR Formative Research (https://formative.jmir.org), 25.03.2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kawasaki</LastName><ForeName>Sarah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7325-7729</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Health, Penn State Health, Hershey, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mills-Huffnagle</LastName><ForeName>Sara</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6722-2586</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Health, Penn State Health, Hershey, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aydinoglo</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9452-1517</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Columbia University, New York, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maxin</LastName><ForeName>Halley</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3793-5147</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Health, Penn State Health, Hershey, PA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nunes</LastName><ForeName>Edward</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2055-3425</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Columbia University, New York, NY, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R21 AT010118</GrantID><Acronym>AT</Acronym><Agency>NCCIH NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Form Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101726394</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2561-326X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital therapeutic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">opioid use disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescription digital therapeutic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reSET-O</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35333189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8994143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/33073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v6i3e33073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hser YI, Hoffman V, Grella CE, Anglin MD. A 33-year follow-up of narcotics addicts. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2001;58(5):503&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.58.5.503.yoa20042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.58.5.503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11343531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veilleux JC, Colvin PJ, Anderson J, York C, Heinz AJ. A review of opioid dependence treatment: pharmacological and psychosocial interventions to treat opioid addiction. Clin Psychol Rev. 2010;30(2):155&#x2013;66. doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2009.10.006.S0272-7358(09)00142-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2009.10.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19926374</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mattick RP, Breen C, Kimber J, Davoli M. Buprenorphine maintenance versus placebo or methadone maintenance for opioid dependence. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014;(2):CD002207. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD002207.pub4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD002207.pub4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10617756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24500948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hser YI, Saxon AJ, Huang D, Hasson A, Thomas C, Hillhouse M, Jacobs P, Teruya C, McLaughlin P, Wiest K, Cohen A, Ling W. Treatment retention among patients randomized to buprenorphine/naloxone compared to methadone in a multi-site trial. Addiction. 2014;109(1):79&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1111/add.12333. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.12333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3947022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23961726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Nunes Jr EV, Novo P, Bachrach K, Bailey GL, Bhatt S, Farkas S, Fishman M, Gauthier P, Hodgkins CC, King J, Lindblad R, Liu D, Matthews AG, May J, Peavy KM, Ross S, Salazar D, Schkolnik P, Shmueli-Blumberg D, Stablein D, Subramaniam G, Rotrosen J. Comparative effectiveness of extended-release naltrexone versus buprenorphine-naloxone for opioid relapse prevention (X:BOT): a multicentre, open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2018;391(10118):309&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32812-X. 
 
S0140-6736(17)32812-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32812-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29150198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wakeman SE, Larochelle MR, Ameli O, Chaisson CE, McPheeters JT, Crown WH, Azocar F, Sanghavi DM. Comparative effectiveness of different treatment pathways for opioid use disorder. JAMA Netw Open. 2020;3(2):e1920622. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.20622. 
 
2760032</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.20622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11143463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32022884</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grimm CA. Geographic disparities affect access to buprenorphine services for opioid use disorder. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Office of the Inspector General. 2020.  [2022-03-14].  
 https://oig.hhs.gov/oei/reports/oei-12-17-00240.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan JR, Schackman BR, Weinstein ZM, Walley AY, Linas BP. Overdose following initiation of naltrexone and buprenorphine medication treatment for opioid use disorder in a United States commercially insured cohort. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2019;200:34&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2019.02.031. 
 
S0376-8716(19)30131-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2019.02.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6613830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31082666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan JR, Schackman BR, Leff JA, Linas BP, Walley AY. Injectable naltrexone, oral naltrexone, and buprenorphine utilization and discontinuation among individuals treated for opioid use disorder in a United States commercially insured population. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2018;85:90&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2017.07.001. 
 
S0740-5472(16)30413-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2017.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5750108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28733097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss RD, Potter JS, Fiellin DA, Byrne M, Connery HS, Dickinson W, Gardin J, Griffin ML, Gourevitch MN, Haller DL, Hasson AL, Huang Z, Jacobs P, Kosinski AS, Lindblad R, McCance-Katz EF, Provost SE, Selzer J, Somoza EC, Sonne SC, Ling W. Adjunctive counseling during brief and extended buprenorphine-naloxone treatment for prescription opioid dependence: a 2-phase randomized controlled trial. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2011;68(12):1238&#x2013;46. doi: 10.1001/archgenpsychiatry.2011.121. 
 
archgenpsychiatry.2011.121</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archgenpsychiatry.2011.121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3470422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22065255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss RD, Potter JS, Griffin ML, Provost SE, Fitzmaurice GM, McDermott KA, Srisarajivakul EN, Dodd DR, Dreifuss JA, McHugh RK, Carroll KM. Long-term outcomes from the national drug abuse treatment clinical trials network prescription opioid addiction treatment study. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2015;150:112&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2015.02.030. 
 
S0376-8716(15)00114-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2015.02.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4407806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25818060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hser YI, Evans E, Huang D, Weiss R, Saxon A, Carroll KM, Woody G, Liu D, Wakim P, Matthews AG, Hatch-Maillette M, Jelstrom E, Wiest K, McLaughlin P, Ling W. Long-term outcomes after randomization to buprenorphine/naloxone versus methadone in a multi-site trial. Addiction. 2016;111(4):695&#x2013;705. doi: 10.1111/add.13238. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.13238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4801718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26599131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hser YI, Huang D, Saxon AJ, Woody G, Moskowitz AL, Matthews AG, Ling W. Distinctive trajectories of opioid use over an extended follow-up of patients in a multisite trial on buprenorphine + naloxone and methadone. J Addict Med. 2017;11(1):63&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000274. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0000000000000274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5291756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27898496</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larochelle MR, Bernson D, Land T, Stopka TJ, Wang N, Xuan Z, Bagley SM, Liebschutz JM, Walley AY. Medication for opioid use disorder after nonfatal opioid overdose and association with mortality: a cohort study. Ann Intern Med. 2018;169(3):137&#x2013;45. doi: 10.7326/M17-3107. 
 
2684924</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M17-3107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6387681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29913516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein BD, Sorbero M, Dick AW, Pacula RL, Burns RM, Gordon AJ. Physician capacity to treat opioid use disorder with buprenorphine-assisted treatment. JAMA. 2016;316(11):1211&#x2013;2. doi: 10.1001/jama.2016.10542. 
 
2553439</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2016.10542</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5257276</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27654608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quest TL, Merrill JO, Roll J, Saxon AJ, Rosenblatt RA. Buprenorphine therapy for opioid addiction in rural Washington: the experience of the early adopters. J Opioid Manag. 2012;8(1):29&#x2013;38. doi: 10.5055/jom.2012.0093. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5055/jom.2012.0093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4367201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22479882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutchinson E, Catlin M, Andrilla CH, Baldwin LM, Rosenblatt RA. Barriers to primary care physicians prescribing buprenorphine. Ann Fam Med. 2014;12(2):128&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1370/afm.1595. 
 
12/2/128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1370/afm.1595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3948759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24615308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeFlavio JR, Rolin SA, Nordstrom BR, Kazal Jr LA. Analysis of barriers to adoption of buprenorphine maintenance therapy by family physicians. Rural Remote Health. 2015;15:3019. 
 
3019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25651434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLellan AT, Arndt IO, Metzger DS, Woody GE, O'Brien CP. The effects of psychosocial services in substance abuse treatment. JAMA. 1993;269(15):1953&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8385230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peirce JM, Petry NM, Stitzer ML, Blaine J, Kellogg S, Satterfield F, Schwartz M, Krasnansky J, Pencer E, Silva-Vazquez L, Kirby KC, Royer-Malvestuto C, Roll JM, Cohen A, Copersino ML, Kolodner K, Li R. Effects of lower-cost incentives on stimulant abstinence in methadone maintenance treatment: a national drug abuse treatment clinical trials network study. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2006;63(2):201&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.63.2.201.63/2/201</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.63.2.201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16461864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nunes EV, Ball S, Booth R, Brigham G, Calsyn DA, Carroll K, Feaster DJ, Hien D, Hubbard RL, Ling W, Petry NM, Rotrosen J, Selzer J, Stitzer M, Tross S, Wakim P, Winhusen T, Woody G. Multisite effectiveness trials of treatments for substance abuse and co-occurring problems: have we chosen the best designs? J Subst Abuse Treat. 2010;38 Suppl 1:S97&#x2013;112. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2010.01.012. 
 
S0740-5472(10)00027-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2010.01.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2909698</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20307801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll KM, Weiss RD. The role of behavioral interventions in buprenorphine maintenance treatment: a review. Am J Psychiatry. 2017;174(8):738&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2016.16070792. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2016.16070792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5474206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27978771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooklyn JR, Sigmon SC. Vermont hub-and-spoke model of care for opioid use disorder: development, implementation, and impact. J Addict Med. 2017;11(4):286&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000310. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0000000000000310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5537005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28379862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kawasaki S, Francis E, Mills S, Buchberger G, Hogentogler R, Kraschnewski J. Multi-model implementation of evidence-based care in the treatment of opioid use disorder in Pennsylvania. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2019;106:58&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2019.08.016. 
 
S0740-5472(19)30243-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2019.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7194237</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31540612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel WK, Marsch LA, Buchhalter AR, Badger GJ. Computerized behavior therapy for opioid-dependent outpatients: a randomized controlled trial. Exp Clin Psychopharmacol. 2008;16(2):132&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1037/1064-1297.16.2.132. 
 
2008-03846-004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1064-1297.16.2.132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18489017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen DR, Landes RD, Jackson L, Marsch LA, Mancino MJ, Chopra MP, Bickel WK. Adding an internet-delivered treatment to an efficacious treatment package for opioid dependence. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2014;82(6):964&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1037/a0037496. 
 
2014-31346-001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0037496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4244262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25090043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>reSET-O/reset: how it works. Pear Therapeutics.  [2020-06-30].  
 https://www.resetforrecovery.com/how-it-works
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafson DH, McTavish FM, Chih MY, Atwood AK, Johnson RA, Boyle MG, Levy MS, Driscoll H, Chisholm SM, Dillenburg L, Isham A, Shah D. A smartphone application to support recovery from alcoholism: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2014;71(5):566&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2013.4642. 
 
1847578</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2013.4642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4016167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24671165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Andrews G, Colpe LJ, Hiripi E, Mroczek DK, Normand SL, Walters EE, Zaslavsky AM. Short screening scales to monitor population prevalences and trends in non-specific psychological distress. Psychol Med. 2002;32(6):959&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1017/s0033291702006074.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s0033291702006074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12214795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews G, Slade T. Interpreting scores on the Kessler Psychological Distress Scale (K10) Aust N Z J Public Health. 2001;25(6):494&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1111/j.1467-842x.2001.tb00310.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-842x.2001.tb00310.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11824981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang AJ, Stein MB. An abbreviated PTSD checklist for use as a screening instrument in primary care. Behav Res Ther. 2005;43(5):585&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2004.04.005.S0005-7967(04)00103-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2004.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15865914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lang AJ, Wilkins K, Roy-Byrne PP, Golinelli D, Chavira D, Sherbourne C, Rose RD, Bystritsky A, Sullivan G, Craske MG, Stein MB. Abbreviated PTSD checklist (PCL) as a guide to clinical response. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2012;34(4):332&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2012.02.003. 
 
S0163-8343(12)00063-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2012.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3383936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22460001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weather FW, Litz BT, Herman DS, Huska JA, Keane TM. The PTSD checklist (PCL): reliability, validity, and diagnostic utility. 9th Annual Convention of the International Society for Traumatic Stress Studies; ISTSS '93; November 13-15, 1993; San Antonio, TX. 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16(9):606&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x. 
 
jgi01114</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1525-1497.2001.016009606.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell LC, Sobell MB. Timeline follow-back: a technique for assessing self-reported alcohol consumption. In: Litten RZ, Allen JP, editors. Measuring alcohol consumption: psychosocial and biological methods. Totowa, NJ: Humana Press; 1992. pp. 41&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell MB, Sobell LC. An excellent springboard. Addiction. 2000;95(11):1712&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11219379</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petry NM, Peirce JM, Stitzer ML, Blaine J, Roll JM, Cohen A, Obert J, Killeen T, Saladin ME, Cowell M, Kirby KC, Sterling R, Royer-Malvestuto C, Hamilton J, Booth RE, Macdonald M, Liebert M, Rader L, Burns R, DiMaria J, Copersino M, Stabile PQ, Kolodner K, Li R. Effect of prize-based incentives on outcomes in stimulant abusers in outpatient psychosocial treatment programs: a national drug abuse treatment clinical trials network study. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005;62(10):1148&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.62.10.1148.62/10/1148</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.62.10.1148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16203960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budney AJ, Higgins ST. Therapy manuals for drug addiction: a community reinforcement plus vouchers approach: treating cocaine addiction. Rockville, MD: National Institute on Drug Abuse; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stitzer M, Petry N. Contingency management for treatment of substance abuse. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2006;2:411&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1146/annurev.clinpsy.2.022305.095219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.clinpsy.2.022305.095219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17716077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>