<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37043272</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2561-326X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>12</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR formative research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Form Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Barriers to and Facilitators of a Blended Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Program for Depression and Anxiety Based on Experiences of University Students: Qualitative Interview Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e45970</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e45970</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e45970</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/45970</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Blended cognitive behavioral therapy (bCBT) programs have been proposed to increase the acceptance and adoption of digital therapeutics (DTx) such as digital health apps. These programs allow for more personalized care by combining regular face-to-face therapy sessions with DTx. However, facilitators of and barriers to the use of DTx in bCBT programs have rarely been examined among students, who are particularly at risk for developing symptoms of depression and anxiety disorders.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate the facilitators of and barriers to the use of a bCBT program with the elona therapy app among university students with mild to moderate depression or anxiety symptoms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Semistructured interviews were conducted via videoconference between January 2022 and April 2022 with 102 students (mean age 23.93, SD 3.63 years; 89/102, 87.2% female) from universities in North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany, after they had completed weekly individual cognitive behavioral therapy sessions (25 minutes each) via videoconference for 6 weeks and regularly used the depression (n=67, 65.7%) or anxiety (n=35, 34.3%) module of the app. The interviews were coded based on grounded theory.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Many participants highlighted the intuitive handling of the app and indicated that they perceived it as a supportive tool between face-to-face sessions. Participants listed other benefits, such as increased self-reflection and disorder-specific knowledge as well as the transfer of the content of therapy sessions into their daily lives. Some stated that they would have benefited from more personalized and interactive tasks. In general, participants mentioned the time requirement, increased use of the smartphone, and the feeling of being left alone with potentially arising emotions while working on tasks for the next therapy session as possible barriers to the use of the app. Data security was not considered a major concern.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Students mostly had positive attitudes toward elona therapy as part of the bCBT program. Our study shows that DTx complementing face-to-face therapy sessions can be perceived as a helpful tool for university students with mild to moderate anxiety or depression symptoms in their daily lives. Future research could elaborate on whether bCBT programs might also be suitable for students with more severe symptoms of mental disorders. In addition, the methods by which such bCBT programs could be incorporated into the university context to reach students in need of psychological support should be explored.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Pia Braun, Ece Atik, Lisa Guthardt, Jennifer Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen, Magnus Sch&#xfc;ckes. Originally published in JMIR Formative Research (https://formative.jmir.org), 12.04.2023.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Braun</LastName><ForeName>Pia</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2179-4842</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Atik</LastName><ForeName>Ece</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1361-6301</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Psychotherapy, Georg-Elias-M&#xfc;ller-Institute of Psychology, University of G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Guthardt</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1550-3829</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5755-9225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sch&#xfc;ckes</LastName><ForeName>Magnus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3059-0673</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for SME Research and Entrepreneurship, University of Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Form Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101726394</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2561-326X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">acceptance</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anxiety</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bCBT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blended cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile phone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">university students</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">user experiences</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: EA declares that she is employed by Elona Health GmbH, the company that developed the app used in this study. MS is a shareholder of Elona Health GmbH. All the other authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37043272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10134026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/45970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v7i1e45970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pearce M, Garcia L, Abbas A, Strain T, Schuch FB, Golubic R, Kelly P, Khan S, Utukuri M, Laird Y, Mok A, Smith A, Tainio M, Brage S, Woodcock J. Association between physical activity and risk of depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2022 Jun 01;79(6):550&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.0609.2790780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.0609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9008579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35416941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malhi GS, Mann JJ. Depression. Lancet. 2018 Nov 24;392(10161):2299&#x2013;312. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31948-2.S0140-6736(18)31948-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31948-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30396512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendriks SM, Spijker J, Licht CM, Beekman AT, Hardeveld F, de Graaf R, Batelaan NM, Penninx BW. Disability in anxiety disorders. J Affect Disord. 2014 Sep;166:227&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2014.05.006.S0165-0327(14)00278-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2014.05.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25012435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Paula W, Breguez GS, Machado EL, Meireles AL. Prevalence of anxiety, depression, and suicidal ideation symptoms among university students: a systematic review. Braz J Health Rev. 2020;3(4):8739&#x2013;56. doi: 10.34119/bjhrv3n4-119. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34119/bjhrv3n4-119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC, Berglund P, Demler O, Jin R, Merikangas KR, Walters EE. Lifetime prevalence and age-of-onset distributions of DSM-IV disorders in the national comorbidity survey replication. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005 Jun;62(6):593&#x2013;602. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.62.6.593.62/6/593</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.62.6.593</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15939837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auerbach RP, Mortier P, Bruffaerts R, Alonso J, Benjet C, Cuijpers P, Demyttenaere K, Ebert DD, Green JG, Kessler R. 19.1 World Health Organization World Mental Health Surveys International College Student Project (WMH-ICS): prevalence and distribution of mental disorders. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2018 Oct;57(10 Supplement):S297. doi: 10.1016/j.jaac.2018.07.723. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaac.2018.07.723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lipshits-Braziler Y, Gati I, Tatar M. Strategies for coping with career indecision: convergent, divergent, and incremental validity. J Career Assess. 2017 May;25(2):183&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1177/1069072715620608. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1069072715620608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mortier P, Auerbach RP, Alonso J, Axinn WG, Cuijpers P, Ebert DD, Green JG, Hwang I, Kessler RC, Liu H, Nock MK, Pinder-Amaker S, Sampson NA, Zaslavsky AM, Abdulmalik J, Aguilar-Gaxiola S, Al-Hamzawi A, Benjet C, Demyttenaere K, Florescu S, De Girolamo G, Gureje O, Haro JM, Hu C, Huang Y, De Jonge P, Karam EG, Kiejna A, Kovess-Masfety V, Lee S, Mcgrath JJ, O'neill S, Nakov V, Pennell BE, Piazza M, Posada-Villa J, Rapsey C, Viana MC, Xavier M, Bruffaerts R. Suicidal thoughts and behaviors among college students and same-aged peers: results from the World Health Organization world mental health surveys. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2018 Mar;53(3):279&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1007/s00127-018-1481-6. 
 
10.1007/s00127-018-1481-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00127-018-1481-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5896296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29340781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hubble S, Bolton P. Support for students with mental health issues in higher education in England: briefing paper. House of Commons Library. 2020. Dec 17,  [2023-03-31].  
 https://researchbriefings.files.parliament.uk/documents/CBP-8593/CBP-8593.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David D, Cristea I, Hofmann SG. Why cognitive behavioral therapy is the current gold standard of psychotherapy. Front Psychiatry. 2018 Jan 29;9:4. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2018.00004. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2018.00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5797481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29434552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xfc;lich L, Br&#xe4;uniger J. Psychotherapie: lange wartezeiten bis zu einem therapieplatz. WDR. 2022. Jul 20,  [2022-09-07].  
 https://www1.wdr.de/nachrichten/psychotherapie-platzsuche-tipps-100.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vidourek RA, Burbage M. Positive mental health and mental health stigma: a qualitative study assessing student attitudes. Ment Health Prev. 2019 Mar;13:1&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.mhp.2018.11.006. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mhp.2018.11.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wada M, Suto MJ, Lee M, Sanders D, Sun C, Le TN, Goldman-Hasbun J, Chauhan S. University students&#x2019; perspectives on mental illness stigma. Ment Health Prev. 2019 Jun;14:200159. doi: 10.1016/j.mph.2019.200159. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mph.2019.200159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright JH, Owen JJ, Richards D, Eells TD, Richardson T, Brown GK, Barrett M, Rasku MA, Polser G, Thase ME. Computer-assisted cognitive-behavior therapy for depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Psychiatry. 2019 Mar 19;80(2):18r12188. doi: 10.4088/JCP.18r12188. 
 
18r12188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.18r12188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30900849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez E, Woldgabreal Y, Day A, Pham T, Gleich B, Aboujaoude E. Live psychotherapy by video versus in-person: a meta-analysis of efficacy and its relationship to types and targets of treatment. Clin Psychol Psychother. 2021 Nov;28(6):1535&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1002/cpp.2594.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpp.2594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33826190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moshe I, Terhorst Y, Philippi P, Domhardt M, Cuijpers P, Cristea I, Pulkki-R&#xe5;back L, Baumeister H, Sander LB. Digital interventions for the treatment of depression: a meta-analytic review. Psychol Bull. 2021 Aug;147(8):749&#x2013;86. doi: 10.1037/bul0000334.2022-09577-001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/bul0000334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34898233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrer M, Adam SH, Fleischmann RJ, Baumeister H, Auerbach R, Bruffaerts R, Cuijpers P, Kessler RC, Berking M, Lehr D, Ebert DD. Effectiveness of an internet- and app-based intervention for college students with elevated stress: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2018 Apr 23;20(4):e136. doi: 10.2196/jmir.9293. 
 
v20i4e136</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.9293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5938594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29685870</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Titov N, Dear BF, Rozental A, Carlbring P. Internet-delivered psychological treatments: from innovation to implementation. World Psychiatry. 2019 Feb;18(1):20&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1002/wps.20610. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6313242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30600624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Noma H, Karyotaki E, Cipriani A, Furukawa TA. Effectiveness and acceptability of cognitive behavior therapy delivery formats in adults with depression: a network meta-analysis. JAMA Psychiatry. 2019 Jul 01;76(7):700&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.0268. 
 
2730724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2019.0268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30994877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weisel KK, Fuhrmann LM, Berking M, Baumeister H, Cuijpers P, Ebert DD. Standalone smartphone apps for mental health-a systematic review and meta-analysis. NPJ Digit Med. 2019 Dec 02;2:118. doi: 10.1038/s41746-019-0188-8. doi: 10.1038/s41746-019-0188-8.188</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-019-0188-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6889400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31815193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Reichler L, Munzinger M, Lin J. The impact of guidance on internet-based mental health interventions &#x2014; a systematic review. Internet Interv. 2014 Oct;1(4):205&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2014.08.003. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2014.08.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Imai H, Tajika A, Narita H, Yoshinaga N, Kimura K, Nakamura H, Takeshima N, Hayasaka Y, Ogawa Y, Furukawa T. Unguided computer-assisted self-help interventions without human contact in patients with obsessive-compulsive disorder: systematic review and meta-analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2022 Apr 21;24(4):e35940. doi: 10.2196/35940. 
 
v24i4e35940</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/35940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9073609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35451993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molloy A, Ellis DM, Su L, Anderson PL. Improving acceptability and uptake behavior for internet-based cognitive-behavioral therapy. Front Digit Health. 2021 Mar 25;3:653686. doi: 10.3389/fdgth.2021.653686. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2021.653686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8521972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34713125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Harrer M, K&#xe4;hlke F, Fritsche L, Salewski C, Ebert DD. Public attitudes toward guided internet-based therapies: web-based survey study. JMIR Ment Health. 2018 May 15;5(2):e10735. doi: 10.2196/10735. 
 
v5i2e10735</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5974457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbe D, Eichert HC, Riper H, Ebert DD. Blending face-to-face and internet-based interventions for the treatment of mental disorders in adults: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2017 Sep 15;19(9):e306. doi: 10.2196/jmir.6588. 
 
v19i9e306</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newby J, Mason E, Kladnistki N, Murphy M, Millard M, Haskelberg H, Allen A, Mahoney A. Integrating internet CBT into clinical practice: a practical guide for clinicians. Clin Psychol. 2021 Mar 15;25(2):164&#x2013;78. doi: 10.1080/13284207.2020.1843968. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13284207.2020.1843968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooistra LC, Wiersma JE, Ruwaard J, Neijenhuijs K, Lokkerbol J, van Oppen P, Smit F, Riper H. Cost and effectiveness of blended versus standard cognitive behavioral therapy for outpatients with depression in routine specialized mental health care: pilot randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2019 Oct 29;21(10):e14261. doi: 10.2196/14261. 
 
v21i10e14261</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6914243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31663855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lungu A, Jun JJ, Azarmanesh O, Leykin Y, Chen CE. Blended care-cognitive behavioral therapy for depression and anxiety in real-world settings: pragmatic retrospective study. J Med Internet Res. 2020 Jul 06;22(7):e18723. doi: 10.2196/18723. 
 
v22i7e18723</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/18723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romijn G, Batelaan N, Koning J, van Balkom A, de Leeuw A, Benning F, Hakkaart van Roijen L, Riper H. Acceptability, effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of blended cognitive-behavioural therapy (bCBT) versus face-to-face CBT (ftfCBT) for anxiety disorders in specialised mental health care: a 15-week randomised controlled trial with 1-year follow-up. PLoS One. 2021 Nov 12;16(11):e0259493. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0259493. 
 
PONE-D-19-32776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0259493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu MS, Wickham RE, Chen SY, Chen C, Lungu A. Examining the impact of digital components across different phases of treatment in a blended care cognitive behavioral therapy intervention for depression and anxiety: pragmatic retrospective study. JMIR Form Res. 2021 Dec 17;5(12):e33452. doi: 10.2196/33452. 
 
v5i12e33452</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/33452</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8726023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34927591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mathiasen K, Andersen TE, Lichtenstein MB, Ehlers LH, Riper H, Kleiboer A, Roessler KK. The clinical effectiveness of blended cognitive behavioral therapy compared with face-to-face cognitive behavioral therapy for adult depression: randomized controlled noninferiority trial. J Med Internet Res. 2022 Sep 07;24(9):e36577. doi: 10.2196/36577. 
 
v24i9e36577</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/36577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9543221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36069798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atik E, Stricker J, Sch&#xfc;ckes M, Pittig A. Effectiveness of a brief blended cognitive behavioral therapy (bCBT) program for the treatment of depression and anxiety in university students: a feasibility trial. JMIR Preprints.  doi: 10.2196/preprints.44742. Preprint posted online on December 1, 2022
 
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/preprints.44742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly KH, Topooco N, Cederlund H, Wallin A, Bergstr&#xf6;m J, Molander O, Carlbring P, Andersson G. Smartphone-supported versus full behavioural activation for depression: a randomised controlled trial. PLoS One. 2015 May 26;10(5):e0126559. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0126559. 
 
PONE-D-14-40400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0126559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4444307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26010890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thase ME, Wright JH, Eells TD, Barrett MS, Wisniewski SR, Balasubramani GK, McCrone P, Brown GK. Improving the efficiency of psychotherapy for depression: computer-assisted versus standard CBT. Am J Psychiatry. 2018 Mar 01;175(3):242&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2017.17010089. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2017.17010089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5848497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28969439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thase ME, McCrone P, Barrett MS, Eells TD, Wisniewski SR, Balasubramani GK, Brown GK, Wright JH. Improving cost-effectiveness and access to cognitive behavior therapy for depression: providing remote-ready, computer-assisted psychotherapy in times of crisis and beyond. Psychother Psychosom. 2020;89(5):307&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1159/000508143. 
 
000508143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000508143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32396917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Gr&#xe4;ssle C, Ebert DD, Kr&#xe4;mer LV. Blended Psychotherapy &#x2013; verzahnte Psychotherapie: Das Beste aus zwei Welten? Psychother Dialog. 2018 Nov 28;19(04):33&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1055/a-0592-0264. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-0592-0264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert DD, Franke M, K&#xe4;hlke F, K&#xfc;chler AM, Bruffaerts R, Mortier P, Karyotaki E, Alonso J, Cuijpers P, Berking M, Auerbach RP, Kessler RC, Baumeister H, WHO World Mental Health - International College Student collaborators  Increasing intentions to use mental health services among university students. Results of a pilot randomized controlled trial within the World Health Organization's World Mental Health International College student initiative. Int J Methods Psychiatr Res. 2019 Jun;28(2):e1754. doi: 10.1002/mpr.1754. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mpr.1754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6877244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30456814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atik E, Sch&#xfc;ckes M, Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J. Patient and therapist expectations for a blended cognitive behavioral therapy program for depression: qualitative exploratory study. JMIR Ment Health. 2022 Dec 30;9(12):e36806. doi: 10.2196/36806. 
 
v9i12e36806</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/36806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36583934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jakob R, Harperink S, Rudolf AM, Fleisch E, Haug S, Mair JL, Salamanca-Sanabria A, Kowatsch T. Factors influencing adherence to mHealth apps for prevention or management of noncommunicable diseases: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2022 May 25;24(5):e35371. doi: 10.2196/35371. 
 
v24i5e35371</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/35371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9178451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35612886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doukani A, Free C, Araya R, Michelson D, Cerga-Pashoja A, Kakuma R. Practitioners' experience of the working alliance in a blended cognitive-behavioural therapy intervention for depression: qualitative study of barriers and facilitators. BJPsych Open. 2022 Jul 25;8(4):e142. doi: 10.1192/bjo.2022.546. 
 
S2056472422005464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjo.2022.546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9344874</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35876079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etzelmueller A, Radkovsky A, Hannig W, Berking M, Ebert DD. Patient's experience with blended video- and internet based cognitive behavioural therapy service in routine care. Internet Interv. 2018 Jun;12:165&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.003. 
 
S2214-7829(17)30089-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Urech A, Krieger T, M&#xf6;seneder L, Biaggi A, Vincent A, Poppe C, Meyer B, Riper H, Berger T. A patient post hoc perspective on advantages and disadvantages of blended cognitive behaviour therapy for depression: a qualitative content analysis. Psychother Res. 2019 Nov;29(8):986&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1080/10503307.2018.1430910.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10503307.2018.1430910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29385964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL. The PHQ-9: a new depression diagnostic and severity measure. Psychiatr Ann. 2002 Sep 01;32(9):509&#x2013;15. doi: 10.3928/0048-5713-20020901-06. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/0048-5713-20020901-06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006 May 22;166(10):1092&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092.166/10/1092</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinte.166.10.1092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerga-Pashoja A, Doukani A, Gega L, Walke J, Araya R. Added value or added burden? A qualitative investigation of blending internet self-help with face-to-face cognitive behaviour therapy for depression. Psychother Res. 2020 Nov;30(8):998&#x2013;1010. doi: 10.1080/10503307.2020.1720932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10503307.2020.1720932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke J, Proudfoot J, Whitton A, Birch MR, Boyd M, Parker G, Manicavasagar V, Hadzi-Pavlovic D, Fogarty A. Therapeutic alliance with a fully automated mobile phone and web-based intervention: secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial. JMIR Ment Health. 2016 Feb 25;3(1):e10. doi: 10.2196/mental.4656. 
 
v3i1e10</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mental.4656</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4786687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26917096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McBride CM, Morrissey EC, Molloy GJ. Patients' experiences of using smartphone apps to support self-management and improve medication adherence in hypertension: qualitative study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020 Oct 28;8(10):e17470. doi: 10.2196/17470. 
 
v8i10e17470</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/17470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7657730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33112251</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titzler I, Saruhanjan K, Berking M, Riper H, Ebert DD. Barriers and facilitators for the implementation of blended psychotherapy for depression: a qualitative pilot study of therapists' perspective. Internet Interv. 2018 Jan 16;12:150&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.002. 
 
S2214-7829(17)30090-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Vaart R, Witting M, Riper H, Kooistra L, Bohlmeijer ET, van Gemert-Pijnen LJ. Blending online therapy into regular face-to-face therapy for depression: content, ratio and preconditions according to patients and therapists using a Delphi study. BMC Psychiatry. 2014 Dec 14;14:355. doi: 10.1186/s12888-014-0355-z. 
 
s12888-014-0355-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-014-0355-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4271498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25496393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun Tie Y, Birks M, Francis K. Grounded theory research: a design framework for novice researchers. SAGE Open Med. 2019 Jan 02;7:2050312118822927. doi: 10.1177/2050312118822927. 
 
10.1177_2050312118822927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050312118822927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6318722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30637106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbin J. Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory. 4th edition. Thousand Oaks, CA, USA: SAGE Publications; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malagon-Maldonado G. Qualitative research in health design. HERD. 2014;7(4):120&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1177/193758671400700411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/193758671400700411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care. 2007 Dec;19(6):349&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1093/intqhc/mzm042.mzm042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gericke F, Ebert DD, Breet E, Auerbach RP, Bantjes J. A qualitative study of university students' experience of internet&#x2010;based CBT for depression. Couns Psychother Res. 2021 Aug 17;21(4):792&#x2013;804. doi: 10.1002/capr.12465. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/capr.12465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Porter RJ. The biopsychosocial model in mental health. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2020 Aug;54(8):773&#x2013;4. doi: 10.1177/0004867420944464.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0004867420944464</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mushquash AR, Grassia E. Coping during COVID-19: examining student stress and depressive symptoms. J Am Coll Health. 2022 Nov;70(8):2266&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1080/07448481.2020.1865379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2020.1865379</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33513079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stawarz K, Preist C, Tallon D, Wiles N, Kessler D, Turner K, Shafran R, Coyle D. Design considerations for the integrated delivery of cognitive behavioral therapy for depression: user-centered design study. JMIR Ment Health. 2020 Sep 03;7(9):e15972. doi: 10.2196/15972. 
 
v7i9e15972</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/15972</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7499168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32880580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merkel S. Umsetzungsbarrieren bei der akzeptanz, implementation und verbreitung von telecare und telehealth &#x2013; ergebnisse einer internationalen literaturstudie. In: M&#xfc;ller-Mielitz S, Lux T, editors. E-Health-&#xd6;konomie. Wiesbaden, Germany: Springer; 2017. pp. 117&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Terhorst Y, Gr&#xe4;ssle C, Freudenstein M, N&#xfc;bling R, Ebert DD. Impact of an acceptance facilitating intervention on psychotherapists' acceptance of blended therapy. PLoS One. 2020 Aug 12;15(8):e0236995. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0236995. 
 
PONE-D-20-00142</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0236995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7423074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32785245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleischmann RJ, Harrer M, Zarski AC, Baumeister H, Lehr D, Ebert DD. Patients' experiences in a guided internet- and app-based stress intervention for college students: a qualitative study. Internet Interv. 2017 Dec 29;12:130&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2017.12.001. 
 
S2214-7829(17)30086-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2017.12.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titzler I, Berking M, Schlicker S, Riper H, Ebert DD. Barriers and facilitators for referrals of primary care patients to blended internet-based psychotherapy for depression: mixed methods study of general practitioners' views. JMIR Ment Health. 2020 Aug 18;7(8):e18642. doi: 10.2196/18642. 
 
v7i8e18642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/18642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7463410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673213</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radi&#x107; M, Donner I, Waack M, Brinkmann C, Stein L, Radi&#x107; D. Digitale gesundheitsanwendungen: die akzeptanz steigern. Dtsch Arztebl. 2021;118(6):A286&#x2013;92. 
 
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjumea J, Ropero J, Rivera-Romero O, Dorronzoro-Zubiete E, Carrasco A. Privacy assessment in mobile health apps: scoping review. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2020 Jul 02;8(7):e18868. doi: 10.2196/18868. 
 
v8i7e18868</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/18868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7367524</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arean PA, Hallgren KA, Jordan JT, Gazzaley A, Atkins DC, Heagerty PJ, Anguera JA. The use and effectiveness of mobile apps for depression: results from a fully remote clinical trial. J Med Internet Res. 2016 Dec 20;18(12):e330. doi: 10.2196/jmir.6482. 
 
v18i12e330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5209607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27998876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xe4;mer R, K&#xf6;hne-Volland L, Schumacher A, K&#xf6;hler S. Efficacy of a web-based intervention for depressive disorders: three-arm randomized controlled trial comparing guided and unguided self-help with waitlist control. JMIR Form Res. 2022 Apr 04;6(4):e34330. doi: 10.2196/34330. 
 
v6i4e34330</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/34330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9016501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35105536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>