<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">30030212</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2019</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2019</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1438-8871</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>20</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>20</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of medical Internet research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Med Internet Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Accuracy of Internet-Based Patient Self-Report of Postdischarge Health Care Utilization and Complications Following Orthopedic Procedures: Observational Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e10405</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e10405</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e10405</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/10405</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The accuracy of patient self-report of health care utilization and complications has yet to be determined. If patients are accurate and engaged self-reporters, collecting this information in a manner that is temporally proximate to the health care utilization events themselves may prove valuable to health care organizations undertaking quality improvement initiatives for which such data are often unavailable.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The objective of this study was to measure the accuracy of patient self-report of health care utilization and complications in the 90 days following orthopedic procedures using an automated digital patient engagement platform.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">We conducted a multicenter real-world observational cohort study across 10 orthopedic practices in California and Nevada. A total of 371 Anthem members with claims data meeting inclusion criteria who had undergone orthopedic procedures between March 1, 2015, and July 1, 2016, at participating practices already routinely using an automated digital patient engagement platform for asynchronous remote guidance and telemonitoring were sent surveys through the platform (in addition to the other materials being provided to them through the platform) regarding 90-day postencounter health care utilization and complications. Their self-reports to structured survey questions of health care utilization and complications were compared to claims data as a reference.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">The mean age of the 371 survey recipients was 56.5 (SD 15.7) years, 48.8% (181/371) of whom were female; 285 individuals who responded to 1 or more survey questions had a mean age of 56.9 (SD 15.4) years and a 49.5% (141/285) female distribution. There were no significant differences in demographics or event prevalence rates between responders and nonresponders. With an overall survey completion rate of 76.8% (285/371), patients were found to have accuracy of self-report characterized by a kappa of 0.80 and agreement of 0.99 and a kappa of 1.00 and agreement of 1.00 for 90-day hospital admissions and pulmonary embolism, respectively. Accuracy of self-report of 90-day emergency room/urgent care visits and of surgical site infection were characterized by a kappa of 0.45 and agreement of 0.96 and a kappa of 0.53 and agreement of 0.97, respectively. Accuracy for other complications such as deep vein thrombosis, hemorrhage, severe constipation, and fracture/dislocation was lower, influenced by low event prevalence rates within our sample.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">In this multicenter observational cohort study using an automated internet-based digital patient engagement platform, we found that patients were most accurate self-reporters of 90-day hospital admissions and pulmonary embolism, followed by 90-day surgical site infection and emergency room/urgent care visits. They were less accurate for deep vein thrombosis and least accurate for hemorrhage, severe constipation, and fracture/dislocation. A total of 76.8% (285/371) of patients completed surveys without the need for clinical staff to collect responses, suggesting the acceptability to patients of internet-based survey dissemination from and collection by clinical teams. While our methods enabled detection of events outside of index institutions, assessment of accuracy of self-report for presence and absence of events and nonresponse bias analysis, low event prevalence rates, particularly for several of the complications, limit the conclusions that may be drawn for some of the findings. Nevertheless, this investigation suggests the potential that engaging patients in self-report through such survey modalities may offer for the timely and accurate measurement of matters germane to health care organizations engaged in quality improvement efforts post discharge.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Benjamin I Rosner, Marc Gottlieb, William N Anderson. Originally published in the Journal of Medical Internet Research (http://www.jmir.org), 20.07.2018.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosner</LastName><ForeName>Benjamin I</ForeName><Initials>BI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3609-6481</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>HealthLoop Inc, Mountain View, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hospital Medicine, Kaiser Permanente, Santa Clara, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gottlieb</LastName><ForeName>Marc</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9755-4717</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Anthem Inc, Atlanta, GA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderson</LastName><ForeName>William N</ForeName><Initials>WN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4204-3415</Identifier></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>J Med Internet Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100959882</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1438-8871</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006760" MajorTopicYN="N">Hospitalization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="Y">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020407" MajorTopicYN="N">Internet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009985" MajorTopicYN="N">Orthopedics</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="Y">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010351" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Discharge</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000639" MajorTopicYN="Y">trends</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057566" MajorTopicYN="N">Self Report</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">complications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">emergency room</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hospital economics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient readmission</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient reported outcome measures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient self-report</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">patient-generated health data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">utilization</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: BIR is an employee of and reports equity interest in HealthLoop Inc. MG is an employee of and reports equity interest in Anthem Inc. WNA is a paid consultant of HealthLoop and reports equity interest in Amgen Inc and Edwards Lifesciences LLC.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30030212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6076369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v20i7e10405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Center for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Innovation.  [2018-06-28].  Bundled Payments for Care Improvement (BPCI) initiative: general information
 https://innovation.cms.gov/initiatives/bundled-payments/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Innovation.  [2018-06-28].  BPCI advanced
 https://innovation.cms.gov/initiatives/bpci-advanced
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Innovation.  [2018-06-28].  Comprehensive care for joint replacement model
 https://innovation.cms.gov/initiatives/cjr
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Compendium on Payment Reform.  [2018-03-13].  
 http://compendium.catalyzepaymentreform.org/compendium-search/4585
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goozner M.  [2018-03-14].  Q&amp;A with Dr. Patrick Conway
 http://www.modernhealthcare.com/article/20180203/NEWS/180209999
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McIlvennan CK, Eapen ZJ, Allen LA. Hospital readmissions reduction program. Circulation. 2015 May 19;131(20):1796&#x2013;1803. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.114.010270. 
 
CIRCULATIONAHA.114.010270</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.114.010270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4439931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25986448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zuckerman RB, Sheingold SH, Orav EJ, Ruhter J, Epstein AM. Readmissions, observation, and the hospital readmissions reduction program. N Engl J Med. 2016 Apr 21;374(16):1543&#x2013;1551. doi: 10.1056/NEJMsa1513024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMsa1513024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26910198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.  [2018-06-28].  Readmissions reduction program
 https://www.cms.gov/Medicare/Medicare-Fee-for-Service-Payment/AcuteInpatientPPS/Readmissions-Reduction-Program.html
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bream E, Black N. What is the relationship between patients' and clinicians' reports of the outcomes of elective surgery? J Health Serv Res Policy. 2009 Jul;14(3):174&#x2013;182. doi: 10.1258/jhsrp.2009.008115.14/3/174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1258/jhsrp.2009.008115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19541877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosner B. The hidden actors in hospital readmissions. Readmission News. 2017;6(8):172.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>St Sauver JL, Hagen PT, Cha SS, Bagniewski SM, Mandrekar JN, Curoe AM, Rodeheffer RJ, Roger VL, Jacobsen SJ. Agreement between patient reports of cardiovascular disease and patient medical records. Mayo Clin Proc. 2005 Feb;80(2):203&#x2013;210.S0025-6196(11)61507-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15704775</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tisnado DM, Adams JL, Liu H, Damberg CL, Chen W, Hu FA, Carlisle DM, Mangione CM, Kahn KL. What is the concordance between the medical record and patient self-report as data sources for ambulatory care? Med Care. 2006 Feb;44(2):132&#x2013;140.00005650-200602000-00006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16434912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu B, Sweetland S, Beral V, Green J, Balkwill A, Casabonne D, Million Women Study Collaborators Self-reported information on joint replacement and cholecystectomy agrees well with that in medical records. J Clin Epidemiol. 2007 Nov;60(11):1190&#x2013;1194. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.02.007.S0895-4356(07)00060-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.02.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parimi N, Lane NE, Bauer D, Hochberg MC, Nevitt MC. Accuracy of self-reported diagnosis of hip replacement. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken) 2010 May;62(5):719&#x2013;724. doi: 10.1002/acr.20111. doi: 10.1002/acr.20111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.20111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2868937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20191473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alazzawi S, Bardakos NV, Hadfield SG, Butt U, Beer ZH, Field RE. Patient-reported complications after elective joint replacement surgery: are they correct? J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2012 Aug;94(8):1120&#x2013;1125. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.94B8.29040.94-B/8/1120</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/0301-620X.94B8.29040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22844056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dushey CH, Bornstein LJ, Alexiades MM, Westrich GH. Short-term coagulation complications following total knee arthroplasty: a comparison of patient-reported and surgeon-verified complication rates. J Arthroplasty. 2011 Dec;26(8):1338&#x2013;1342. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2010.11.007.S0883-5403(10)00635-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2010.11.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21256700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenbaum JN, Bornstein LJ, Lyman S, Alexiades MM, Westrich GH. The validity of self-report as a technique for measuring short-term complications after total hip arthroplasty in a joint replacement registry. J Arthroplasty. 2012 Aug;27(7):1310&#x2013;1315. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2011.10.031.S0883-5403(11)00596-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2011.10.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22197286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrold L, Pascal S, Lewis C, O'Keefe R, Pellegrini V, Allison J, Ayers D, Franklin P. Patient report improves posthospital discharge event capture in total joint replacement: a novel approach to capturing all posthospital event data. EGEMS (Wash DC) 2014;2(1):1107. doi: 10.13063/2327-9214.1107. 
 
egems1107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13063/2327-9214.1107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4371383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25848596</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown JB, Adams ME. Patients as reliable reporters of medical care process. Recall of ambulatory encounter events. Med Care. 1992 May;30(5):400&#x2013;411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1583918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carsj&#xf6; K, Thorslund M, W&#xe4;rneryd B. The validity of survey data on utilization of health and social services among the very old. J Gerontol. 1994 May;49(3):S156&#x2013;S164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8169350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhandari A, Wagner T. Self-reported utilization of health care services: improving measurement and accuracy. Med Care Res Rev. 2006 Apr;63(2):217&#x2013;235. doi: 10.1177/1077558705285298.63/2/217</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077558705285298</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16595412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrou S, Murray L, Cooper P, Davidson LL. The accuracy of self-reported healthcare resource utilization in health economic studies. Int J Technol Assess Health Care. 2002;18(3):705&#x2013;710.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12391960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duseja R, Bardach NS, Lin GA, Yazdany J, Dean ML, Clay TH, Boscardin WJ, Dudley RA. Revisit rates and associated costs after an emergency department encounter: a multistate analysis. Ann Intern Med. 2015 Jun 02;162(11):750&#x2013;756. doi: 10.7326/M14-1616.2299853</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M14-1616</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26030633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolford M, Palso K, Bercovitz A. National Center for Health Statistics.  [2018-03-14].  NCHS data brief, no. 186: Hospitalization for total hip replacement among inpatients aged 45 and over: United States, 2000-2010
 https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/products/databriefs/db186.htm
.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25714040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer R, Gentry-Maharaj A, Nordin A, Liston R, Burnell M, Das N, Desai R, Gornall R, Beardmore-Gray A, Hillaby K, Leeson S, Linder A, Lopes A, Meechan D, Mould T, Nevin J, Olaitan A, Rufford B, Ryan A, Shanbhag S, Thackeray A, Wood N, Reynolds K, Menon U. Patient-reporting improves estimates of postoperative complication rates: a prospective cohort study in gynaecological oncology. Br J Cancer. 2013 Aug 06;109(3):623&#x2013;632. doi: 10.1038/bjc.2013.366. doi: 10.1038/bjc.2013.366.bjc2013366</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bjc.2013.366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3738134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23846170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C, Lai M, Syu C, Chang S, Tseng F. Accuracy of diabetes diagnosis in health insurance claims data in Taiwan. J Formos Med Assoc. 2005 Mar;104(3):157&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15818428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robinson JR, Young TK, Roos LL, Gelskey DE. Estimating the burden of disease. Comparing administrative data and self-reports. Med Care. 1997 Sep;35(9):932&#x2013;947.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9298082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu S, Chang H, Lin M, Lin Y. Agreement between self-reported and health insurance claims on utilization of health care: a population study. J Clin Epidemiol. 2009 Dec;62(12):1316&#x2013;1322. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2009.01.016.S0895-4356(09)00056-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2009.01.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19403264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer L, Johnston SS, Rousculp MD, Chu B, Nichol KL, Mahadevia PJ. Agreement between Internet-based self- and proxy-reported health care resource utilization and administrative health care claims. Value Health. 2012 May;15(3):458&#x2013;465. doi: 10.1016/j.jval.2011.12.015. 
 
S1098-3015(12)00016-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2011.12.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22583456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosner BI, Gottlieb M, Anderson WN. Effectiveness of an automated digital remote guidance and telemonitoring platform on costs, readmissions, and complications after hip and knee arthroplasties. J Arthroplasty. 2018 Apr;33(4):988&#x2013;996. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2017.11.036. 
 
S0883-5403(17)31041-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2017.11.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29229238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benchimol EI, Smeeth L, Guttmann A, Harron K, Moher D, Petersen I, S&#xf8;rensen HT, von Elm E, Langan SM, RECORD Working Committee  The reporting of studies conducted using observational routinely-collected health data (RECORD) statement. PLoS Med. 2015 Oct;12(10):e1001885. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1001885. 
 
PMEDICINE-D-15-00711</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1001885</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4595218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26440803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>STROBE statement: available checklists.  [2018-03-14].  
 https://www.strobe-statement.org/index.php?id=available-checklists
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>SQUIRE 2: revised standards for quality improvement reporting excellence.  
 http://squire-statement.org/index.cfm?fuseaction=Page.ViewPage&amp;PageID=471
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>CONSORT-EHEALTH checklist v1.6.1.  [2018-07-11].  
 https://asset.jmir.pub/assets/public/CONSORT-EHEALTH-v1-6.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker TB, Gustafson DH, Shaw B, Hawkins R, Pingree S, Roberts L, Strecher V. Relevance of CONSORT reporting criteria for research on eHealth interventions. Patient Educ Couns. 2010 Dec;81 Suppl:S77&#x2013;S86. doi: 10.1016/j.pec.2010.07.040. 
 
S0738-3991(10)00441-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pec.2010.07.040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2993846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20843621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steele JR, Jones AK, Clarke RK, Shiao SJ, Wei W, Shoemaker S, Parmar S. Use of an online education platform to enhance patients' knowledge about radiation in diagnostic imaging. J Am Coll Radiol. 2017 Mar;14(3):386&#x2013;392. doi: 10.1016/j.jacr.2016.11.018.S1546-1440(16)31327-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacr.2016.11.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28111051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bozic KJ, Chiu VW, Takemoto SK, Greenbaum JN, Smith TM, Jerabek SA, Berry DJ. The validity of using administrative claims data in total joint arthroplasty outcomes research. J Arthroplasty. 2010 Sep;25(6 Suppl):58&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2010.04.006.S0883-5403(10)00238-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arth.2010.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20570479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stirnemann PM, Takemoto SK, Schnitzler MA, Brennan DC, Abbott KC, Salvalaggio P, Burroughs TE, Gavard JA, Willoughby LM, Lentine KL. Agreement of immunosuppression regimens described in Medicare pharmacy claims with the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network survey. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2006 Aug;17(8):2299&#x2013;2306. doi: 10.1681/ASN.2006030258. 
 
ASN.2006030258</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1681/ASN.2006030258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16825328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altman D. Practical Statistics for Medical Research. London: CRC Press; 1990.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleiss J, Levin B, Paik M. Statistical Methods for Rates and Proportions. Hoboken: Wiley, John &amp; Sons, Incorporated; 2003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G. Improving the quality of Web surveys: the checklist for reporting results of internet e-surveys (CHERRIES) J Med Internet Res. 2004 Sep 29;6(3):e34. doi: 10.2196/jmir.6.3.e34. 
 
v6e34</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6.3.e34</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1550605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15471760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ungar WJ, Davidson-Grimwood SR, Cousins M. Parents were accurate proxy reporters of urgent pediatric asthma health services: a retrospective agreement analysis. J Clin Epidemiol. 2007 Nov;60(11):1176&#x2013;1183. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.02.002. 
 
S0895-4356(07)00039-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4940178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17938060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Joint Registry: 7-year report. National Joint Registry, New Zealand Orthopaedic Association; 2007.  [2018-07-11].  
 https://nzoa.org.nz/system/files/NJR%207%20Year%20Report.pdf
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cockbain A, Carolan M, Berridge D, Toogood G. Performance and quality indicators: the importance of accurate coding. Bull R Coll Surg Engl. 2012;94(2):46&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1308/147363512X13189526439151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1308/147363512X13189526439151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khanna G, Singh JA, Pomeroy DL, Gioe TJ. Comparison of patient-reported and clinician-assessed outcomes following total knee arthroplasty. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2011 Oct 19;93(20):e117. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.J.00850.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.J.00850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22012534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>White RH, Garcia M, Sadeghi B, Tancredi DJ, Zrelak P, Cuny J, Sama P, Gammon H, Schmaltz S, Romano PS. Evaluation of the predictive value of ICD-9-CM coded administrative data for venous thromboembolism in the United States. Thromb Res. 2010 Jul;126(1):61&#x2013;67. doi: 10.1016/j.thromres.2010.03.009.S0049-3848(10)00198-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.thromres.2010.03.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20430419</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mears SC, Bawa M, Pietryak P, Jones LC, Rajadhyaksha AD, Hungerford DS, Mont MA. Coding of diagnoses, comorbidities, and complications of total hip arthroplasty. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2002 Sep;(402):164&#x2013;170.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12218480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon NP, Hornbrook MC. Differences in access to and preferences for using patient portals and other eHealth technologies based on race, ethnicity, and age: a database and survey study of seniors in a large health plan. J Med Internet Res. 2016 Mar 04;18(3):e50. doi: 10.2196/jmir.5105. 
 
v18i3e50</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.5105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4799429</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26944212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith A.  Older adults and technology use. Washington: Pew Internet and American Life Project; 2014.  [2018-07-11].  
 http://www.pewinternet.org/2014/04/03/older-adults-and-technology-use
.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvedar JC, Fogel AL. Why real-world results are so challenging for digital health. 2017.  [2018-06-18].  
 https://catalyst.nejm.org/real-world-results-digital-health-products/
</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>