<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">32715388</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2649</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>30</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Quality of life research : an international journal of quality of life aspects of treatment, care and rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Qual Life Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Using implementation science to inform the integration of electronic patient-reported experience measures (ePREMs) into healthcare quality improvement: description of a theory-based application in primary care.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>3073</StartPage><EndPage>3084</EndPage><MedlinePgn>3073-3084</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11136-020-02588-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Collecting and monitoring the information from patients through patient-reported experience measures (PREMs) about the quality of care they receive is important for tracking changes in healthcare quality, stimulate innovation, and enhance person-centred care. The objective of this theoretical paper is to discuss the use of implementation science theories, models, and frameworks to inform and evaluate the integration of the electronic collection of PREMs (ePREMs) in healthcare quality improvement for primary care in Canada.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">To assess potential knowledge-to-practice gaps in implementing ePREMs in primary care in Alberta, the overarching implementation model that will be used is the Knowledge to Action Cycle. An integrated knowledge translation approach will ensure ongoing engagement of key stakeholders (e.g. primary care providers, patients) throughout the study. ePREM implementation will be informed by the identification of barriers and facilitators to implementation using the Consolidated Framework for Implementation Research (CFIR). The CFIR brings an organizational perspective providing an opportunity to explore the intervention characteristics, the context of implementation, individual factors, and the processes that influence implementation of ePREMs in healthcare. Identified barriers and facilitators to ePREM implementation will be mapped to evidence-based implementation strategies and prioritized by stakeholders. The RE-AIM framework will be used to guide the evaluation of ePREM implementation outcomes after six months of implementation by assessing Reach, Effectiveness, Adoption, Implementation, and Maintenance (sustainability).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Consultations with stakeholders affirm the importance of using integrated knowledge translation approaches and the need to better understand how to integrate ePREMs in primary care. Using an implementations science approach, this study can provide guidance for mitigating important ePREM implementation challenges and promote the successful uptake and use of ePREMs for quality improvement in healthcare.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020. Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manalili</LastName><ForeName>Kimberly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0826-7298</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Teaching Research and Wellness Building, Calgary, AB, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santana</LastName><ForeName>Maria J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0202-5952</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Teaching Research and Wellness Building, Calgary, AB, Canada. mjsantan@ucalgary.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Strategy for Patient-Oriented Research, Patient Engagement Platform, Alberta, Canada. mjsantan@ucalgary.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, Cumming School of Medicine, University of Calgary, Calgary, AB, Canada. mjsantan@ucalgary.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>ISOQOL PROMs/PREMs in clinical practice implementation science work group</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>20190002</GrantID><Agency>Government of Alberta</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Qual Life Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9210257</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0962-9343</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000416" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Alberta</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004581" MajorTopicYN="N">Electronics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000077626" MajorTopicYN="Y">Implementation Science</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000071066" MajorTopicYN="N">Patient Reported Outcome Measures</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011320" MajorTopicYN="N">Primary Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058996" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality Improvement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Electronic data collection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Implementation science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient-reported experience measures</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Person-centred care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality improvement</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-020-02588-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11136-020-02588-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Institute for Healthcare Improvement. (2008). The IHI Triple Aim. https://www.ihi.org/Engage/Initiatives/TripleAim/Pages/default.aspx .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S., Kemp, K., Johnson, D., Quan, H., &amp; Santana, M. J. (2019). Identifying areas for improvement in paediatric inpatient care using the Child HCAHPS survey. Paediatrics &amp; Child Health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp, K., McCormack, B., Chan, N., Santana, M. J., &amp; Quan, H. (2015). Correlation of inpatient experience survey items and domains with overall hospital rating. Journal of patient experience, 2(2), 29&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28725821</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5513631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2374373515615977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stewart, M., Brown, J. B., Donner, A., McWhinney, I. R., Oates, J., Weston, W. W., et al. (2000). The impact of patient-centered care on outcomes. Journal of Family Practice, 49(9), 796&#x2013;796.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anhang Price, R., Elliott, M. N., Zaslavsky, A. M., Hays, R. D., Lehrman, W. G., Rybowski, L., et al. (2014). Examining the role of patient experience surveys in measuring health care quality. Medical Care Research and Review, 71(5), 522&#x2013;554.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25027409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077558714541480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp, K. A., Ahmed, S., Quan, H., Johnson, D., &amp; Santana, M. J. (2018). Family Experiences of Pediatric Inpatient Care in Alberta, Canada: Results From the Child HCAHPS Survey. Hospital pediatrics, 8(6), 338&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29724754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1542/hpeds.2017-0191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies, E., Shaller, D., Edgman-Levitan, S., Safran, D. G., Oftedahl, G., Sakowski, J., et al. (2008). Evaluating the use of a modified CAHPS&#xae; survey to support improvements in patient-centred care: lessons from a quality improvement collaborative. Health Expectations, 11(2), 160&#x2013;176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18494960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">5060434</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1369-7625.2007.00483.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana, M. J., Manalili, K., Jolley, R. J., Zelinsky, S., Quan, H., &amp; Lu, M. (2018). How to practice person-centred care: A conceptual framework. Health Expectations, 21(2), 429&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151269</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hex.12640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benson, T. (2020). Measure what we want: a taxonomy of short generic person-reported outcome and experience measures (PROMs and PREMs). BMJ open quality, 9(1), e000789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198234</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7103852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjoq-2019-000789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Canadian Institute for Health Information. (2018). Patient Experience https://www.cihi.ca/en/patient-experience .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Quality Council of Alberta (2018). Primary Care Experience Survey. https://www.hqca.ca/surveys/patient-experience-survey/ .</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen, R. E., Snyder, C. F., Abernethy, A. P., Basch, E., Potosky, A. L., Roberts, A. C., et al. (2013). Review of electronic patient-reported outcomes systems used in cancer clinical care. Journal of Oncology Practice, 10(4), e215&#x2013;e222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24301843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4094646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JOP.2013.001067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snyder, C. F., Aaronson, N. K., Choucair, A. K., Elliott, T. E., Greenhalgh, J., Halyard, M. Y., et al. (2012). Implementing patient-reported outcomes assessment in clinical practice: a review of the options and considerations. Quality of Life Research, 21(8), 1305&#x2013;1314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22048932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11136-011-0054-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana, M. J., Feeny, D., Weinkauf, J., Nador, R., Kapasi, A., Jackson, K., et al. (2010). The use of patient-reported outcomes becomes standard practice in the routine clinical care of lung&#x2013;heart transplant patients. Patient related outcome measures, 1, 93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22915956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3417902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/PROM.S11943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haverman, L., van Oers, H. A., Limperg, P. F., Hijmans, C. T., Schepers, S. A., Nicolaas, S., et al. (2014). Implementation of electronic patient reported outcomes in pediatric daily clinical practice: The KLIK experience. Clinical Practice in Pediatric Psychology, 2(1), 50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/cpp0000043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basch, E., &amp; Abernethy, A. P. (2011). Supporting clinical practice decisions with real-time patient-reported outcomes. Journal of Clinical Oncology, 29(8), 954&#x2013;956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21282536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2010.33.2668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straus, S. E., Tetroe, J., &amp; Graham, I. D. (2013). Introduction. In S. E. Straus, J. Tetroe, &amp; I. D. Graham (Eds.), Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice (2nd ed., pp. 3&#x2013;13): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham, I. D., Logan, J., Harrison, M. B., Straus, S. E., Tetroe, J., Caswell, W., et al. (2006). Lost in knowledge translation: time for a map? Journal of Continuing Education in the Health Professions, 26(1), 13&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/chp.47</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handley, M. A., Gorukanti, A., &amp; Cattamanchi, A. (2016). Strategies for implementing implementation science: a methodological overview. Emerg Med J, 33(9), 660&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26893401</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/emermed-2015-205461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nilsen, P. (2015). Making sense of implementation theories, models and frameworks. Implementation Science, 10(1), 53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4406164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4406164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-015-0242-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doktorchik, C., Manalili, K., Jolley, R., Gibbons, E., Lu, M., Quan, H., et al. (2018). Identifying Canadian patient-centred care measurement practices and quality indicators: a survey. CMAJ open, 6(4), E643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6298869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9778/cmajo.20170143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S., Siad, F. M., Manalili, K., Lorenzetti, D. L., Barbosa, T., Lantion, V., et al. (2018). How to measure cultural competence when evaluating patient-centred care: a scoping review. British Medical Journal Open, 8(7), e021525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana, M.-J., Ahmed, S., Lorenzetti, D., Jolley, R. J., Manalili, K., Zelinsky, S., et al. (2019). Measuring patient-centred system performance: a scoping review of patient-centred care quality indicators. British Medical Journal Open, 9(1), e023596.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed, S., Djurkovic, A., Manalili, K., Sahota, B., &amp; Santana, M. J. (2019). A qualitative study on measuring patient-centered care: Perspectives from clinician-scientists and quality improvement experts. Health Science Reports, 2(12), e140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31890898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6920695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hsr2.140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi, A. R., Berta, W., Kothari, A., Boyko, J., &amp; Urquhart, R. (2015). Integrated knowledge translation (IKT) in health care: a scoping review. Implementation Science, 11(1), 38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-016-0399-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wandersman, A., Duffy, J., Flaspohler, P., Noonan, R., Lubell, K., Stillman, L., et al. (2008). Bridging the gap between prevention research and practice: The interactive systems framework for dissemination and implementation. American Journal of Community Psychology, 41(3&#x2013;4), 171&#x2013;181.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18302018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10464-008-9174-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander, J. A., &amp; Hearld, L. R. (2011). The science of quality improvement implementation: developing capacity to make a difference. Medical Care, S6-S20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott, C., Seidel, J., Bowen, S., &amp; Gall, N. (2009). Integrated health systems and integrated knowledge: creating space for putting knowledge into action. Healthcare Quarterly, 13(15), 30&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20057246</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12927/hcq.2009.21094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner, B. J. (2009). A theory of organizational readiness for change. Implementation Science, 4(1), 67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19840381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2770024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-4-67</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>May, C. R., Mair, F., Finch, T., MacFarlane, A., Dowrick, C., Treweek, S., et al. (2009). Development of a theory of implementation and integration: Normalization Process Theory. Implementation Science, 4(1), 1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-4-29</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stover, A. M., Haverman, L., van Oers, H. A., Greenhalgh, J., &amp; Potter, C. M. (2020). Using an implementation science approach to implement and evaluate patient-reported outcome measures (PROM) initiatives in routine care settings. Quality of Life Research, 1&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harrison, M. B., Graham, I. D., Fervers, B., &amp; van den Hoek, J. (2013). Adapting knowledge to local context. In S. E. Straus, J. Tetroe, &amp; I. D. Graham (Eds.), Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice (2nd ed., pp. 110&#x2013;120): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Legare, F., &amp; Zhang, P. (2013). Barriers and facilitators. In S. E. Straus, J. Tetroe, &amp; I. D. Graham (Eds.), Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice (pp. 121&#x2013;136): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wensing, M., Bosch, M., &amp; Grol, R. (2013). Methods to identify determinants of change in healthcare. In R. Grol, M. Wensing, M. Eccles, &amp; D. Davis (Eds.), Improving patient care: the implementation of change in health care (2nd ed., pp. 151&#x2013;162): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palinkas, L. A., Aarons, G. A., Horwitz, S., Chamberlain, P., Hurlburt, M., &amp; Landsverk, J. (2011). Mixed method designs in implementation research. Administration and Policy in Mental Health and Mental Health Services Research, 38(1), 44&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20967495</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10488-010-0314-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan, D. L. (2013). Integrating qualitative and quantitative methods: A pragmatic approach: Sage Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehman, W. E., Greener, J. M., &amp; Simpson, D. D. (2002). Assessing organizational readiness for change. Journal of substance abuse treatment, 22(4), 197&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12072164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0740-5472(02)00233-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder, L. J., Aron, D. C., Keith, R. E., Kirsh, S. R., Alexander, J. A., &amp; Lowery, J. C. (2009). Fostering implementation of health services research findings into practice: a consolidated framework for advancing implementation science. Implementation Science, 4(1), 50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2736161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2736161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-4-50</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colquhoun, H., Grimshaw, J., &amp; Wensing, M. (2013). Mapping KT interventions to barriers and facilitators. In S. E. Straus, J. Tetroe, &amp; I. D. Graham (Eds.), Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice (2nd ed., pp. 137&#x2013;149).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grol, R., Bosch, M., &amp; Wensing, M. (2013). Development and selection of strategies to improve patient care. In R. Grol, M. Wensing, M. Eccles, &amp; D. Davis (Eds.), Improving patient care: the implementation of change in health care (2nd ed., pp. 167&#x2013;183): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell, B. J., Waltz, T. J., Chinman, M. J., Damschroder, L. J., Smith, J. L., Matthieu, M. M., et al. (2015). A refined compilation of implementation strategies: results from the Expert Recommendations for Implementing Change (ERIC) project. Implementation Science, 10(1), 21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25889199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4328074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-015-0209-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones, J., &amp; Hunter, D. (1995). Consensus methods for medical and health services research. British Medical Journal, 311(7001), 376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7640549</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2550437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.311.7001.376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fixsen, D. L., Naoom, S. F., Blase, K. A., &amp; Friedman, R. M. (2005). Implementation research: a synthesis of the literature (T. N. I. R. Network, Trans.). Tampa, FL: University of South Florida: Louis de la Parte Florida Mental Health Institute.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grol, R., Ouwens, M., &amp; Wollershein, H. (2013). Planning and organizing the change process. In R. Grol, M. Wensing, M. Eccles, &amp; D. Davis (Eds.), Improving patient care: the implementation of change in health care (2nd ed., pp. 64&#x2013;74): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Straus, S. E., Tetroe, J., Bhattacharyya, O., Zwarenstein, M., &amp; Graham, I. D. (2013). Monitoring knowledge and evaluating outcomes. In S. E. Straus, J. Tetroe, &amp; I. D. Graham (Eds.), Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice (2nd ed., pp. 227&#x2013;236): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sales, A. (2013). Quality improvement theories. In S. E. Straus, J. Tetroe, &amp; I. D. Graham (Eds.), Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice (2nd ed., pp. 320&#x2013;328): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasgow, R. E., Vogt, T. M., &amp; Boles, S. M. (1999). Evaluating the public health impact of health promotion interventions: the RE-AIM framework. American Journal of Public Health, 89(9), 1322&#x2013;1327.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10474547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1508772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.89.9.1322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhattacharyya, O., Hayden, L., &amp; Zwarenstein, M. (2013). Methodologies to evalute effectiveness of knowledge translation interventions. In S. E. Straus, J. Tetroe, &amp; I. D. Graham Eds, Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice (2nd ed., pp. 331&#x2013;348): John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaplan, H. C., Brady, P. W., Dritz, M. C., Hooper, D. K., Linam, W. M., Froehle, C. M., et al. (2010). The influence of context on quality improvement success in health care: a systematic review of the literature. The Milbank Quarterly, 88(4), 500&#x2013;559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21166868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3037175</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-0009.2010.00611.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies, B., &amp; Edwards, N. (2013). Sustaining knowledge use. In S. E. Straus, J. Tetroe, &amp; I. D. Graham (Eds.), Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice (2nd ed., pp. 237&#x2013;248).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh, T., Robert, G., Macfarlane, F., Bate, P., &amp; Kyriakidou, O. (2004). Diffusion of innovations in service organizations: systematic review and recommendations. The Milbank Quarterly, 82(4), 581&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15595944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2690184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0887-378X.2004.00325.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis, K., Schoenbaum, S. C., &amp; Audet, A.-M. (2005). A 2020 vision of patient-centered primary care. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 20(10), 953&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16191145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">1490238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1525-1497.2005.0178.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haggerty, J., Burge, F., L&#xe9;vesque, J.-F., Gass, D., Pineault, R., Beaulieu, M.-D., et al. (2007). Operational definitions of attributes of primary health care: consensus among Canadian experts. The Annals of Family Medicine, 5(4), 336&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17664500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1370/afm.682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berwick, D. M., Nolan, T. W., &amp; Whittington, J. (2008). The triple aim: care, health, and cost. Health Affairs, 27(3), 759&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.27.3.759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18474969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starfield, B., Shi, L., &amp; Macinko, J. (2005). Contribution of primary care to health systems and health. The Milbank Quarterly, 83(3), 457&#x2013;502.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16202000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">2690145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-0009.2005.00409.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rathert, C., Wyrwich, M. D., &amp; Boren, S. A. (2013). Patient-centered care and outcomes: a systematic review of the literature. Medical Care Research and Review, 70(4), 351&#x2013;379.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23169897</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077558712465774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoff, T., Weller, W., &amp; DePuccio, M. (2012). The patient-centered medical home: a review of recent research. Medical Care Research and Review, 69(6), 619&#x2013;644.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22645100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077558712447688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson, G. L., Powers, B. J., Chatterjee, R., Bettger, J. P., Kemper, A. R., Hasselblad, V., et al. (2013). The patient-centered medical home: a systematic review. Annals of Internal Medicine, 158(3), 169&#x2013;178.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24779044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-158-3-201302050-00579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen, D., McDaniel, R. R., Jr., Crabtree, B. F., &amp; Ruhe, M. C. (2004). A practice change model for quality improvement in primary care practice. Journal of Healthcare Management, 49(3), 155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15190858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00115514-200405000-00005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh, T. (2013). Primary health care: theory and practice: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Primary Care Network Management Office. (2019). Alberta PCNs.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The College of Family Physicians of Canadain. (2019). A New Vision for Canada: Family Practice - The Patient&#x2019;s Medical Home 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang, A., &amp; Ritchie, C. (2015). Patient-centered models of care: closing the gaps in physician readiness. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 30(7), 870&#x2013;872.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25801696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">4471006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-015-3282-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>