<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">35227873</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-8503</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of renal nutrition : the official journal of the Council on Renal Nutrition of the National Kidney Foundation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Ren Nutr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Protocol for the IMPACT Trial: Improving Healthcare Outcomes in American Transplant Recipients Using Culturally-Tailored Novel Technology.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e1</StartPage><EndPage>e12</EndPage><MedlinePgn>e1-e12</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1053/j.jrn.2022.02.004</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1051-2276(22)00019-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Kidney transplant (KT) recipients face post-transplant health issues. Immunosuppressive agents can cause hyperlipidemia, hypertension, post-transplant diabetes, and glomerulopathy. Post-transplant weight gain and decreased activity are associated with poor quality of life, sleep, and cardiometabolic outcomes. This study will test the feasibility and acceptability of a culturally tailored diet and exercise intervention for KT patients delivered immediately post-transplant using novel technology. A registered dietitian nutritionist (RDN) and physical rehabilitation therapist will examine participants' cultural background, preferences, and health-related obstacles (with consultation from the transplant team) to create an individualized exercise and meal plan. The RDN will provide medical nutrition therapy via the nutrition care process throughout the course of the intervention. The Twistle Patient Engagement Platform will be used to deliver and collect survey data, communicate with participants, and promote retention. Outcomes to be assessed include intervention feasibility and acceptability and intervention efficacy on patients' adherence, medical, quality of life, and occupational outcomes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 National Kidney Foundation, Inc. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rice</LastName><ForeName>Claudia M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Healthcare Equity in Kidney Disease (CHEK-D), University of New Mexico Health Science Center, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Pooja P</ForeName><Initials>PP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology Division, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico, School of Medicine, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Judd</LastName><ForeName>Nila S</ForeName><Initials>NS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Healthcare Equity in Kidney Disease (CHEK-D), University of New Mexico Health Science Center, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jimenez</LastName><ForeName>Elizabeth Yakes</ForeName><Initials>EY</Initials><Suffix>Dr</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Pediatrics and Internal Medicine and College of Population Health, University of New Mexico Health Sciences Center, New Mexico; Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blair</LastName><ForeName>Cindy K</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Epidemiology, Biostatistics, and Preventive Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico, New Mexico; University of New Mexico Comprehensive Cancer Center, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Washburn</LastName><ForeName>Amy</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Healthcare Equity in Kidney Disease (CHEK-D), University of New Mexico Health Science Center, New Mexico; Presbyterian Healthcare Services, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Calvin</LastName><ForeName>Christine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Healthcare Equity in Kidney Disease (CHEK-D), University of New Mexico Health Science Center, New Mexico; Center for Diabetes and Nutrition Education, University of New Mexico Health Sciences Center, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steiber</LastName><ForeName>Alison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Suffix>Dr</Suffix><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Yiliang</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Epidemiology, Biostatistics, and Preventive Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Argyropoulos</LastName><ForeName>Christos</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology Division, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico, School of Medicine, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Unruh</LastName><ForeName>Mark</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology Division, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico, School of Medicine, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dew</LastName><ForeName>Mary Amanda</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, School of Medicine, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Departments of Epidemiology and Biostatistics, Graduate School of Public Health, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Department of Psychology, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Department of Acute and Tertiary Care, School of Nursing, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Myaskovsky</LastName><ForeName>Larissa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Healthcare Equity in Kidney Disease (CHEK-D), University of New Mexico Health Science Center, New Mexico; Nephrology Division, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico, School of Medicine, New Mexico. Electronic address: lmyaskovsky@salud.unm.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K07 CA215937</GrantID><Acronym>CA</Acronym><Agency>NCI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR001449</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Ren Nutr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9112938</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1051-2276</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="N">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013672" MajorTopicYN="N">Technology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D066027" MajorTopicYN="Y">Transplant Recipients</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015430" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Gain</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diet and exercise</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kidney transplant</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle modification</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical nutrition therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-transplant</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35227873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1784046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9058226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jrn.2022.02.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1051-2276(22)00019-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hariharan S, Israni AK, Danovitch G. Long-Term Survival after Kidney Transplantation. N Engl J Med. 2021;385(8):729&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34407344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neale J, Smith AC. Cardiovascular risk factors following renal transplant. World J Transpl. 2015. Dec 24;5(4):183&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4689929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26722646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangaswami J, Mathew RO, Parasuraman R, Tantisattamo E, Lubetzky M, Rao S, et al. Cardiovascular disease in the kidney transplant recipient: epidemiology, diagnosis and management strategies. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2019;34(5):760&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30984976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saran R, Robinson B, Abbott KC, Agodoa LY, Albertus P, Ayanian J, et al. US Renal Data System 2016 Annual Data Report: Epidemiology of Kidney Disease in the United States. Am J Kidney Dis. 2017. Mar;69(3 Suppl 1):A7&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6605045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28236831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moons P, Vanrenterghem Y, Van Hooff JP, Squifflet JP, Margodt D, Mullens M, et al. Health-related quality of life and symptom experience in tacrolimus-based regimens after renal transplantation: A multicentre study. Transpl Int. 2003;16(9):653&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12748758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burne-Taney MJ, Yokota N, Rabb H. Persistent renal and extrarenal immune changes after severe ischemic injury. Kidney Int. 2005. Mar;67(3):1002&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15698438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Covic A, Mardare N, Gusbeth-Tatomir P, Buhaescu I, Goldsmith DJ. Acute effect of CyA A (Neoral) on large artery hemodynamics in renal transplant patients. Kidney Int. 2005. Feb;67(2):732&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15673323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juskowa J, Bart&#x142;omiejczyk J, Paczek L, Rowinski W, Szmidt J, Foroncewicz B, et al. Total homocysteine as a risk factor for vascular disease in renal transplant recipients. Transpl Proc. 2002;34(2):576&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12009629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merkel M Homocysteine as a risk factor of cardiovascular disease. Int Congr Ser. 2004;1262:376&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pavarino-Bertelli EC, Sanches de Alvarenga MP, Goloni-Bertollo EM, Baptista MA, Haddad R, Hoerh NF, et al. Hyperhomocysteinemia and MTHFR C677T and A1298C polymorphisms are associated with chronic allograft nephropathy in renal transplant recipients. Transpl Proc. 2004. Dec;36(10):2979&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15686674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cosio FG, Pesavento TE, Kim S, Osei K, Henry M, Ferguson RM. Patient survival after renal transplantation: IV. Impact of post-transplant diabetes. Kidney Int. 2002. Oct;62(4):1440&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12234317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir MR, Burgess ED, Cooper JE, Fenves AZ, Goldsmith D, McKay D, et al. Assessment and management of hypertension in transplant patients. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2015. Jun;26(6):1248&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4446882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25653099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shivaswamy V, Boerner B, Larsen J. Post-Transplant Diabetes Mellitus: Causes, Treatment, and Impact on Outcomes. Endocr Rev. 2016. Feb;37(1):37&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4740345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26650437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi A, Hu SL, Bostom A. Physical Activity in Kidney Transplant Recipients: A Review. Am J Kidney Dis. 2018. Feb 23;</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29482935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tania Janaudis-Ferreira Sunita Mathur, Deliva Robin, Howes Nancy, Patterson Catherine, R&#xe4;kel Agn&#xe8;s, et al. Exercise for Solid Organ Transplant Candidates and Recipients: A Joint Position Statement of the Canadian Society of Transplantation and CAN-RESTORE. Transplantation. 2019;103:e220&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31461743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calella P, Hern&#xe1;ndez-S&#xe1;nchez S, Garofalo C, Ruiz JR, Carrero JJ, Bellizzi V. Exercise training in kidney transplant recipients: a systematic review. J Nephrol. 2019;32(4):567&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30649716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer SC, Maggo JK, Campbell KL, Craig JC, Johnson DW, Sutanto B, et al. Dietary interventions for adults with chronic kidney disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;4(Article # CD011998).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6478277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28434208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Janaudis-Ferreira T, Mathur S, Konidis S, Tansey CM, Beaurepaire C. Outcomes in randomized controlled trials of exercise interventions in solid organ transplant. World J Transpl. 2016. Dec 24;6(4):774&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5175238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28058230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klaassen G, Zelle DM, Navis GJ, Dijkema D, Bemelman FJ, Bakker SJL, et al. Lifestyle intervention to improve quality of life and prevent weight gain after renal transplantation: Design of the Active Care after Transplantation (ACT) randomized controlled trial. BMC Nephrol. 2017. Sep 15;18(1):296.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5599936</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28915863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pooranfar S, Shakoor E, Shafahi M, Salesi M, Karimi M, Roozbeh J, et al. The effect of exercise training on quality and quantity of sleep and lipid profile in renal transplant patients: a randomized clinical trial. Int J Organ Transpl Med. 2014;5(4):157&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4243047</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25426284</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Preventive Services Task Force, Krist AH, Davidson KW, Mangione CM, Barry MJ, Cabana M, et al. Behavioral Counseling Interventions to Promote a Healthy Diet and Physical Activity for Cardiovascular Disease Prevention in Adults With Cardiovascular Risk Factors: US Preventive Services Task Force Recommendation Statement. JAMA. 2020. Nov 24;324(20):2069.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33231670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evert AB, Dennison M, Gardner CD, Garvey WT, Lau KHK, MacLeod J, et al. Nutrition Therapy for Adults With Diabetes or Prediabetes: A Consensus Report. Diabetes Care. 2019. May;42(5):731&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7011201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31000505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilding JPH, Batterham RL, Calanna S, Davies M, Van Gaal LF, Lingvay I, et al. Once-Weekly Semaglutide in Adults with Overweight or Obesity. N Engl J Med. 2021. Mar 18;384(11):989&#x2013;1002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33567185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah T, Kasravi A, Huang E, Hayashi R, Young B, Cho YW, et al. Risk factors for development of new-onset diabetes mellitus after kidney transplantation. Transplantation. 2006;82(12):1673&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17198258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Hooff JP, Christiaans MH, van Duijnhoven EM. Evaluating mechanisms of post-transplant diabetes mellitus. Nephrol Dial Transpl. 2004. Dec;19 Suppl 6:vi8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15575024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weir MR, Fink JC. Risk for posttransplant diabetes mellitus with current immunosuppressive medications. Am J Kidney Dis. 1999;34(1):1&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10401009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didsbury M, McGee RG, Tong A, Craig JC, Chapman JR, Chadban S, et al. Exercise training in solid organ transplant recipients: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Transplantation. 2013. Mar 15;95(5):679&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23364480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter PL, Hector L, Ray K, Lynes L, Dibble S, Paul SM, et al. A randomized trial of exercise training after renal transplantation. Transplantation. 2002;71(1):42&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12134097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter PL, Hector L, Ray K, Lynes L, Paul SM, Dodd M, et al. Effects of exercise training on coronary heart disease risk factors in renal transplant recipients. Am J Kidney Dis. 2003;42(2):362&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Standards of medical care in diabetes&#x2014;2006. Diabetes Care. 2006;29(Suppl 1):S4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16373931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson J, Wilkinson A, Dantal J, Dotta F, Haller H, Hernandez D, et al. New-onset diabetes after transplantation: 2003 International consensus guidelines. Proceedings of an international expert panel meeting. Barcelona, Spain, 19 February 2003. Transplantation. 2003. May 27;75(10 Suppl):SS3&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12775942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikizler TA, Burrowes JD, Byham-Gray LD, Campbell KL, Carrero J-J, Chan W, et al. KDOQI Clinical Practice Guideline for Nutrition in CKD: 2020 Update. Am J Kidney Dis. 2020. Sep;76(3):S1&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32829751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics. CKD Macronutrients Executive Summary of Reccomendations [Internet]. Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics; 2020.  [cited 2021 Jul 23]. Available from: https://www.andeal.org/topic.cfm?menu=5303&amp;cat=5558</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network and Scientific Registry of Transplant Recipients. Transplants in the U.S. by Recipient Ethnicity. 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22107249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albarracin D, Wilson K, Chan MS, Durantini M, Sanchez F. Action and inaction in multi-behaviour recommendations: a meta-analysis of lifestyle interventions. Health Psychol Rev. 2018. Mar;12(1):1&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7069597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28831848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh Kulmeet, Ross Dave. Twistle Inc., [Internet]. 2018.  [cited 2021 Oct 4]. Available from: https://www.twistle.com/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sautenet B, Tong A, Manera KE, Chapman JR, Warrens AN, Rosenbloom D, et al. Developing Consensus-Based Priority Outcome Domains for Trials in Kidney Transplantation: A Multinational Delphi Survey With Patients, Caregivers, and Health Professionals. Transplantation. 2017. Aug;101(8):1875&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5603314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28738403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastelz A, Tzvetanov IG, Fernhall B, Shetty A, Gallon L, West-Thielke P, et al. Experimental protocol of a randomized controlled clinical trial investigating the effects of personalized exercise rehabilitation on kidney transplant recipients&#x2019; outcomes. Contemp Clin Trials. 2015. Nov;45(Pt B):170&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26475662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tzvetanov I, West-Thielke P, D&#x2019;Amico G, Johnsen M, Ladik A, Hachaj G, et al. A novel and personalized rehabilitation program for obese kidney transplant recipients. Transpl Proc. 2014. Dec;46(10):3431&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25498067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickerson L, Rozenberg D, Janaudis-Ferreira T, Deliva R, Lo V, Beauchamp G, et al. Physical rehabilitation for lung transplant candidates and recipients: An evidence-informed clinical approach. World J Transpl. 2016. Sep 24;6(3):517&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5036121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27683630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KDIGO 2012 Clinical Practice Guideline for the Evaluation and Management of Chronic Kidney Disease. 2013;1&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23989362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inker LA, Astor BC, Fox CH, Isakova T, Lash JP, Peralta CA, et al. KDOQI US commentary on the 2012 KDIGO clinical practice guideline for the evaluation and management of CKD. Am J Kidney Dis. 2014. May;63(5):713&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24647050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong T, Bull F. Development of the World Health Organization Global Physical Activity Questionnaire (GPAQ). J Public Health. 2006. Apr;14(2):66&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strath SJ, Kaminsky LA, Ainsworth BE, Ekelund U, Freedson PS, Gary RA, et al. Guide to the Assessment of Physical Activity: Clinical and Research Applications: A Scientific Statement From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2013. Nov 12;128(20):2259&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Thoracic Society. ATS Committee on Proficiency Standards for Clinical Pulmonary Function Laboratories. ATS statement: guidelines for the six-minute walk test. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine; 2015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12091180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessie Jones C, Roberta E
Rikli, Beam William C.. A 30-s chair-stand test as a measure of lower body strength in community-residing older adults [Internet]. Research Quarterly for Exercise and Sport; 1999. Available from: https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/A-30-s-chair-stand-test-as-a-measure-of-lower-body-Jones-Rikli/2be926f0f014ce4bb4ac4488c29784660a682570</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10380242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lesinski M, Hortob&#xe1;gyi T, Muehlbauer T, Gollhofer A, Granacher U. Effects of Balance Training on Balance Performance in Healthy Older Adults: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Sports Med Auckl NZ. 2015. Dec;45(12):1721&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4656699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26325622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Springer BA, Marin R, Cyhan T, Roberts H, Gill NW. Normative Values for the Unipedal Stance Test with Eyes Open and Closed. J Geriatr Phys Ther [Internet]. 2007;30(1). Available from: https://journals.lww.com/jgpt/Fulltext/2007/04000/Normative_Values_for_the_Unipedal_Stance_Test_with.3.aspx</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19839175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Briggs Randall C, Gossman Marilyn R, Birch Robert, Drews Judith E, Shaddeau Shirley A. Balance Performance Among Noninstitutionalized Elderly Women. Phys Ther. 1989. Sep 1;69(9):748&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2772037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borg GA. Psychophysical bases of perceived exertion. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1982;14(5):377&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7154893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyden K, Keadle SK, Staudenmayer J, Freedson PS. The activPALTM Accurately Classifies Activity Intensity Categories in Healthy Adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2017. May;49(5):1022&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5469371</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28410327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kozey-Keadle S, Libertine A, Lyden K, Staudenmayer J, Freedson PS. Validation of wearable monitors for assessing sedentary behavior. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2011. Aug;43(8):1561&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21233777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greater Metropolitan Clinical Task Force (Renal Service Network). Evidence based practice guidelines for the nutritional management of adult renal transplant recipients. Sydney, Australia; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ikizler TA, Burrowes JD, Byham-Gray LD, Campbell KL, Carrero J-J, Chan W, et al. KDOQI Clinical Practice Guideline for Nutrition in CKD: 2020 Update. Am J Kidney Dis. 2020. Sep;76(3):S1&#x2013;107.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32829751</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallegos Danielle, Millichamp Anna. HACC food service client cultural food preferences assessment tool [Internet]. Queensland University of Technology; 2012.  [cited 2021 Jul 23]. Available from: https://eprints.qut.edu.au/55544/8/HACC_FoodServiceClient_CulturalFoodPreferencesAssessmentTool.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swan WI, Vivanti A, Hakel-Smith NA, Hotson B, Orrevall Y, Trostler N, et al. Nutrition Care Process and Model Update: Toward Realizing People-Centered Care and Outcomes Management. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2017. Dec;117(12):2003&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28988837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG. Research electronic data capture (REDCap)&#x2014;A metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support. J Biomed Inform. 2009. Apr;42(2):377&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake C, Zhang Y, Chaiyachati KH, Polsky D. The Limitations of Poor Broadband Internet Access for Telemedicine Use in Rural America: An Observational Study. Ann Intern Med. 2019;epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31108509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Struminger BB, Arora S. Leveraging Telehealth to Improve Health Care Access in Rural America: It Takes More Than Bandwidth. Ann Intern Med. 2019;epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31108511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attkisson CC, Larsen DL, Hargreaves WA, LeVois M, Nguyen TD, Roberts RE, et al. Client Satisfaction Questionnaire-8 (CSQ-8). In: American Psychiatric Association Task Force for the Handbook of Psychiatric Measures; John Rush A, editor. Handbook of psychiatric measures. Washington, DC: American Psychiatric Publishing; 2007. p. 176&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke John. SUS - A quick and dirty usability scale. In: Jordan PW, Thomas B, Weerdmeester B, McClelland IL, editors. Usability Evaluation In Industry. Bristol, PA: Taylor and Francis; 1996. p. 189&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berendsen BA, Hendriks MR, Meijer K, Plasqui G, Schaper NC, Savelberg HH. Which activity monitor to use? Validity, reproducibility and user friendliness of three activity monitors. BMC Public Health. 2014. Dec;14(1):749.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4133601</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25059233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Measures. PROMIS (Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System). 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flythe JE, Hilliard TS, Ikeler K, Keller S, Gipson DS, Grandinetti AC, et al. Toward Patient-Centered Innovation. Concept Framew Patient-Rep Outcome Meas Transform Kidney Replace Devices. 2020;CJN.00110120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hays RD, Spritzer KL, Schalet BD, Cella D. PROMIS&#xae;&#x2212;29 v2.0 profile physical and mental health summary scores. Qual Life Res. 2018. Jul 1;27(7):1885&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5999556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29569016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang E, Ekundayo O, Peipert JD, Edwards N, Bansal A, Richardson C, et al. Validation of the Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS)-57 and &#x2212;29 item short forms among kidney transplant recipients. Qual Life Res. 2019. Mar;28(3):815&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30467780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verberne WR, Das-Gupta Z, Allegretti AS, Bart HAJ, van Biesen W, Garcia-Garcia G, et al. Development of an International Standard Set of Value-Based Outcome Measures for Patients With Chronic Kidney Disease: A Report of the International Consortium for Health Outcomes Measurement (ICHOM) CKD Working Group. Am J Kidney Dis. 2019. Mar;73(3):372&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30579710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whiteneck GG, Charlifue SW, Gerhart KA, Overholser JD, Richardson GN. Quantifying handicap: A new measure of long-term rehabilitation outcomes. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1992;73:519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1622299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sander AM, Pappadis MR, Davis LC, Clark AN, Evans G, Struchen MA, et al. Relationship of race/ethnicity and income to community integration following traumatic brain injury: Investigation in a non-rehabilitation trauma sample. Neuro Rehabil. 2009;24(1):15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19208954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mays VM, Ponce NA, Washington DL, Cochran SD. Classification of race and ethnicity: Implications for public health. Annu Rev Public Health. 2003;24:83&#x2013;110.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3681827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12668755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jassal SV, Schaubel DE, Fenton SSA. Baseline comorbidity in kidney transplant recipients: A comparison of comorbidity indices. Transplantation. 2005;46(1):136&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15983967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tkachuk Gregg A., Harris Cheryl A.. Psychometric Properties of the Tampa Scale for Kinesiophobia-11 (TSK-11). J Pain. 2012;13(10):970&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23031396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pearlin L, Schooler C. The structure of coping. J Health Soc Behav. 1978;19:2&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">649936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dew MA, DiMartini AF, De Vito Dabbs A, Zomak R, De Geest S, Dobbels F, et al. Adherence to the medical regimen during the first two years after lung transplantation. Transplantation. 2008;85(2):193&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3387784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18212623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myaskovsky L, Switzer GE, Dew MA, Shapiro R, Unruh M, Ford AF, et al. Understanding Race and Culture in Living Donor Kidney Transplantation. NIDDK; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran GM, Bauer M, Mittman B, Pyne JM, Stetler C. Effectiveness-implementation hybrid designs: Combining elements of clinical effectiveness and implementation research to enhance public health impact. Med Care. 2012;50(3):217&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3731143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22310560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder LJ, Hagedorn HJ. A guiding framework and approach for implementation research in substance use disorders treatment. Psychol Addict Behav J Soc Psychol Addict Behav. 2011;25(2):194&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21443291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Minor BL, Elliott V, Fernandez M, O&#x2019;Neal L, et al. The REDCap consortium: Building an international community of software platform partners. J Biomed Inform. 2019. Jul;95:103208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7254481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31078660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore CG, Carter RE, Nietert PJ, Stewart PW. Recommendations for Planning Pilot Studies in Clinical and Translational Research. Clin Transl Sci. 2011;4:332&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3203750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22029804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SocioCultural Research Consultants, LLC. Dedoose Version 9.0.17, web application for managing, analyzing, and presenting qualitative and mixed method research data. 2021. Available from: www.dedoose.com.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller W, Crabtree BF. Primary care research: a multi typology and qualitative road map. In: Crabtree BF, Miller WL, editors. Doing Qualitative Research. London: Sage Press; 1992.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Painter PL, Hector L, Ray K, Lynes L, Paul SM, Dodd M, et al. Effects of exercise training on coronary heart disease risk factors in renal transplant recipients. Am J Kidney Dis. 2003;42(2):362&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12900820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor EM, Koufaki P, Mercer TH, Lindup H, Nugent E, Goldsmith D, et al. Long-term pulse wave velocity outcomes with aerobic and resistance training in kidney transplant recipients - A pilot randomised controlled trial. PLoS One. 2017;12(2):e0171063.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5291475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28158243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wesselman H, Ford CG, Leyva Y, Li X, Chang C-CH, Dew MA, et al. 
Social Determinants of Health and Race Disparities in Kidney Transplant. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol [Internet]. 2021. 
Jan
28 [cited 2021 Jan 28]; Available from: https://cjasn.asnjournals.org/content/early/2021/01/27/CJN.04860420</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7863655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33509963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myaskovsky L, Kendall K, Li X, Chang CCH, Pleis JR, Croswell E, et al. Unexpected race and ethnicity differences in the U.S. National Veterans Affairs Kidney Transplant Program. Transplantation. 2019;103(12):2701&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6937592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31397801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>