<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36348406</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2056-7529</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Research involvement and engagement</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Res Involv Engagem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Co-designing person-centred quality indicator implementation for primary care in Alberta: a consensus study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>59</StartPage><MedlinePgn>59</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">59</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40900-022-00397-z</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">We aimed to contribute to developing practical guidance for implementing person-centred quality indicators (PC-QIs) for primary care in Alberta, Canada. As a first step in this process, we conducted stakeholder-guided prioritization of PC-QIs and implementation strategies. Stakeholder engagement is necessary to ensure PC-QI implementation is adapted to the context and local needs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We used an adapted nominal group technique (NGT) consensus process. Panelists were presented with 26 PC-QIs, and implementation strategies. Both PC-QIs and strategies were identified from our extensive previous engagement of patients, caregivers, healthcare providers, and quality improvement leaders. The NGT objectives were to: 1. Prioritize PC-QIs and implementation strategies; and 2. Facilitate the participation of diverse primary care stakeholders in Alberta, including patients, healthcare providers, and quality improvement staff. Panelists participated in three rounds of activities. In the first, panelists individually ranked and commented on the PC-QIs and strategies. The summarized results were discussed in the second-round face-to-face group meeting. For the last round, panelists provided their final individual rankings, informed by the group discussion. Finally, we conducted an evaluation of the consensus process from the panelists' perspectives.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Eleven primary care providers, patient partners, and quality improvement staff from across Alberta participated. The panelists prioritized the following PC-QIs: 'Patient and caregiver involvement in decisions about their care and treatment'; 'Trusting relationship with healthcare provider'; 'Health information technology to support person-centred care'; 'Co-designing care in partnership with communities'; and 'Overall experience'. Implementation strategies prioritized included: 'Develop partnerships'; 'Obtain quality improvement resources'; 'Needs assessment (stakeholders are engaged about their needs/priorities for person-centred measurement)'; 'Align measurement efforts'; and 'Engage champions'. Our evaluation suggests that panelists felt that the process was valuable for planning the implementation and obtaining feedback, that their input was valued, and that most would continue to collaborate with other stakeholders to implement the PC-QIs.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study demonstrates the value of co-design and participatory approaches for engaging stakeholders in adapting PC-QI implementation for the primary care context in Alberta, Canada. Collaboration with stakeholders can promote buy-in for ongoing engagement and ensure implementation will lead to meaningful improvements that matter to patients and providers.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manalili</LastName><ForeName>Kimberly</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0826-7298</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, Cumming School of Medicine, 3D10, University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 4Z6, Canada. kmanalil@ucalgary.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patient Engagement Platform - Alberta Strategy for Patient Oriented Research, University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Cal Wenzel Precision Health Building, Calgary, AB, Canada. kmanalil@ucalgary.ca.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Scott</LastName><ForeName>Catherine M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, Cumming School of Medicine, 3D10, University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 4Z6, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sociology, University of Calgary, 2500 University Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 1N4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hemmelgarn</LastName><ForeName>Brenda</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Alberta, 2J2.00 Walter C Mackenzie Health Sciences Centre 8440 112 St. NW, Edmonton, AB, T6G 2R7, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Beirne</LastName><ForeName>Maeve</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, Cumming School of Medicine, 3D10, University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 4Z6, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, University of Calgary, 2500 University Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 1N4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bailey</LastName><ForeName>Allan L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, University of Alberta, 5-16 University Terrace, 8303 112 St., Edmonton, AB, T6G 1K4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haener</LastName><ForeName>Michel K</ForeName><Initials>MK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Grande Prairie Primary Care Network, 11745 105 St #104, Grande Prairie, AB, T8V 8L1, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Banerjee</LastName><ForeName>Cyrene</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patient and Community Engagement Research Program (PaCER), University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 4Z6, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Peters</LastName><ForeName>Sue P</ForeName><Initials>SP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Quality Council of Alberta, 210, 811 14 St NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 2A4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chiodo</LastName><ForeName>Mirella</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, University of Alberta, 5-16 University Terrace, 8303 112 St., Edmonton, AB, T6G 1K4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Aghajafari</LastName><ForeName>Fariba</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, Cumming School of Medicine, 3D10, University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 4Z6, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, University of Calgary, 2500 University Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 1N4, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santana</LastName><ForeName>Maria J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Community Health Sciences, Cumming School of Medicine, 3D10, University of Calgary, 3280 Hospital Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T2N 4Z6, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department Paediatrics, Alberta Children's Hospital, University of Calgary, 28 Oki Drive NW, Calgary, AB, T3B 6A8, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>201709PJT</GrantID><Agency>Canadian Institutes for Health Research</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Res Involv Engagem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101708164</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2056-7529</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Person-centred care (PCC) is a model of care where patient needs and preferences are included in decisions about care and treatment. To improve PCC in primary care in Alberta, Canada, we plan to use person-centred quality indicators (PC-QIs). Using PC-QIs involves surveying patients about their care experiences and using this information to make improvements. For example, if 20% of patients do not feel they are getting enough information, the clinic may create a checklist for the providers so information is not missed. We engaged a panel of 11 people, including patients, family doctors, and staff who support quality improvement in clinics across the province to decide together which PC-QIs primary care clinics in Alberta should use. We also asked the panel to decide the most important strategies that would make using the PC-QIs more successful. The panel chose PC-QIs related to: patient and caregiver involvement in decisions about care and treatment, a trusting relationship with the healthcare provider, having health information technology to support PCC, partnering with communities in healthcare, and the patient&#x2019;s overall experience. The most important strategies were: developing partnerships among people working in primary care in Alberta, discussing their needs and common efforts for improving PCC, engaging &#x201c;champions,&#x201d; and securing funding that would be needed. Finally, we asked the panelists to share their experiences with participating in this process. Panelists found the process useful and that their input was valued. Most panelists would also like to continue to work together to put the PC-QIs into practice.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Context consensus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Implementation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Participatory research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Person-centred care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality indicators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Strategies</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36348406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9641306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40900-022-00397-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40900-022-00397-z</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Haggerty J, et al. Operational definitions of attributes of primary health care: consensus among Canadian experts. Ann Fam Med. 2007;5(4):336&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1934980</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17664500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T. Primary health care: theory and practice. Wiley; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montague T, et al. Patient-centred care in canada: key components and the path forward. Healthc Q. 2017;20(1):50&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28550701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis K, Schoenbaum SC, Audet A-M. A 2020 vision of patient-centered primary care. J Gen Intern Med. 2005;20(10):953&#x2013;957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1490238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16191145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berwick DM, Nolan TW, Whittington J. The triple aim: care, health, and cost. Health Aff. 2008;27(3):759&#x2013;769.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18474969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana M-J, et al. Improving the quality of person-centred healthcare from the patient perspective: development of person-centred quality indicators. BMJ Open. 2020;10(10):e037323.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7597468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33122312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The College of Family Physicians of Canada. A New Vision for Canada: Family Practice - The Patient&#x2019;s Medical Home 2019. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manalili K, Santana MJ. Using implementation science to inform the integration of electronic patient-reported experience measures (ePREMs) into healthcare quality improvement: description of a theory-based application in primary care. Qual Life Res. 2021;30(11):1&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32715388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Handley MA, Gorukanti A, Cattamanchi A. Strategies for implementing implementation science: a methodological overview. Emerg Med J. 2016;33(9):660&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8011054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26893401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell BJ, et al. Enhancing the impact of implementation strategies in healthcare: a research agenda. Front Public Health. 2019;7:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6350272</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30723713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell BJ, et al. Methods to improve the selection and tailoring of implementation strategies. J Behav Health Serv Res. 2017;44(2):177&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4761530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26289563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rooijen M, et al. Stakeholder engagement from problem analysis to implementation strategies for a patient-reported experience measure in disability care: a qualitative study on the process and experiences. Health Expect. 2021;24(1):53&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7879541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33125177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham ID, et al. Lost in knowledge translation: time for a map? J Contin Educ Heal Prof. 2006;26(1):13&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16557505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen S, Graham ID. Integrated knowledge translation. In: Straus SE, Tetroe J, Graham ID, editors. Knowledge translation in health care: moving from evidence to practice. Wiley; 2013. pp. 14&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenhalgh T, et al. Diffusion of innovations in service organizations: systematic review and recommendations. Milbank Q. 2004;82(4):581&#x2013;629.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2690184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15595944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen D, et al. A practice change model for quality improvement in primary care practice. J Healthc Manag. 2004;49(3):155.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15190858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Riet Paap J, et al. Strategies to implement evidence into practice to improve palliative care: recommendations of a nominal group approach with expert opinion leaders. BMC Palliat Care. 2015;14(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4589187</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26419434</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen J, Dyas J, Jones M. Building consensus in health care: a guide to using the nominal group technique. Br J Community Nurs. 2004;9(3):110&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15028996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey N, Holmes CA. Nominal group technique: an effective method for obtaining group consensus. Int J Nurs Pract. 2012;18(2):188&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22435983</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones J, Hunter D. Consensus methods for medical and health services research. BMJ Br Med J. 1995;311(7001):376.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2550437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7640549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leech NL, Onwuegbuzie AJ. Guidelines for conducting and reporting mixed research in the field of counseling and beyond. J Couns Dev. 2010;88(1):61&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Staniszewska S. et al. GRIPP2 reporting checklists: tools to improve reporting of patient and public involvement in research. BMJ. 2017;358:j3453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28768629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Potter M, Gordon S, Hamer P. The nominal group technique: a useful consensus methodology in physiotherapy research. N Z J Physiother. 2004;32:126&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana MJ, et al. How to practice person-centred care: a conceptual framework. Health Expect. 2018;21(2):429&#x2013;440.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5867327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29151269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana MJ, Sadia A, Lorenzetti DL, Jolley RJ, Manalili K, Quan H, Lu M. Measuring patient-centred system performance: a scoping review of patient-centred care quality indicators. BMJ Open. 2019;9(1):e023596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6326310</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30617101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmed S, et al. A qualitative study on measuring patient-centered care: Perspectives from clinician-scientists and quality improvement experts. Health Sci Rep. 2019;2(12):e140.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6920695</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31890898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doktorchik C, et al. Identifying Canadian patient-centred care measurement practices and quality indicators: a survey. CMAJ Open. 2018;6(4):E643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6298869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manalili K, et al. Codesigning person-centred quality indicators with diverse communities: a qualitative patient engagement study. Health Expect. 2021;25:2188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9615079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34854190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donabedian A. The quality of care: how can it be assessed? JAMA. 1988;260(12):1743&#x2013;1748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3045356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damschroder LJ, et al. Fostering implementation of health services research findings into practice: a consolidated framework for advancing implementation science. Implement Sci. 2009;4(1):50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2736161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19664226</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell BJ, et al. A refined compilation of implementation strategies: results from the expert recommendations for implementing change (ERIC) project. Implement Sci. 2015;10(1):21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4328074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25889199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leslie M, et al. An implementation history of primary health care transformation: Alberta&#x2019;s primary care networks and the people, time and culture of change. BMC Fam Pract. 2020;21(1):1&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7718828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33278880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qualtrics. 2021; Available from: https://www.qualtrics.com/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore JE, Khan S. Designing for implementation course and workbook. Ontario: The Center for Implementation; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan SS, et al. Using the nominal group technique: how to analyse across multiple groups. Health Serv Outcomes Res Method. 2014;14(3):92&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guetterman TC, Fetters MD, Creswell JW. Integrating quantitative and qualitative results in health science mixed methods research through joint displays. Ann Fam Med. 2015;13(6):554&#x2013;561.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4639381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26553895</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh H-F, Shannon SE. Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qual Health Res. 2005;15(9):1277&#x2013;1288.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rankin NM, et al. Adapting the nominal group technique for priority setting of evidence-practice gaps in implementation science. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2016;16(1):1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5002198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27566679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boivin A, et al. Target for improvement: a cluster randomised trial of public involvement in quality-indicator prioritisation (intervention development and study protocol) Implement Sci. 2011;6(1):1&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3118228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21554691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alberta Medical Association. Community-based primary care estimate. 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charif AB, et al. Effective strategies for scaling up evidence-based practices in primary care: a systematic review. Implement Sci. 2017;12(1):139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5700621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29166911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health Quality Council of Alberta. A case study evaluation: Crowfoot village famly practice and the taber clinic. Calgary, Alberta; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jull J, Giles A, Graham ID. Community-based participatory research and integrated knowledge translation: advancing the co-creation of knowledge. Implement Sci. 2017;12(1):150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5735911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29258551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Domecq JP, et al. Patient engagement in research: a systematic review. BMC Health Serv Res. 2014;14(1):89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3938901</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24568690</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jagosh J, et al. Uncovering the benefits of participatory research: implications of a realist review for health research and practice. Milbank Q. 2012;90(2):311&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3460206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22709390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott C, et al. Integrated health systems and integrated knowledge: creating space for putting knowledge into action. Healthc Q. 2009;13:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20057246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodyear-Smith F, Jackson C, Greenhalgh T. Co-design and implementation research: challenges and solutions for ethics committees. BMC Med Ethics. 2015;16(1):1&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4647576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26573410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banner D, et al. Patient and public engagement in integrated knowledge translation research: are we there yet? Res Involv Engagem. 2019;5(1):1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6373045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30805202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassan Z. The social labs revolution: a new approach to solving our most complex challenges. Berrett-Koehler Publishers; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tiesinga H, Berkhout R. Labcraft: how social labs cultivate change through innovation and collaboration. Labcraft Publishing; 2014.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>