<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38178914</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-2360</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>11</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in pediatrics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Pediatr</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Optimizing CFTR modulator therapy management for cystic fibrosis through the ReX platform.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1300968</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1300968</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1300968</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fped.2023.1300968</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cystic fibrosis (CF) is a chronic multi-systemic disease that requires a complex daily treatment regimen. Therefore, there is sub-optimal adherence to CF therapies, and it was shown to impact its clinical and economic burden. Cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator modulators (CFTRm) are high-cost medications that demonstrated significant benefit in clinical trials. The aim of this study was to evaluate the safety, usability, and efficacy of the ReX platform in medication management of CFTRm for the treatment of people with CF (pwCF).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">ReX is a patient engagement platform consisting of a cloud-based management system and a cell-enabled handheld device intended to dispense oral medication into the patient's mouth, following a pre-programmed treatment protocol. It provides real-time adherence data to caregivers and timely, personalized reminders to patients. This is a prospective multi-center open study for pwCFs older than 12 years, who had been prescribed CFTRm [elexacaftor/tezacaftor/ivacaftor (ETI) or tezacaftor/ivacaftor (TI)], and provided consent to use ReX platform to receive CFTRm and record their health condition. Study duration was 12-24 months, with clinic visits where physical examination, body mass index (BMI), and pulmonary function tests were performed, and user experience questionnaires were filled in.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ten pwCFs from two CF centers in Israel were included. The mean age was 31.5 years (range 15-74 years); eight were taking ETI and two TI. Median adherence to CFTRm was 97.5% (range 70%-100%) in the first year and 94% (range 84%-99%) in the second year, which is higher than the previously reported CFTRm adherence of &#x223c;80%. No adverse events related to the use of the platform were reported. Patients reported ReX to be valuable to their treatment management and user friendly. Estimated mean forced expiratory volume in 1&#x2005;s (FEV<sub>1</sub>%) increased from 74.4% to 80.8% (<i>p</i>&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.004) over 2&#x2005;years. Similarly, estimated BMI percentile increased from 53.5 to 59.0 (<i>p</i>&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Using the ReX platform in medication management of pwCF treated by CFTRm is safe, easy to use, and effective in improving the adherence to treatment and the clinical outcomes. Consequently, this device may potentially reduce costs to healthcare providers. Further larger and long-term studies are required to examine the clinical benefits of the ReX platform.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 Yaacoby-Bianu, Cohen-Cymberknoh, Shoseyov, Lavi, Ostrovski, Shteinberg and Livnat.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yaacoby-Bianu</LastName><ForeName>Karin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Pulmonology Unit and CF Center, Carmel Medical Center, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>B. Rappaport Faculty of Medicine, Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cohen-Cymberknoh</LastName><ForeName>Malena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Pulmonology Unit and Cystic Fibrosis Center, Hadassah Medical Center and Faculty of Medicine, Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shoseyov</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Pulmonology Unit and Cystic Fibrosis Center, Hadassah Medical Center and Faculty of Medicine, Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lavi</LastName><ForeName>Tal</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pharmacy Services, Carmel Medical Center, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ostrovski</LastName><ForeName>Ana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Pulmonology Unit and CF Center, Carmel Medical Center, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shteinberg</LastName><ForeName>Michal</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonology Institute and CF Center, Carmel Medical Center, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>B. Rappaport Faculty of Medicine, Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Livnat</LastName><ForeName>Galit</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pediatric Pulmonology Unit and CF Center, Carmel Medical Center, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>B. Rappaport Faculty of Medicine, Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Pediatr</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101615492</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-2360</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CFTR modulators</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adherence to chronic treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cystic fibrosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elexacaftor/tezacaftor/ivacaftor</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medication delivery platforms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">remote patient monitoring</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>MS declares grants from GSK, during the conduct of the study; personal fees and non-financial support from GSK&#xd0; grants; personal fees from Novartis; personal fees and non-financial support from Bohringer- Ingelheim; personal fees from Astra Zeneca; personal fees from Kamada; personal fees from Teva; non-financial support from Actelion; grants, personal fees, and non-financial support from GSK; grants from Novartis; non-financial support from Rafa; personal fees from Zambon; personal fees from Airphysio; personal fees from Bonus Biogroup; and personal fees from Syncrony medical, outside the submitted work. The remaining authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38178914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10766369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fped.2023.1300968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Cohen-Cymberknoh M, Shoseyov D, Kerem E. Managing cystic fibrosis: strategies that increase life expectancy and improve quality of life. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. (2011) 183(11):1463&#x2013;71. 10.1164/rccm.201009-1478CI</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201009-1478CI</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21330455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell SC, Mall MA, Gutierrez H, Macek M, Madge S, Davies JC, et al. The future of cystic fibrosis care: a global perspective. Lancet Respir Med. (2020) 8(1):65&#x2013;124. 10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30337-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30337-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8862661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31570318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donohoe R, Fullen BM. Adherence of subjects with cystic fibrosis to their home program: a systematic review. Respir Care. (2014) 59(11):1731&#x2013;46. 10.4187/respcare.02990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.02990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25233386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narayanan S, Mainz JG, Gala S, Tabori H, Grossoehme D. Adherence to therapies in cystic fibrosis: a targeted literature review. Expert Rev Respir Med. (2017) 11(2):129&#x2013;45. 10.1080/17476348.2017.1280399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17476348.2017.1280399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28107795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mall MA, Mayer-Hamblett N, Rowe SM. Cystic fibrosis: emergence of highly effective targeted therapeutics and potential clinical implications. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. (2020) 201(10):1193&#x2013;208. 10.1164/RCCM.201910-1943SO</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/RCCM.201910-1943SO</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233349</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31860331</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palla JB. Disparities and therapeutic advances in cystic fibrosis. Pediatr Pulmonol. (2023). 10.1002/PPUL.26445</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/PPUL.26445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11601024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37133222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta Z, Kamal KM, Miller R, Covvey JR, Giannetti V. Adherence to cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR) modulators: analysis of a national specialty pharmacy database. J Drug Assess. (2021) 10(1):62&#x2013;7. 10.1080/21556660.2021.1912352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21556660.2021.1912352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8078929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33968464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shtrichman R, Conrad S, Schimo K, Shachar R, Machluf E, Mindal E, et al. Use of a digital medication management system for effective assessment and enhancement of patient adherence to therapy (ReX): feasibility study. JMIR Hum Factors. (2018) 5(4):e10128. 10.2196/10128</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6288592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30478020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirz S, Conrad S, Shtrichman R, Schimo K, Hoffmann E. Clinical evaluation of a novel technology for oral patient-controlled analgesia, the PCoA&#xae; acute device, for hospitalized patients with postoperative pain, in pilot feasibility study. Pain Res Manag. (2017) 2017. 10.1155/2017/7962135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2017/7962135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5637857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29093632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wirz S, Seidensticker S, Shtrichman R. Patient-controlled analgesia (PCA): intravenous administration (IV-PCA) versus oral administration (oral-PCA) by using a novel device (PCoA&#xae; acute) for hospitalized patients with acute postoperative pain&#x2014;a comparative retrospective study. Pain Res Manag. (2021) 2021. 10.1155/2021/2542010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/2542010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8112920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34055117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham BL, Steenbruggen I, Barjaktarevic IZ, Cooper BG, Hall GL, Hallstrand TS, et al. Standardization of spirometry 2019 update. An official American Thoracic Society and European respiratory society technical statement. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. (2019) 200(8):e70. 10.1164/RCCM.201908-1590ST</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/RCCM.201908-1590ST</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6794117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31613151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper BG, Stocks J, Hall GL, Culver B, Steenbruggen I, Carter KW, et al. The global lung function initiative (GLI) network: bringing the world&#x2019;s respiratory reference values together. Breathe (Sheffield, England). (2017) 13(3):e56&#x2013;64. 10.1183/20734735.012717</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/20734735.012717</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5607614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28955406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bo&#xeb;lle PY, Viviani L, Busson PF, Olesen HV, Ravilly S, Stern M, et al. Reference percentiles for FEV1 and BMI in European children and adults with cystic fibrosis. Orphanet J Rare Dis. (2012) 7(1):64. 10.1186/1750-1172-7-64</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1172-7-64</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3520808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22958330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Browne SH, Peloquin C, Santillo F, Haubrich R, Muttera L, Moser K, et al. Digitizing medicines for remote capture of oral medication adherence using co-encapsulation. Clin Pharmacol Ther. (2018) 103(3):502&#x2013;10. 10.1002/cpt.760</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpt.760</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5836848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28597911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith S, Calthorpe R, Herbert S, Smyth AR. Digital technology for monitoring adherence to inhaled therapies in people with cystic fibrosis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. (2023) 2023(2). 10.1002/14651858.CD013733.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD013733.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9896904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36734528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fai&#xe7;al AVB, Mota LR, Correia D, Monteiro LP, de Souza EL, Terse-Ramos R. Telehealth for children and adolescents with chronic pulmonary disease: systematic review. Rev Paul Pediatr. (2023) 42:e2024111. 10.1590/1984-0462/2024/42/2022111</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1984-0462/2024/42/2022111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10185001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37194911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Middleton PG, Mall MA, D&#x159;ev&#xed;nek P, Lands LC, McKone EF, Polineni D, et al. Elexacaftor-tezacaftor-ivacaftor for cystic fibrosis with a single Phe508del allele. N Engl J Med. (2019) 381(19):1809&#x2013;19. 10.1056/NEJMOA1908639</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMOA1908639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7282384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31697873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heijerman HGM, McKone EF, Downey DG, Van Braeckel E, Rowe SM, Tullis E, et al. Efficacy and safety of the elexacaftor plus tezacaftor plus ivacaftor combination regimen in people with cystic fibrosis homozygous for the F508del mutation: a double-blind, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet. (2019) 394(10212):1940&#x2013;8. 10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32597-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32597-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7571408</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31679946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowe SM, Daines C, Ringshausen FC, Kerem E, Wilson J, Tullis E, et al. Tezacaftor&#x2013;ivacaftor in residual-function heterozygotes with cystic fibrosis. N Engl J Med. (2017) 377(21):2024&#x2013;35. 10.1056/nejmoa1709847</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/nejmoa1709847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6472479</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29099333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor-Cousar JL, Munck A, McKone EF, van der Ent CK, Moeller A, Simard C, et al. Tezacaftor&#x2013;ivacaftor in patients with cystic fibrosis homozygous for Phe508del. N Engl J Med. (2017) 377(21):2013&#x2013;23. 10.1056/NEJMOA1709846</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMOA1709846</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29099344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>