<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32874927</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2214-7829</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Internet interventions</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Internet Interv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Feasibility, effectiveness and safety of the self-management intervention deprexis in routine medical care: Results of an uncontrolled observational study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100341</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100341</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100341</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.invent.2020.100341</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Numerous RCTs have demonstrated the effectiveness of internet-based self-management interventions (SMIs) in the treatment of depressive symptoms. These stud&#xed;es often recruit outside routine clinical practice. For the present study, we investigated the feasibility, effectiveness and safety of an SMI (deprexis) in routine medical care using a non-interventional design.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A total of 104 patients with a depressive disorder (60.58% female, mean age 45.82&#xa0;yrs) were recruited in 25 outpatient practices in Germany (mostly psychiatric practices, <i>n</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;16). They received 12&#xa0;week access to the SMI in addition to their usual care (76.0% took concomitant antidepressant medication). Guidance could optionally be offered by the treating physician. The effectiveness of the intervention was assessed using the clinician-rated short version of the Montgomery Asberg-Depression Scale (svMADRS) and the Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-9), a self-rating for depressive symptoms. Outcomes were assessed at baseline as well as at weeks 3, 6, 9 and 12.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Most patients reported using the intervention at least once (<i>n</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;87, 83.6%), among these users the mean number of sessions was 18.05 (SD&#xa0;=&#xa0;11.33). Only a minority of patients received the guided version of the intervention (<i>n</i>&#xa0;=&#xa0;7, 8.0%). The severity of depressive symptoms decreased significantly over the observation period from 29.72 (SD&#xa0;=&#xa0;10.03) to 15.73 (SD&#xa0;=&#xa0;9.74) for the svMADRS (Cohen's d&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.42, 95% CI 0.08-2.76) and from 15.20 (SD&#xa0;=&#xa0;5.03) to 8.77 (SD&#xa0;=&#xa0;5.03) for the PHQ-9 (d&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.29, 95% CI 0.60-1.97).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The size of the pre-post effect on depressive symptoms observed in this study is comparable to the pre-post effect size reported in an RCT using the same intervention in patients suffering from depressive symptoms of the same severity. Limitations of this study include the lack of a control group and the fact that the recruitment rate was far lower than expected.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This non-interventional study conducted in outpatient practices confirms results from numerous RCTs. Taken together, these data show that deprexis can be used effectively and safely in the routine care of depressed outpatients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klein</LastName><ForeName>Jan Philipp</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, L&#xfc;beck University, L&#xfc;beck, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barthel</LastName><ForeName>Bettina</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Servier Deutschland GmbH, Medical Affairs, M&#xfc;nchen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berger</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bern University, Department of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moritz</LastName><ForeName>Steffen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eppendorf University Medical Center, Department and Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Internet Interv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101631612</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2214-7829</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depressive disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Observational study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-management intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>BBA is an employee of Servier Deutschland GmbH, Medical Affairs, Munich, Germany. JPK received funding for clinical trials (German Federal Ministry of Health, Servier - distributor of the internet intervention &#x201c;deprexis&#x201d;), payments for presentations on internet interventions (Servier), payments for workshops and books (Beltz, Elsevier, Hogrefe and Springer) on psychotherapy for chronic depression and on psychiatric emergencies.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32874927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7450999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2020.100341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2214-7829(20)30107-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Attkisson C.G., Greenfield T.K. The UCSF client satisfaction scales: I. The client satisfaction questionnaire-8. - PsycNET. In: Maruish M., editor. The Use of Psychological Testing for Treatment Planning and Outcome Assessment. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; Mahwah, NJ: 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T., Hammerli K., Gubser N., Andersson G., Caspar F. Internet-based treatment of depression: a randomized controlled trial comparing guided with unguided self-help. Cogn. Behav. Ther. 2011;40:251&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22060248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T., Krieger T., Sude K., Meyer B., Maercker A. Evaluating an e-mental health program (&#x201c;deprexis&#x201d;) as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J. Affect. Disord. 2018;227:455&#x2013;462. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Besser B., Rumpf H.-J., Bischof A., Meerkerk G.-J., Higuchi S., Bischof G. Internet-related disorders: development of the short compulsive internet use scale. Cyberpsychol. Behav. Soc. Netw. 2017;20:709&#x2013;717. doi: 10.1089/cyber.2017.0260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/cyber.2017.0260</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29125788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;cker L., Bierbrodt J., Hand I., Wittekind C., Moritz S. Effects of a depression-focused internet intervention in slot machine gamblers: a randomized controlled trial. PLoS One. 2018;13 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0198859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0198859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5993308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29883479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carli V., Durkee T., Wasserman D., Hadlaczky G., Despalins R., Kramarz E., Wasserman C., Sarchiapone M., Hoven C.W., Brunner R., Kaess M. The association between pathological internet use and comorbid psychopathology: a systematic review. Psychopathology. 2013;46:1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1159/000337971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000337971</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22854219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P., Stringaris A., Wolpert M. Treatment outcomes for depression: challenges and opportunities. Lancet Psychiatry. 2020;0366:2019&#x2013;2020. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30036-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(20)30036-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A., Schr&#xf6;der J., Vettorazzi E., Wolf O.T., P&#xf6;ttgen J., Lau S., Heesen C., Moritz S., Gold S.M. An online programme to reduce depression in patients with multiple sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Psychiatry. 2015;2:217&#x2013;223. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00049-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(14)00049-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flett J.A.M., Fletcher B.D., Riordan B.C., Patterson T., Hayne H., Conner T.S. The peril of self-reported adherence in digital interventions: a brief example. Internet Interv. 2019;18:100267. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2019.100267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2019.100267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6926264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31890620</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geirhos A., Klein J.P., Ebert D.D., Baumeister H. Onlinetherapie verringert bestehende L&#xfc;cken in der Versorgung. InFo Neurol. Psychiatr. 2019;21:36&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1007/s15005-019-0170-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s15005-019-0170-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbody S., Littlewood E., Hewitt C., Brierley G., Tharmanathan P., Araya R., Barkham M., Bower P., Cooper C., Gask L., Kessler D., Lester H., Lovell K., Parry G., Richards D.A., Andersen P., Brabyn S., Knowles S., Shepherd C., Tallon D., White D., REEACT Team Computerised cognitive behaviour therapy (cCBT) as treatment for depression in primary care (REEACT trial): large scale pragmatic randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2015;351:h5627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26559241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi F., H&#xf6;fler M., Strehle J., Mack S., Gerschler A., Scholl L., Busch M.A., Maske U., Hapke U., Gaebel W., Maier W., Wagner M., Zielasek J., Wittchen H.-U. Mental disorders in the general population: study on the health of adults in Germany and the additional module mental health (DEGS1-MH) Nervenarzt. 2014;85:77&#x2013;87. doi: 10.1007/s00115-013-3961-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00115-013-3961-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24441882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson D., Deterding S., Kuhn K.-A., Staneva A., Stoyanov S., Hides L. Gamification for health and wellbeing: a systematic review of the literature. Internet Interv. 2016;6:89&#x2013;106. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2016.10.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2016.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E., Riper H., Twisk J., Hoogendoorn A., Kleiboer A., Mira A., Mackinnon A., Meyer B., Botella C., Littlewood E., Andersson G., Christensen H., Klein J.P., Schr&#xf6;der J., Bret&#xf3;n-L&#xf3;pez J., Scheider J., Griffiths K., Farrer L., Huibers M.J.H., Phillips R., Gilbody S., Moritz S., Berger T., Pop V., Spek V., Cuijpers P. Efficacy of self-guided internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy in the treatment of depressive symptoms. JAMA Psychiatry. 2017;74:351. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28241179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E., Ebert D.D., Donkin L., Riper H., Twisk J., Burger S., Rozental A., Lange A., Williams A.D., Zarski A.C., Geraedts A., van Straten A., Kleiboer A., Meyer B., &#xdc;nl&#xfc; Ince B.B., Buntrock C., Lehr D., Snoek F.J., Andrews G., Andersson G., Choi I., Ruwaard J., Klein J.P., Newby J.M., Schr&#xf6;der J., Laferton J.A.C., Van Bastelaar K., Imamura K., Vernmark K., Bo&#xdf; L., Sheeber L.B., Kivi M., Berking M., Titov N., Carlbring P., Johansson R., Kenter R., Perini S., Moritz S., Nobis S., Berger T., Kaldo V., Forsell Y., Lindefors N., Kraepelien M., Bj&#xf6;rkelund C., Kawakami N., Cuijpers P. Do guided internet-based interventions result in clinically relevant changes for patients with depression? An individual participant data meta-analysis. Clin. Psychol. Rev. 2018;63:80&#x2013;92. doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2018.06.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2018.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29940401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E., Kemmeren L., Riper H., Twisk J., Hoogendoorn A., Kleiboer A., Mira A., Mackinnon A., Meyer B., Botella C., Littlewood E., Andersson G., Christensen H., Klein J.P., Schr&#xf6;der J., Bret&#xf3;n-L&#xf3;pez J., Scheider J., Griffiths K., Farrer L., Huibers M.J.H., Phillips R., Gilbody S., Moritz S., Berger T., Pop V., Spek V., Cuijpers P. Is self-guided internet-based cognitive behavioural therapy (iCBT) harmful? An individual participant data meta-analysis. Psychol. Med. 2018;48:2456&#x2013;2466. doi: 10.1017/S0033291718000648.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291718000648</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6190066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29540243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler R.C., Berglund P.A., Bruce M.L., Koch J.R., Laska E.M., Leaf P.J., Manderscheid R.W., Rosenheck R.A., Walters E.E., Wang P.S. The prevalence and correlates of untreated serious mental illness. Health Serv. Res. 2001;36:987&#x2013;1007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1089274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11775672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J.P., Berger T., Schr&#xf6;der J., Sp&#xe4;th C., Meyer B., Caspar F., Lutz W., Arndt A., Greiner W., Gr&#xe4;fe V., Hautzinger M., Fuhr K., Rose M., Nolte S., L&#xf6;we B., Andersson G., Vettorazzi E., Moritz S., Hohagen F. Effects of a psychological internet intervention in the treatment of mild to moderate depressive symptoms: results of the EVIDENT study, a randomized controlled trial. Psychother. Psychosom. 2016;85:218&#x2013;228. doi: 10.1159/000445355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000445355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J.P., Gamon C., Sp&#xe4;th C., Berger T., Meyer B., Hohagen F., Hautzinger M., Lutz W., Vettorazzi E., Moritz S., Schr&#xf6;der J. Does recruitment source moderate treatment effectiveness? A subgroup analysis from the EVIDENT study, a randomised controlled trial of an internet intervention for depressive symptoms. BMJ Open. 2017;7 doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2016-015391.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2016-015391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5734368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28710212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K., Spitzer R.L., Williams J.B.W., L&#xf6;we B., Lowe B. The patient health questionnaire somatic, anxiety, and depressive symptom scales: a systematic review. Gen. Hosp. Psychiatry. 2010;32:345&#x2013;359. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2010.03.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2010.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20633738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leichsenring F. Randomized controlled versus naturalistic studies: a new research agenda. Bull. Menn. Clin. 2004;68:137&#x2013;151. doi: 10.1521/bumc.68.2.137.35952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1521/bumc.68.2.137.35952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15262616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;bner M., Pabst A., Stein J., Dorow M., Matschinger H., Luppa M., Maro&#xdf; A., Kersting A., K&#xf6;nig H.-H., Riedel-Heller S.G. Computerized cognitive behavior therapy for patients with mild to moderately severe depression in primary care: a pragmatic cluster randomized controlled trial (@ktiv) J. Affect. Disord. 2018;238:317&#x2013;326. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2018.06.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2018.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29902736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B., Berger T., Caspar F., Beevers C.G., Andersson G., Weiss M. Effectiveness of a novel integrative online treatment for depression (Deprexis): randomized controlled trial. J. Med. Internet Res. 2009;11 doi: 10.2196/jmir.1151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19632969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B., Bierbrodt J., Schr&#xf6;der J., Berger T., Beevers C.G., Weiss M., Jacob G., Sp&#xe4;th C., Andersson G., Lutz W., Hautzinger M., L&#xf6;we B., Rose M., Hohagen F., Caspar F., Greiner W., Moritz S., Klein J.P. Effects of an internet intervention (Deprexis) on severe depression symptoms: randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. 2015;2:48&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2014.12.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2014.12.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montgomery S.A., Asberg M. A new depression scale designed to be sensitive to change. Br. J. Psychiatry. 1979;134:382&#x2013;389. doi: 10.1192/bjp.134.4.382.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.134.4.382</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">444788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S., Nestoriuc Y., Rief W., Klein J.P., Jelinek L., Peth J. It can&#x2019;t hurt, right? Adverse effects of psychotherapy in patients with depression. Eur. Arch. Psychiatry Clin. Neurosci. 2019;269:577&#x2013;586. doi: 10.1007/s00406-018-0931-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00406-018-0931-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30088072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfc;bel J., M&#xfc;llender S., Hapke U., Jacobi F. Epidemic of depression?: development of prevalence and help-seeking behaviour. Nervenarzt. 2019:1177&#x2013;1186. doi: 10.1007/s00115-019-0681-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00115-019-0681-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30719537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J., Br&#xfc;ckner K., Fischer A., Lindenau M., K&#xf6;ther U., Vettorazzi E., Moritz S. Efficacy of a psychological online intervention for depression in people with epilepsy: a randomized controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55:2069&#x2013;2076. doi: 10.1111/epi.12833.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25410633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J., Berger T., Westermann S., Klein J.P., Moritz S. Internet interventions for depression: new developments. Dialogues Clin. Neurosci. 2016;18:203&#x2013;212.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4969707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27489460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster R., Laireiter A.-R., Berger T., Moritz S., Meyer B., Hohagen F., Klein J.P. Immediate and long-term effectiveness of adding an internet intervention for depression to routine outpatient psychotherapy: subgroup analysis of the EVIDENT trial. J. Affect. Disord. 2020;274:643&#x2013;651. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2020.05.122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2020.05.122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan K.H., Sheehan D.V. Assessing treatment effects in clinical trials with the Discan metric of the Sheehan disability scale. Int. Clin. Psychopharmacol. 2008;23:70&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1097/YIC.0b013e3282f2b4d6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YIC.0b013e3282f2b4d6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18301121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sp&#xe4;th C., Hapke U., Maske U., Schr&#xf6;der J., Moritz S., Berger T., Meyer B., Rose M., Nolte S., Klein J.P. Characteristics of participants in a randomized trial of an internet intervention for depression (EVIDENT) in comparison to a national sample (DEGS1) Internet Interv. 2017;9:46&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2017.05.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2017.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart E.A., Bradshaw C.P., Leaf P.J. Assessing the generalizability of randomized trial results to target populations. Prev. Sci. 2015;16:475&#x2013;485. doi: 10.1007/s11121-014-0513-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11121-014-0513-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4359056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25307417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C., O&#x2019;Reilly G., Meyer B. Effectiveness of an individually-tailored computerised CBT programme (Deprexis) for depression: a meta-analysis. Psychiatry Res. 2017;256:371&#x2013;377. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2017.06.081.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2017.06.081</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28686935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C., O&#x2019;Reilly G., B&#xfc;ltmann O., Meyer B. Effectiveness of a tailored, integrative internet intervention (deprexis) for depression: updated meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0228100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0228100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31999743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams A.D., Andrews G. The effectiveness of internet cognitive behavioural therapy (iCBT) for depression in primary care: a quality assurance study. PLoS One. 2013;8 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0057447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0057447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3579844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23451231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wind T.R., Rijkeboer M., Andersson G., Riper H. The COVID-19 pandemic: the &#x2018;black swan&#x2019; for mental health care and a turning point for e-health. Internet Interv. 2020;20:100317. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2020.100317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2020.100317</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7104190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwerenz R., Becker J., Knickenberg R.J., Siepmann M., Hagen K., Beutel M.E. Online self-help as an add-on to inpatient psychotherapy: efficacy of a new blended treatment approach. Psychother. Psychosom. 2017;86:341&#x2013;350. doi: 10.1159/000481177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000481177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwerenz R., Baumgarten C., Becker J., Tibubos A., Siepmann M., Knickenberg R.J., Beutel M.E. Improving the course of depressive symptoms after inpatient psychotherapy using adjunct web-based self-help: follow-up results of a randomized controlled trial. J. Med. Internet Res. 2019;21 doi: 10.2196/13655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/13655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838691</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31651403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>