<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39608327</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-5126</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>130</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Parkinsonism &amp; related disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Parkinsonism Relat Disord</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Context-dependency of the REM sleep behavior disorder screening questionnaire - Clinical utility under scrutiny.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>107211</StartPage><MedlinePgn>107211</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2024.107211</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1353-8020(24)01223-9</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The REM Sleep Behavior Disorder (RBD) Screening Questionnaire (RBDSQ) is a widely established screening tool for detecting isolated RBD (iRBD). However, its accuracy may depend on its application context, e.g., the individuals' awareness of their RBD status. The present work aims to describe the context-dependency and retest reliability of the RBDSQ in an iRBD cohort setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Ninety-four individuals with video-polysomnography confirmed iRBD answered the RBDSQ during pre-polysomnography screening (V0) and post-diagnosis (V1).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The RBDSQ total score significantly differed between V0 and V1 (F(1,92)&#xa0;=&#xa0;8.02, p&#xa0;=&#xa0;.006, &#x3b7;<sub>p</sub><sup>2</sup>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.019). The intraclass correlation coefficient (ICC<sub>2,1</sub>) of the RBDSQ showed moderate reliability between consecutive timepoints (<sup>V0-V1</sup>ICC<sub>2,1</sub>&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.544). The highest Cohen's &#x3ba; was reached for items 5, 6.3, 6.4, 8, and 9 across timepoint comparisons (0.409&#xa0;&#x2264;&#xa0;Cohen's &#x3ba;&#xa0;&#x2264;&#xa0;0.660).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our findings underscore the context-dependency of the RBDSQ and fluctuations in self-awareness of sleep-related behaviors, necessitating a critical appraisal of questionnaire-based RBD screening tools. Future studies should explore strategies to improve the reliability and accuracy of RBD screening tools, considering the dynamic nature of sleep-related behavior.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R&#xf6;ttgen</LastName><ForeName>Sinah</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cognitive Neuroscience, Institute for Neuroscience and Medicine, INM-3, Research Centre Juelich, Juelich, Germany; Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany. Electronic address: s.roettgen@fz-juelich.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Doppler</LastName><ForeName>Christopher E J</ForeName><Initials>CEJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cognitive Neuroscience, Institute for Neuroscience and Medicine, INM-3, Research Centre Juelich, Juelich, Germany; Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany. Electronic address: christopher.doppler@uk-koeln.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Seger</LastName><ForeName>Aline</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany. Electronic address: aline.seger@uk-koeln.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalbe</LastName><ForeName>Elke</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies, Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany. Electronic address: elke.kalbe@uk-koeln.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fink</LastName><ForeName>Gereon R</ForeName><Initials>GR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cognitive Neuroscience, Institute for Neuroscience and Medicine, INM-3, Research Centre Juelich, Juelich, Germany; Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany. Electronic address: g.r.fink@fz-juelich.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sommerauer</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cognitive Neuroscience, Institute for Neuroscience and Medicine, INM-3, Research Centre Juelich, Juelich, Germany; Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany; Center of Neurology, Department of Parkinson, Sleep and Movement Disorders, University of Bonn, Bonn, Germany. Electronic address: michael.sommerauer@ukbonn.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ophey</LastName><ForeName>Anja</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cognitive Neuroscience, Institute for Neuroscience and Medicine, INM-3, Research Centre Juelich, Juelich, Germany; Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies, Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany. Electronic address: anja.ophey@uk-koeln.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Parkinsonism Relat Disord</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9513583</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1353-8020</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020187" MajorTopicYN="Y">REM Sleep Behavior Disorder</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000592" MajorTopicYN="N">standards</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017286" MajorTopicYN="N">Polysomnography</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disease awareness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">REM sleep behavior disorder</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Reliability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Screening questionnaire</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: SR: none. CEJD is supported by the Clinician Scientist Program (CCSP)/Faculty of Medicine/University of Cologne, Germany, funded by the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (DFG, German Research Foundation, FI 773/15-1, Germany). AS: none. EK received grants from the German Ministry of Education and Research, Germany, the Joint Federal Committee, Germany, and The German Parkinson Foundation, Germany, all outside the submitted work. EK received honoraria from the companies EISAI GmbH, Germany, memodio GmbH, Germany, Desitin GmbH, Germany, and Prolog GmbH, Germany, all outside the submitted work. GRF serves as an editorial board member of Cortex, Neurological Research and Practice, NeuroImage: Clinical, Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Neuropsychologie, and Info Neurologie &amp; Psychiatrie; receives royalties from the publication of the books Funktionelle MRT in Psychiatrie und Neurologie, Neurologische Differentialdiagnose, SOP Neurologie, and Therapiehandbuch Neurologie; receives royalties from the publication of the neuropsychological tests KAS and K&#xf6;pps; received honoraria for speaking engagements from Deutsche Gesellschaft f&#xfc;r Neurologie (DGN) and Forum f&#xfc;r medizinische Fortbildung FomF GmbH; receives funding from the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (CRC 1451; Project-ID 431549029), all outside the submitted work. MS received grants from the Else Kr&#xf6;ner-Fresenius-Stiftung (grant number 2019_EKES.02), Germany, and the Koeln Fortune Program, Faculty of Medicine, University of Cologne, Germany. M.S. is receiving funding from the program "Netzwerke 2021&#x2033;, an initiative of the Ministry of Culture and Science of the State of Northrhine Westphalia, Germany. AO received grants from the Koeln Fortune Program (grant-no. 329/2021, 142/2023), Faculty of Medicine, University of Cologne, Germany, and the &#x201c;Novartis-Stiftung f&#xfc;r therapeutische Forschung&#x201d;, Germany, all outside the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39608327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2024.107211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1353-8020(24)01223-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>