<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">41437278</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>27</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Computerized cognitive training vs. care as usual to strengthen cognitive, motor, and (neuro)psychological outcomes in people with advanced Parkinson's disease (TrainParC-Advanced): study protocol of a randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>76</StartPage><MedlinePgn>76</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">76</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-025-09330-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Cognitive impairment is common in Parkinson's disease (PD). Up to 80% of people with PD develop dementia over the disease course, heavily impacting their quality of life. While pharmacological treatment options are scarce, previous research highlights the potential benefits of non-pharmacological interventions, such as cognitive training (CT), on cognition and non-cognitive outcomes. This study's purpose is to examine the feasibility as well as short- and long-term effects of a 5-week digital CT in people with advanced PD, compared to people with advanced PD receiving care as usual, and to explore possible predictors of CT responsiveness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This ongoing monocentric, two-armed randomized controlled trial (RCT) seeks to include 140 participants with advanced PD according to the established 5-2-1 criteria. Participants are randomized into either the experimental group, receiving a structured 5-week digital CT and additional psychoeducational videos on cognitive health, or a passive control group receiving care as usual. CT will be carried out remotely from home and supervised by the study team. Feasibility will be assessed using a training diary (e.g., motivation, satisfaction) and technical data (e.g., training duration). Neuropsychological assessments will be carried out pre- and post-CT and after a 3-month follow-up period. The primary outcome will be global cognition measured with the Montr&#xe9;al Cognitive Assessment (MoCA). Secondary outcomes include further cognitive, motor, and (neuro)psychological variables (e.g., quality of life, motor symptoms, mood, activities of daily living).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Studies on CT in people with PD have demonstrated positive effects on cognition, promoting the application of CT as a non-pharmacological treatment approach. However, studies targeting people in more advanced PD stages are rare or non-existent, despite it being a clinically relevant target group. Further, few studies have looked at long-term CT effects in PD, and very little data exists regarding CT predictors. Therefore, this large-cohort study of a multi-domain digital CT in people with advanced PD aims to provide insights into the effects, feasibility, and acceptability of CT within a representative sample of people with PD, allowing for statistically high-powered analyses and the identification of potential CT predictors.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">German Clinical Trials Register (DRKS) DRKS00028876. Registered on 21 November 2022.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Olgem&#xf6;ller</LastName><ForeName>Paulina M</ForeName><Initials>PM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3972-3567</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies, Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalbe</LastName><ForeName>Elke</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8603-2545</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies, Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>van der Linden</LastName><ForeName>Christina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2091-4638</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Cologne and Faculty of Medicine, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barbe</LastName><ForeName>Michael T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1149-8054</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University Hospital Cologne and Faculty of Medicine, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hellmich</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5174-928X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Statistics and Computational Biology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Folkerts</LastName><ForeName>Ann-Kristin</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2168-140X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies, Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany. ann-kristin.folkerts@uk-koeln.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015928" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005240" MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013813" MajorTopicYN="Y">Therapy, Computer-Assisted</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009043" MajorTopicYN="Y">Motor Activity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000091942" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Training</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuropsychology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-motor symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of life</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized controlled trial</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate {24}: All procedures were approved by the Ethics Commission of Cologne University&#x2019;s Faculty of Medicine, reference number 22-1241_1. Written informed consent to participate is obtained from all participants. Participation is voluntary, and subjects are free to leave the study at any time. Consent for publication {32}: A model consent form will be available upon request from the corresponding author. Competing interests {28}: P. M. O. reports no competing interests. A. K. F. has received grants from the German Parkinson Society, the German Alzheimer&#x2019;s Society, the German Parkinson Foundation, STADApharm GmbH, and the General Joint Committee Germany as well as honoraria from Springer Medizin Verlag GmbH, Heidelberg, Germany; Springer-Verlag GmbH, Berlin; ProLog WISSEN GmbH, Cologne, Germany; Seminar- und Fortbildungszentrum Rheine, Germany; LOGOMANIA, Fendt &amp; Sax GbR, Munich, Germany; LOGUAN, Ulm, Germany; dbs e.V., Moers, Germany; STADApharm GmbH, Bad Vilbel, Germany; NEUROPSY, St. Konrad, Austria; Multiple Sclerosis Society Vienna, Vienna, Austria; and Gossweiler Foundation, Bern, Switzerland. A. K. F. is one of the authors of the cognitive intervention series &#x201c;NEUROvitalis&#x201d; but receives no corresponding honoraria. E. K. has received grants from the German Ministry of Education and Research, General Joint Committee, Germany, the German Parkinson Society, and STADApharm GmbH, honoraria from AbbVie GmbH Germany and memodio GmbH Germany, and license fees from ProLog GmbH, Germany. E. K. is one of the authors of the cognitive intervention series &#x201c;NEUROvitalis&#x201d; but receives no corresponding honoraria. C. v. d. L. was supported by the Cologne Clinician Scientist Program (CCSP), Faculty of Medicine, University of Cologne. M. T. B. received speaker&#x2019;s honoraria from Medtronic, Boston Scientific, Abbott (formerly St. Jude), FomF, GE Medical, UCB, Bial, Apothekerverband K&#xf6;ln e.V., BDN, and Esteve; research funding from the Felgenhauer-Stiftung, Forschungspool Klinische Studien (University of Cologne), Horizon 2020 (Gondola), Medtronic (ODIS, OPEL, BeAble), and Boston Scientific; and advisory honoraria for the IQWiG, Medtronic, Esteve, and AbbVie.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41437278</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12829061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-025-09330-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-025-09330-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Lamptey RNL, Chaulagain B, Trivedi R, Gothwal A, Layek B, Singh J. A review of the common neurodegenerative disorders: current therapeutic approaches and the potential role of nanotherapeutics. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23:1851. 10.3390/ijms23031851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms23031851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8837071</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35163773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorsey ER, Sherer T, Okun MS, Bloem BR. The emerging evidence of the Parkinson pandemic. J Park Dis. 2018;8:3&#x2013;8. 10.3233/JPD-181474.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JPD-181474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6311367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30584159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinmetz JD, Seeher KM, Schiess N, Nichols E, Cao B, Servili C, et al. Global, regional, and national burden of disorders affecting the nervous system, 1990&#x2013;2021: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2021. Lancet Neurol. 2024;23:344&#x2013;81. 10.1016/S1474-4422(24)00038-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(24)00038-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10949203</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38493795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Postuma RB, Berg D, Stern M, Poewe W, Olanow CW, Oertel W, et al. MDS clinical diagnostic criteria for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: MDS-PD clinical diagnostic criteria. Mov Disord. 2015;30:1591&#x2013;601. 10.1002/mds.26424.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.26424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26474316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xf6;glinger G, Trenkwalder C, et. al. Parkinson-Krankheit, S2k-Leitlinie. Leitlinien F&#xfc;r Diagn Ther Neurol. 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong MJ, Okun MS. Diagnosis and treatment of Parkinson disease: a review. JAMA. 2020;323:548. 10.1001/jama.2019.22360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2019.22360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32044947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez&#x2010;Blazquez C, Schrag A, Rizos A, Chaudhuri KR, Martinez&#x2010;Martin P, Weintraub D. Prevalence of non&#x2010;motor symptoms and non&#x2010;motor fluctuations in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease using the MDS&#x2010;NMS. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2021;8:231&#x2013;9. 10.1002/mdc3.13122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7853195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33553493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aarsland D, Batzu L, Halliday GM, Geurtsen GJ, Ballard C, Ray Chaudhuri K, et al. Parkinson disease-associated cognitive impairment. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2021;7:47. 10.1038/s41572-021-00280-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41572-021-00280-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berganzo K, Tijero B, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Eizaguirre A, Somme J, Lezcano E, Gabilondo I, et al. Motor and non-motor symptoms of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and their impact on quality of life and on different clinical subgroups. Neurolog&#xed;a (English Edition). 2016;31:585&#x2013;91. 10.1016/j.nrleng.2014.10.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nrleng.2014.10.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25529173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monchi O, Hanganu A, Bellec P. Markers of cognitive decline in PD: the case for heterogeneity. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2016;24:8&#x2013;14. 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2016.01.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2016.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26774536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boel JA, De Bie RMA, Schmand BA, Dalrymple&#x2010;Alford JC, Marras C, Adler CH, et al. Level I PD&#x2010;MCI using global cognitive tests and the risk for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease dementia. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2022;9:479&#x2013;83. 10.1002/mdc3.13451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mdc3.13451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9092740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35582313</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldman JG, Vernaleo BA, Camicioli R, Dahodwala N, Dobkin RD, Ellis T, et al. Cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a report from a multidisciplinary symposium on unmet needs and future directions to maintain cognitive health. NPJ Parkinsons Dis. 2018;4:19. 10.1038/s41531-018-0055-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41531-018-0055-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6018742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29951580</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baiano C, Barone P, Trojano L, Santangelo G. Prevalence and clinical aspects of mild cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a meta&#x2010;analysis. Mov Disord. 2020;35:45&#x2013;54. 10.1002/mds.27902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.27902</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31743500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monastero R, Cicero CE, Baschi R, Dav&#xec; M, Luca A, Restivo V, et al. Mild cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: the Parkinson&#x2019;s disease cognitive study (PACOS). J Neurol. 2018;265:1050&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s00415-018-8800-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-018-8800-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29478221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muslimovi&#x107; D, Post B, Speelman JD, Schmand B. Cognitive profile of patients with newly diagnosed Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2005;65:1239&#x2013;45. 10.1212/01.wnl.0000180516.69442.95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000180516.69442.95</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16247051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hanagasi HA, Tufekcioglu Z, Emre M. Dementia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Neurol Sci. 2017;374:26&#x2013;31. 10.1016/j.jns.2017.01.012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2017.01.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28088312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severiano E Sousa C, Alarc&#xe3;o J, Pav&#xe3;o Martins I, Ferreira JJ. Frequency of dementia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci. 2022;432:120077. 10.1016/j.jns.2021.120077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2021.120077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34896923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hely MA, Reid WGJ, Adena MA, Halliday GM, Morris JGL. The Sydney multicenter study of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: the inevitability of dementia at 20 years. Mov Disord. 2008;23:837&#x2013;44. 10.1002/mds.21956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.21956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18307261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson R, Yarnall A, Johnston F, Duncan G, Khoo T, Collerton D, et al. Cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: impact on quality of life of carers. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2017;32:1362&#x2013;70. 10.1002/gps.4623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gps.4623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5724657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27925292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson RA, Collerton D, Taylor J-P, Burn DJ, Brittain KR. Coping with cognitive impairment in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and their carers: a qualitative study. Parkinsons Dis. 2018;2018:1&#x2013;10. 10.1155/2018/1362053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/1362053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5911314</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29850013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiesli D, Meyer A, Fuhr P, Gschwandtner U. Influence of mild cognitive impairment, depression, and anxiety on the quality of life of patients with Parkinson disease. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord Extra. 2017;7:297&#x2013;308. 10.1159/000478849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000478849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5662998</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29118782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Lau LML, Verbaan D, Marinus J, Van Hilten JJ. Survival in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Relation with motor and non-motor features. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2014;20:613&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2014.02.030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2014.02.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24679900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodel R, Tinelli M, Deuschl G, Petersen G, Oertel W, Ahmerkamp&#x2010;B&#xf6;hme J. The economic benefit of timely, adequate, and adherence to Parkinson&#x2019;s disease treatment: the value of treatment project 2. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:707&#x2013;16. 10.1111/ene.14584.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.14584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33048415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vossius C, Larsen JP, Janvin C, Aarsland D. The economic impact of cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2011;26:1541&#x2013;4. 10.1002/mds.23661.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21538519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cammisuli DM, Cammisuli SM, Fusi J, Franzoni F, Pruneti C. Parkinson&#x2019;s disease-mild cognitive impairment (PD-MCI): a useful summary of update knowledge. Front Aging Neurosci. 2019;11:303. 10.3389/fnagi.2019.00303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2019.00303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6856711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31780918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun C, Armstrong MJ. Treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with cognitive impairment: current approaches and future directions. Behav Sci. 2021;11:54. 10.3390/bs11040054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bs11040054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Csoti I, Herbst H, Urban P, Woitalla D, W&#xfc;llner U. Polypharmacy in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: risks and benefits with little evidence. J Neural Transm. 2019;126:871&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s00702-019-02026-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-019-02026-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31222606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishii N, Mochizuki H, Sakai K, Ogawa G, Shiomi K, Nakazato M. Polypharmacy associated with cognitive decline in newly diagnosed Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a cross-sectional study. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord Extra. 2019;9:338&#x2013;43. 10.1159/000502351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000502351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6787424</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31608098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung IHK, Walton CC, Hallock H, Lewis SJG, Valenzuela M, Lampit A. Cognitive training in Parkinson disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurology. 2015;85:1843&#x2013;51. 10.1212/WNL.0000000000002145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000002145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4662707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26519540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orgeta V, McDonald KR, Poliakoff E, Hindle JV, Clare L, Leroi I. Cognitive training interventions for dementia and mild cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020. 10.1002/14651858.CD011961.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011961.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7043362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32101639</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence BJ, Gasson N, Bucks RS, Troeung L, Loftus AM. Cognitive training and noninvasive brain stimulation for cognition in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a meta-analysis. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2017;31:597&#x2013;608. 10.1177/1545968317712468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968317712468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28583011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couture M, Gigu&#xe8;re-Rancourt A, Simard M. The impact of cognitive interventions on cognitive symptoms in idiopathic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review. Aging Neuropsychol Cogn. 2019;26:637&#x2013;59. 10.1080/13825585.2018.1513450.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13825585.2018.1513450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30221586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nousia A, Martzoukou M, Tsouris Z, Siokas V, Aloizou A-M, Liampas I, et al. The beneficial effects of computer-based cognitive training in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review. Arch Clin Neuropsychol. 2020;35:434&#x2013;47. 10.1093/arclin/acz080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/arclin/acz080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31942917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavelin HM, Domell&#xf6;f ME, Leung I, Neely AS, Launder NH, Nategh L, et al. Computerized cognitive training in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev. 2022;80:101671. 10.1016/j.arr.2022.101671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arr.2022.101671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35714854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill NTM, Mowszowski L, Naismith SL, Chadwick VL, Valenzuela M, Lampit A. Computerized cognitive training in older adults with mild cognitive impairment or dementia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Psychiatry. 2017;174:329&#x2013;40. 10.1176/appi.ajp.2016.16030360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2016.16030360</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27838936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aarsland D, Andersen K, Larsen JP, Lolk A. Prevalence and characteristics of dementia in Parkinson disease: an 8-year prospective study. Arch Neurol. 2003;60:387. 10.1001/archneur.60.3.387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.60.3.387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12633150</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton CC, Naismith SL, Lampit A, Mowszowski L, Lewis SJG. Cognitive training in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a theoretical perspective. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2017;31:207&#x2013;16. 10.1177/1545968316680489.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968316680489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27899737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ophey A, Rehberg S, Giehl K, Eggers C, Reker P, Van Eimeren T, et al. Predicting working memory training responsiveness in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: both &#x201c;system hardware&#x201d; and room for improvement are needed. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2021;35:117&#x2013;30. 10.1177/1545968320981956.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1545968320981956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33410387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alloni A, Quaglini S, Panzarasa S, Sinforiani E, Bernini S. Evaluation of an ontology-based system for computerized cognitive rehabilitation. Int J Med Inform. 2018;115:64&#x2013;72. 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2018.04.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2018.04.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29779721</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernini S, Alloni A, Panzarasa S, Picascia M, Quaglini S, Tassorelli C, et al. A computer-based cognitive training in mild cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. NeuroRehabilitation. 2019;44:555&#x2013;67. 10.3233/NRE-192714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/NRE-192714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31256092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Folkerts A-K, Dorn ME, Roheger M, Maassen M, Koerts J, Tucha O, et al. Cognitive stimulation for individuals with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease dementia living in long-term care: preliminary data from a randomized crossover pilot study. Parkinsons Dis. 2018;2018:1&#x2013;9. 10.1155/2018/8104673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/8104673</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6304852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30631420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SJ, McMillan I, Leroi I, Champ CL, Barr S, McDonald KR, et al. Feasibility and acceptability of computerised cognitive training of everyday cognition in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Parkinsons Dis. 2019;2019:1&#x2013;11. 10.1155/2019/5258493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/5258493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6679888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31428303</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van De Weijer SCF, Duits AA, Bloem BR, De Vries NM, Kessels RPC, K&#xf6;hler S, et al. Feasibility of a cognitive training game in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: the randomized Parkin&#x2019;Play study. Eur Neurol. 2020;83:426&#x2013;32. 10.1159/000509685.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000509685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32756067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalbe E, Folkerts A-K, Ophey A, Eggers C, Elben S, Dimenshteyn K, et al. Enhancement of executive functions but not memory by multidomain group cognitive training in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and mild cognitive impairment: a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Parkinsons Dis. 2020. 10.1155/2020/4068706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/4068706</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7721510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33312495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang H, Norris SA. Managing advanced Parkinson disease. J Geriatr Psychiatry Neurol. 2021;34:289&#x2013;300. 10.1177/08919887211018277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08919887211018277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34219527</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kr&#xfc;ger R, Klucken J, Weiss D, T&#xf6;nges L, Kolber P, Unterecker S, et al. Classification of advanced stages of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: translation into stratified treatments. J Neural Transm. 2017;124:1015&#x2013;27. 10.1007/s00702-017-1707-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-017-1707-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5514193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28342083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titova N, Martinez-Martin P, Katunina E, Chaudhuri KR. Advanced Parkinson&#x2019;s or &#x201c;complex phase&#x201d; Parkinson&#x2019;s disease? Re-evaluation is needed. J Neural Transm. 2017;124:1529&#x2013;37. 10.1007/s00702-017-1799-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00702-017-1799-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5686262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29116411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aarsland D, Creese B, Politis M, Chaudhuri KR, Ffytche DH, Weintraub D, et al. Cognitive decline in Parkinson disease. Nat Rev Neurol. 2017;13:217&#x2013;31. 10.1038/nrneurol.2017.27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2017.27</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5643027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28257128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt N, T&#xf6;dt I, Berg D, Schlenstedt C, Folkerts A-K, Ophey A, et al. Memory enhancement by multidomain group cognitive training in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and mild cognitive impairment: long-term effects of a multicenter randomized controlled trial. J Neurol. 2021;268:4655&#x2013;66. 10.1007/s00415-021-10568-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-021-10568-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8563628</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33904966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ophey A, Wenzel J, Paul R, Giehl K, Rehberg S, Eggers C, et al. Cognitive performance and learning parameters predict response to working memory training in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Parkinsons Dis. 2022;12:2235&#x2013;47. 10.3233/JPD-223448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JPD-223448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9661332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36120792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roheger M, Folkerts A-K, Krohm F, Skoetz N, Kalbe E. Prognostic factors for change in memory test performance after memory training in healthy older adults: a systematic review and outline of statistical challenges. Diagn Progn Res. 2020;4:7. 10.1186/s41512-020-0071-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41512-020-0071-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32478173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basak C, Qin S, O&#x2019;Connell MA. Differential effects of cognitive training modules in healthy aging and mild cognitive impairment: a comprehensive meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Psychol Aging. 2020;35:220&#x2013;49. 10.1037/pag0000442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pag0000442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7050567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32011155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roheger M, Liebermann-Jordanidis H, Krohm F, Adams A, Kalbe E. Prognostic factors and models for changes in cognitive performance after multi-domain cognitive training in healthy older adults: a systematic review. Front Hum Neurosci. 2021;15:636355. 10.3389/fnhum.2021.636355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2021.636355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8110835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33986652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curran GM, Bauer M, Mittman B, Pyne JM, Stetler C. Effectiveness-implementation hybrid designs: combining elements of clinical effectiveness and implementation research to enhance public health impact. Med Care. 2012;50:217&#x2013;26. 10.1097/MLR.0b013e3182408812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MLR.0b013e3182408812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3731143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22310560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baller G, Folkerts A-K, Bintener C, Kessler J, Kalbe E. HeadApp/NEUROvitalis Digital. 2020. https://start-headapp.helferservices.net/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, Phillips NA, B&#xe9;dirian V, Charbonneau S, Whitehead V, Collin I, et al. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: a brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2005;53:695&#x2013;9. 10.1111/j.1532-5415.2005.53221.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.2005.53221.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gibb WR, Lees AJ. The relevance of the Lewy body to the pathogenesis of idiopathic Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1988;51:745&#x2013;52. 10.1136/jnnp.51.6.745.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.51.6.745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1033142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2841426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antonini A, Stoessl AJ, Kleinman LS, Skalicky AM, Marshall TS, Sail KR, et al. Developing consensus among movement disorder specialists on clinical indicators for identification and management of advanced Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a multi-country Delphi-panel approach. Curr Med Res Opin. 2018;34:2063&#x2013;73. 10.1080/03007995.2018.1502165.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03007995.2018.1502165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30016901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos-Garc&#xed;a D, De Deus Fonticoba T, Su&#xe1;rez Castro E, Aneiros D&#xed;az A, McAfee D. 5-2-1 criteria: a simple screening tool for identifying advanced PD patients who need an optimization of Parkinson&#x2019;s treatment. Parkinsons Dis. 2020;2020:1&#x2013;6. 10.1155/2020/7537924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/7537924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7128051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32269748</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dalrymple-Alford JC. Well-suited screen for cognitive impairment in Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2010:1717&#x2013;25. 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181fc29c9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21060094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Steer RA, Brown G. Beck Depression Inventory&#x2013;II (BDI-II). 1996. 10.1037/t00742-000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association. WMA Declaration of Helsiniki - Ethical Principles for Medical Research Involving Human Participants. 2024. https://www.wma.net/policies-post/wma-declaration-of-helsinki/. Accessed 31 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appelbaum PS. Assessment of patients&#x2019; competence to consent to treatment. N Engl J Med. 2007. 10.1056/NEJMcp074045.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMcp074045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17978292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baller G, Kalbe E, Kaseberg S, Kessler J. NEUROvitalis. K&#xf6;ln: ProLog Therapie; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrelli A, Kaesberg S, Barbe MT, Timmermann L, Fink GR, Kessler J, et al. Effects of cognitive training in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a randomized controlled trial. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2014;20:1196&#x2013;202. 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2014.08.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2014.08.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25242806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petrelli A, Kaesberg S, Barbe MT, Timmermann L, Rosen JB, Fink GR, et al. Cognitive training in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease reduces cognitive decline in the long term. Eur J Neurol. 2015;22:640&#x2013;7. 10.1111/ene.12621.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.12621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25534579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roheger M, Kessler J, Kalbe E. Structured cognitive training yields best results in healthy older adults, and their ApoE4 state and baseline cognitive level predict training benefits. Cogn Behav Neurol. 2019;32:76&#x2013;86. 10.1097/WNN.0000000000000195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNN.0000000000000195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31205121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ophey A, Giehl K, Rehberg S, Eggers C, Reker P, Van Eimeren T, et al. Effects of working memory training in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease without cognitive impairment: a randomized controlled trial. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2020;72:13&#x2013;22. 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2020.02.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2020.02.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32078917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartusch S, Zipper S. Montr&#xe9;al Cognitive Assessment (MoCA): German version. 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Parkinson and Movemend Disorder Society (MDS). MDS-Reccomended Rating Scales. https://www.movementdisorders.org/MDS/Education/Rating-Scales/MDS-Recommended-Rating-Scales.htm. Accessed 31 Oct 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalbe E, Folkerts A-K, Witt K, Buhmann C, Liepelt-Scarfone I, German Parkinson&#x2019;s Guidelines Group. German society of neurology guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of cognitive impairment and affective disorders in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: new spotlights on diagnostic procedures and non-pharmacological interventions. J Neurol. 2024;271:7330&#x2013;57. 10.1007/s00415-024-12503-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00415-024-12503-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11561078</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39120709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenzuela MJ, Sachdev P. Assessment of complex mental activity across the lifespan: development of the lifetime of experiences questionnaire (LEQ). Psychol Med. 2007;37:1015&#x2013;25. 10.1017/S003329170600938X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S003329170600938X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17112402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roeske S, Wolfsgruber S, Kleineidam L, Zulka L, Buerger K, Ewers M, et al. P3&#x2010;591: a GERMAN version of the lifetime of experiences questionnaire (LEQ) to measure cognitive reserve: validation results from the DELCODE study. Alzheimers Dement. 2018;14:7S_Part_25. 10.1016/j.jalz.2018.06.1957.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2018.06.1957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris JC, Heyman A, Mohs RC, Hughes JP, Van Belle G, Fillenbaum G, et al. The Consortium to Establish a Registry for Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease (CERAD). Part I. Clinical and neuropsychological assesment of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Neurology. 1989;39:1159&#x2013;1159. 10.1212/WNL.39.9.1159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2771064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid NS, Ehrensperger MM, Berres M, Beck IR, Monsch AU. The extension of the German CERAD neuropsychological assessment battery with tests assessing subcortical, executive and frontal functions improves accuracy in dementia diagnosis. Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord Extra. 2014;4:322&#x2013;34. 10.1159/000357774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000357774</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4176468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25298776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aebi C. Validierung der neuropsychologischen Testbatterie CERAD-NP - Eine Multi-Center Studie. University of Basel; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sturm W, Wilmes K, Horn W. Leistungspr&#xfc;fsystem f&#xfc;r 50&#x2013;90j&#xe4;hrige (LPS 50+). Handanweisung. G&#xf6;ttingen: Hogrefe; 1993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wechsler D. WMS-R: Wechsler Memory Scale&#x2013;Revised: Manual. Psychological Corporation; 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schretlen D, Bobholz JH, Brandt J. Development and psychometric properties of the brief test of attention. Clin Neuropsychol. 1996;10:80&#x2013;9. 10.1080/13854049608406666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13854049608406666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benton A, Hannay HJ, Varney NR. Visual perception of line direction in patients with unilateral brain disease. Neurology. 1975;25:907&#x2013;907. 10.1212/WNL.25.10.907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.25.10.907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1237101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benton AL. Contributions to neuropsychological assessment: a clinical manual. Oxford University Press; 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalbe E, Reinhold N, Brand M, Markowitsch HJ, Kessler J. A new test battery to assess aphasic disturbances and associated cognitive dysfunctions &#x2014; German normative data on the Aphasia Check List. J Clin Exp Neuropsychol. 2005;27:779&#x2013;94. 10.1080/13803390490918273.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13803390490918273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16183613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ophey A, Krohm F, Kalbe E, Greuel A, Drzezga A, Tittgemeyer M, et al. Neural correlates and predictors of subjective cognitive decline in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Neurol Sci. 2022;43:3153&#x2013;63. 10.1007/s10072-021-05734-w.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-021-05734-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9018636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34820745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ophey A, R&#xf6;ttgen S, Pauquet J, Wei&#xdf; K-L, Scharfenberg D, Doppler CEJ, et al. Cognitive training and promoting a healthy lifestyle for individuals with isolated REM sleep behavior disorder: study protocol of the delayed-start randomized controlled trial CogTrAiL-RBD. Trials. 2024;25:428. 10.1186/s13063-024-08265-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-024-08265-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11214208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38943191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goetz CG, Tilley BC, Shaftman SR, Stebbins GT, Fahn S, Martinez&#x2010;Martin P, et al. Movement Disorder Society&#x2010;sponsored revision of the Unified Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease Rating Scale (MDS&#x2010;UPDRS): scale presentation and clinimetric testing results. Mov Disord. 2008;23:2129&#x2013;70. 10.1002/mds.22340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.22340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19025984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podsiadlo D, Richardson S. The timed &#x201c;Up &amp; go&#x201d;: a test of basic functional mobility for frail elderly persons. J Am Geriatr Soc. 1991;39:142&#x2013;8. 10.1111/j.1532-5415.1991.tb01616.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1532-5415.1991.tb01616.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1991946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zirek E, Ersoz Huseyinsinoglu B, Tufekcioglu Z, Bilgic B, Hanagasi H. Which cognitive dual-task walking causes most interference on the Timed Up and Go test in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a controlled study. Neurol Sci. 2018;39:2151&#x2013;7. 10.1007/s10072-018-3564-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-018-3564-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30232665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giladi N, Shabtai H, Simon ES, Biran S, Tal J, Korczyn AD. Construction of freezing of gait questionnaire for patients with Parkinsonism. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2000;6:165&#x2013;70. 10.1016/S1353-8020(99)00062-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1353-8020(99)00062-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10817956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vogler A, Janssens J, Nyffeler T, Bohlhalter S, Vanbellingen T. German translation and validation of the &#x201c;Freezing of Gait Questionnaire&#x201d; in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease. Parkinsons Dis. 2015;2015:1&#x2013;5. 10.1155/2015/982058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2015/982058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4325214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25705546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Washburn RA, Smith KW, Jette AM, Janney CA. The physical activity scale for the elderly (PASE): development and evaluation. J Clin Epidemiol. 1993;46:153&#x2013;62. 10.1016/0895-4356(93)90053-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0895-4356(93)90053-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8437031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lueken U, Seidl U, Schwarz M, V&#xf6;lker L, Naumann D, Mattes K, et al. Die Apathy Evaluation Scale: Erste Ergebnisse zu den psychometrischen Eigenschaften einer deutschsprachigen &#xdc;bersetzung der Skala. Fortschr Neurol Psychiatr. 2006;74:714&#x2013;22. 10.1055/s-2006-932164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-2006-932164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17167730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin RS, Biedrzycki RC, Firinciogullari S. Reliability and validity of the apathy evaluation scale. Psychiatry Res. 1991;38:143&#x2013;62. 10.1016/0165-1781(91)90040-V.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0165-1781(91)90040-V</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1754629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehnert A, Herschbach P, Berg P, Henrich G, Koch U. Progredienzangst bei Brustkrebspatientinnen - Validierung der Kurzform des Progredienzangstfragebogens PA-F-KF/ Fear of progression in breast cancer patients &#x2013; validation of the short form of the Fear of Progression Questionnaire (FoP-Q-SF). Z Psychosom Med Psychother. 2006;52:274&#x2013;88. 10.13109/zptm.2006.52.3.274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13109/zptm.2006.52.3.274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17156600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yardley L, Beyer N, Hauer K, Kempen G, Piot-Ziegler C, Todd C. Development and initial validation of the Falls Efficacy Scale-International (FES-I). Age Ageing. 2005;34:614&#x2013;9. 10.1093/ageing/afi196.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afi196</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16267188</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jonasson SB, Nilsson MH, Lexell J. Psychometric properties of the original and short versions of the Falls Efficacy Scale-International (FES-I) in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2017;15:116. 10.1186/s12955-017-0689-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-017-0689-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5452359</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28569162</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trenkwalder C, Kohnen R, H&#xf6;gl B, Metta V, Sixel&#x2010;D&#xf6;ring F, Frauscher B, et al. Parkinson&#x2019;s disease sleep scale&#x2014;validation of the revised version PDSS&#x2010;2. Mov Disord. 2011;26:644&#x2013;52. 10.1002/mds.23476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23476</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21312275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penner I, Raselli C, St&#xf6;cklin M, Opwis K, Kappos L, Calabrese P. The fatigue scale for motor and cognitive functions (FSMC): validation of a new instrument to assess multiple sclerosis-related fatigue. Mult Scler J. 2009;15:1509&#x2013;17. 10.1177/1352458509348519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458509348519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19995840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peto V, Jenkinson C, Fitzpatrick R, Greenhall R. The development and validation of a short measure of functioning and well being for individuals with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Qual Life Res. 1995;4:241&#x2013;8. 10.1007/BF02260863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02260863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7613534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger K, Broil S, Muller T, Ries V. deutschen Version des PDQ-39: Ein krankheitsspezifischer Fragebogen zur Erfassung der Lebensqualit&#xe4;t von Parkinson-Patienten. 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jerusalem M, Schwarzer R. SWE - Skala zur Allgemeinen Selbstwirksamkeitserwartung. 2003. 10.23668/PSYCHARCHIVES.4515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hindmarch I, Lehfeld H, De Jongh P, Erzigkeit H. The Bayer activities of daily living scale (B-ADL). Dement Geriatr Cogn Disord. 1998;9(Suppl. 2):20&#x2013;6. 10.1159/000051195.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000051195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9718231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri KR, Martinez&#x2010;Martin P, Schapira AHV, Stocchi F, Sethi K, Odin P, et al. International multicenter pilot study of the first comprehensive self&#x2010;completed nonmotor symptoms questionnaire for Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: the NMSQuest study. Mov Disord. 2006;21:916&#x2013;23. 10.1002/mds.20844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.20844</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16547944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litvan I, Goldman JG, Tr&#xf6;ster AI, Schmand BA, Weintraub D, Petersen RC, et al. Diagnostic criteria for mild cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: <i>Movement</i> disorder society task force guidelines. Mov Disord. 2012;27:349&#x2013;56. 10.1002/mds.24893.
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.24893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3641655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22275317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou KL, Amick MM, Brandt J, Camicioli R, Frei K, Gitelman D, et al. A recommended scale for cognitive screening in clinical trials of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2010;25:2501&#x2013;7. 10.1002/mds.23362.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.23362</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2978783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20878991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill DJ, Freshman A, Blender JA, Ravina B. The montreal cognitive assessment as a screening tool for cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord. 2008;23:1043&#x2013;6. 10.1002/mds.22017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.22017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18381646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoops S, Nazem S, Siderowf AD, Duda JE, Xie SX, Stern MB, et al. Validity of the MoCA and MMSE in the detection of MCI and dementia in Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2009;73:1738&#x2013;45. 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181c34b47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3181c34b47</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2788810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19933974</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalbe E, Rehberg SP, Heber I, Kronenbuerger M, Schulz JB, Storch A, et al. Subtypes of mild cognitive impairment in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: evidence from the LANDSCAPE study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016;87:1099&#x2013;105. 10.1136/jnnp-2016-313838.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2016-313838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27401782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cro S, Morris TP, Kenward MG, Carpenter JR. Reference-based sensitivity analysis via multiple imputation for longitudinal trials with protocol deviation. The Stata Journal: Promoting communications on statistics and Stata. 2016;16:443&#x2013;63. 10.1177/1536867X1601600211.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1536867X1601600211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5796638</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29398978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalbe E, Aarsland D, Folkerts A-K. Cognitive interventions in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: where we want to go within 20 years. J Park Dis. 2018;8:107&#x2013;13. 10.3233/JPD-181473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JPD-181473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6311377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30584158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pigott JS, Davies N, Chesterman E, Read J, Nimmons D, Walters K, et al. Delivering optimal care to people with cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a qualitative study of patient, caregiver, and professional perspectives. Parkinsons Dis. 2023;2023:1&#x2013;16. 10.1155/2023/9732217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/9732217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10480026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37675146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons KD. Self-management of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: guidelines for program development and evaluation. Phys Occup Ther Geriatr. 2003;21:17&#x2013;31. 10.1080/J148v21n03_02.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/J148v21n03_02</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulcsarova K, Skorvanek M, Postuma RB, Berg D. Defining Parkinson&#x2019;s Disease: Past and Future. J Park Dis. 2024:1&#x2013;15. 10.3233/JPD-230411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11492139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38489197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aslam S, Manfredsson F, Stokes A, Shill H. Advanced&#x201d; Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a review. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2024;123:106065. 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2024.106065.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parkreldis.2024.106065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38418318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>