<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41335306</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2198-6576</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>13</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Rheumatology and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Rheumatol Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Methotrexate Maintenance After Initiation of Biological or Targeted Synthetic DMARDs in Rheumatoid Arthritis: Results from the 2-Year Longitudinal Prospective Non-interventional STRATEGE2 Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>157</StartPage><EndPage>177</EndPage><MedlinePgn>157-177</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40744-025-00806-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The primary objective was to describe the therapeutic approach to methotrexate (MTX) use at the initiation of the first biologic or targeted synthetic disease-modifying antirheumatic drug (b/tsDMARD) in the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis (RA). Secondary objectives included characterising participants initiating b/tsDMARD treatment, examining treatment strategies over time, monitoring disease progression, and identifying factors influencing treatment choices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This longitudinal, prospective, non-interventional, multicentre study (STRATEGE2) enrolled adult participants with RA who had been treated with MTX for at least 3&#xa0;months and required b/tsDMARD treatment due to persistent disease activity. Outcomes were assessed at 12&#xa0;months (M12) and 24&#xa0;months (M24) after initiating b/tsDMARD treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At baseline, 173 participants with RA had a mean (SD) disease duration of 5.6 (7.3) years and a mean Disease Activity Score in 28 joints (DAS28) score of 4.3 (1.2). Approximately two-thirds had been on MTX for over a year, with a mean weekly dose of 18.8 (4.2) mg (median 20.0), and 72.3% received it subcutaneously. MTX was continued at the initiation of b/tsDMARD therapy in 97.7% of participants. By M12, 83.2% of participants remained on MTX, with 39.9% (95%&#xa0;CI 32.5-47.6) maintaining the same dosage and route of administration. Discontinuation of MTX was primarily due to participant choice or adverse events. At M24, the mean change in DAS28 score was -&#x2009;2.0 (1.3), with 66.0% of participants achieving remission. On the basis of European Alliance of Associations for Rheumatology (EULAR) classification criteria, 65.2% had a good response, 19.1% a moderate response, and 15.6% an inadequate response.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The STRATEGE2 study investigators adhered to current clinical guidelines by continuing MTX in combination with b/tsDMARD initiation for the management of RA.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov: Therapeutic Strategy Associated with bDMARDs or tsDMARDs in Rheumatoid Arthritis and Psoriatic Arthritis (STRATEGE2), NCT05082805.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gaujoux-Viala</LastName><ForeName>C&#xe9;cile</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2099-6496</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>UM1318, Desbrest Institute of Epidemiology and Public Health, University of Montpellier, INSERM, Rheumatology, N&#xee;mes University Hospital, Montpellier, France. cecile.gaujoux.viala@chu-nimes.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Service de Rhumatologie, CHU de N&#xee;mes, Place du Pr. Robert Debr&#xe9;, 30029, N&#xee;mes Cedex 9, France. cecile.gaujoux.viala@chu-nimes.fr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dernis</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuelle</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6113-166X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHU, Department of Rheumatology, University of Caen, Caen, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Senbel</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0001-6290-6110</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rheumatology Specialty Center, 24 Place Castellane, Marseille, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Herman-Demars</LastName><ForeName>H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-3780-9418</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Affairs Department, Nordic Pharma, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Becker</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-8554-4281</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Affairs Department, Nordic Pharma, Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Flipo</LastName><ForeName>Ren&#xe9;-Marc</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5528-8070</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CHU Roger Salengro, Rheumatology Department, Lille University Hospital, Lille, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05082805</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Rheumatol Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101674543</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2198-6576</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DMARDs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Methotrexate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rheumatoid arthritis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Treat-to-target</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: C&#xe9;cile Gaujoux-Viala: AbbVie; Alfasigma; Amgen; Biocon; Biogen; Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol-Myers Squibb; Celgene; Celltrion; Eli Lilly; Galapagos; Gilead Sciences; Janssen; Medac; Merck-Serono; Mylan; Nordic Pharma; Novartis; Pfizer; Roche; Sandoz; Sanofi; UCB Pharma and Viatrix. Emmanuelle Dernis: AbbVie, Amgen, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Celgene, Eli Lilly, Galapagos, Gilead, Janssen, MSD, Nordic Pharma, Novartis, Pfizer, Roche, Roche-Chuga&#xef;, Sandoz, Sanofi and UCB Pharma. Eric Senbel: Abbvie, Celltrion, Fresenius Kabi, Lilly, Medac, Nordic Pharma, Novartis, Pfizer, Sandoz and UCB. H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne Herman-Demars and Jennifer Becker: employees Nordic Pharma France. Ren&#xe9;-Marc Flipo: Abbvie, Bristol-Myers Squibb, Eli-Lilly, Janssen, MSD, Nordic Pharma, Novartis, Pfizer, Roche-Chuga&#xef;, Sandoz and Sanofi. Ethical Approval: This study was approved on 12 November 2018, by an independent ethics committee (Comit&#xe9; de Protection des Personnes Sud M&#xe9;diterran&#xe9;e V; Reference 18.068). All participating study sites accepted the single ethics committee approval. The ethics committee expressly authorized the use of oral non-opposition, as permitted for non-interventional research conducted in France and involving no risk or constraint beyond routine clinical practice. Participants received comprehensive written information about the study objectives, procedures, and their rights, in compliance with Articles L.1121-1 and L.1122-1-1 of the French Public Health Code. Oral non-opposition to the collection of their personal data was obtained prior to participant inclusion and documented in the study records, as required by local regulations governing non-interventional studies in France. All data were processed in compliance with the reference methodology MR-003 from the French Data Protection Authority (CNIL), ensuring the protection of participant privacy and data integrity.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41335306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12816463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40744-025-00806-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40744-025-00806-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Almutairi KB, Nossent JC, Preen DB, Keen HI, Inderjeeth CA. The prevalence of rheumatoid arthritis: a systematic review of population-based studies. J Rheumatol. 2021;48(5):669&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.200367</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33060323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Personnes prises en charge pour polyarthrite rhumato&#xef;de et maladies apparent&#xe9;es en 2022. Caisse Nationale de l'Assurance Maladie&#x2014;CNAM [updated 2024 Dec 06]. https://www.assurance-maladie.ameli.fr/sites/default/files/2022_fiche_polyarthrite-rhumatoide-et-maladies-apparentees.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillemin F, Saraux A, Guggenbuhl P, et al. Prevalence of rheumatoid arthritis in France: 2001. Ann Rheum Dis. 2005;64(10):1427&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2004.029199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1755224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15800010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daien C, Hua C, Gaujoux-Viala C, et al. Update of French Society for Rheumatology recommendations for managing rheumatoid arthritis. Jt Bone Spine. 2019;86(2):135&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2018.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30315988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Radner H, Smolen JS, Aletaha D. Remission in rheumatoid arthritis: benefit over low disease activity in patient-reported outcomes and costs. Arthritis Res Ther. 2014;16(1):R56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/ar4491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3979137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24555808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu J, Xiao L, Zhu J, Qin Q, Fang Y, Zhang JA. Methotrexate use reduces mortality risk in rheumatoid arthritis: a systematic review and meta-analysis of cohort studies. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2022;55:152031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2022.152031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35671648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaujoux-Viala C, Gossec L, Cantagrel A, et al. Recommendations of the French Society for Rheumatology for managing rheumatoid arthritis. Jt Bone Spine. 2014;81(4):287&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2014.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24986683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fautrel B, Benhamou M, Foltz V, et al. Early referral to the rheumatologist for early arthritis patients: evidence for suboptimal care. Results from the ESPOIR cohort. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2010;49(1):147&#x2013;55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kep340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19933784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benhamou M, Rincheval N, Roy C, et al. The gap between practice and guidelines in the choice of first-line disease modifying antirheumatic drug in early rheumatoid arthritis: results from the ESPOIR cohort. J Rheumatol. 2009;36(5):934&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.080762</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2850375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19286850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smolen JS, Landewe RBM, Bergstra SA, et al. EULAR recommendations for the management of rheumatoid arthritis with synthetic and biological disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs: 2022 update. Ann Rheum Dis. 2023;82(1):3&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard-2022-223356</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36357155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fautrel B, Kedra J, Juge P-A, et al. 2024 update of the recommendations of the French Society of Rheumatology for the diagnosis and management of patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Jt Bone Spine. 2024;91(6):105790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2024.105790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39389412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Choy E, Aletaha D, Behrens F, et al. Monotherapy with biologic disease-modifying anti-rheumatic drugs in rheumatoid arthritis. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2017;56(5):689&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27550301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaujoux-Viala C, Bergmann JF, Goguillot M, et al. Suboptimal management of rheumatoid arthritis in France: a real-world study based on data from the French National Health Data System. RMD Open. 2023. 10.1136/rmdopen-2023-003075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/rmdopen-2023-003075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10619049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37914177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue M, Kanda H, Tateishi S, Fujio K. Evaluation of response criteria in rheumatoid arthritis treated with biologic disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2020;72(7):942&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.23914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31058442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekhon S, Pope J, Canadian Scleroderma Research Group, Baron M. The minimally important difference in clinical practice for patient-centered outcomes including health assessment questionnaire, fatigue, pain, sleep, global visual analog scale, and SF-36 in scleroderma. J Rheumatol. 2010;37(3):591&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.090375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20080913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaujoux-Viala C, Rincheval N, Dougados M, Combe B, Fautrel B. Optimal methotrexate dose is associated with better clinical outcomes than non-optimal dose in daily practice: results from the ESPOIR early arthritis cohort. Ann Rheum Dis. 2017;76(12):2054&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-211268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28866645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung JY, Lee E, Kim JW, et al. Unveiling difficult-to-treat rheumatoid arthritis: long-term impact of biologic or targeted synthetic DMARDs from the KOBIO registry. Arthritis Res Ther. 2023;25(1):174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-023-03165-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10507947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37726808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraenkel L, Bathon JM, England BR, et al. 2021 American College of Rheumatology guideline for the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2021;73(7):1108&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.41752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34101376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg V, Chodick G, Xue Z, Faccin F, Amital H. Real-world data of adherence and drug survival of biologics in treatment-naive and treatment-experienced adult patients with rheumatoid arthritis. Adv Ther. 2023;40(10):4504&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-023-02607-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10499743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37566157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Mulligen E, Weel AE, Hazes JM, van der Helm-van MA, de Jong PHP. Tapering towards DMARD-free remission in established rheumatoid arthritis: 2-year results of the TARA trial. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(9):1174&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-217485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7456559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32482645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Mulligen E, Weel AE, Kuijper TM, et al. Two-year cost effectiveness between two gradual tapering strategies in rheumatoid arthritis: cost-utility analysis of the TARA trial. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(12):1550&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-217528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7677489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32907801</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaujoux-Viala C. &#xc9;valuation de l&#x2019;activit&#xe9; de la polyarthrite rhumato&#xef;de. Rev Rhum Monogr. 2017;84(4):343&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Mulligen E, de Jong PHP, Kuijper TM, et al. Gradual tapering TNF inhibitors versus conventional synthetic DMARDs after achieving controlled disease in patients with rheumatoid arthritis: first-year results of the randomised controlled TARA study. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78(6):746&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2018-214970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30954969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Looijen AEM, van Mulligen E, van der Helm-van Mil AHM, de Jong PHP. Tapering subcutaneous methotrexate causes more disease flares compared with tapering oral administration in established rheumatoid arthritis patients. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2022;61(8):e216&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keac154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35266525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haschka J, Englbrecht M, Hueber AJ, et al. Relapse rates in patients with rheumatoid arthritis in stable remission tapering or stopping antirheumatic therapy: interim results from the prospective randomised controlled RETRO study. Ann Rheum Dis. 2016;75(1):45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2014-206439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25660991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherbini AA, Sharma SD, Gwinnutt JM, Hyrich KL, Verstappen SMM. Prevalence and predictors of adverse events with methotrexate mono- and combination-therapy for rheumatoid arthritis: a systematic review. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2021;60(9):4001&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keab304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8410011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perez-Garcia LF, Roder E, Krijthe BP, et al. Is methotrexate safe for men with an immune-mediated inflammatory disease and an active desire to become a father? Results of a prospective cohort study (iFAME-MTX). Ann Rheum Dis. 2023;82(8):1068&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard-2023-224032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10359513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37263756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ytterberg SR, Bhatt DL, Mikuls TR, et al. Cardiovascular and cancer risk with tofacitinib in rheumatoid arthritis. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(4):316&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2109927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35081280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. Xeljanz (tofacitinib): Initial clinical trial results of increased risk of major adverse cardiovascular events and malignancies (excluding NMSC) with use of tofacitinib relative to TNF-alpha inhibitors. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bessette L, Florica B, Naik L, et al. A Canadian retrospective chart review evaluating concomitant methotrexate de-escalation patterns in patients with rheumatoid arthritis treated with biologic or targeted synthetic DMARDs. Rheumatol Ther. 2024;11(5):1165&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40744-024-00696-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11422300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38976169</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope JE, Haraoui B, Thorne JC, Vieira A, Poulin-Costello M, Keystone EC. The Canadian methotrexate and etanercept outcome study: a randomised trial of discontinuing versus continuing methotrexate after 6&#xa0;months of etanercept and methotrexate therapy in rheumatoid arthritis. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73(12):2144&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2013-203684</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4251190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23979914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SB, Pope J, Haraoui B, et al. Methotrexate withdrawal in patients with rheumatoid arthritis who achieve low disease activity with tofacitinib modified-release 11&#xa0;mg once daily plus methotrexate (ORAL shift): a randomised, phase&#xa0;3b/4, non-inferiority trial. Lancet Rheumatol. 2019;1(1):e23&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2665-9913(19)30005-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38229356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goss SL, Klein CE, Jin Z, et al. Methotrexate dose in patients with early rheumatoid arthritis impacts methotrexate polyglutamate pharmacokinetics, adalimumab pharmacokinetics, and efficacy: pharmacokinetic and exposure-response analysis of the CONCERTO trial. Clin Ther. 2018;40(2):309&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2018.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29402521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bechman K, Oke A, Yates M, et al. Is background methotrexate advantageous in extending TNF inhibitor drug survival in elderly patients with rheumatoid arthritis? An analysis of the British Society for Rheumatology Biologics Register. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2020;59(9):2563&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kez671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7449803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31998962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roubille C, Coffy A, Rincheval N, et al. Ten-year analysis of the risk of severe outcomes related to low-dose glucocorticoids in early rheumatoid arthritis. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2021;60(8):3738&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keaa850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33320245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijlsma JWJ. Annals of the Rheumatic Diseases collection on glucocorticoids (2020&#x2013;2023): novel insights and advances in therapy. Ann Rheum Dis. 2024;83(1):4&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37739452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakellariou G, Scire CA, Rumi F, et al. Influence of initial glucocorticoid co-medication on mortality and hospitalization in early inflammatory arthritis: an investigation by record linkage of clinical and administrative databases. Arthritis Res Ther. 2022;24(1):144.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-022-02824-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9204953</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35710524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almayali AAH, Boers M, Hartman L, et al. Three-month tapering and discontinuation of long-term, low-dose glucocorticoids in senior patients with rheumatoid arthritis is feasible and safe: placebo-controlled double blind tapering after the GLORIA trial. Ann Rheum Dis. 2023;82(10):1307&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard-2023-223977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37541762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mierau M, Schoels M, Gonda G, Fuchs J, Aletaha D, Smolen JS. Assessing remission in clinical practice. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2007;46(6):975&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kem007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17341506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bykerk VP, Massarotti EM. The new ACR/EULAR remission criteria: rationale for developing new criteria for remission. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2012;51(Suppl 6):vi16-20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/kes281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23221582</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richette P, Allez M, Descamps V, et al. Impact of COVID-19 on initiation of biologic therapy prescriptions for chronic inflammatory diseases. Jt Bone Spine. 2022;89(1):105253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2021.105253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8305295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34314887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benucci M, Damiani A, Infantino M, Manfredi M, Quartuccio L. Old and new antirheumatic drugs for the treatment of COVID-19. Joint Bone Spine. 2020;87(3):195&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2020.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7167223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32321635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>