<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">19956668</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-6203</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>11</Issue><PubDate><Year>2009</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PloS one</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLoS One</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Impact of empire expansion on household diet: the Inka in Northern Chile's Atacama Desert.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e8069</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e8069</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e8069</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pone.0008069</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The impact of expanding civilization on the health of American indigenous societies has long been studied. Most studies have focused on infections and malnutrition that occurred when less complex societies were incorporated into more complex civilizations. The details of dietary change, however, have rarely been explored. Using the analysis of starch residues recovered from coprolites, here we evaluate the dietary adaptations of indigenous farmers in northern Chile's Atacama Desert during the time that the Inka Empire incorporated these communities into their economic system. This system has been described as "complementarity" because it involves interaction and trade in goods produced at different Andean elevations. We find that as local farming societies adapted to this new asymmetric system, a portion of their labor had to be given up to the Inka elite through a corv&#xe9;e tax system for maize production. In return, the Inka system of complementarity introduced previously rare foods from the Andean highlands into local economies. These changes caused a disruption of traditional communities as they instituted a state-level economic system on local farmers. Combined with previously published infection information for the same populations under Inka rule, the data suggest that there may have been a dual health impact from disruption of nutrition and introduction of crowd disease.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vinton</LastName><ForeName>Sheila Dorsey</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Anthropology, University of Kentucky, Lexington, Kentucky, United States of America.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perry</LastName><ForeName>Linda</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reinhard</LastName><ForeName>Karl J</ForeName><Initials>KJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Santoro</LastName><ForeName>Calogero M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira-Santos</LastName><ForeName>Isabel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016456">Historical Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLoS One</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101285081</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-6203</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001106" MajorTopicYN="N">Archaeology</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002677" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Chile</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018556" MajorTopicYN="N">Crops, Agricultural</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005191" MajorTopicYN="N">Family Characteristics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005502" MajorTopicYN="Y">Food</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005580" MajorTopicYN="Y">Fossils</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D049690" MajorTopicYN="N">History, Ancient</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013696" MajorTopicYN="N">Temperature</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003313" MajorTopicYN="N">Zea mays</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Competing Interests: </b>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2008</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2009</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2009</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19956668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2777378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0008069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Poinar HN, Kuch M, Sobolik KD, Barnes I, Stankiewicz AB, et al. A molecular analysis of dietary diversity for three Archaic Native Americans. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2001;98:4317&#x2013;4322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC31832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11296282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas M, Gilbert P, Jenkins DL, G&#xf6;therstrom A, Naveran N, et al. DNA from pre-Clovis human coprolites in Oregon, North America. Science. 2008;320:786&#x2013;789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhard KJ. Cultural ecology of prehistoric parasitism on the Colorado Plateau as evidenced by coprology. Am J Phys Anthropol. 1988;77:355&#x2013;366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3067587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhard KJ, Byrant VM. Pathoecology and the future of coprolite studies. In: Stodder AWM, editor. Reanalysis and reinterpretation in southwestern bioarchaeology. Tempe: Arizona State University Press; 2008. pp. 199&#x2013;216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro C, Vinton SD, Reinhard K. Inca expansion and parasitism in the Lluta Valley: preliminary data. Mem Inst Oswaldo Cruz. 2003;98:161&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12687777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dillehay TD, Williams VI, Santoro CM. &#xc1;reas perif&#xe9;ricas y nucleares. Contextos de interacciones sociales complejas y multidireccionales. Chungara Rev Antropol Chil. 2006;38:249&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bryant VM. Invisible clues to New World plant domestication. Science. 2003;299:1029&#x2013;1030.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12586933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murra JV. The limits and limitations of the &#x201c;Vertical Archipielago&#x201d; in the Andes. In: Masuda S, Shimada I, Morris C, editors. Andean ecology and civilization, an interdisciplinary perspective on Andean ecological complementarity. Tokyo: University of Tokyo Press; 1985. pp. 15&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murra JV. El control de un m&#xe1;ximo de pisos ecol&#xf3;gicos en la econom&#xed;a de las sociedades andinas. In: Murra JV, editor. I&#xf1;igo Ortiz de Z&#xfa;&#xf1;iga, Visita de la Provincia de Le&#xf3;n de Huanuco [1562] volumen 2. Huanuco: Universidad Hermilio Valdizan; 1972. pp. 428&#x2013;468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hidalgo J, Durston A. Reconstituci&#xf3;n &#xe9;tnica colonial en la Sierra de Arica: El Cacicazgo de Codpa, 1650&#x2013;1780. Actas del IV Congreso Internacional de Etnohistoria Tomo. 1998;II:32&#x2013;75.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buren M. Rethinking the vertical archipelago. Amer Anthropol. 1996;98:338&#x2013;351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro CM, Hidalgo J, Valenzuela D, Romero &#xc1;, Rothhammer F, et al. &#xbf;Espacios multi&#xe9;tnicos y verticalidad costera? revisita al &#x201c;Tercer Caso&#x201d; de Murra y a la arqueolog&#xed;a del valle de Lluta, &#xe1;rea Centro Sur Andina. Chungara Rev Antropol Chil 41, in press 2009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastorf CA. The effect of the Inka State on Sausa agricultural production and crop consumption. Amer Antiq. 1990;55:262&#x2013;290.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santoro CM. Pittsburgh: University of Pittsburgh; 1995. Late prehistoric regional interaction and social change in a coastal valley of northern Chile. Ph.D. thesis.220</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holden TG. Evidence of prehistoric diet from northern Chile: coprolites, gut contents and flotation samples from the Tulan Quebrada. World Archaeol. 1991;22:320&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16471006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams IR. Analysis of coprolites recovered from six sites in northern Chile. In: Meighan CW, True DL, editors. Prehistoric trails of Atacama: archaeology of northern Chile. Los Angeles: University of California; 1980. pp. 195&#x2013;204.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez L, Hall H. An&#xe1;lisis de dieta y movilidad en un campamiento arcaico del norte de Chile (Analysis of diet and mobility in an Archaic camp of northern Chile). Bol Inst Franc Estud Andin. 1982;11:91&#x2013;114.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhard KJ, Byrant VM. Coprolite analysis: a biological perspective on archaeology. In: Schiffer MB, editor. Advances in archaeological method and theory 4. Tucson: University of Arizona Press; 1992. pp. 245&#x2013;288.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhard KJ, Byrant VM, Vinton SD. Reinterpreting the pollen data from Dos Cabezas. Internat J Osteoarchaeol. 2007;17:531&#x2013;541.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinton SD. (1997) Dietary analysis of coprolites from the Lluta Valley in Arica, Chile. M.A. thesis. Lincoln, University of Nebraska-Lincoln, Lincoln. 212 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reinhard KJ, Edwards SK, Damon TR, Meier DK. Pollen concentration analysis of Ancestral Pueblo dietary variation. Palaeogeog Palaeoclimatol Palaeoecol. 2006;237:92&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastorf CA, Johannessen S. Pre-Hispanic political change and the role of maize in the Central Andes of Peru. Amer Anthropol. 1993;95:115&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Altroy T. Washington, D.C.: Smithsonian Institution Press; 1992. Provincial power in the Inka Empire.284</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>D'Altroy T, Hastorf C. The distribution and contents of Inca state storehouses in the Xauxa region of Peru. Am Antiq. 1984;49:334&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murra JV. Greenwich: JAI Press; 1980. The Economic organization of the Inca State.214</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murra JV. La mit'a al Tawantinsuyu: prestaciones de los grupos &#xe9;tnicos. Chungara Rev Antropol Chil. 1983;10:77&#x2013;94.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris C, Thompson DE. London: Thames and Hudson; 1985. Hu&#xe1;nuco Pampa - an Inca city and its hinterland.181</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murra JV. Lima: Instituto de Estudios Peruanos; 1975. Formaciones econ&#xf3;micas y pol&#xed;ticas del mundo Andino.230</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piperno DR, Ranere AJ, Holst I, Hansell P. Starch grains reveal early root crop horticulture in the Panamanian tropical forest. Nature. 2000;407:894&#x2013;897.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11057665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pohl MED, Pipperno DR, Pope KO, Jones JG. Microfossil evidence for pre-Columbian maize dispersals in the neotropics from San Andre's, Tabasco, Mexico. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2007;104:6870&#x2013;6875.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1871877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17426147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wivinis GP, Maywald EC. Photographs of starches. In: Wivinis GP, Maywald EC, editors. Starch, Chemistry and Technology. New York: Academic Press; 1967. pp. 649&#x2013;685.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babot, M. del P. Starch grain damage as an indicator of food processing. In: Hart DM, Wallis LA, editors. Phytolith and starch research in the Australian-Pacific-Asian regions: the state of the art. Canberra: Pandanus Books; 2003. pp. 69&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henry AG, Hudson HF, Piperno DR. Changes in starch grain morphologies from cooking. J Archaeol Sci. 2009;36:915&#x2013;922.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry L, Sandweiss D, Piperno D, Rademaker K, Malpass M, et al. Early maize agriculture and interzonal interaction in southern Peru. Natur. 2006;440:76&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16511492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>