<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">38171708</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1558-3597</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>83</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>02</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of the American College of Cardiology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Am Coll Cardiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Contemporary Management and Outcomes of Patients With High-Risk&#xa0;Pulmonary Embolism.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>35</StartPage><EndPage>43</EndPage><MedlinePgn>35-43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.026</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0735-1097(23)07981-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Contemporary care patterns/outcomes in high-risk pulmonary embolism (PE) patients are unknown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">This study sought to characterize the management of high-risk PE patients and identify factors associated with poor outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A retrospective analysis of the PERT (Pulmonary Embolism Response Team) Consortium Registry was performed. Patients presenting with intermediate-risk PE, high-risk PE, and catastrophic PE (those with hemodynamic collapse) were identified. Patient characteristics were compared with chi-square testing for categorical covariates and Student's t-test for continuous covariates. Multivariable logistic regression was used to assess associations between clinical characteristics and outcomes in the high-risk population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of 5,790 registry patients, 2,976 presented with intermediate-risk PE and 1,442 with high-risk PE. High-risk PE patients were more frequently treated with advanced therapies than intermediate-risk PE patients (41.9% vs 30.2%; P&#xa0;&lt; 0.001). In-hospital mortality (20.6% vs 3.7%; P&#xa0;&lt; 0.001) and major bleeding (10.5% vs. 3.5%; P&#xa0;&lt; 0.001) were more common in high-risk PE. Multivariable regression analysis demonstrated vasopressor use (OR: 4.56; 95%&#xa0;CI: 3.27-6.38; P&#xa0;&lt; 0.01), extracorporeal membrane oxygenation use (OR: 2.86; 95%&#xa0;CI: 1.12-7.30; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.03), identified clot-in-transit (OR: 2.26; 95%&#xa0;CI: 1.13-4.52; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.02), and malignancy (OR:&#xa0;=&#xa0;1.70; 95%&#xa0;CI: 1.13-2.56; P&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.01) as factors associated with in-hospital mortality. Catastrophic PE patients (n&#xa0;=&#xa0;197 [13.7% of high-risk PE patients]) had higher in-hospital mortality (42.1% vs 17.2%; P&#xa0;&lt; 0.001) than those presenting with noncatastrophic high-risk PE. Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (13.3% vs. 4.8% P&#xa0;&lt; 0.001) and systemic thrombolysis (25% vs 11.3%; P&#xa0;&lt; 0.001) were used more commonly in catastrophic PE.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">In the largest analysis of high-risk PE patients to date, mortality rates were high with the worst outcomes among patients with hemodynamic collapse.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 American College of Cardiology Foundation. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kobayashi</LastName><ForeName>Taisei</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Medicine Division, Perelman School of Medicine. University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA; Penn Cardiovascular Outcomes, Quality and Evaluative Research Center, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pugliese</LastName><ForeName>Steven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Hospital of the University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sethi</LastName><ForeName>Sanjum S</ForeName><Initials>SS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Interventional Cardiovascular Care, Columbia University Irving Medical Center, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parikh</LastName><ForeName>Sahil A</ForeName><Initials>SA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Interventional Cardiovascular Care, Columbia University Irving Medical Center, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldberg</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiothoracic Surgery Division, Westchester Medical Center, Westchester, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alkhafan</LastName><ForeName>Fahad</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boston Clinical Research Institute, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vitarello</LastName><ForeName>Clara</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boston Clinical Research Institute, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenfield</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lookstein</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Mount Sinai Medical Center, New York, New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keeling</LastName><ForeName>Brent</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiothoracic Surgery, Emory University Hospital, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klein</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Piedmont Heart Institute, Atlanta, Georgia, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gibson</LastName><ForeName>C Michael</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boston Clinical Research Institute, Boston, Massachusetts, USA; Smith Center for Cardiovascular Outcomes Research, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glassmoyer</LastName><ForeName>Lauren</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Medicine Division, Perelman School of Medicine. University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Khandhar</LastName><ForeName>Sameer</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Medicine Division, Perelman School of Medicine. University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Secemsky</LastName><ForeName>Eric</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Smith Center for Cardiovascular Outcomes Research, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giri</LastName><ForeName>Jay</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Medicine Division, Perelman School of Medicine. University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA; Penn Cardiovascular Outcomes, Quality and Evaluative Research Center, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA. Electronic address: jay.giri@pennmedicine.upenn.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL150290</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Am Coll Cardiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8301365</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0735-1097</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>J Am Coll Cardiol. 2024 Jan 2;83(1):44-46. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2023.11.001.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">38171709</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006470" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hemorrhage</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016015" MajorTopicYN="N">Logistic Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011655" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pulmonary Embolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015912" MajorTopicYN="N">Thrombolytic Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ECMO</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">catheter-directed embolectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">catheter-directed thrombolysis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-risk pulmonary embolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary embolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systemic thrombolysis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Funding Support and Author Disclosures This work was funded through a grant from the PERT Consortium, a 501(c)3 not-for-profit organization. Dr Kobayashi&#x2019;s institution has received funding for research from Inari medical and Endovascular Engineering. Dr Sethi has received honoraria/consulting fees from Boston Scientific, Janssen, Chiesi, Terumo, and Inari. Dr Parikh has received institutional research funding from Abbott, Boston Scientific, TriReme Medical, Shockwave Medical, Surmodics, Reflow Medical, Concept Medical, Veryan Medical, and MedAlliance; has served as an advisor to Abbott, Boston Scientific, Cordis, Medtronic, and Philips; and has served as a consultant for Terumo, Inari, Penumbra, and Canon. Dr Rosenfield has served as a consultant or on the scientific advisory board for Abbott Vascular, Althea Medical, Angiodynamics, Auxetics, Becton Dickinson, Boston Scientific, Contego, Crossliner, Imperative Care/Truvic, Innova Vascular, Inspire MD, Janssen/Johnson and Johnson, Magneto, Mayo Clinic, MedAlliance, Medtronic, Neptune Medical, Penumbra, Philips, Surmodics, Terumo, Thrombolex, Vasorum, Vantis Vascular, and Vumedi; owns equity or stock options in Access Vascular, Aerami, Althea Medical, Auxetics, Contego, Endospan, Imperative Care/Truvic, Innova Vascular, InspireMD, JanaCare, Magneto, MedAlliance, Neptune Medical, Orchestra, Prosomnus, Shockwave, Skydance, Summa Therapeutics, Thrombolex, Valcare, Vantis Vascular, Vasorum, and Vumedi; his institution has received funding from the National Institutes of Health, Abiomed, Boston Scientific, Novo Nordisk, Penumbra, Gettinge-Atrium; and has served on the Board of Directors of the National PERT Consortium. Dr Lookstein has served on the advisory board for Boston Scientific and Medtronic; has served as a consultant for Penumbra Vascular, Abbott Vascular, Neptune Medical, Imperative Vascular, Becton Dickinson Vascular, Biosense Webster, and Cordis Vascular; and owns equity in Imperative Vascular, Innova Vascular, Thrombolex, and Summa Vascular. Dr Gibson has served as a consultant for Alexion, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Janssen, and CytoSorbents. Dr Khandhar has received consulting fees from Inari Medical. Dr Secemsky has received consulting fees from Abbott, Bayer, BD, Boston Scientific, Cook, Cordis, CSI, HeartFlow, Inari, InfraRedx, Medtronic, Philips, RapidAI, Shockwave, and VentureMed; and his institution has received research funding from the National Institutes of Health/National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (K23HL150290), the U.S. Food and Drug Administration, the Society for Cardiovascular Angiography and Interventions, BD, Boston Scientific, Cook, CSI, Laminate Medical, Medtronic, and Philips. Dr Giri has served on the advisory board for and his institution has received research funding from Boston Scientific, Abbott Vascular, Recor Medical, Inari Medical, Edwards, and Abiomed; and owns equity in Endovascular Engineering. All other authors have reported that they have no relationships relevant to the contents of this paper to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38171708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2129948</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12737870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2023.10.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0735-1097(23)07981-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Martin KA, Molsberry R, Cuttica MJ, Desai KR, Schimmel DR, Khan SS. Time trends in pulmonary embolism mortality rates in the United States, 1999 to 2018. J Am Heart Assoc. 2020;9:e016784. 10.1161/JAHA.120.016784</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.120.016784</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7660782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32809909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldhaber SZ, Bounameaux H. Pulmonary embolism and deep vein thrombosis. Lancet. 2012;379:1835&#x2013;1846. 10.1016/S0140-6736(11)61904-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)61904-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22494827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinides SV. 2014 ESC Guidelines on the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism. Eur Heart J. 2014;35:3145&#x2013;3146. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehu393</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehu393</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25452462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Giri J, Sista AK, Weinberg I, et al. Interventional therapies for acute pulmonary embolism: current status and principles for the development of novel evidence: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2019;140:e774&#x2013;e801. 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000707</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31585051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooke TW, Hirsch AT, Misra S, et al. 2011 ACCF/AHA focused update of the guideline for the management of patients with peripheral artery disease (updating the 2005 guideline): a report of the American College of Cardiology Foundation/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;58:2020&#x2013;2045. 10.1016/j.jacc.2011.08.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2011.08.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4714326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21963765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kucher N, Rossi E, De Rosa M, Goldhaber SZ. Massive pulmonary embolism. Circulation. 2006;113:577&#x2013;582. 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.105.592592</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.105.592592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16432055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torbicki A, Gali&#xe9; N, Covezzoli A, Rossi E, De Rosa M, Goldhaber SZ, ICOPER Study Group. Right heart thrombi in pulmonary embolism: results from the International Cooperative Pulmonary Embolism Registry. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2003;41:2245&#x2013;2251. 10.1016/s0735-1097(03)00479-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0735-1097(03)00479-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaff MR, McMurtry MS, Archer SL, et al. Management of massive and submassive pulmonary embolism, iliofemoral deep vein thrombosis, and chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2011;123:1788&#x2013;1830. 10.1161/CIR.0b013e318214914f</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0b013e318214914f</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21422387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Secemsky E, Chang Y, Jain CC, et al. Contemporary management and outcomes of patients with massive and submassive pulmonary embolism. Am J Med. 2018;131:1506&#x2013;1514.e0. 10.1016/j.amjmed.2018.07.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2018.07.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30102908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg JB, Giri J, Kobayashi T, et al. Surgical management and mechanical circulatory support in high-risk pulmonary embolisms: historical context, current status, and future directions: a scientific statement from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2023;147:e628&#x2013;e647. 10.1161/CIR.0000000000001117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000001117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36688837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldhaber SZ, Visani L, De Rosa M. Acute pulmonary embolism: clinical outcomes in the International Cooperative Pulmonary Embolism Registry (ICOPER). Lancet. 1999;353:1386&#x2013;1389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10227218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver M, Gibson CM, Giri J, et al. Outcomes in high-risk pulmonary embolism patients undergoing FlowTriever mechanical thrombectomy or other contemporary therapies: results from the FLAME study. Circ Cardiovasc Interv. 2023;16:e013406. 10.1161/CIRCINTERVENTIONS.123.013406</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCINTERVENTIONS.123.013406</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10573120</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37847768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulman S, Anger&#xe5;s U, Bergqvist D, Eriksson B, Lassen MR, Fisher W. Subcommittee on Control of Anticoagulation of the Scientific and Standardization Committee of the International Society on Thrombosis and Haemostasis. Definition of major bleeding in clinical investigations of antihemostatic medicinal products in surgical patients. J Thromb Haemost. 2010;8:202&#x2013;204. 10.1111/j.1538-7836.2009.03678.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1538-7836.2009.03678.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19878532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanni S, Nazerian P, Pepe G, et al. Comparison of 2 prognostic models for acute pulmonary embolism: clinical vs. right ventricular dysfunction-guided approach. J Thromb Haemost. 2011;9:1916&#x2013;1923. 10.1111/j.1538-7836.2011.04459.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1538-7836.2011.04459.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21819540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becattini C, Agnelli G, Lankeit M, et al. Acute pulmonary embolism: mortality prediction by the 2014 European Society of Cardiology risk stratification model. Eur Respir J. 2016;48:780&#x2013;786. 10.1183/13993003.00024-2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00024-2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27174887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kasper W, Konstantinides S, Geibel A, et al. Management strategies and determinants of outcome in acute major pulmonary embolism: results of a multicenter registry. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1997;30:1165&#x2013;1171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9350909</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kreit JW. The impact of right ventricular dysfunction on the prognosis and therapy of normotensive patients with pulmonary embolism. Chest. 2004;125:1539&#x2013;1545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15078772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grifoni S, Olivotto I, Cecchini P, et al. Short-term clinical outcome of patients with acute pulmonary embolism, normal blood pressure, and echocardiographic right ventricular dysfunction. Circulation. 2000;101:2817&#x2013;2822.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10859287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin BW, Schreiber DH, Liu G, et al. Therapy and outcomes in massive pulmonary embolism from the Emergency Medicine Pulmonary Embolism in the Real World Registry. Am J Emerg Med. 2012;30:1774&#x2013;1781. 10.1016/j.ajem.2012.02.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajem.2012.02.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22633723</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feit F, Voeltz MD, Attubato MJ, et al. Predictors and impact of major hemorrhage on mortality following percutaneous coronary intervention from the REPLACE-2 Trial. Am J Cardiol. 2007;100:1364&#x2013;1369. 10.1016/j.amjcard.2007.06.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2007.06.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17950791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chhatriwalla AK, Amin AP, Kennedy KF, et al. National Cardiovascular Data Registry. Association between bleeding events and in-hospital mortality after percutaneous coronary intervention. JAMA. 2013;309:1022&#x2013;1029. 10.1001/jama.2013.1556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.1556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23483177</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Athappan G, Sengodan P, Chacko P, Gandhi S. Comparative efficacy of different modalities for treatment of right heart thrombi in transit: a pooled analysis. Vasc Med. 2015;20:131&#x2013;138. 10.1177/1358863X15569009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1358863X15569009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25832601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrios D, Rosa-Salazar V, Morillo R, et al. Prognostic significance of right heart thrombi in patients with acute symptomatic pulmonary embolism: systematic review and meta-analysis. Chest. 2017;151:409&#x2013;416. 10.1016/j.chest.2016.09.038</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2016.09.038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27746202</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrios D, Chavant J, Jim&#xe9;nez D, et al. Treatment of right heart thrombi associated with acute pulmonary embolism. Am J Med. 2017;130:588&#x2013;595. 10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.11.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjmed.2016.11.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28011316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhury P, Gadre SK, Schneider E, et al. Impact of multidisciplinary pulmonary embolism response team availability on management and outcomes. Am J Cardiol. 2019;124:1465&#x2013;1469. 10.1016/j.amjcard.2019.07.043</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amjcard.2019.07.043</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31495443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McNamara RL, Wang Y, Herrin J, et al. Effect of door-to-balloon time on mortality in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2006;47:2180&#x2013;2186. 10.1016/j.jacc.2005.12.072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2005.12.072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16750682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nallamothu BK, Normand SL, Wang Y, et al. Relation between door-to-balloon times and mortality after primary percutaneous coronary intervention over time: a retrospective study. Lancet. 2015;385:1114&#x2013;1122. 10.1016/S0140-6736(14)61932-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(14)61932-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4409657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25467573</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Man S, Xian Y, Holmes DN, et al. Association between thrombolytic door-to-needle time and 1-year mortality and readmission in patients with acute ischemic stroke. JAMA. 2020;323:2170&#x2013;2184. 10.1001/jama.2020.5697</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.5697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267850</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32484532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosovsky R, Chang Y, Rosenfield K, et al. Changes in treatment and outcomes after creation of a pulmonary embolism response team (PERT), a 10-year analysis. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2019;47:31&#x2013;40. 10.1007/s11239-018-1737-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11239-018-1737-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30242551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabrhel C, Rosovsky R, Channick R, et al. A multidisciplinary pulmonary embolism response team: initial 30-month experience with a novel approach to delivery of care to patients with submassive and massive pulmonary embolism. Chest. 2016;150:384&#x2013;393. 10.1016/j.chest.2016.03.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2016.03.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27006156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xenos ES, Davis GA, He Q, Green A, Smyth SS. The implementation of a pulmonary embolism response team in the management of intermediate- or high-risk pulmonary embolism. J Vasc Surg Venous Lymphat Disord. 2019;7:493&#x2013;500. 10.1016/j.jvsv.2018.11.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jvsv.2018.11.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30930079</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>