<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">42108271</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1546-170X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>10</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The microRNA inhibitor CDR132L in patients with reduced left ventricular ejection fraction after myocardial infarction: a randomized phase 2 trial.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41591-026-04408-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>MicroRNA-132 (miR-132) is a central regulator of adverse cardiac remodeling. Here we evaluated CDR132L, a synthetic antisense oligonucleotide miR-132 inhibitor, in a multinational, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 trial (HF-REVERT) in patients with recent myocardial infarction (MI) and left ventricular (LV) systolic dysfunction. Within 3-14&#x2009;days after MI, 294 patients were randomized to receive CDR132L 5&#x2009;mg&#x2009;kg<sup>-1</sup>, CDR132L 10&#x2009;mg&#x2009;kg<sup>-1</sup> or placebo as three intravenous doses at 4-week intervals plus guideline-directed therapy. In total, 280 patients (245 men and 35 women) who received at least one dose of the study drug were included in the modified intention-to-treat population. CDR132L was well tolerated, with no hepatic, renal, hematologic or cardiac toxicity signals. The primary endpoint-the percentage change in LV end-systolic volume index at 6&#x2009;months-improved in all groups but did not differ significantly between the CDR132L groups (5&#x2009;mg&#x2009;kg<sup>-1</sup> and 10&#x2009;mg&#x2009;kg<sup>-1</sup>) and the placebo group. Secondary endpoints, including LV ejection fraction, global longitudinal strain and N-terminal pro B-type natriuretic peptide, were also not significantly different between the CDR132L and placebo groups. Prespecified exploratory analyses suggested potential benefits of CDR132L treatment in patients with advanced adverse remodeling at baseline, supporting further evaluation of CDR132L, including in chronic heart failure conditions. ClinicalTrials.gov: NCT05350969 .</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Bauersachs</LastName><ForeName>Johann</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9341-117X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology and Angiology, Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Solomon</LastName><ForeName>Scott D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3698-9597</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Division, Brigham and Women's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anker</LastName><ForeName>Stefan D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0805-8683</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology (CVK) of German Heart Center Charit&#xe9;; German Centre for Cardiovascular Research (DZHK), partner site Berlin, Charit&#xe9; Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antorrena-Miranda</LastName><ForeName>Isabel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9523-3787</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, La Paz University Hospital, Research Institute IdiPAZ, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>de Boer</LastName><ForeName>Rudolf A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4775-9140</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Erasmus University Medical Centre, Rotterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Filippatos</LastName><ForeName>Gerasimos</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Athens University Hospital Attikon, School of Medicine, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friede</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5347-7441</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Statistics, University Medical Centre G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>German Centre for Cardiovascular Research (DZHK), partner site Lower Saxony, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hauke</LastName><ForeName>Wilfried</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardior Pharmaceuticals GmbH, a Novo Nordisk company, Hannover, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ponikowski</LastName><ForeName>Piotr</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Heart Diseases, University Hospital, Medical University Wroclaw, Wroclaw, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vardeny</LastName><ForeName>Orly</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6387-1351</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Minnesota Medical School, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Altschul</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novo Nordisk A/S, S&#xf8;borg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gamborg</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novo Nordisk A/S, S&#xf8;borg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vinther</LastName><ForeName>Kasper</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Novo Nordisk A/S, S&#xf8;borg, Denmark.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thum</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4360-1511</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardior Pharmaceuticals GmbH, a Novo Nordisk company, Hannover, Germany. thum.thomas@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Molecular and Translational Therapeutic Strategies (IMTTS), Hannover Medical School, Hannover, Germany. thum.thomas@mh-hannover.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05350969</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9502015</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1078-8956</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CoiStatement>Competing interests: J.B. received honoraria for lectures/consulting from Abbott Laboratories, Amgen, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, Cardior Pharmaceuticals, CVRx, Edwards, Lilly, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pfizer, Roche and Zoll and research support for the department from Abiomed, CVRx, Norgine, Roche and Zoll. S.D.S. has received research grants from Alexion, Alnylam, Applied Therapeutics, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Bellerophon, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boston Scientific, BridgeBio, Cytokinetics, Edgewise, Gossamer, GlaxoSmithKline, Ionis, Intellia, Lexicon, Lilly, National Institutes of Health/National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Respicardia, Sanofi Pasteur, Tenaya, Theracos and US2.AI and has consulted for Abbott Laboratories, Action, Akros, Alexion, Alnylam, American Regent, Amgen, AnaCardio, Arena, AskBio, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Bristol Myers Squibb, BridgeBio, Cardior Pharmaceuticals, Cardurion, CellProthera, Corvia, Cytokinetics, DiNAQOR, GlaxoSmithKline, Intellia, Lilly, Moderna, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Quantum Genomics, Recordati, Roche, Sanofi Pasteur, Sarepta, Synhale, Tenaya, Theracos, Tremeau and Valo. S.D.A. reports grants from Abbott Laboratories and CSL/Vifor and personal fees for consultancies, trial committee work and/or lectures from Actimed, Alleviant, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Berlin Heals, BiMyo, Boehringer Ingelheim, Brahms, Cardiac Dimensions, Cardior Pharmaceuticals, Cordio, Corvia, CSL/Vifor, CVRx, Cytokinetics, Edwards, Impulse Dynamics, Lilly, Mankind Pharma, Novo Nordisk, Occlutech, Pfizer, Pulnovo, Regeneron, Relaxera, Repairon, Scirent, Sensible Medical, Vectorious, Veru, VisCardia, Vivus and V-Wave. S.D.A. is a named co-inventor of two patent applications regarding MR-proANP (DE 102007010834 and DE 102007022367) but does not benefit personally from the related issued patents. I.A.-M. reports honoraria for lectures, advisory board and/or consulting from AstraZeneca, Boehringer Ingelheim, Cardior Pharmaceuticals and Daiichi Sankyo. R.A.d.B. reports research grants and/or fees from Abbott Laboratories, Alnylam, AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb and Novo Nordisk; speaker engagements with and/or received fees from and/or service on an advisory board for Abbott Laboratories, AstraZeneca and Novo Nordisk. G.F. reports lecture fees and/or advisory and/or trial committee membership for Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Cardior Pharmaceuticals, Impulse Dynamics, Medtronic, Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Servier and Vifor and research grants from the European Union. T.F. reports receiving institutional grants from the European Commission, the Federal Joint Committee and the German Research Foundation and personal fees for statistical consultancies, including data monitoring committees, from Actimed Therapeutics, Apellis, argenx, Aslan, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Berlin Heals, Boehringer Ingelheim, Biogen, Biosense Webster, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardior Pharmaceuticals, CSL Behring, CVRx, Daiichi Sankyo, eCovery, Enanta Pharmaceuticals, Fresenius Kabi, Galapagos, IQVIA, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Novartis, PINK! Aktiv gegen Brustkrebs, PPD, Priothera, Recardio, Recordati, Relaxera, Roche, Sarfez, Upstream Bio, Viatris, VICO Therapeutics and Vifor. W.H. is an employee of Cardior Pharmaceuticals, a Novo Nordisk Company. P.P. received consultancy fees and speakers&#x2019; honoraria from Abbott Vascular, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Boehringer Ingelheim, Moderna, Novartis, Novo Nordisk, Pharmacosmos, Relaxera, Servier, Vifor and WhiteSwell. O.V. received honoraria for consulting from AstraZeneca, Bayer, Cardior Pharmaceuticals, Cytokinetics and Novo Nordisk and research support to her institution from AstraZeneca, Bayer and Cardurion. R.A., M.G. and K.V. are employees of Novo Nordisk A/S. T.T. is the founder, CSO, CMO and Managing Director of Cardior Pharmaceuticals, a Novo Nordisk company.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">42108271</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-026-04408-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41591-026-04408-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Anderson, J. L. &amp; Morrow, D. A. Acute myocardial infarction. N. Engl. J. Med. 376, 2053&#x2013;2064 (2017).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra1606915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frantz, S., Hundertmark, M. J., Schulz-Menger, J., Bengel, F. M. &amp; Bauersachs, J. Left ventricular remodelling post-myocardial infarction: pathophysiology, imaging, and novel therapies. Eur. Heart J. 43, 2549&#x2013;2561 (2022).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehac223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35511857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">9336586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hill, J. A. &amp; Olson, E. N. Cardiac plasticity. N. Engl. J. Med. 358, 1370&#x2013;1380 (2008).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra072139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18367740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foinquinos, A. et al. Preclinical development of a miR-132 inhibitor for heart failure treatment. Nat. Commun. 11, 633 (2020).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-14349-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32005803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">6994493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ucar, A. et al. The miRNA-212/132 family regulates both cardiac hypertrophy and cardiomyocyte autophagy. Nat. Commun. 3, 1078 (2012).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms2090</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23011132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">3657998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batkai, S. et al. CDR132L improves systolic and diastolic function in a large animal model of chronic heart failure. Eur. Heart J. 42, 192&#x2013;201 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33089304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7813625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hinkel, R. et al. AntimiR-132 attenuates myocardial hypertrophy in an animal model of percutaneous aortic constriction. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 77, 2923&#x2013;2935 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2021.04.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34112319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Batkai, S. et al. MiR-132 inhibition improves myocardial strain in a large animal model of chronic left ventricular adverse remodelling. Eur. Heart J. Imaging Methods Pract. 3, qyaf088 (2025).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ehjimp/qyaf088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40761305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">12318716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>T&#xe4;ubel, J. et al. Novel antisense therapy targeting microRNA-132 in patients with heart failure: results of a first-in-human phase 1b randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Eur. Heart J. 42, 178&#x2013;188 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa898</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33245749</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">7954267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauersachs, J. et al. Efficacy and safety of CDR132L in patients with reduced left ventricular ejection fraction after myocardial infarction: rationale and design of the HF-REVERT trial. Eur. J. Heart Fail. 26, 674&#x2013;682 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejhf.3139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38269451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos-Gallego, C. G. et al. Randomized trial of empagliflozin in nondiabetic patients with heart failure and reduced ejection fraction. J. Am. Coll. Cardiol. 77, 243&#x2013;255 (2021).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.11.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33197559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viereck, J. &amp; Thum, T. Development of a mechanism-based next-generation therapeutic for heart failure derived from the dark genome. JACC Basic Transl. Sci. 8, 1595&#x2013;1598 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacbts.2023.09.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38205345</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">10774590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>