<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36569031</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0040-1625</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>166</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Technological forecasting and social change</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Technol Forecast Soc Change</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Great Reset. Restratification for lives, livelihoods, and the planet.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>120636</StartPage><MedlinePgn>120636</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.techfore.2021.120636</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In reviewing the Great Reset, an initiative launched by the World Economic Forum (WEF) in response to the global coronavirus crisis, this perspective article considers the scenario of an epochal transition from capitalism to "restorism". To facilitate the observation of underlying trends and assumptions, a systems-theoretical framework is developed for the observation of both this Great Reset scenario and those scenarios that are by implication excluded by the WEF vision. It is thus shown that the "shared goals" advocated by the WEF would converge to a transition from a modern pluralist to a "new-normative" order stratified to the primacy of individual, institutional, and planetary&#xa0;health. In discussing sociological implications of this transition, a vision&#xa0;emerges of a new digitally enhanced medieval era where health plays the role once played by religion. In this restorist scenario of a neo-medieval world health society, the emergence of new social strata corresponding to different levels of purity, infection, or pollution would be a probable consequence. The paper concludes that idea of deliberately caused great resets and other control illusions nurtured by the WEF initiative are barely smarter than and spur what the UN Secretary-General refers to as "wild conspiracy theories".</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roth</LastName><ForeName>Steffen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Strategy, La Rochelle Business School, 102 Rue de Coureilles, 17000 La Rochelle, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Social Research, University of Turku, Assistentinkatu 7, Turku 20014, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Technol Forecast Soc Change</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101085131</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0040-1625</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fourth industrial revolution</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Great reset initiative</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Restorism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scenario</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Social theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">World economic forum</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36569031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9757815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.techfore.2021.120636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0040-1625(21)00068-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amer M., Daim T.U., Jetter A. A review of scenario planning. Futures. 2013;46:23&#x2013;40.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broom D.  2020. Could this COVID-19 &#x2018;health passport&#x2019; be the Future of Travel and Events?https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/07/covid-19-passport-app-health-travel-covidpass-quarantine-event/ Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dave P.  2020. This Wearable Tech is Being used by Care Homes to Stem Outbreaks of COVID-19.https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/05/elderly-home-wearables-contact-tracing-apple-google Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harari Y.N. Harper Collins; New York: 2017. Homo Deus: A Brief History of Tomorrow.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harari Y.N.  2020. How to Survive the 21st Century. Speech at the 2020 WEF Annual Meeting in Davos.https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/01/yuval-hararis-warning-davos-speech-future-predications/ Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heylighen F. Towards an intelligent network for matching offer and demand: From the sharing economy to the global brain. Technol. Forecast. Soc. Change. 2017;114:74&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holton R.J. Handbook of Social Theory. Sage Publications; London, Thousand Oaks, New Delhi: 2001. Talcott Parsons: Conservative apologist or irreplaceable icon; pp. 152&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphrey, A. (2005), &#x201c;SWOT analysis for management consulting&#x201d;, <i>SRI alumni Newsletter</i>, pp. 7-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hutt R.  2020. &#x2018;Untact&#x2019;: South Korea's Plan for a Contact-Free Society.https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/08/south-korea-contactless-coronavirus-economy/ Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huxley A. Harper and Brothers; New York: 1958. The Brave New World Revisited.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lenartowicz M. Creatures of the semiosphere: A problematic third party in the &#x2018;humans plus technology'cognitive architecture of the future global superintelligence. Technol. Forecast. Soc. Change. 2017;114:35&#x2013;42.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis J.P. Coronavirus disease 2019: the harms of exaggerated information and non-evidence-based measures. Eur. J. Clin. Invest. 2020;50(4):e13222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7163529</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32191341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ioannidis J.P. Global perspective of COVID-19 epidemiology for a full-cycle pandemic. Eur. J. Clin. Invest. 2020:e13423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33026101</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luhmann N. Polity; Cambridge: 2013. Introduction to Systems Theory.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luhmann N. Vol. 2. Stanford University Press; Stanford: 2013. (Theory of Society).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magsamen B., Shutko G.  2020. These 5 COVID-Fighting Technologies Show the Power of Global Ingenuity.https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/08/5-technology-advancements-during-covid-19-wearables-ai/ Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan J. Will we work in twenty-first century capitalism? A critique of the fourth industrial revolution literature. Economy Soc. 2019;48(3):371&#x2013;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons T. Vol. 1. McGraw-Hill Book Company; New York: 1937. (The Structure of Social Action).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons T. Free Press; New York: 1951. The Social System.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth S., Clark C., Trofimov N., Mkrtichyan A., Heidingsfelder M., Appignanesi L.&#x2026;Kaivo-Oja J. Futures of a distributed memory. A global brain wave measurement (1800&#x2013;2000) Technol. Forecast. Soc. Change. 2017;118:307&#x2013;323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth S., Schwede P., Valentinov V., &#x17d;a&#x17e;ar K., Kaivo-oja J. Big data insights into social macro trends (1800&#x2013;2000): A replication study. Technol. Forecast. Soc. Change. 2019;149</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roth S. Digital transformation of social theory. A research update. Technol. Forecast. Soc. Change. 2019;146:88&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanvee C.  2020. 3 Ways Young People Can Heal Our Divided World.https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/08/3-ways-young-people-can-heal-our-divided-world/ Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sault S.  2020. This is What Bill Gates had to Say About Epidemics, Back in 2015.https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/03/bill-gates-epidemic-pandemic-preparedness-ebola-covid-19/ Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schimank U. Modernity as a functionally differentiated capitalist society: A general theoretical model. Eur. J. Soc. Theory. 2015;18(4):413&#x2013;430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab K., Davis N. World Economic Forum; Cologny: 2018. Shaping the Fourth Industrial Revolution.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab K.  2020. Now is the Time for a 'great reset'.https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/06/now-is-the-time-for-a-great-reset/ Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab K., Mallert T. World Economic Forum Publishing; 2020. COVID-19. The Great Reset.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schi&#xf8;lin K. Revolutionary dreams: Future essentialism and the sociotechnical imaginary of the fourth industrial revolution in Denmark. Soc. Stud. Sci. 2020;50(4):542&#x2013;566.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31464575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S., Soederberg S. Redesigning the business of development: the case of the World Economic Forum and global risk management. Rev. Int. Political Economy. 2020;27(4):828&#x2013;854.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer Brown G. E. P. Dutton; New York: 1979. Laws of Form.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer Brown G.  2013. Interview Excerpt, Horningsham, England, June 2013 (Interviewer: Markus Heidingsfelder)https://vimeo.com/181216140 Available online at:</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trauth-Goik A. Repudiating the fourth industrial revolution discourse: a new episteme of technological progress. World Futures. 2020:1&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veltmeyer H. Development and globalization as imperialism. Can. J. Dev. Stud./Revue canadienne d'&#xe9;tudes du d&#xe9;veloppement. 2005;26(1):89&#x2013;106.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward S. Honesty and dissimulation in upper-class interaction in early modern France: Madame and the old German sincerity. Seventeenth-Century French Stud. 2003;25(1):247&#x2013;258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward S. Madame chats with coquettes: The evolution of early modern theories of conversation. The Seventeenth Century. 2005;20(2):281&#x2013;293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward S. Functional differentiation and the crisis in early modern upper-class conversation: the second Madame, interaction, and isolation. Seventeenth-Century French Stud. 2006;28(1):235&#x2013;247.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ward S. From Fontainebleau to Facebook: The early modern discourse of personal sincerity and its echoes in the contemporary discourse of organisational transparency. Syst. Res. Behav. Sci. 2017;34(2):139&#x2013;147.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weihrich H. The TOWS matrix&#x2014;a tool for situational analysis. Long Range Plann. 1982;15(2):54&#x2013;66.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>