<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35137607</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0921</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Season>Jan-Feb</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sports health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sports Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Chronic Adaptations of Shoulder Muscle Synergies in Healthy Baseball Players.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>97</StartPage><EndPage>104</EndPage><MedlinePgn>97-104</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/19417381211069564</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Previous research has demonstrated that muscle synergy structure can adapt owing to training and injury; however, muscle synergies have not been evaluated in baseball players.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="HYPOTHESIS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The throwing arm would have a similar muscle synergy structure but different levels of individual muscle activity within each synergy, relative to the nonthrowing arm.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="STUDY DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Cross-sectional study in a controlled laboratory setting.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fourteen healthy competitive baseball players were included. Participants were tested bilaterally during a center-out planar reaching task using the KINARM robot, where kinematic data and surface electromyography data from 14 glenohumeral and scapular muscles were synchronized. Principal component analysis was used to extract muscle synergies, the variance accounted for (VAF) of each synergy, and individual muscle coefficients. The dominant (DOM) arm was compared with the nondominant (NDOM) arm using paired <i>t</i> tests for all dependent variables.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The same number of muscle synergies were extracted on the DOM and NDOM arms, along with no differences in VAF. In the first synergy, the infraspinatus (DOM 0.798 vs NDOM 0.587, <i>P</i> = 0.038) and lower trapezius (DOM 0.872 vs NDOM 0.480, <i>P</i> = 0.005) muscle coefficients significantly increased on the DOM arm. The second synergy had a significantly increased anterior deltoid (DOM 0.764 vs NDOM 0.374, <i>P</i> = 0.003) and a significantly decreased posterior deltoid (DOM -0.069 vs NDOM 0.197, <i>P</i> = 0.041) muscle coefficient on the DOM arm.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The DOM shoulder exhibits a higher proportion of infraspinatus and lower trapezius muscle activation during the external rotation and abduction synergy. Also, the DOM shoulder has increased muscle activation of the teres major and latissimus dorsi during the internal rotation synergy, and increased muscle activation of the pectoralis major during the cross-body adduction synergy, compared with the NDOM shoulder.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL RELEVANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">By exploring these neuromuscular adaptations, the improved understanding of muscle synergy adaptations in baseball players will help optimize injury prevention and rehabilitation techniques.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wambold</LastName><ForeName>Morgan</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Germantown Friends School, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taylor</LastName><ForeName>Chris</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Kinesiology, Temple University, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tucker</LastName><ForeName>Carole A</ForeName><Initials>CA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Paul</LastName><ForeName>Ryan W</ForeName><Initials>RW</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6846-3349</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rothman Orthopaedic Institute, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thomas</LastName><ForeName>Stephen J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Exercise Science, Thomas Jefferson University, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Sports Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101518422</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1941-0921</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012782" MajorTopicYN="N">Shoulder</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001484" MajorTopicYN="Y">Baseball</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000293" MajorTopicYN="N">injuries</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012785" MajorTopicYN="Y">Shoulder Joint</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018482" MajorTopicYN="N">Muscle, Skeletal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016059" MajorTopicYN="N">Range of Motion, Articular</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000070599" MajorTopicYN="Y">Shoulder Injuries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">baseball</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">muscle synergy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nervous system</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuromuscular adaptations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">shoulder</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The following author declared potential conflict of
interest: S.J.T. reports receiving publishing royalties from Human
Kinetics, outside the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35137607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9808840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19417381211069564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Astolfi MM, Struminger AH, Royer TD, Kaminski TW, Swanik CB. Adaptations of the shoulder to overhead throwing in youth athletes. J Athl Train. 2015;50:726-732.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4532184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25811844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bengoetxea A, Leurs F, Hoellinger T, et al. Physiological modules for generating discrete and rhythmic movements: component analysis of EMG signals. Front Comput Neurosci. 2015;8:169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4288127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25620928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brochier T, Spinks RL, Umilta MA, Lemon RN. Patterns of muscle activity underlying object-specific grasp by the macaque monkey. J Neurophysiol. 2004;92:1770-1782.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15163676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll TJ, Riek S, Carson RG. The sites of neural adaptation induced by resistance training in humans. J Physiol. 2002;544:641-652.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2290590</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12381833</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson RG. Changes in muscle coordination with training. J Appl Physiol (1985). 2006;101:1506-1513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16888047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang YJ, Kulig K. The neuromechanical adaptations to Achilles tendinosis.J Physiol. 2015;593:3373-3387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4553058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26046962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark DJ, Ting LH, Zajac FE, Neptune RR, Kautz SA. Merging of healthy motor modules predicts reduced locomotor performance and muscle coordination complexity post-stroke. J Neurophysiol. 2010;103:844-857.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2822696</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20007501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conte S, Camp CL, Dines JS. Injury trends in Major League Baseball over 18 seasons: 1998-2015. Am J Orthop (Belle Mead NJ). 2016;45:116-123.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26991562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cools AM, Witvrouw EE, De Clercq GA, et al. Scapular muscle recruitment pattern: electromyographic response of the trapezius muscle to sudden shoulder movement before and after a fatiguing exercise. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2002;32:221-229.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12014826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Marchis C, Schmid M, Bibbo D, Bernabucci I, Conforto S. Inter-individual variability of forces and modular muscle coordination in cycling: a study on untrained subjects. Hum Mov Sci. 2013;32:1480-1494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24060224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digiovine NM, Jobe FW, Pink M, Perry J. An electromyographic analysis of the upper extremity in pitching. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 1992;1:15-25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22958966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebaugh DD, McClure PW, Karduna AR. Scapulothoracic and glenohumeral kinematics following an external rotation fatigue protocol. J Orthop Sports Phys Ther. 2006;36:557-571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16915977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Enoka RM, Duchateau J. Muscle fatigue: what, why and how it influences muscle function. J Physiol. 2008;586:11-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2375565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17702815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Escamilla RF, Andrews JR. Shoulder muscle recruitment patterns and related biomechanics during upper extremity sports. Sports Med Auckl NZ. 2009;39:569-590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19530752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleisig GS, Andrews JR, Dillman CJ, Escamilla RF. Kinetics of baseball pitching with implications about injury mechanisms. J Sports Med. 1995;23:233-239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7778711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fleisig GS, Barrentine SW, Zheng N, Escamilla RF, Andrews JR. Kinematic and kinetic comparison of baseball pitching among various levels of development.J Biomech. 1999;32:1371-1375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10569718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gowan ID, Jobe FW, Tibone JE, Perry J, Moynes DR. A comparative electromyographic analysis of the shoulder during pitching. Professional versus amateur pitchers. Am J Sports Med. 1987;15:586-590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3425786</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heales LJ, Hug F, MacDonald DA, Vicenzino B, Hodges PW. Is synergistic organisation of muscle coordination altered in people with lateral epicondylalgia? A case-control study. Clin Biomech (Bristol, Avon). 2016;35:124-131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27179317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermens HJ, Freriks B, Disselhorst-Klug C, Rau G. Development of recommendations for SEMG sensors and sensor placement procedures.J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2000;10:361-374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11018445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibberd EE, Shutt CE, Oyama S, Blackburn JT, Myers JB. Physical contributors to glenohumeral internal rotation deficit in high school baseball players. J Sport Health Sci. 2015;4:299-306.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horsley IG, Herrington LC, Rolf C. Does a SLAP lesion affect shoulder muscle recruitment as measured by EMG activity during a rugby tackle? J Orthop Surg. 2010;5:12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2842247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20184752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hug F, Turpin NA, Gu&#xe9;vel A, Dorel S. Is interindividual variability of EMG patterns in trained cyclists related to different muscle synergies? J Appl Physiol (1985). 2010;108:1727-1736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20299611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ishigaki T, Ishida T, Samukawa M, et al. Does restriction of glenohumeral horizontal adduction reflect posterior capsule thickening of the throwing shoulder? J Phys Ther Sci. 2015;27:1299-1302.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4483383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26157205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly BT, Backus SI, Warren RF, Williams RJ. Electromyographic analysis and phase definition of the overhead football throw. Am J Sports Med. 2002;30:837-844.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12435650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kristiansen M, Samani A, Madeleine P, Hansen EA. Muscle synergies during bench press are reliable across days. J Electromyogr Kinesiol. 2016;30:81-88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27323305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leite MJ, S&#xe1; MC, Lopes MJ, Matos RM, Sousa AN, Torres JM. Coracohumeral distance and coracoid overlap as predictors of subscapularis and long head of the biceps injuries. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2019;28:1723-1727.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31014558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair AV, Rao SN, Kumaran CK, Kochukunju BV. Clinico-radiological correlation of subcoracoid impingement with reduced coracohumeral interval and its relation to subscapularis tears in Indian patients. J Clin Diagn Res. 2016;10:RC17-RC20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5072034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27790534</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Overduin SA, d&#x2019;Avella A, Roh J, Bizzi E. Modulation of muscle synergy recruitment in primate grasping. J Neurosci. 2008;28:880-892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6671000</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18216196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page P. Shoulder muscle imbalance and subacromial impingement syndrome in overhead athletes. Int J Sports Phys Ther. 2011;6:51-58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3105366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21655457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pappas AM, Zawacki RM, Sullivan TJ. Biomechanics of baseball pitching. A preliminary report. Am J Sports Med. 1985;13:216-222.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4025673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reuther KE, Sheridan S, Thomas SJ. Differentiation of bony and soft-tissue adaptations of the shoulder in professional baseball pitchers. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2018;27:1491-1496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29730137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safavynia SA, Torres-Oviedo G, Ting LH. Muscle synergies: implications for clinical evaluation and rehabilitation of movement. Top Spinal Cord Inj Rehabil. 2011;17:16-24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3143193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21796239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sainburg RL, Kalakanis D. Differences in control of limb dynamics during dominant and nondominant arm reaching. J Neurophysiol. 2000;83:2661-2675.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10709817</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10805666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholz J, Klein MC, Behrens TEJ, Johansen-Berg H. Training induces changes in white matter architecture. Nat Neurosci. 2009;12:1370-1371.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2770457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19820707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott SH, Dukelow SP. Potential of robots as next-generation technology for clinical assessment of neurological disorders and upper-limb therapy. J Rehabil Res Dev. 2011;48:335-353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21674387</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takenaga T, Sugimoto K, Goto H, et al. Posterior shoulder capsules are thicker and stiffer in the throwing shoulders of healthy college baseball players: a quantitative assessment using shear-wave ultrasound elastography. Am J Sports Med. 2015;43:2935-2942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26473012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas SJ, Cobb J, Sheridan S, Rauch J, Paul RW. Chronic adaptations of the posterior rotator cuff in professional pitchers. Am J Sports Med. 2021;49:892-898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33591811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas SJ, Swanik CB, Higginson JS, et al. A bilateral comparison of posterior capsule thickness and its correlation with glenohumeral range of motion and scapular upward rotation in collegiate baseball players. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2011;20:708-716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21167742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torres-Oviedo G, Ting LH. Muscle synergies characterizing human postural responses. J Neurophysiol. 2007;98:2144-2156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17652413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaz JR, Olstad BH, Cabri J, Kjendlie PL, Pezarat-Correia P, Hug F. Muscle coordination during breaststroke swimming: comparison between elite swimmers and beginners. J Sports Sci. 2016;34:1941-1948.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26878097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilk KE, Meister K, Andrews JR. Current concepts in the rehabilitation of the overhead throwing athlete. Am J Sports Med. 2002;30:136-151.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11799012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>