<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39381302</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2250-0685</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of orthopaedic case reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Orthop Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Finding the Truth: Cadaver and CT scan Study of Differences in Glenoid Width Size in the Indian Population.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>270</StartPage><EndPage>274</EndPage><MedlinePgn>270-274</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.13107/jocr.2024.v14.i10.4886</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Glenoid mass issues have been extensively published in the recent literature. The controversy arose from our need to compare and obtain the appropriate implant size for reverse shoulder arthroplasty patients. Some well-known authors and surgeons say that Indian patients have a smaller glenoid than their Western friends and patients. Therefore, we decided to examine the glenoid size obtained on a computed tomography (CT) scan and the size obtained on a cadaver, preferably the same cadaver in tertiary care medical school. Necessary permissions were obtained from the relatives of the cadaver, the ethical board, the anatomy department, and the radiology department.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We evaluated 3D CT scans of 100 patients from our medical college during the global pandemic. Of these, we evaluated only 12 patients whose families agreed to postmortem studies and CT scans. Our research focuses on the shoulder of non-orthopedic diseases conducted at KCGMCH and measured the glenoid height, width, and version using a commercially available computer.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The mean age of the patients was 38.5 (range 19-59). The mean glenoid height was 33.8 &#xb1; 3.2 mm, maximum glenoid width was 24.3 &#xb1; 2.2 mm. The mean glenoid version is 3.48 &#xb1; 4 retrospectively. The glenoid width appears to be 23-25 mm on CT scan film, which is similar to cadaver studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings from the cadaver study indicate that the average glenoid size is smaller in the Indian demographic when compared to CT scans. Glenoid width is less in one subset of the population, especially female patients than of the average population than Westerners. However, our studies are limited by the small size of the population and a larger study is recommended in our institution in the future. A better understanding of this glenoid size could help us design a smaller glenoid plate plan, especially for patients in the Indian subcontinent.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; Indian Orthopaedic Research Group.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Upadhyay</LastName><ForeName>Gunjan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, MMIMISR, Ambala, Haryana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jain</LastName><ForeName>Himanshu</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, MMIMISR, Ambala, Haryana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Munde</LastName><ForeName>Santosh Laxman Rao</ForeName><Initials>SLR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Kalpana Chawla Government Medical College, Karnal, Haryana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arya</LastName><ForeName>Ashish</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Kalpana Chawla Government Medical College, Karnal, Haryana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Agarwal</LastName><ForeName>Sashank</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedics, Kalpana Chawla Government Medical College, Karnal, Haryana, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>India</Country><MedlineTA>J Orthop Case Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101641392</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2250-0685</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Glenoid base mismatch</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glenoid version</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glenoid width</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reverse total shoulder arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict of Interest: Nil</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39381302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11458207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13107/jocr.2024.v14.i10.4886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JOCR-14-270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Inui H, Sugamoto K, Miyamoto T, Machida A, Hashimoto J, Nobuhara K. Evaluation of three-dimensional glenoid structure using MRI. J Anat. 2001;199:323&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1468334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11554509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inui H, Sugamoto K, Miyamoto T, Yoshikawa H, Machida A, Hashimoto J, et al. Glenoid shape in atraumatic posterior instability of the shoulder. Clin Orthop. 2002;403:87&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12360012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couteau B, Mansat P, Darmana R, Mansat M, Egan J. Morphological and mechanical analysis of the glenoid by 3D geometric reconstruction using computed tomography. Clin Biomech. 2000;15:S8&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11078898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon YW, Powell KA, Yum JK, Brems JJ, Iannotti JP. Use of three-dimensional computed tomography for the analysis of the glenoid anatomy. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2005;14:85&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15723018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Schroeder HP, Kuiper SD, Botte MJ. Osseus anatomy of the GLENOID. Clin Orthop. 2001;383:131&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11210947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walch G, Badet R, Boulahia A, Khoury A. Morphologic study of the glenoid in primary glenohumeral osteoarthritis. J Arthroplasty. 1999;14:756&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10512449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallino M, Santamaria E, Doro T. Anthropometry of the GLENOID:Clinical and surgical considerations. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 1998;7:284&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9658354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyffeler RW, Werner CM, Simmen BR, Gerber C. Analisys of a retrived Delta III total shoulder prosthesis. J Bone Joint Surg Br. 2004;86B:1187&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15568535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nyffeler RW, Werner CM, Gerber C. Biomechanical relevance of glenoid component positioning in the reverse Delta III total shoulder prosthesis. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2005;14:524&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16194746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delloye C, Joris D, Colette A, Eudier A, Dubuc JE. Complications m&#xe9;caniques de la proth&#xe8;se totale invers&#xe9;e de l'&#xe9;paule. Rev Chir Orthop. 2002;88:410&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12124542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Couteau B, Mansat P, Mansat M, Darmana R, Egan J. In vivo characterization of glenoid with use of computed tomography. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2001;10:116&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11307073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edelson JG. Variations in the anatomy of the GLENOID with reference to the snapping GLENOID. Clin Orthop. 1996;322:111&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8542685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Favard L, Sirveau F, Mestdagh H, Walch G, Kempf JF, Franceschi JP, et al. La proth&#xe8;se invers&#xe9;e de Grammont dans le traitment des arthropathies de l'&#xe9;paule &#xe0;coiffe d&#xe9;truite. R&#xe9;sultats d'une s&#xe9;rie multicentrique de 42 cas. Rev Chir Orthop. 1998;84:82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frankle M, Siegal S, Pupello D, Saleem A, Mighell M, Vasey M. The reverse shoulder prosthesis for glenohumeral arthritis associated with severe rotator cuff deficiency. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2005;87A:1697&#x2013;705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16085607</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Churchill RS, Brems JJ, Kotschi H. Glenoid size, inclination, and version:An anatomic study. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2001;10:327&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11517362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Wilde LF, Berghs BM, Audenaert EA, Sys G, Van Maele GO, Barbaix E. About the variability of the shape of the glenoid cavity. Surg Radiol Anat. 2004;26:54&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14504818</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Welsch G, Mamisch TC, Kikinis R, Schmidt R, Lang P, Forst R, et al. CT-based preoperative analysis of GLENOID morphology and glenohumeral joint geometry. Comput Aided Surg. 2003;8:264&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15529956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werner CM, Steinmann PA, Gilbart M, Gerber C. Treatment of painful pseudoparesis due to irreparable rotator cuff dysfunction with the Delta III reverse-ball-and-socket total shoulder prosthesis. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2005;87A:1476&#x2013;86.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15995114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedman RJ, Hawthorne KB, Genez BM. The use of computerized tomography in the measurement of glenoid version. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1992;74A:1032&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1522089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prescher A, Kl&#xfc;mpen T. The glenoid notch and its relation to the shape of the glenoid cavity of the GLENOID. J Anat. 1997;190:457&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1467625</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9147231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Wilde LF, Audenaert EA, Berghs BM. Shoulder prostheses treating cuff tear arthropathy:A comparative biomechanical study. J Ortho Res. 2004;22:1222&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15475201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehtinen JT, Tingart MJ, Apreleva M, Warner JJ. Quantitative morphology of the GLENOID:Normal variation of the superomedial GLENOIDr angle, and superior and inferior pole thickness. Orthopedics. 2005;28:481&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15945605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallon WJ, Brown HR, Vogler JB, Mart&#xed;nez S. Radiographic and geometric anatomy of the GLENOID. Clin Orthop. 1992;277:142&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1555335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heller JG, Estes BT, Decatur G, Zaouali M, Rang-du-Fliers Diop A. Biomechanical study of screws in the lateral masses:Variables affecting pull-out resistance. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1996;78A:1315&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8816645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valenti P, Sauzieres P, Vaysse V. R&#xe9;sultats pr&#xe9;liminaires des proth&#xe8;ses totales d'&#xe9;paule invers&#xe9;e dans les ruptures de ciffe irr&#xe9;parables avec arthropathie gl&#xe9;no-humerale (25 cas) Rev Chir Orthop. 1998;8f4:81&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Codsi MJ, Bennetts C, Gordiev K, Boeck DM, Kwan Y, Brems J, et al. Normal glenoid vault anatomy and validation of a novel glenoid implant shape. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2008;17:471&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18328741</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>