<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">29939361</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-1701</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>45</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>07</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Schizophrenia bulletin</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Schizophr Bull</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Multiple Dimensions of Insight in Schizophrenia-Spectrum Disorders.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>277</StartPage><EndPage>283</EndPage><MedlinePgn>277-283</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/schbul/sby092</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The concept of insight is used to indicate the propensity of patients with schizophrenia and other severe mental disorders to recognize their illness and engage in treatment. Thus, insight may have notable consequences for the ill individual: Those who lack insight are at higher risk of nonadherence to treatments, negative clinical outcomes, and worse community functioning. Although insight is an intuitive concept, its essence remains difficult to capture. However, many rating scales are available to aid assessment, both for clinical and research purposes. Insight cannot be reduced to a symptom, a psychological mechanism, or a neuropsychological function. It is likely to have dynamic relationships with all these dimensions and with responses to personal events and contextual factors. In particular, social consequences of mental illness and explanatory models that are alternative to the medical model may fundamentally shape insight and treatment choice. Moreover, the cultural or individual stigmatization of mental illness may turn the acquisition of insight into a painful event and increase the risk of depression. Clinicians need to carefully evaluate and promote insight through a personalized approach to aid patient process of care and personal growth.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2018. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Maryland Psychiatric Research Center. All rights reserved. For permissions, please email: journals.permissions@oup.com.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Belvederi Murri</LastName><ForeName>Martino</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychiatric Clinic, Department of Neuroscience, Rehabilitation, Ophthalmology, Genetics and Maternal and Child Science, University of Genoa, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istituto di Ricovero e Cura a Carattere Scientifico per l'Oncologia, Ospedale Policlinico San Martino, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychological Medicine, Institute of Psychiatry, Psychology and Neuroscience, King's College London, London, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Amore</LastName><ForeName>Mario</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Psychiatric Clinic, Department of Neuroscience, Rehabilitation, Ophthalmology, Genetics and Maternal and Child Science, University of Genoa, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Istituto di Ricovero e Cura a Carattere Scientifico per l'Oncologia, Ospedale Policlinico San Martino, Genoa, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Schizophr Bull</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0236760</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0586-7614</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001364" MajorTopicYN="Y">Awareness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059026" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diagnostic Self Evaluation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000067489" MajorTopicYN="Y">Metacognition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Schizophrenia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012938" MajorTopicYN="Y">Social Perception</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057545" MajorTopicYN="Y">Social Stigma</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adherence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">schizophrenia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">social cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stigma</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29939361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6403083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sby092</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">5043318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Stevenson A, ed.Oxford Dictionary of English. Oxford University Press; 2010; doi: 10.1093/acref/9780199571123.001.0001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/acref/9780199571123.001.0001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooke MA, Peters ER, Kuipers E, Kumari V. Disease, deficit or denial? Models of poor insight in psychosis. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2005;112:4&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15952940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob KS. Insight in psychosis: standards, science, ethics and value judgment. Int J Soc Psychiatry. 2017;63:345&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28504043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacob KS. The assessment of insight across cultures. Indian J Psychiatry. 2010;52:373&#x2013;377.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3025167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21267375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fulford B (KWM). Insight and delusion: from Jaspers to Kraepelin and back again via Austin. In: Amador XF, David AS, eds. Insight and Psychosis: Awareness of Illness in Schizophrenia and Related Disorders. 2nd ed. New York, NY: Oxford University Press; 2004:51&#x2013;78; doi: 10.1093/med/9780198525684.003.0003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/med/9780198525684.003.0003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysaker PH, Pattison ML, Leonhardt BL, Phelps S, Vohs JL. Insight in schizophrenia spectrum disorders: relationship with behavior, mood and perceived quality of life, underlying causes and emerging treatments. World Psychiatry. 2018;17:12&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5775127</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29352540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake RJ. Insight into illness: impact on diagnosis and outcome of nonaffective psychosis. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2008;10:210&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysaker PH, Hamm JA, Hasson-Ohayon I, Pattison ML, Leonhardt BL. Promoting recovery from severe mental illness: implications from research on metacognition and metacognitive reflection and insight therapy. World J Psychiatry. 2018;8:1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5862649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29568726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klaas HS, Cl&#xe9;mence A, Marion-Veyron R, et al. Insight as a social identity process in the evolution of psychosocial functioning in the early phase of psychosis. Psychol Med. 2017;47:718&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5426321</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27866482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crumlish N, Samalani P, Sefasi A, Kinsella A, O&#x2019;Callaghan E, Chilale H. Insight, psychopathology and global functioning in schizophrenia in urban Malawi. Br J Psychiatry. 2007;191:262&#x2013;263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17766770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson S, Sathyaseelan M, Charles H, Jeyaseelan V, Jacob KS. Insight, psychopathology, explanatory models and outcome of schizophrenia in India: a prospective 5-year cohort study. BMC Psychiatry. 2012;12:159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23013057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake RJ. Insight into illness: impact on diagnosis and outcome of nonaffective psychosis. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2008;10:210&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652788</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirmayer LJ, Corin E, Jarvis GE. Inside knowledge: cultural constructions of insight in psychosis. In: Amador XF, David AS, eds. Insight and Psychosis: Awareness of Illness in Schizophrenia and Related Disorders. 2nd ed. New York, NY: Oxford University Press; 2004:197&#x2013;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Linden M, Godemann F. The differentiation between &#x2018;lack of insight&#x2019; and &#x2018;dysfunctional health beliefs&#x2019; in schizophrenia. Psychopathology. 2007;40:236&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17396050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Favrod J, Andreou C, et al. Beyond the usual suspects: positive attitudes towards positive symptoms is associated with medication noncompliance in psychosis. Schizophr Bull. 2013;39:917&#x2013;922.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3686441</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22337789</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asher L, Fekadu A, Hanlon C. Global mental health and schizophrenia. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2018;31: 193&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29474265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chilale HK, Silungwe ND, Gondwe S, Masulani-Mwale C. Clients and carers perception of mental illness and factors that influence help-seeking: where they go first and why. Int J Soc Psychiatry. 2017;63:418&#x2013;425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28604146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln TM, L&#xfc;llmann E, Rief W. Correlates and long-term consequences of poor insight in patients with schizophrenia. A systematic review. Schizophr Bull. 2007;33:1324&#x2013;1342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2779879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17289653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sendt KV, Tracy DK, Bhattacharyya S. A systematic review of factors influencing adherence to antipsychotic medication in schizophrenia-spectrum disorders. Psychiatry Res. 2015;225:14&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25466227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman D, Dunn G, Garety P, et al. Patients&#x2019; beliefs about the causes, persistence and control of psychotic experiences predict take-up of effective cognitive behaviour therapy for psychosis. Psychol Med. 2013;43:269&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3544544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22781166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kvrgic S, Cavelti M, Beck EM, R&#xfc;sch N, Vauth R. Therapeutic alliance in schizophrenia: the role of recovery orientation, self-stigma, and insight. Psychiatry Res. 2013;209:15&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23200319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Witt K, van Dorn R, Fazel S. Risk factors for violence in psychosis: systematic review and meta-regression analysis of 110 studies. PLoS One. 2013;8:e55942.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3572179</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23418482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krakowski MI, Czobor P. The denial of aggression in violent patients with schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2012;141:228&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23010487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Volavka J, Laska E, Baker S, Meisner M, Czobor P, Krivelevich I. 
History of violent behaviour and schizophrenia in different cultures. Analyses based on the WHO study on determinants of outcome of severe mental disorders. Br J Psychiatry. 1997;171:9&#x2013;14. http://ovidsp.ovid.com/ovidweb.cgi?T=JS&amp;PAGE=reference&amp;D=med4&amp;NEWS=N&amp;AN=9328487</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9328487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln TM, Hodgins S. Is lack of insight associated with physically aggressive behavior among people with schizophrenia living in the community?J Nerv Ment Dis. 2008;196:62&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18195643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McEvoy JP, Apperson LJ, Appelbaum PS, et al. Insight in schizophrenia. Its relationship to acute psychopathology. J Nerv Ment Dis. 1989;177:43&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2562850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belvederi Murri M, Respino M, Innamorati M, et al. Is good insight associated with depression among patients with schizophrenia? Systematic review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2015;162:234&#x2013;247.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25631453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kay SR, Fiszbein A, Opler LA. The positive and negative syndrome scale (PANSS) for schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 1987;13:261&#x2013;276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3616518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David AS. Insight and psychosis. Br J Psychiatry. 1990;156:798&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2207510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp R, David A. Insight and compliance. In: Blackwell B, ed. Treatment Compliance and the Treatment Alliance in Serious Mental Illness. The Netherlands: Harwood Academic Publishers; 1997:61&#x2013;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birchwood M, Smith J, Drury V, Healy J, Macmillan F, Slade M. A self-report insight scale for psychosis: reliability, validity and sensitivity to change. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1994;89:62&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7908156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amador XF, Strauss DH, Yale SA, Flaum MM, Endicott J, Gorman JM. Assessment of insight in psychosis. Am J Psychiatry. 1993;150:873&#x2013;879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8494061</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dumas R, Baumstarck K, Michel P, Lan&#xe7;on C, Auquier P, Boyer L. Systematic review reveals heterogeneity in the use of the scale to assess unawareness of mental disorder (SUMD). Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2013;15:361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23636985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Baruch E, Balter JM, Steer RA, Warman DM. A new instrument for measuring insight: the Beck cognitive insight scale. Schizophr Res. 2004;68:319&#x2013;329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15099613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Riggs SE, Grant PM, Perivoliotis D, Beck AT. Assessment of cognitive insight: a qualitative review. Schizophr Bull. 2012;38:338&#x2013;350.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3283158</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20693342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiffen BD, Rabinowitz J, Lex A, David AS. Correlates, change and &#x201c;state or trait&#x201d; properties of insight in schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2010;122:94&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20382507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysaker PH, Vohs J, Hillis JD, et al. Poor insight into schizophrenia: contributing factors, consequences and emerging treatment approaches. Expert Rev Neurother. 2013;13:785&#x2013;793.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23898850</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xia J, Merinder LB, Belgamwar MR. Psychoeducation for schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2011;37:21&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3004189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21147896</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tranulis C, Corin E, Kirmayer LJ. Insight and psychosis: comparing the perspectives of patient, entourage and clinician. Int J Soc Psychiatry. 2008;54:225&#x2013;241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18575378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berg AO, Barrett EA, Nerhus M, et al. Psychosis: clinical insight and beliefs in immigrants in their first episode. Early Interv Psychiatry. 2015;12:185&#x2013;192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26663787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caqueo-Ur&#xed;zar A, Boyer L, Baumstarck K, Gilman SE. The relationships between patients&#x2019; and caregivers&#x2019; beliefs about the causes of schizophrenia and clinical outcomes in Latin American countries. Psychiatry Res. 2015;229:440&#x2013;446.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4546864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26188641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stuart H. Reducing the stigma of mental illness. Glob Ment Health (Camb). 2016;3:e17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5314742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y. Japanese attitudes towards insight in schizophrenia. In: Amador XF, David AS, (eds). Insight and Psychosis: Awareness of Illness in Schizophrenia and Related Disorders. 2nd ed. New York, NY: Oxford University Press; 2004:231&#x2013;241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck EM, Cavelti M, Kvrgic S, Kleim B, Vauth R. Are we addressing the &#x2018;right stuff&#x2019; to enhance adherence in schizophrenia? Understanding the role of insight and attitudes towards medication. Schizophr Res. 2011;132:42&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21820875</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mittal D, Sullivan G, Chekuri L, Allee E, Corrigan PW. Empirical studies of self-stigma reduction strategies: a critical review of the literature. Psychiatr Serv. 2012;63:974&#x2013;981.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22855130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wood L, Byrne R, Varese F, Morrison AP. Psychosocial interventions for internalised stigma in people with a schizophrenia-spectrum diagnosis: a systematic narrative synthesis and meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2016;176:291&#x2013;303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27256518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips J. Conceptual models for psychiatry. Curr Opin Psychiatry. 2000;13:683&#x2013;688.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan B, David A, Bhugra D, Prince M, Jacob KS. Insight in people with psychosis: the influence of culture. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2005;17:83&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16194776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan B, Jacob KS, Prince M, Bhugra D, David AS. Culture and insight revisited. Br J Psychiatry. 2004;184:107&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14754821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazare A. Hidden conceptual models in clinical psychiatry. N Engl J Med. 1973;288:345&#x2013;351.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4682944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biswas J, Gangadhar BN, Keshavan M. Cross cultural variations in psychiatrists&#x2019; perception of mental illness: a tool for teaching culture in psychiatry. Asian J Psychiatr. 2016;23:1&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27969065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upthegrove R, Atulomah O, Brunet K, Chawla R. Cultural and social influences of negative illness appraisals in first-episode psychosis. Early Interv Psychiatry. 2013;7:399&#x2013;406.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22947417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bhui K, Aslam RW, Palinski A, et al. Interventions designed to improve therapeutic communications between black and minority ethnic people and professionals working in psychiatric services: a systematic review of the evidence for their effectiveness. Health Technol Assess. 2015;19:vii&#x2013;xxiv, 1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4780955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25921977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerretsen P, Plitman E, Rajji TK, Graff-Guerrero A. The effects of aging on insight into illness in schizophrenia: a review. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2014;29:1145&#x2013;1161.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4472640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25055980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerretsen P, Takeuchi H, Ozzoude M, Graff-Guerrero A, Uchida H. Insight into illness and its relationship to illness severity, cognition and estimated antipsychotic dopamine receptor occupancy in schizophrenia: an antipsychotic dose reduction study. Psychiatry Res. 2017;251:20&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28187335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijnenborg GH, Timmerman ME, Derks EM, Fleischhacker WW, Kahn RS, Aleman A. Differential effects of antipsychotic drugs on insight in first episode schizophrenia: data from the European First-Episode Schizophrenia Trial (EUFEST). Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2015;25:808&#x2013;816.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25907250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijnenborg GH, van Donkersgoed RJ, David AS, Aleman A. Changes in insight during treatment for psychotic disorders: a meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2013;144:109&#x2013;117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23305612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quee PJ, van der Meer L, Krabbendam L, et al. Insight change in psychosis: relationship with neurocognition, social cognition, clinical symptoms and phase of illness. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2014;129:126&#x2013;133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23600752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mintz AR, Dobson KS, Romney DM. Insight in schizophrenia: a meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2003;61:75&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12648738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xavier RM, Pan W, Dungan JR, Keefe RSE, Vorderstrasse A. Unraveling interrelationships among psychopathology symptoms, cognitive domains and insight dimensions in chronic schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2018;193: 83&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28693755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Upthegrove R, Ross K, Brunet K, McCollum R, Jones L. Depression in first episode psychosis: the role of subordination and shame. Psychiatry Res. 2014;217:177&#x2013;184.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24726817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavelti M, Kvrgic S, Beck EM, R&#xfc;sch N, Vauth R. Self-stigma and its relationship with insight, demoralization, and clinical outcome among people with schizophrenia spectrum disorders. Compr Psychiatry. 2012;53:468&#x2013;479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21956043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysaker PH, Roe D, Yanos PT. Toward understanding the insight paradox: internalized stigma moderates the association between insight and social functioning, hope, and self-esteem among people with schizophrenia spectrum disorders. Schizophr Bull. 2007;33:192&#x2013;199.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2012366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16894025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krupchanka D, Katliar M. The role of insight in moderating the association between depressive symptoms in people with schizophrenia and stigma among their nearest relatives: a pilot study. Schizophr Bull. 2016;42:600&#x2013;607.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4838116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26970100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poole NA, Crabb J, Osei A, Hughes P, Young D. Insight, psychosis, and depression in Africa: a cross-sectional survey from an inpatient unit in Ghana. Transcult Psychiatry. 2013;50:433&#x2013;441.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23740893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belvederi Murri M, Amore M, Calcagno P, et al. The &#x201c;insight paradox&#x201d; in schizophrenia: magnitude, moderators and mediators of the association between insight and depression. Schizophr Bull. 2016;42:1225&#x2013;1233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4988746</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27069064</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf3;pez-Mor&#xed;&#xf1;igo JD, Ramos-R&#xed;os R, David AS, Dutta R. Insight in schizophrenia and risk of suicide: a systematic update. Compr Psychiatry. 2012;53:313&#x2013;322.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21821236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett EA, Mork E, F&#xe6;rden A, et al. The development of insight and its relationship with suicidality over one year follow-up in patients with first episode psychosis. Schizophr Res. 2015;162:97&#x2013;102.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25620119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bourgeois M, Swendsen J, Young F, et al. ; InterSePT Study Group. Awareness of disorder and suicide risk in the treatment of schizophrenia: results of the international suicide prevention trial. Am J Psychiatry. 2004;161: 1494&#x2013;1496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15285981</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melle I, Barrett EA. Insight and suicidal behavior in first-episode schizophrenia. Expert Rev Neurother. 2012;12: 353&#x2013;359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22364334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pompili M, Belvederi Murri M, Patti S, et al. The communication of suicidal intentions: a meta-analysis. Psychol Med. 2016;46:2239&#x2013;2253.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27239944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nair A, Palmer EC, Aleman A, David AS. Relationship between cognition, clinical and cognitive insight in psychotic disorders: a review and meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2014;152:191&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24355529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysaker PH, Vohs J, Minor KS, et al. Metacognitive deficits in schizophrenia: presence and associations with psychosocial outcomes. J Nerv Ment Dis. 2015;203:530&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vohs JL, George S, Leonhardt BL, Lysaker PH. An integrative model of the impairments in insight in schizophrenia: emerging research on causal factors and treatments. Expert Rev Neurother. 2016;16:1193&#x2013;1204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27278672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Mahlke CI, Westermann S, et al. Embracing psychosis: a cognitive insight intervention improves personal narratives and meaning-making in patients with schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2018;44:307&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5814991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29106693</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lam KCK, Ho CPS, Wa JC, et al. Metacognitive training (MCT) for schizophrenia improves cognitive insight: a randomized controlled trial in a Chinese sample with schizophrenia spectrum disorders. Behav Res Ther. 2015;64:38&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25513971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vaillant GE. Involuntary coping mechanisms: a psychodynamic perspective. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2011;13:366&#x2013;370.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22034454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moore O, Cassidy E, Carr A, O&#x2019;Callaghan E. Unawareness of illness and its relationship with depression and self-deception in schizophrenia. Eur Psychiatry. 1999;14: 264&#x2013;269.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10572356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kruck CL, Flashman LA, Roth RM, Koven NS, McAllister TW, Saykin AJ. Lack of relationship between psychological denial and unawareness of illness in schizophrenia-spectrum disorders. Psychiatry Res. 2009;169:33&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2829772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19616309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGlashan TH, Docherty JP, Siris S. Integrative and sealing-over recoveries from schizophrenia: distinguishing case studies. Psychiatry. 1976;39:325&#x2013;338.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">996183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hur JW, Kwon JS, Lee TY, Park S. The crisis of minimal self-awareness in schizophrenia: a meta-analytic review. Schizophr Res. 2014;152:58&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24055201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henriksen MG, Parnas J. Self-disorders and schizophrenia: a phenomenological reappraisal of poor insight and noncompliance. Schizophr Bull. 2014;40:542&#x2013;547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3984518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23798710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xavier RM, Vorderstrasse A. Neurobiological basis of insight in schizophrenia: a systematic review. Nurs Res. 2016;65:224&#x2013;237.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27124258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sapara A, Ffytche DH, Birchwood M, et al. Preservation and compensation: the functional neuroanatomy of insight and working memory in schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2014;152:201&#x2013;209.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3906535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24332795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x106;ur&#x10d;i&#x107;-Blake B, van der Meer L, Pijnenborg GH, David AS, Aleman A. Insight and psychosis: functional and anatomical brain connectivity and self-reflection in Schizophrenia. Hum Brain Mapp. 2015;36:4859&#x2013;4868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6869637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26467308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xavier RM, Vorderstrasse A, Keefe RSE, Dungan JR. Genetic correlates of insight in schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2018;195:290&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29054485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vohs JL, Leonhardt BL, James AV, et al. Metacognitive reflection and insight therapy for early psychosis: a preliminary study of a novel integrative psychotherapy. Schizophr Res. 2018;195:428&#x2013;433.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29108671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>J&#xf8;rgensen R, Licht RW, Lysaker PH, et al. Effects on cognitive and clinical insight with the use of guided self-determination in outpatients with schizophrenia: a randomized open trial. Eur Psychiatry. 2015;30:655&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25601635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>