<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36947286</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1178-1661</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The patient</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Patient</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>So You Want to Build Your Disease's First Online Patient Registry: An Educational Guide for Patient Organizations Based on US and European Experience.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>183</StartPage><EndPage>199</EndPage><MedlinePgn>183-199</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40271-023-00619-w</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Patient registries fulfill a number of key roles for clinicians, researchers, non-profit organizations, payers, and policy makers. They can help the field understand the natural history of a condition, determine the effectiveness of interventions, measure safety, and audit the quality of care provided. Successful registries in cystic fibrosis, Duchenne's muscular dystrophy, and other rare diseases have become a model for accelerating progress. However, the complex tasks required to develop a modern registry can seem overwhelming, particularly for those who are not from a technical background. In this Education article, a team of co-authors from across patient advocacy, technology, privacy, and commercial perspectives who have worked on a number of such projects offer a "Registry 101" primer to help get started. We will outline the promise and potential of patient registries with worked case examples, identify some of the key technical considerations you will need to consider, describe the type of data you might want to collect, consider privacy risks to protect your users, sketch out some of the paths towards long-term financial sustainability we have observed, and conclude with plans to mitigate some of the challenges that can occur and signpost interested readers to further resources. While rapid growth in the digital health market has presented numerous opportunities to those at the beginning of their journey, it is important to start with the long-term goals in mind and to benefit from the learnings of those who have walked this path before.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wicks</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2293-9284</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wicks Digital Health Ltd, Lichfield, UK. paul@wicksdigitalhealth.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wahlstrom-Edwards</LastName><ForeName>Lindsey</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9861-3782</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sano Genetics, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fillingham</LastName><ForeName>Sam</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5224-4996</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>PIP-UK, Stockport, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Downing</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Light Collective, Eugene, OR, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davies</LastName><ForeName>Elin Haf</ForeName><Initials>EH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4987-0088</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aparito Ltd, Wrexham, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Patient</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101309314</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1178-1653</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004522" MajorTopicYN="N">Educational Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010361" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patients</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003550" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cystic Fibrosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012042" MajorTopicYN="N">Registries</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035583" MajorTopicYN="N">Rare Diseases</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>PW is an associate editor at the <i>Journal of Medical Internet Research</i> and is on the editorial advisory boards of the <i>BMJ</i>, <i>BMC Medicine</i>, <i>The Patient</i>, and <i>Digital Biomarkers</i>. PW is employed by Wicks Digital Health Ltd, which has received funding from Ada Health, AstraZeneca, Biogen, Bold Health, Camoni, Compass Pathways, Coronna, EIT, Endava, Happify, HealthUnlocked, Inbeeo, Kheiron Medical, Lindus Health, MedRhythms, PatientsLikeMe, Sano Genetics, Self Care Catalysts, The Learning Corp, The Wellcome Trust, THREAD Research, United Genomics, VeraSci, and Woebot. PW and spouse are shareholders of WDH Investments, Ltd., which owns stock in BlueSkeye AI Ltd, Earswitch Ltd, Sano Genetics Ltd, and Una Health Gmbh. EHD is an employee of Aparito and owns stock in the company. Aparito provides registry software. LWE is an employee of Sano Genetics, a technology company that provides registry software for third parties, including patient advocacy organizations. She owns stock in both Sano Genetics Ltd and Antidote Technologies Ltd. SF is an employee of PIP-UK. AD reports no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36947286</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10031688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40271-023-00619-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40271-023-00619-w</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gliklich RE, Leavy MB, Dreyer NA. Registries for evaluating patient outcomes: a user&#x2019;s guide. Fourth edition. Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ); 2020. https://effectivehealthcare.ahrq.gov/products/registries-guide-4th-edition/users-guide. Accessed 9 Mar 2023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24945055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson EC, Dixon-Woods M, Batalden PB, Homa K, Van Citters AD, Morgan TS, et al. Patient focused registries can improve health, care, and science. BMJ. 2016 doi: 10.1136/bmj.i3319.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.i3319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5367618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27370543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Okun S, Goodwin K. Building a learning health community: by the people, for the people. Learn Health Syst. 2017;1:e10028. doi: 10.1002/lrh2.10028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lrh2.10028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6508568</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31245561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradley M, Braverman J, Harrington M, Wicks P. Patients&#x2019; motivations and interest in research: characteristics of volunteers for patient-led projects on PatientsLikeMe. Res Involv Engagem. 2016;2:33. doi: 10.1186/s40900-016-0047-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40900-016-0047-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5831886</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29507767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis HE, Assaf GS, McCorkell L, Wei H, Low RJ, Reem Y, et al. Characterizing long COVID in an international cohort: 7 months of symptoms and their impact. eClinicalMedicine. 2021;38:101019. doi: 10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.101019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8280690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34308300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landfeldt E, Lindgren P, Bell CF, Schmitt C, Guglieri M, Straub V, et al. The burden of Duchenne muscular dystrophy: an international, cross-sectional study. Neurology. 2014;83:529&#x2013;536. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000000669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4141999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24991029</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Medicines Agency. Patient Registries Workshop, 28 October 2016. 2017. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/report/report-patient-registries-workshop_en.pdf. Accessed 9 Mar 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muenzer J, Jones SA, Tylki-Szyma&#x144;ska A, Harmatz P, Mendelsohn NJ, Guffon N, et al. Ten years of the Hunter Outcome Survey (HOS): insights, achievements, and lessons learned from a global patient registry. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2017;12:82. doi: 10.1186/s13023-017-0635-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-017-0635-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5414331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28464912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>TREAT-NMD Neuromuscular Network. TREAT-NMD diseases: data and Information. 2022. https://treat-nmd.org/what-we-do/data-and-information/treat-nmd-diseases/. Accessed 9 Mar 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maelstrom. Multiple Sclerosis Metadata Collective: a collaborative effort of North American observational studies in multiple sclerosis. 2022. https://www.maelstrom-research.org/network/msmdc. Accessed 24 Oct 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olmo CA, McGettigan P, Kurz X. Barriers and opportunities for use of patient registries in medicines regulation. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2019;106:39&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1002/cpt.1414.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpt.1414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6617975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30970160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Food and Drug Administration. Assessing registries to support regulatory decision-making for drug and biological products guidance for industry: draft guidance. 2021. https://www.fda.gov/media/154449/download. Accessed 9 Mar 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viviani L, Zolin A, Mehta A, Olesen HV. The European Cystic Fibrosis Society Patient Registry: valuable lessons learned on how to sustain a disease registry. Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2014;9:81. doi: 10.1186/1750-1172-9-81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-1172-9-81</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4066270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24908055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowell WB, Merkel PA, McBurney RN, Young K, Venkatachalam S, Shaw DG, et al. Patient-powered research networks of the Autoimmune Research Collaborative: rationale, capacity, and future directions. Patient. 2021;14:699&#x2013;710. doi: 10.1007/s40271-021-00515-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40271-021-00515-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8075709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33904145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marrie RA, Cutter GR, Fox RJ, Vollmer T, Tyry T, Salter A. NARCOMS and other registries in multiple sclerosis: issues and insights. The Consortium of Multiple Sclerosis Centers. Int J MS Care. 2021;23:276&#x2013;284. doi: 10.7224/1537-2073.2020-133.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7224/1537-2073.2020-133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8745235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35035299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rangel V, Martin AS, Peay HL. DuchenneConnect registry report. PLoS Curr. 2012;4:1309. doi: 10.1371/currents.RRN1309.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/currents.RRN1309</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3299489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22453902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bolton SC, Soran V, Marfa MP, Imrie J, Gissen P, Jahnova H, et al. Clinical disease characteristics of patients with Niemann-Pick disease type C: findings from the International Niemann-Pick Disease Registry (INPDR) Orphanet J Rare Dis. 2022;17:51. doi: 10.1186/s13023-022-02200-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-022-02200-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8842861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35164809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collin-Histed T, Milce J, Reed S, Braham-Chaouche L, Jaffe D, Revel-Vilk S, et al. SA73 addressing unmet needs of patients with neuronopathic Gaucher disease type 2 and type 3: creation of the GARDIAN Patient Registry. Value Health. 2022;25:S497. doi: 10.1016/j.jval.2022.09.2466.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2022.09.2466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PIP UK. Poland Syndrome Community Register. https://pip-uk.org/poland-syndrome-community-register. Accessed 25 Jan 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rechtman L, Brenner S, Wright M, Ritsick M, Rahman F, Han M, et al. Impact of the National Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Registry: analysis of registry-funded research. Ann Clin Transl Neurol. 2022;9:1692&#x2013;1701. doi: 10.1002/acn3.51660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acn3.51660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9639630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36259277</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friend S, Richman S, Bloomgren G, Cristiano LM, Wenten M. Evaluation of pregnancy outcomes from the Tysabri&#xae; (natalizumab) pregnancy exposure registry: a global, observational, follow-up study. BMC Neurol. 2016;16:150. doi: 10.1186/s12883-016-0674-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12883-016-0674-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4995778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27552976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deeb W, Rossi PJ, Porta M, Visser-Vandewalle V, Servello D, Silburn P, et al. The international deep brain stimulation registry and database for Gilles de la Tourette syndrome: how does it work? Front Neurosci. 2016 doi: 10.3389/fnins.2016.00170/abstract.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2016.00170/abstract</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4842757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27199634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padula AS, Pappas DA, Fiore S, Blachley TS, Ford K, Emeanuru K, et al. The effect of targeted rheumatoid arthritis therapeutics on systemic inflammation and anemia: analysis of data from the CorEvitas RA registry. Arthritis Res Ther. 2022;24:276. doi: 10.1186/s13075-022-02955-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13075-022-02955-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9769058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36544236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady CB, Trevor KT, Stein TD, Deykin EY, Perkins SD, Averill JG, et al. The Department of Veterans Affairs Biorepository Brain Bank: a national resource for amyotrophic lateral sclerosis research. Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis and Frontotemporal Degeneration. 2013;14:591&#x2013;597. doi: 10.3109/21678421.2013.822516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/21678421.2013.822516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23971854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kashian N, Jacobson S. Factors of engagement and patient-reported outcomes in a stage IV breast cancer Facebook group. Health Commun. 2020;35:75&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1080/10410236.2018.1536962.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10410236.2018.1536962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30351185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eaneff S, Wang V, Hanger M, Levy M, Mealy MA, Brandt AU, et al. Patient perspectives on neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: data from the PatientsLikeMe online community. Multiple Scler Relat Disord. 2017;17:116&#x2013;122. doi: 10.1016/j.msard.2017.07.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2017.07.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29055439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lazar J, Goldstein DF, Taylor A. Ensuring digital accessibility through process and policy. Amsterdam: Morgan Kaufmann/Elsevier; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodwin K. Designing for the digital age: how to create human-centered products and services. Indianapolis: Wiley Publications; 2009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindoerfer D, Mansmann U. Data for the elaboration of the CIPROS checklist with items for a patient registry software system: examples and explanations. Data Brief. 2017;14:494&#x2013;497. doi: 10.1016/j.dib.2017.07.075.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dib.2017.07.075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5558619</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28840183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt P, Von dem Bussche A. The eu general data protection regulation (GDPR): a practical guide, vol 10. 1. Cham: Springer International Publishing; 2017. pp. 10&#x2013;5555.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Department of Health and Human Services National Institute of Health. To whom does the privacy rule apply and whom will it affect? 2022. https://privacyruleandresearch.nih.gov/pr_06.asp#:~:text=Covered%20entities%20are%20defined%20in,which%20HHS%20has%20adopted%20standards. Accessed 24 Oct 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steinsbekk KS, K&#xe5;reMyskja B, Solberg B. Broad consent versus dynamic consent in biobank research: is passive participation an ethical problem? Eur J Hum Genet. 2013;21:897&#x2013;902. doi: 10.1038/ejhg.2012.282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejhg.2012.282</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3746258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23299918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose S. Planning for a zero trust architecture: a planning guide for Federal administrators. Gaithersburg (MD): National Institute of Standards and Technology; 2022: Report No.: NIST CSWP 20. https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/CSWP/NIST.CSWP.20.pdf. Accessed 9 Mar 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stine K, Dang Q. Encryption basics. J Am Health Inform Manage Assoc. 2011;82:44&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21667865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wikipedia. There are known knowns. 2022. https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/There_are_known_knowns. Accessed 9 Mar 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bove R, Secor E, Healy BC, Musallam A, Vaughan T, Glanz BI, et al. Evaluation of an online platform for multiple sclerosis research: patient description, validation of severity scale, and exploration of BMI effects on disease course. PLoS ONE. 2013;8:e59707. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0059707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0059707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3603866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23527256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodson N, Wicks P, Morgan J, Hashem L, Callinan S, Reites J. Opportunities and counterintuitive challenges for decentralized clinical trials to broaden participant inclusion. NPJ Digit Med. 2022;5:58. doi: 10.1038/s41746-022-00603-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-022-00603-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9072305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35513479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bove R, Vaughan T, Chitnis T, Wicks P, De Jager PL. Women&#x2019;s experiences of menopause in an online MS cohort: a case series. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2016;9:56&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.msard.2016.06.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.msard.2016.06.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5031240</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27645345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michelucci P, editor. Handbook of human computation. New York: Springer; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wicks P, Vaughan T, Heywood J. Subjects no more: what happens when trial participants realize they hold the power? BMJ. 2014;348:g368. doi: 10.1136/bmj.g368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.g368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3905107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24472779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard DN. The European cystic fibrosis patient registry: the power of sharing data. J Cystic Fibrosis. 2010;9:S1&#x2013;2. doi: 10.1016/j.jcf.2010.08.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcf.2010.08.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20980207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schechter MS, Fink AK, Homa K, Goss CH. The Cystic Fibrosis Foundation Patient Registry as a tool for use in quality improvement. BMJ Qual Saf. 2014;23:i9&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1136/bmjqs-2013-002378.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjqs-2013-002378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24443584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>University of Florda Clinical and Translational Science Institute. REDCap pricing. 2022. https://www.ctsi.ufl.edu/research/study-design-and-analysis/redcap/redcap-pricing/. Accessed 24 Oct 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomashow B, Walsh J, Malanga E. The COPD Foundation: celebrating a decade of progress and looking ahead to a cure. J COPD F. 2014;1:4&#x2013;16. doi: 10.15326/jcopdf.1.1.2014.0122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15326/jcopdf.1.1.2014.0122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5559136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28848806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bedlack RS, Wicks P, Heywood J, Kasarskis E. Modifiable barriers to enrollment in American ALS research studies. Amyotrophic Lateral Scler. 2010;11:502&#x2013;507. doi: 10.3109/17482968.2010.484494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/17482968.2010.484494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20446890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Politico. Suicide hotline shares data with for-profit spinoff, raising ethical questions. 2022. https://www.politico.com/news/2022/01/28/suicide-hotline-silicon-valley-privacy-debates-00002617. Accessed 9 Mar 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang S. Facebook groups as therapy. 2018. https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2018/10/facebook-emotional-support-groups/572941/. Accessed 24 Oct 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prior R. This breast cancer advocate says she discovered a Facebook flaw that put the health data of millions at risk. 2020. https://edition.cnn.com/2020/02/29/health/andrea-downing-facebook-data-breach-wellness-trnd/index.html. Accessed 24 Oct 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohlheiser A. Facebook is bombarding cancer patients with ads for unproven treatments. 2022. https://www.technologyreview.com/2022/06/27/1054784/facebook-meta-cancer-treatment-ads-misinformation/. Accessed 9 Mar 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feathers T, Fondrie-Teitler S, Waller A, Mattu S. Facebook is receiving sensitive medical information from hospital websites. 2022. https://themarkup.org/pixel-hunt/2022/06/16/facebook-is-receiving-sensitive-medical-information-from-hospital-websites. Accessed 24 Oct 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>