<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35981873</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>10</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1555-905X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical journal of the American Society of Nephrology : CJASN</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Continuous KRT: A Contemporary Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>256</StartPage><EndPage>269</EndPage><MedlinePgn>256-269</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2215/CJN.04350422</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>AKI is a common complication of critical illness and is associated with substantial morbidity and risk of death. Continuous KRT comprises a spectrum of dialysis modalities preferably used to provide kidney support to patients with AKI who are hemodynamically unstable and critically ill. The various continuous KRT modalities are distinguished by different mechanisms of solute transport and use of dialysate and/or replacement solutions. Considerable variation exists in the application of continuous KRT due to a lack of standardization in how the treatments are prescribed, delivered, and optimized to improve patient outcomes. In this manuscript, we present an overview of the therapy, recent clinical trials, and outcome studies. We review the indications for continuous KRT and the technical aspects of the treatment, including continuous KRT modality, vascular access, dosing of continuous KRT, anticoagulation, volume management, nutrition, and continuous KRT complications. Finally, we highlight the need for close collaboration of a multidisciplinary team and development of quality assurance programs for the provision of high-quality and effective continuous KRT.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the American Society of Nephrology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Teixeira</LastName><ForeName>J Pedro</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2466-9644</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Divisions of Nephrology and Pulmonary, Critical Care, and Sleep Medicine, Department of Internal Medicine, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neyra</LastName><ForeName>Javier A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2817-2459</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Bone, and Mineral Metabolism, Department of Internal Medicine, University of Kentucky, Lexington, Kentucky.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tolwani</LastName><ForeName>Ashita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, University of Alabama at Birmingham, Birmingham, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Am Soc Nephrol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101271570</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1555-9041</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D015314">Dialysis Solutions</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017582" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renal Replacement Therapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006435" MajorTopicYN="N">Renal Dialysis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015314" MajorTopicYN="N">Dialysis Solutions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acute Kidney Injury</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016638" MajorTopicYN="N">Critical Illness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>J.A. Neyra reports serving on the editorial boards of <i>Advances in Chronic Kidney Disease</i>, <i>American Journal of Kidney Diseases</i>, and <i>Kidney360</i>; serving as a guest editor for critical care nephrology in <i>Advances in Chronic Kidney Disease</i> and a section editor for <i>Clinical Nephrology</i>; and having consultancy agreements with Baxter Healthcare Inc., Biomedical Insights, and Leadiant Biosciences. J.P. Teixeira reports receiving research funding from Astute Medical/bioM&#xe9;rieux, La Jolla Pharmaceutical Company, Pfizer, Rediscovery Life Sciences LLC, and Sentien Biotechnologies Inc.; having ownership interest <i>via</i> current or previous stocks and/or options (in the last 24 months) in Clever Leaves Holdings, Flora Growth Corp., Green Thumb Industries Inc., Juva Life Inc., NeoGenomics Inc., Novocure Ltd., and Novo Nordisk A/S; and having consultancy agreements with, and serving on a speakers bureau for, Outset Medical. J.P. Teixeira's spouse reports honoraria from Cara Therapeutics. A. Tolwani reports serving on a speakers bureau for Baxter; having a patent on 0.5% trisodium citrate solution for CRRT anticoagulation (the license has been bought by Baxter); having consultancy agreements with Baxter Healthcare; serving on the editorial boards of <i>CJASN</i> and <i>Kidney International</i>; and receiving honoraria from UpToDate.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>19</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>21</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35981873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10103212</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.04350422</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01277230-202302000-00016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Hoste EA, Bagshaw SM, Bellomo R, Cely CM, Colman R, Cruz DN, Edipidis K, Forni LG, Gomersall CD, Govil D, Honor&#xe9; PM, Joannes-Boyau O, Joannidis M, Korhonen AM, Lavrentieva A, Mehta RL, Palevsky P, Roessler E, Ronco C, Uchino S, Vazquez JA, Vidal Andrade E, Webb S, Kellum JA: Epidemiology of acute kidney injury in critically ill patients: The multinational AKI-EPI study. Intensive Care Med 41: 1411&#x2013;1423, 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26162677</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard J, Acharya A, Cerda J, Maccariello ER, Madarasu RC, Tolwani AJ, Liang X, Fu P, Liu ZH, Mehta RL: A prospective international multicenter study of AKI in the intensive care unit. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 10: 1324&#x2013;1331, 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4527019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26195505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wald R, McArthur E, Adhikari NK, Bagshaw SM, Burns KE, Garg AX, Harel Z, Kitchlu A, Mazer CD, Nash DM, Scales DC, Silver SA, Ray JG, Friedrich JO: Changing incidence and outcomes following dialysis-requiring acute kidney injury among critically ill adults: A population-based cohort study. Am J Kidney Dis 65: 870&#x2013;877, 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25533599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchino S Kellum JA Bellomo R Doig GS Morimatsu H Morgera S Schetz M Tan I Bouman C Macedo E Gibney N Tolwani A Ronco C; Beginning and Ending Supportive Therapy for the Kidney (BEST Kidney) Investigators : Acute renal failure in critically ill patients: A multinational, multicenter study. JAMA 294: 813&#x2013;818, 2005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16106006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palevsky PM Zhang JH O&#x2019;Connor TZ Chertow GM Crowley ST Choudhury D Finkel K Kellum JA Paganini E Schein RM Smith MW Swanson KM Thompson BT Vijayan A Watnick S Star RA Peduzzi P; VA/NIH Acute Renal Failure Trial Network : Intensity of renal support in critically ill patients with acute kidney injury. N Engl J Med 359: 7&#x2013;20, 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2574780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18492867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellomo R Cass A Cole L Finfer S Gallagher M Lo S McArthur C McGuinness S Myburgh J Norton R Scheinkestel C Su S; RENAL Replacement Therapy Study Investigators : Intensity of continuous renal-replacement therapy in critically ill patients. N Engl J Med 361: 1627&#x2013;1638, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19846848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chan L Chaudhary K Saha A Chauhan K Vaid A Zhao S Paranjpe I Somani S Richter F Miotto R Lala A Kia A Timsina P Li L Freeman R Chen R Narula J Just AC Horowitz C Fayad Z Cordon-Cardo C Schadt E Levin MA Reich DL Fuster V Murphy B He JC Charney AW B&#xf6;ttinger EP Glicksberg BS Coca SG Nadkarni GN; Mount Sinai COVID Informatics Center (MSCIC) : AKI in hospitalized patients with COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol 32: 151&#x2013;160, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7894657</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32883700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta S Coca SG Chan L Melamed ML Brenner SK Hayek SS Sutherland A Puri S Srivastava A Leonberg-Yoo A Shehata AM Flythe JE Rashidi A Schenck EJ Goyal N Hedayati SS Dy R Bansal A Athavale A Nguyen HB Vijayan A Charytan DM Schulze CE Joo MJ Friedman AN Zhang J Sosa MA Judd E Velez JCQ Mallappallil M Redfern RE Bansal AD Neyra JA Liu KD Renaghan AD Christov M Molnar MZ Sharma S Kamal O Boateng JO Short SAP Admon AJ Sise ME Wang W Parikh CR Leaf DE; STOP-COVID Investigators : AKI treated with renal replacement therapy in critically ill patients with COVID-19. J Am Soc Nephrol 32: 161&#x2013;176, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7894677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33067383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaieski DF, Edwards JM, Kallan MJ, Carr BG: Benchmarking the incidence and mortality of severe sepsis in the United States. Crit Care Med 41: 1167&#x2013;1174, 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23442987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ponce D, Balbi A, Cullis B: Acute PD: Evidence, guidelines, and controversies. Semin Nephrol 37: 103&#x2013;112, 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153190</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shimonov D, Srivatana V: Peritoneal dialysis for acute kidney injury during the COVID-19 pandemic. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 15: 1829&#x2013;1831, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7769024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32801119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chionh CY, Soni SS, Finkelstein FO, Ronco C, Cruz DN: Use of peritoneal dialysis in AKI: A systematic review. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 8: 1649&#x2013;1660, 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3789336</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23833316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nash DM, Przech S, Wald R, O&#x2019;Reilly D: Systematic review and meta-analysis of renal replacement therapy modalities for acute kidney injury in the intensive care unit. J Crit Care 41: 138&#x2013;144, 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28525779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lins RL Elseviers MM Van der Niepen P Hoste E Malbrain ML Damas P Devriendt J; SHARF investigators : Intermittent versus continuous renal replacement therapy for acute kidney injury patients admitted to the intensive care unit: Results of a randomized clinical trial. Nephrol Dial Transplant 24: 512&#x2013;518, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18854418</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vinsonneau C Camus C Combes A Costa de Beauregard MA Klouche K Boulain T Pallot JL Chiche JD Taupin P Landais P Dhainaut JF; Hemodiafe Study Group : Continuous venovenous haemodiafiltration versus intermittent haemodialysis for acute renal failure in patients with multiple-organ dysfunction syndrome: A multicentre randomised trial. Lancet 368: 379&#x2013;385, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16876666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schefold JC, von Haehling S, Pschowski R, Bender T, Berkmann C, Briegel S, Hasper D, J&#xf6;rres A: The effect of continuous versus intermittent renal replacement therapy on the outcome of critically ill patients with acute renal failure (CONVINT): A prospective randomized controlled trial. Crit Care 18: R11, 2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4056033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24405734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Augustine JJ, Sandy D, Seifert TH, Paganini EP: A randomized controlled trial comparing intermittent with continuous dialysis in patients with ARF. Am J Kidney Dis 44: 1000&#x2013;1007, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15558520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bouchard J Soroko SB Chertow GM Himmelfarb J Ikizler TA Paganini EP Mehta RL; Program to Improve Care in Acute Renal Disease (PICARD) Study Group : Fluid accumulation, survival and recovery of kidney function in critically ill patients with acute kidney injury. Kidney Int 76: 422&#x2013;427, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19436332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodward CW, Lambert J, Ortiz-Soriano V, Li Y, Ruiz-Conejo M, Bissell BD, Kelly A, Adams P, Yessayan L, Morris PE, Neyra JA: Fluid overload associates with major adverse kidney events in critically ill patients with acute kidney injury requiring continuous renal replacement therapy. Crit Care Med 47: e753&#x2013;e760, 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31162196</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport A: Practical guidance for dialyzing a hemodialysis patient following acute brain injury. Hemodial Int 12: 307&#x2013;312, 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18638083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport A: Continuous renal replacement therapies in patients with acute neurological injury. Semin Dial 22: 165&#x2013;168, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19426422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diaz-Buxo JA, Loredo JP: Standard Kt/V: Comparison of calculation methods. Artif Organs 30: 178&#x2013;185, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16480392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghannoum M, Roberts DM, Hoffman RS, Ouellet G, Roy L, Decker BS, Bouchard J: A stepwise approach for the management of poisoning with extracorporeal treatments. Semin Dial 27: 362&#x2013;370, 2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24697864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark WR, Leblanc M, Ricci Z, Ronco C: Quantification and dosing of renal replacement therapy in acute kidney injury: A reappraisal. Blood Purif 44: 140&#x2013;155, 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28586767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosner MH, Connor MJ, Jr: Management of severe hyponatremia with continuous renal replacement therapies. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 13: 787&#x2013;789, 2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5969490</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29463598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yessayan LT, Szamosfalvi B, Rosner MH: Management of dysnatremias with continuous renal replacement therapy. Semin Dial 34: 472&#x2013;479, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34218456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark WR, Soltys PJ: Hemodialysis systems for intermittent, semi-continuous, and continuous therapies in acute renal failure. Home Hemodial Int (1997) 2: 30&#x2013;33, 1998</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28466521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchino S, Fealy N, Baldwin I, Morimatsu H, Bellomo R: Pre-dilution vs. post-dilution during continuous veno-venous hemofiltration: Impact on filter life and azotemic control. Nephron Clin Pract 94: c94&#x2013;c98, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12972719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldhoff P, Turnham T, Klein E: Effect of plasma proteins on the sieving spectra of hemofilters. Artif Organs 8: 186&#x2013;192, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6732546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrich JO, Wald R, Bagshaw SM, Burns KE, Adhikari NK: Hemofiltration compared to hemodialysis for acute kidney injury: Systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care 16: R146, 2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3580734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22867021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Combes A, Br&#xe9;chot N, Amour J, Cozic N, Lebreton G, Guidon C, Zogheib E, Thiranos JC, Rigal JC, Bastien O, Benhaoua H, Abry B, Ouattara A, Trouillet JL, Mallet A, Chastre J, Leprince P, Luyt CE: Early high-volume hemofiltration versus standard care for post-cardiac surgery shock. The HEROICS Study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 192: 1179&#x2013;1190, 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26167637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borthwick EM, Hill CJ, Rabindranath KS, Maxwell AP, McAuley DF, Blackwood B: High-volume haemofiltration for sepsis in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 1: CD008075, 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6464723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28141912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Califano AM, Bitker L, Baldwin I, Fealy N, Bellomo R: Circuit survival during continuous venovenous hemodialysis versus continuous venovenous hemofiltration. Blood Purif 49: 281&#x2013;288, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32088713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brain M, Winson E, Roodenburg O, McNeil J: Non anti-coagulant factors associated with filter life in continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT): A systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Nephrol 18: 69, 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5319031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28219324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney Disease Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) Acute Kideny Injury Work Group : KDIGO clinical practice guideline for acute kidney injury. Available at: https://kdigo.org/guidelines/acute-kidney-injury/. Accessed April 11, 2022</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan D, Ho K, Murray C, Davies H, Louw J: A randomized trial of catheters of different lengths to achieve right atrium versus superior vena cava placement for continuous renal replacement therapy. Am J Kidney Dis 60: 272&#x2013;279, 2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22497790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parienti JJ Thirion M M&#xe9;garbane B Souweine B Ouchikhe A Polito A Forel JM Marqu&#xe9; S Misset B Airapetian N Daurel C Mira JP Ramakers M du Cheyron D Le Coutour X Daubin C Charbonneau P; Members of the Cathedia Study Group : Femoral vs jugular venous catheterization and risk of nosocomial events in adults requiring acute renal replacement therapy: A randomized controlled trial. JAMA 299: 2413&#x2013;2422, 2008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18505951</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parienti JJ M&#xe9;garbane B Fischer MO Lautrette A Gazui N Marin N Hanouz JL Ramakers M Daubin C Mira JP Charbonneau P du Cheyron D; Cathedia Study Group : Catheter dysfunction and dialysis performance according to vascular access among 736 critically ill adults requiring renal replacement therapy: A randomized controlled study. Crit Care Med 38: 1118&#x2013;1125, 2010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20154599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Rifai A, Sukul N, Wonnacott R, Heung M: Safety of arteriovenous fistulae and grafts for continuous renal replacement therapy: The Michigan experience. Hemodial Int 22: 50&#x2013;55, 2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28295984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Claure-Del Granado R, Macedo E, Chertow GM, Soroko S, Himmelfarb J, Ikizler TA, Paganini EP, Mehta RL: Effluent volume in continuous renal replacement therapy overestimates the delivered dose of dialysis. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 6: 467&#x2013;475, 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3082402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21115626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neyra JA, Tolwani A: CRRT prescription and delivery of dose. Semin Dial 34: 432&#x2013;439, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prowle JR, Schneider A, Bellomo R: Clinical review: Optimal dose of continuous renal replacement therapy in acute kidney injury. Crit Care 15: 207, 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3219403</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21489322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark EG, Vijayan A: Intensive RRT for AKI: Dial down your enthusiasm! [published online ahead of print June 3, 2022]. Kidney360 10.34067/KID.0000972022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34067/KID.0000972022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9416838</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36176669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uchino S Toki N Takeda K Ohnuma T Namba Y Katayama S Kawarazaki H Yasuda H Izawa J Uji M Tokuhira N Nagata I; Japanese Society for Physicians and Trainees in Intensive Care (JSEPTIC) Clinical Trial Group : Validity of low-intensity continuous renal replacement therapy. Crit Care Med 41: 2584&#x2013;2591, 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23939357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leypoldt JK, Kamerath CD, Gilson JF, Friederichs G: Dialyzer clearances and mass transfer-area coefficients for small solutes at low dialysate flow rates. ASAIO J 52: 404&#x2013;409, 2006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16883120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark WR, Turk JE, Kraus MA, Gao D: Dose determinants in continuous renal replacement therapy. Artif Organs 27: 815&#x2013;820, 2003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12940904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fealy N, Aitken L, du Toit E, Lo S, Baldwin I: Faster blood flow rate does not improve circuit life in continuous renal replacement therapy: A randomized controlled trial. Crit Care Med 45: e1018&#x2013;e1025, 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28658026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szamosfalvi B, Puri V, Sohaney R, Wagner B, Riddle A, Dickinson S, Napolitano L, Heung M, Humes D, Yessayan L: Regional citrate anticoagulation protocol for patients with presumed absent citrate metabolism. Kidney360 2: 192&#x2013;204, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8740983</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35373034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baldwin I, Bellomo R, Koch B: Blood flow reductions during continuous renal replacement therapy and circuit life. Intensive Care Med 30: 2074&#x2013;2079, 2004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatamizadeh P, Tolwani A, Palevsky P: Revisiting filtration fraction as an index of the risk of hemofilter clotting in continuous venovenous hemofiltration. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 15: 1660&#x2013;1662, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7646243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32404338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastwood GM, Peck L, Young H, Bailey M, Reade MC, Baldwin I, Bellomo R: Haemodynamic impact of a slower pump speed at start of continuous renal replacement therapy in critically Ill adults with acute kidney injury: A prospective before-and-after study. Blood Purif 33: 52&#x2013;58, 2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22179304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valle EO, Cabrera CPS, Albuquerque CCC, Silva GVD, Oliveira MFA, Sales GTM, Smolentzov I, Reichert BV, Andrade L, Seabra VF, Lins PRG, Rodrigues CE: Continuous renal replacement therapy in COVID-19-associated AKI: Adding heparin to citrate to extend filter life-A retrospective cohort study. Crit Care 25: 299, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8375288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34412667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu C, Mao Z, Kang H, Hu J, Zhou F: Regional citrate versus heparin anticoagulation for continuous renal replacement therapy in critically ill patients: A meta-analysis with trial sequential analysis of randomized controlled trials. Crit Care 20: 144, 2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4866420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27176622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zarbock A K&#xfc;llmar M Kindgen-Milles D Wempe C Gerss J Brandenburger T Dimski T Tyczynski B Jahn M M&#xfc;lling N Mehrl&#xe4;nder M Rosenberger P Marx G Simon TP Jaschinski U Deetjen P Putensen C Schewe JC Kluge S Jarczak D Slowinski T Bodenstein M Meybohm P Wirtz S Moerer O Kortgen A Simon P Bagshaw SM Kellum JA Meersch M; RICH Investigators and the Sepnet Trial Group : Effect of regional citrate anticoagulation vs systemic heparin anticoagulation during continuous kidney replacement therapy on dialysis filter life span and mortality among critically ill patients with acute kidney injury: A randomized clinical trial. JAMA 324: 1629&#x2013;1639, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7585036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33095849</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neyra JA, Yessayan L, Thompson Bastin ML, Wille KM, Tolwani AJ: How to prescribe and troubleshoot continuous renal replacement therapy: A case-based review. Kidney360 2: 371&#x2013;384, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8741005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35373031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davenport A, Tolwani A: Citrate anticoagulation for continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT) in patients with acute kidney injury admitted to the intensive care unit. NDT Plus 2: 439&#x2013;447, 2009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4421325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25949376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meier-Kriesche HU, Gitomer J, Finkel K, DuBose T: Increased total to ionized calcium ratio during continuous venovenous hemodialysis with regional citrate anticoagulation. Crit Care Med 29: 748&#x2013;752, 2001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11373461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng Y, Zhuang F, Zhu Q, Ma S, Xu Y, Lu J, Hao G, Gu Y, Hao C, Zhu M, Ding F: Albumin-corrected total/ionized calcium ratio is not superior to total/ionized calcium ratio as an indicator of citrate accumulation. Int J Artif Organs 40: 602&#x2013;606, 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28708212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan JN, Haroon SWP, Mukhopadhyay A, Lau T, Murali TM, Phua J, Tan ZY, Lee N, Chua HR: Hyperlactatemia predicts citrate intolerance with regional citrate anticoagulation during continuous renal replacement therapy. J Intensive Care Med 34: 418&#x2013;425, 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28372501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang W, Bai M, Yu Y, Li L, Zhao L, Sun S, Chen X: Safety and efficacy of regional citrate anticoagulation for continuous renal replacement therapy in liver failure patients: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care 23: 22, 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6345001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30678706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chua HR, Baldwin I, Bailey M, Subramaniam A, Bellomo R: Circuit lifespan during continuous renal replacement therapy for combined liver and kidney failure. J Crit Care 27: 744.e7&#x2013;744.e15, 2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23102533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gerss J Meersch M Kindgen-Milles D Brandenburger T Willam C Kellum JA Zarbock A; RICH investigators : The effect of filter lifespan during continuous renal replacement therapy in critically ill patients with AKI on the rate of new onset infection: Analysis from the RICH Randomized Controlled Trial [published online ahead of print May 13, 2022]. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 10.1164/rccm.202201-0063LE</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.202201-0063LE</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35549654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bitker L, Bayle F, Yonis H, Gobert F, Leray V, Taponnier R, Debord S, Stoian-Cividjian A, Gu&#xe9;rin C, Richard JC: Prevalence and risk factors of hypotension associated with preload-dependence during intermittent hemodialysis in critically ill patients. Crit Care 20: 44, 2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4765055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26907782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douvris A, Zeid K, Hiremath S, Bagshaw SM, Wald R, Beaubien-Souligny W, Kong J, Ronco C, Clark EG: Mechanisms for hemodynamic instability related to renal replacement therapy: A narrative review. Intensive Care Med 45: 1333&#x2013;1346, 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6773820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31407042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murugan R, Bellomo R, Palevsky PM, Kellum JA: Ultrafiltration in critically ill patients treated with kidney replacement therapy. Nat Rev Nephrol 17: 262&#x2013;276, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33177700</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murugan R, Kerti SJ, Chang CH, Gallagher M, Clermont G, Palevsky PM, Kellum JA, Bellomo R: Association of net ultrafiltration rate with mortality among critically ill adults with acute kidney injury receiving continuous venovenous hemodiafiltration: A secondary analysis of the Randomized Evaluation of Normal vs Augmented Level (RENAL) of Renal Replacement Therapy Trial. JAMA Netw Open 2: e195418, 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6563576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Demirjian S, Teo BW, Guzman JA, Heyka RJ, Paganini EP, Fissell WH, Schold JD, Schreiber MJ: Hypophosphatemia during continuous hemodialysis is associated with prolonged respiratory failure in patients with acute kidney injury. Nephrol Dial Transplant 26: 3508&#x2013;3514, 2011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21382993</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sharma S, Kelly YP, Palevsky PM, Waikar SS: Intensity of renal replacement therapy and duration of mechanical ventilation: Secondary analysis of the Acute Renal Failure Trial Network Study. Chest 158: 1473&#x2013;1481, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8173776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32470389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aubier M, Murciano D, Lecocguic Y, Viires N, Jacquens Y, Squara P, Pariente R: Effect of hypophosphatemia on diaphragmatic contractility in patients with acute respiratory failure. N Engl J Med 313: 420&#x2013;424, 1985</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3860734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson Bastin ML, Stromberg AJ, Nerusu SN, Liu LJ, Mayer KP, Liu KD, Bagshaw SM, Wald R, Morris PE, Neyra JA: Association of phosphate-containing versus phosphate-free solutions on ventilator days in patients requiring continuous kidney replacement therapy. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 17: 634&#x2013;642, 2022 10.2215/CJN.12410921</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.12410921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9269583</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35477673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson Bastin ML, Adams PM, Nerusu S, Morris PE, Mayer KP, Neyra JA: Association of phosphate containing solutions with incident hypophosphatemia in critically ill patients requiring continuous renal replacement therapy. Blood Purif 51: 122&#x2013;129, 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33915554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley KE, DeGrado JR, Charytan DM: Serum glucose and phosphorus concentrations during continuous renal replacement therapy using commercial replacement solutions with or without phosphorus. Hemodial Int 24: 330&#x2013;334, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32351011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coutrot M, H&#xe9;kimian G, Moulin T, Br&#xe9;chot N, Schmidt M, Besset S, Nieszkowska A, Franchineau G, Bourcier S, Bourron O, Luyt CE, Combes A: Euglycemic ketoacidosis, a common and underecognized complication of continuous renal replacement therapy using glucose-free solutions. Intensive Care Med 44: 1185&#x2013;1186, 2018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29536124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Afshinnia F, Belanger K, Palevsky PM, Young EW: Effect of ionized serum calcium on outcomes in acute kidney injury needing renal replacement therapy: Secondary analysis of the acute renal failure trial network study. Ren Fail 35: 1310&#x2013;1318, 2013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4082331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23992422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thongprayoon C, Cheungpasitporn W, Radhakrishnan Y, Zabala Genovez JL, Petnak T, Shawwa K, Qureshi F, Mao MA, Kashani KB: Association of serum potassium derangements with mortality among patients requiring continuous renal replacement therapy [published online ahead of print January 22, 2022]. Ther Apher Dial 10.1111/1744-9987.13804</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1744-9987.13804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35067000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhingra S, Solven F, Wilson A, McCarthy DS: Hypomagnesemia and respiratory muscle power. Am Rev Respir Dis 129: 497&#x2013;498, 1984</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6703506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang P, Lv Q, Lai T, Xu F: Does hypomagnesemia impact on the outcome of patients admitted to the intensive care unit? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Shock 47: 288&#x2013;295, 2017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27753792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zakharchenko M, Los F, Brodska H, Balik M: The effects of high level magnesium dialysis/substitution fluid on magnesium homeostasis under regional citrate anticoagulation in critically ill. PLoS One 11: e0158179, 2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4938518</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27391902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz EF Ortiz-Soriano VM Talbott M Klein BA Thompson Bastin ML Mayer KP Price EB Dorfman R Adams BN Fryman L Neyra JA; University of Kentucky CRRT Quality Assurance Group : Development, implementation and outcomes of a quality assurance system for the provision of continuous renal replacement therapy in the intensive care unit. Sci Rep 10: 20616, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7692557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33244053</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rewa OG Tolwani A Mottes T Juncos LA Ronco C Kashani K Rosner M Haase M Kellum J Bagshaw SM; ADQI Consensus Meeting Members on behalf of ADQI XXII : Quality of care and safety measures of acute renal replacement therapy: Workgroup statements from the 22nd acute disease quality initiative (ADQI) consensus conference. J Crit Care 54: 52&#x2013;57, 2019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31349160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McClave SA Taylor BE Martindale RG Warren MM Johnson DR Braunschweig C McCarthy MS Davanos E Rice TW Cresci GA Gervasio JM Sacks GS Roberts PR Compher C; Society of Critical Care Medicine; American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition : Guidelines for the provision and assessment of nutrition support therapy in the adult critically ill patient: Society of Critical Care Medicine (SCCM) and American Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (A.S.P.E.N.). JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr 40: 159&#x2013;211, 2016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26773077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beumier M, Casu GS, Hites M, Seyler L, Cotton F, Vincent JL, Jacobs F, Taccone FS: &#x3b2;-lactam antibiotic concentrations during continuous renal replacement therapy. Crit Care 18: R105, 2014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4075122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24886826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts DM Roberts JA Roberts MS Liu X Nair P Cole L Lipman J Bellomo R; RENAL Replacement Therapy Study Investigators : Variability of antibiotic concentrations in critically ill patients receiving continuous renal replacement therapy: A multicentre pharmacokinetic study. Crit Care Med 40: 1523&#x2013;1528, 2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22511133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onichimowski D, Zi&#xf3;&#x142;kowski H, Nosek K, Jaroszewski J, Rypulak E, Czuczwar M: Comparison of adsorption of selected antibiotics on the filters in continuous renal replacement therapy circuits: In vitro studies. J Artif Organs 23: 163&#x2013;170, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7228979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31630269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mayer KP, Joseph-Isang E, Robinson LE, Parry SM, Morris PE, Neyra JA: Safety and feasibility of physical rehabilitation and active mobilization in patients requiring continuous renal replacement therapy: A systematic review. Crit Care Med 48: e1112&#x2013;e1120, 2020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33001619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neyra JA, Kashani K: Improving the quality of care for patients requiring continuous renal replacement therapy. Semin Dial 34: 501&#x2013;509, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Opgenorth D, Reil E, Lau V, Fraser N, Zuege D, Wang X, Bagshaw SM, Rewa O: Improving the quality of the performance and delivery of continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT) to critically ill patients across a healthcare system: QUALITY CRRT: A study protocol. BMJ Open 12: e054583, 2022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8819828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35121604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolwani A: Continuous renal-replacement therapy for acute kidney injury. N Engl J Med 367: 2505&#x2013;2514, 2012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23268665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verma S, Palevsky PM: Prescribing continuous kidney replacement therapy in acute kidney injury: A narrative review. Kidney Med 3: 827&#x2013;836, 2021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34693262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>