<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37826848</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-233X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>142</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Nov</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Obstetrics and gynecology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Obstet Gynecol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Health Care Disparities in Patients Undergoing Hysterectomy for Benign Indications: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1044</StartPage><EndPage>1054</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1044-1054</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/AOG.0000000000005389</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To explore how markers of health care disparity are associated with access to care and outcomes among patients seeking and undergoing hysterectomy for benign indications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DATA SOURCES">PubMed, EMBASE, and ClinicalTrials.gov were searched through January 23, 2022.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS OF STUDY SELECTION">The population of interest included patients in the United States who sought or underwent hysterectomy by any approach for benign indications. Health care disparity markers included race, ethnicity, geographic location, insurance status, and others. Outcomes included access to surgery, patient level outcomes, and surgical outcomes. Eligible studies reported multivariable regression analyses that described the independent association between at least one health care disparity risk marker and an outcome. We evaluated direction and strengths of association within studies and consistency across studies.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TABULATION, INTEGRATION, AND RESULTS">Of 6,499 abstracts screened, 39 studies with a total of 46 multivariable analyses were included. Having a Black racial identity was consistently associated with decreased access to minimally invasive, laparoscopic, robotic, and vaginal hysterectomy. Being of Hispanic ethnicity and having Asian or Pacific Islander racial identities were associated with decreased access to laparoscopic and vaginal hysterectomy. Black patients were the only racial or ethnic group with an increased association with hysterectomy complications. Medicare insurance was associated with decreased access to laparoscopic hysterectomy, and both Medicaid and Medicare insurance were associated with increased likelihood of hysterectomy complications. Living in the South or Midwest or having less than a college degree education was associated with likelihood of prior hysterectomy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Studies suggest that various health care disparity markers are associated with poorer access to less invasive hysterectomy procedures and with poorer outcomes for patients who are undergoing hysterectomy for benign indications. Further research is needed to understand and identify the causes of these disparities, and immediate changes to our health care system are needed to improve access and opportunities for patients facing health care disparities.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="SYSTEMATIC REVIEW REGISTRATION">PROSPERO, CRD42021234511.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 by the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists. Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wieslander</LastName><ForeName>Cecilia K</ForeName><Initials>CK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, David Geffen School of Medicine at UCLA, Los Angeles, California; the Division of Urogynecology &amp; Reconstructive Pelvic Surgery, Departments of Obstetrics and Gynecology and Urology, New York Medical College, Valhalla, New York; the Center for Evidence Synthesis in Health, Brown University School of Public Health, Providence, Rhode Island; the Division of Female Pelvic Medicine and Reconstructive Surgery, Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, Wayne State University School of Medicine, Detroit, Michigan; the Division of Urogynecology &amp; Reconstructive Pelvic Surgery, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut; the Division of Female Pelvic Medicine and Reconstructive Surgery, Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, Howard University College of Medicine, Washington, DC; the Division of Female Pelvic Medicine and Reconstructive Surgery, Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, University of Florida Health, Jacksonville, Florida; Occom Health, Newton, Massachusetts; the Division of Urogynecology &amp; Reconstructive Pelvic Surgery, Cooper Health University, Cooper Medical School at Rowan University, Camden, New Jersey; the Division of Female Pelvic Medicine and Reconstructive Surgery, Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, University of Louisville Health, Louisville, Kentucky; the Division of Female Pelvic Medicine and Reconstructive Surgery, Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, University of Texas at Austin Dell Medical School, Austin, and the Division of Female Pelvic Medicine and Reconstructive Surgery, Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, Baylor College of Medicine, the Division of Urogynecology, Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, Houston Methodist Hospital, Houston, Texas; and the Division of Female Pelvic Medicine and Reconstructive Surgery, Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grimes</LastName><ForeName>Cara L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Balk</LastName><ForeName>Ethan M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hobson</LastName><ForeName>Deslyn T G</ForeName><Initials>DTG</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ringel</LastName><ForeName>Nancy E</ForeName><Initials>NE</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sanses</LastName><ForeName>Tatiana V D</ForeName><Initials>TVD</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Ruchira</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Richardson</LastName><ForeName>Monica L</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lipetskaia</LastName><ForeName>Lioudmila</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gupta</LastName><ForeName>Ankita</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>White</LastName><ForeName>Amanda B</ForeName><Initials>AB</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Orejuela</LastName><ForeName>Francisco</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meriwether</LastName><ForeName>Kate</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Antosh</LastName><ForeName>Danielle D</ForeName><Initials>DD</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>P30 AG028747</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Obstet Gynecol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0401101</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0029-7844</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014481" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">United States</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054625" MajorTopicYN="Y">Healthcare Disparities</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006278" MajorTopicYN="Y">Medicare</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007044" MajorTopicYN="N">Hysterectomy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005006" MajorTopicYN="N">Ethnicity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007045" MajorTopicYN="N">Hysterectomy, Vaginal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Financial Disclosure Cara L. Grimes is the research chair for the Society of Gynecologic Surgeons (board position, travel support), Consultant, Provepharm Inc. and she received institutional research support from Reia. Ethan M. Balk received funding from SGS for methodology consultation. Amanda White reports receiving payment from Boston Scientific. Kate Meriwether is the research chair for the Society of Gynecologic Surgeons (board position, travel support). She received book royalties from Elsevier Publishing, has been a consultant for RBI Medical (industry device company, paid position), and received research support from Cook Myosure and Caldera Medical. The other authors did not report any potential conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>18</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>12</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37826848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000005389</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00006250-202311000-00009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wright JD, Herzog TJ, Tsui J, Ananth CV, Lewin SN, Lu YS, et al. Nationwide trends in the performance of inpatient hysterectomy in the United States. Obstet Gynecol 2013;122:233&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0b013e318299a6cf</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0b013e318299a6cf</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JM, Wechter ME, Geller EJ, Nguyen TV, Visco AG. Hysterectomy rates in the United States, 2003. Obstet Gynecol 2007;110:1091&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1097/01.AOG.0000285997.38553.4b</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.AOG.0000285997.38553.4b</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahkola-Soisalo P, Brummer T, Jalkanen J, Sj&#xf6;berg J, Sintonen H, Roine RP, et al. Hysterectomy provides benefit in health-related quality of life: a 10-year follow-up study. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2020;27:868&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2019.08.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2019.08.009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexander AL, Strohl AE, Rieder S, Holl J, Barber EL. Examining disparities in route of surgery and postoperative complications in Black race and hysterectomy. Obstet Gynecol 2019;133:6&#x2013;12. doi: 10.1097/aog.0000000000002990</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/aog.0000000000002990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta A, Xu T, Hutfless S, Makary MA, Sinno AK, Tanner EJ, et al. Patient, surgeon, and hospital disparities associated with benign hysterectomy approach and perioperative complications. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2017;216:497.e1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2016.12.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2016.12.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravi P, Sood A, Schmid M, Abdollah F, Sammon JD, Sun M, et al. Racial/ethnic disparities in perioperative outcomes of major procedures: results from the national surgical quality improvement program. Ann Surg 2015;262:955&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1097/SLA.0000000000001078</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000001078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traylor J, Koelper N, Kim SW, Sammel MD, Andy UU. Impact of surgical wait time to hysterectomy for benign gynecologic disease. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2021;28:982&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2020.08.486</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2020.08.486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera Drew JA. Hysterectomy and disability among U.S. women. Perspect Sex Reprod Health 2013;45:157&#x2013;63. doi: 10.1363/4515713</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1363/4515713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erekson EA, Weitzen S, Sung VW, Raker CA, Myers DL. Socioeconomic indicators and hysterectomy status in the United States, 2004. J Reprod Med 2009;54:553&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower JK, Schreiner PJ, Sternfeld B, Lewis CE. Black-White differences in hysterectomy prevalence: the CARDIA study. Am J Public Health 2009;99:300&#x2013;7. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2008.133702</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2008.133702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brett KM, Higgins JA. Hysterectomy prevalence by Hispanic ethnicity: evidence from a national survey. Am J Public Health 2003;93:307&#x2013;12. doi: 10.2105/ajph.93.2.307</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/ajph.93.2.307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brett KM, Marsh JV, Madans JH. Epidemiology of hysterectomy in the United States: demographic and reproductive factors in a nationally representative sample. J Womens Health 1997;6:309&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1089/jwh.1997.6.309</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jwh.1997.6.309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer JR, Rao RS, Adams-Campbell LL, Rosenberg L. Correlates of hysterectomy among African-American women. Am J Epidemiol 1999;150:1309&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1093/oxfordjournals.aje.a009962</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/oxfordjournals.aje.a009962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marks NF, Shinberg DS. Socioeconomic differences in hysterectomy: the Wisconsin longitudinal study. Am J Public Health 1997;87:1507&#x2013;14. doi: 10.2105/ajph.87.9.1507</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/ajph.87.9.1507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meilahn EN, Matthews KA, Egeland G, Kelsey SF. Characteristics of women with hysterectomy. Maturitas 1989;11:319&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1016/0378-5122(89)90028-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0378-5122(89)90028-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjerulff K, Langenberg P, Guzinski G. The socioeconomic correlates of hysterectomies in the United States. Am J Public Health 1993;83:106&#x2013;8. doi: 10.2105/ajph.83.1.106</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/ajph.83.1.106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abenhaim HA, Azziz R, Hu J, Bartolucci A, Tulandi T. Socioeconomic and racial predictors of undergoing laparoscopic hysterectomy for selected benign diseases: analysis of 341487 hysterectomies. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2008;15:11&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2007.07.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2007.07.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bougie O, Singh SS, Chen I, McCarthy EP. Relationship between race/ethnicity and hysterectomy outcomes for benign gynecologic conditions. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2019;26:456&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2018.05.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2018.05.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Callegari LS, Katon JG, Gray KE, Doll K, Pauk S, Lynch KE, et al. Associations between race/ethnicity, uterine fibroids, and minimally invasive hysterectomy in the VA health care system. Womens Health Issues 2019;29:48&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/j.whi.2018.08.005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.whi.2018.08.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SL, Vitonis AF, Einarsson JI. Updated hysterectomy surveillance and factors associated with minimally invasive hysterectomy. JSLS 2014;18:e2014.00096. doi: 10.4293/JSLS.2014.00096</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4293/JSLS.2014.00096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacoby VL, Autry A, Jacobson G, Domush R, Nakagawa S, Jacoby A. Nationwide use of laparoscopic hysterectomy compared with abdominal and vaginal approaches. Obstet Gynecol 2009;114:1041&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0b013e3181b9d222</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0b013e3181b9d222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel PR, Lee J, Rodriguez AM, Borahay MA, Snyder RR, Hankins GD, et al. Disparities in use of laparoscopic hysterectomies: a nationwide analysis. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2014;21:223&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2013.08.709</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2013.08.709</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pollack LM, Olsen MA, Gehlert SJ, Chang S-H, Lowder JL. Racial/ethnic disparities/differences in hysterectomy route in women likely eligible for minimally invasive surgery. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2020;27:1167&#x2013;77.e2. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2019.09.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2019.09.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price JT, Zimmerman LD, Koelper NC, Sammel MD, Lee S, Butts SF. Social determinants of access to minimally invasive hysterectomy: reevaluating the relationship between race and route of hysterectomy for benign disease. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2017;217:572.e1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2017.07.036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2017.07.036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanei-Moghaddam A, Kang C, Edwards RP, Lounder PJ, Ismail N, Goughnour SL, et al. Racial and socioeconomic disparities in hysterectomy route for benign conditions. J Racial Ethnic Health Disparities 2018;5:758&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1007/s40615-017-0420-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40615-017-0420-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Traylor J, Simon M, Tsai S, Feinglass J. Patient and hospital characteristics associated with minimally invasive hysterectomy: evidence from 143 Illinois hospitals, 2016 to 2018. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2020;27:1337&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2020.02.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2020.02.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waldman I, Wagner S, Kulaylat AS, Deimling TA. Physical well-being and route of benign hysterectomy. Womens Health Issues 2018;28:456&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1016/j.whi.2018.03.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.whi.2018.03.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zaritsky E, Ojo A, Tucker L-Y, Raine-Bennett TR. Racial disparities in route of hysterectomy for benign indications within an integrated health care system. JAMA Netw Open 2019;2:e1917004. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.17004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.17004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranjit A, Sharma M, Romano A, Jiang W, Staat B, Koehlmoos T, et al. Does universal insurance mitigate racial differences in minimally invasive hysterectomy? J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2017;24:790&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2017.03.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2017.03.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith AJB, AlAshqar A, Chaves KF, Borahay MA. Association of demographic, clinical, and hospital-related factors with use of robotic hysterectomy for benign indications: a national database study. Int J Med Robot 2020;16:e2107. doi: 10.1002/rcs.2107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/rcs.2107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright JD, Ananth CV, Lewin SN, Burke WM, Lu YS, Neugut AI, et al. Robotically assisted vs laparoscopic hysterectomy among women with benign gynecologic disease. JAMA 2013;309:689&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1001/jama.2013.186</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.186</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen SL, Ajao MO, Clark NV, Vitonis AF, Einarsson JI. Outpatient hysterectomy volume in the United States. Obstet Gynecol 2017;130:130&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000002103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000002103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen NT, Merchant M, Ritterman Weintraub ML, Salyer C, Poceta J, Diaz L, et al. Alternative treatment utilization before hysterectomy for benign gynecologic conditions at a large integrated health system. J Minim Invasive Gynecol 2019;26:847&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1016/j.jmig.2018.08.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jmig.2018.08.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjerulff KH, Langenberg PW, Rhodes JC, Harvey LA, Guzinski GM, Stolley PD. Effectiveness of hysterectomy. Obstet Gynecol 2000;95:319&#x2013;26. doi: 10.1016/s0029-7844(99)00544-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0029-7844(99)00544-x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bretschneider CE, Casas-Puig V, Sheyn D, Hijaz A, Ferrando CA. Delayed recognition of lower urinary tract injuries following hysterectomy for benign indications: a NSQIP-based study. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2019;221:132.e1&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2019.03.015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2019.03.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dessources K, Hou JY, Tergas AI, Burke WM, Ananth CV, Prendergast E, et al. Factors associated with 30-day hospital readmission after hysterectomy. Obstet Gynecol 2015;125:461&#x2013;70. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000000623</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000000623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakim RB, Benedict MB, Merrick NJ. Quality of care for women undergoing a hysterectomy: effects of insurance and race/ethnicity. Am J Public Health 2004;94:1399&#x2013;405. doi: 10.2105/ajph.94.8.1399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/ajph.94.8.1399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kjerulff KH, Guzinski GM, Langenberg PW, Stolley PD, Moye NE, Kazandjian VA. Hysterectomy and race. Obstet Gynecol 1993;82:757&#x2013;64. https://www.ama-assn.org/press-center/press-releases/new-ama-policies-recognize-race-social-not-biological-construct</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan DM, Swenson CW, Streifel KM, Kamdar NS, Uppal S, Burgunder-Zdravkovski L, et al. Surgical site infection following hysterectomy: adjusted rankings in a regional collaborative. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2016;214:259.e1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2015.10.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2015.10.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penn CA, Morgan DM, Rice LW, Harris JA, Rauh-Hain JA, Uppal S. Timing of and reasons for unplanned 30-day readmission after hysterectomy for benign disease. Obstet Gynecol 2016;128:889&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000001599</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000001599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pepin KJ, Cook EF, Cohen SL. Risk of complication at the time of laparoscopic hysterectomy: a prediction model built from the National Surgical Quality Improvement Program database. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2020;223:555.e1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2020.03.023</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajog.2020.03.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qi AC, Peacock K, Luke AA, Barker A, Olsen MA, Joynt Maddox KE. Associations between social risk factors and surgical site infections after colectomy and abdominal hysterectomy. JAMA Netw Open 2019;2:e1912339. doi: 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.12339</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.12339</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swenson CW, Kamdar NS, Levy H, Campbell DA, Morgan DM. Insurance type and major complications after hysterectomy. Female Pelvic Med Reconstr Surg 2017;23:39&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1097/SPV.0000000000000325</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SPV.0000000000000325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallis CJD, Cheung DC, Garbens A, Kroft J, Carr L, Nathens AB, et al. Occurrence of and risk factors for urological intervention during benign hysterectomy: analysis of the national surgical quality improvement program database. Urology 2016;97:66&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/j.urology.2016.06.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.urology.2016.06.037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang E, Glazer KB, Howell EA, Janevic TM. Social determinants of pregnancy-related mortality and morbidity in the United States: a systematic review. Obstet Gynecol 2020;135:896&#x2013;915. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000003762</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000003762</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karanth S, Fowler ME, Mao X, Wilson LE, Huang B, Pisu M, et al. Race, socioeconomic status, and health-care access disparities in ovarian cancer treatment and mortality: systematic review and meta-analysis. JNCI Cancer Spectr 2019;3:pkz084. doi: 10.1093/jncics/pkz084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jncics/pkz084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallenstein MR, Ananth CV, Kim JH, Burke WM, Hershman DL, Lewin SN, et al. Effect of surgical volume on outcomes for laparoscopic hysterectomy for benign indications. Obstet Gynecol 2012;119:709&#x2013;16. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0b013e318248f7a8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0b013e318248f7a8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knisely A, Huang Y, Melamed A, Gockley A, Tergas AI, St Clair CM, et al. Disparities in access to high-volume surgeons within high-volume hospitals for hysterectomy. Obstet Gynecol 2021;138:208&#x2013;17. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000004456</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000004456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz MP, Chen L, Hou JY, Tergas AI, St Clair CM, Ananth CV, et al. Outcomes of hysterectomy performed by very low-volume surgeons. Obstet Gynecol 2018;131:981&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000002597</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000002597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Medical Association. New AMA policies recognize race as a social, not biological, construct. Accessed January 20, 2023. https://www.ama-assn.org/press-center/press-releases/new-ama-policies-recognize-race-social-not-biological-construct</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institutes of Health. Racial and ethnic categories and definitions for NIH diversity programs and for other reporting purposes; 2015. Accessed September 13, 2022. https://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/notice-files/not-od-15-089.html</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>