<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38323855</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2641-7650</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Kidney360</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Kidney360</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Tenapanor as Therapy for Hyperphosphatemia in Maintenance Dialysis Patients: Results from the OPTIMIZE Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>732</StartPage><EndPage>742</EndPage><MedlinePgn>732-742</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.34067/KID.0000000000000387</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS">Tenapanor, a first-in-class local inhibitor of sodium/hydrogen exchanger isoform 3, acts as a phosphate absorption inhibitor by decreasing paracellular phosphate absorption. Tenapanor alone or with phosphate binders achieved <i>P</i> &#x2264; 5.5 mg/dl over 10 weeks in 34%&#x2013;38% of patients taking phosphate binders at baseline. Tenapanor can help adults with CKD on maintenance dialysis achieve normal serum phosphate concentrations.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">OPTIMIZE was a randomized, open-label study evaluating different tenapanor initiation methods. OPTIMIZE evaluated tenapanor alone and in combination with phosphate binders (PBs) to achieve target serum phosphate (P) &#x2264;5.5 mg/dl.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">Patients with inadequately controlled P receiving maintenance dialysis from 42 US locations who were taking PBs with baseline <i>P</i> &gt; 5.5 mg/dl and &#x2264; 10.0 mg/dl, or were PB-naive with baseline <i>P</i> &gt; 4.5 mg/dl and &#x2264; 10.0 mg/dl, were included in OPTIMIZE. Participants taking PBs at baseline were randomized to switch from PBs to tenapanor (<i>Straight Switch</i>; <i>n</i>=151) or reduce PB dosage by &#x2265;50% and add tenapanor (<i>Binder Reduction</i>; <i>n</i>=152); PB-naive patients started tenapanor alone (<i>Binder-Naive</i>; <i>n</i>=30). Participants received tenapanor 30 mg twice a day for 10 weeks (part A), followed by an elective, 16-week open-label extension (part B). Outcomes included changes from baseline in P, intact fibroblast growth factor 23, parathyroid hormone, serum calcium, and medication burden; patient-reported outcomes; and safety.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">By part A end point, 34.4% (<i>Straight Switch</i>), 38.2% (<i>Binder Reduction</i>), and 63.3% (<i>Binder-Naive</i>) of patients achieved <i>P</i> &#x2264; 5.5 mg/dl. Mean P reduction and median pill burden reduction from baseline to part A end point were 0.91&#xb1;1.7 mg/dl and 4 pills/d for the <i>Straight Switch</i> and 0.99&#xb1;1.8 mg/dl and 1 pill/d for the <i>Binder Reduction</i> group. The mean P reduction for <i>Binder-Naive</i> patients was 0.87&#xb1;1.5 mg/dl. Among <i>Straight Switch</i> and <i>Binder Reduction</i> patients who completed patient experience questionnaires, 205 of 243 (84.4%) reported an improved phosphate management routine. Diarrhea was the most common adverse event (133 of 333 [39.9%]).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Tenapanor as monotherapy or in combination with PBs effectively lowered P toward the target range in patients who were PB-naive or who were not at goal despite PB use.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CLINICAL TRIAL REGISTRATION NUMBER">NCT04549597.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sprague</LastName><ForeName>Stuart M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3330-0179</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>NorthShore University Health System, Evanston, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Chicago Pritzker School of Medicine, Chicago, Illinois.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiner</LastName><ForeName>Daniel E</ForeName><Initials>DE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8775-394</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Tufts Medical Center, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tietjen</LastName><ForeName>David P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Nephrology Consultants LLC, Huntsville, Alabama.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pergola</LastName><ForeName>Pablo E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5876-894</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Renal Associates PA, San Antonio, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fishbane</LastName><ForeName>Steven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2238-8574</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Zucker School of Medicine at Hofstra &amp; Northwell Health, Great Neck, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Block</LastName><ForeName>Geoffrey A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4646-7074</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>US Renal Care, Denver, Colorado.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silva</LastName><ForeName>Arnold L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Boise Kidney and Hypertension Institute, Meridian, Idaho.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fadem</LastName><ForeName>Stephen Z</ForeName><Initials>SZ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kidney Associates, PLLC and Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lynn</LastName><ForeName>Robert I</ForeName><Initials>RI</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kidney Medical Associates, Bronx, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fadda</LastName><ForeName>George</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Balboa Nephrology Medical Group, La Mesa, California.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pagliaro</LastName><ForeName>Lynae</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ardelyx, Inc., Waltham, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhao</LastName><ForeName>Suling</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0006-8356-876</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ardelyx, Inc., Waltham, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Edelstein</LastName><ForeName>Susan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0000-9620-7580</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ardelyx, Inc., Waltham, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spiegel</LastName><ForeName>David M</ForeName><Initials>DM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ardelyx, Inc., Waltham, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenbaum</LastName><ForeName>David P</ForeName><Initials>DP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9371-391</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ardelyx, Inc., Waltham, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02081534</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT02675998</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT03427125</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT03824587</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT03988920</AccessionNumber><AccessionNumber>NCT04549597</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>Ardelyx, Inc.</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Kidney360</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101766381</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2641-7650</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007546">Isoquinolines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D013449">Sulfonamides</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>Kidney360. 2026 May 1;7(5):1192. doi: 10.34067/KID.0000001230.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">41996191</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054559" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hyperphosphatemia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007546" MajorTopicYN="N">Isoquinolines</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006435" MajorTopicYN="Y">Renal Dialysis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013449" MajorTopicYN="N">Sulfonamides</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>G.A. Block reports the following: Employer: US Renal Care; Ownership Interest: Ardelyx, Inc. and US Renal Care, Inc.; Research Funding: Akebia; and Advisory or Leadership Role: Ardelyx, Inc.. S. Edelstein reports the following: Employer: Ardelyx, Inc.; Ownership Interest: Ardelyx, Inc.; Research Funding: Ardelyx, Inc.; Patents or Royalties: Ardelyx, Inc.; and Advisory or Leadership Role: Ardelyx, Inc.. G. Fadda reports the following: Employer: Balboa Nephrology Medical Group; Research Funding: AstraZeneca, Calliditas, and GSK; Honoraria: AstraZeneca, Calliditas, and GSK; and Speakers Bureau: AstraZeneca, Bayer, Calliditas, and GSK. S.Z. Fadem reports the following: Employer: Kidney Associates, PLLC; Ownership Interest: Apple&#x2014;few shares; DaVita&#x2014;few shares; and The rest&#x2014;money managers; Research Funding: I am a PI and do research for Reata, Ardelyx, Inc. through DaVita Clinical Research; Patents or Royalties: Have patent on encrypted software&#x2014;no royalties yet; Advisory or Leadership Role: AAKP Chair Medical Advisory Board and Co-editor of aakpRenalife; NKF Serving Texas&#x2014;Chair Medical Advisory Board; and Other Interests or Relationships: Own Touchcalc, Founded Nephron Information Center. S. Fishbane reports the following: Employer: Northwell Health; Consultancy: Aredelyx, Inc., AstraZeneca, Cara Therapeutics, Galderma, GSK, and Vifor; Research Funding: AstraZeneca, Galderma, Otsuka, and Vertex; and Honoraria: Ardelyx, Inc., AstraZeneca, GSK, and Vifor. R.I. Lynn reports the following: Employer: Kidney Medical Associates. L. Pagliaro reports the following: Employer: Ardelyx, Inc.. P.E. Pergola reports the following: Employer: Renal Associates, P.A.; Consultancy: Ardelyx, Inc., AstraZeneca, Bayer, Calico, Furoscix, GSK, Lilac, Novo Nordisk, Renibus, and Unicycive; Ownership Interest: Unicycive Therapeutics; Research Funding: Prinicipal or subinvestigator on multiple clinical trials. The contracts are with my practice, not individual; and Advisory or Leadership Role: Ardelyx, Inc. and Unicycive. D.P. Rosenbaum reports the following: Employer: Ardelyx, Inc.; Ownership Interest: Ardelyx, Inc.; and Advisory or Leadership Role: Ardelyx, Inc.. A.L. Silva reports the following: Employer: Boise Kidney &amp; Hypertension Institute; Consultancy: Aurinia, Boehringer-Ingelheim, GSK, Novartis, ProKidney, Reata Pharmaceuticals, and Travere; Research Funding: Akebia, Ardelyx, Inc., AstraZeneca, Cara, Cincor, Diamedica, Gilead, Goldfinch Bio, GSK, Mineralys, Novartis, OPKO Renal, ProKidney, Reata Pharmaceuticals, Regulus, Takeda, and Travere; Advisory or Leadership Role: Ardelyx, Inc., Aurinia, Boehringer Ingelheim, GSK, Novartis, ProKidney, Reata, and Travere; and Speakers Bureau: Amgen, AstraZeneca, Aurinia, Bayer, Boehringer-Ingelheim, Janssen, OPKO Renal, and Vifor. D.M. Spiegel reports the following: Employer: Ardelyx, Inc.; Ownership Interest: Stock grants and options from Ardelyx, Inc.; and Other Interests or Relationships: Member: ASN, ISN, and NKF. S.M. Sprague reports the following: Employer: NorthShore University Health System and University of Chicago Pritzker School of Medicine; Consultancy: Amgen, Ardelyx, Inc., Bayer, Fresenius, Horizon, Litholink Corp, OPKO, Shire, and Vifor; Ownership Interest: Individually owned stocks; Apple, Baxter, Bristol Myers, Coca Cola, First Australia Fund, IBM, and Walgreens; Research Funding: Amgen, Amylot, Ardelyx, Inc., OPKO, Reata, and Takeda; Honoraria: Amgen, Ardelyx, Inc., Bayer, Fresenius, OPKO, and Vifor; Advisory or Leadership Role: American Association of Endocrine Surgeons, <i>American Journal of Nephrology</i>, International Federation of Clinical Chemistry and Laboratory Medicine Work Group for Parathyroid Hormone, and National Kidney Foundation of Illinois; and Speakers Bureau: Amgen, Bayer, Fresenius, and OPKO. D.P. Tietjen reports the following: Employer: Nephrology Consultants, L.L.C. D.E. Weiner reports the following: Employer: Tufts Medical Center Physicians Organization; Research Funding: All compensation paid to Tufts MC: Bayer (site PI), Cara (site PI), and Vertex (site PI); Advisory or Leadership Role: Co Editor-in-Chief, NKF Primer on Kidney Diseases, 8th Edition; Editor-in-Chief, <i>Kidney Medicine</i>; Medical Director of Clinical Research, Dialysis Clinic Inc.; Member, ASN Quality and Policy Committees and ASN representative to KCP; Member, Scientific Advisory Board, National Kidney Foundation; and Other Interests or Relationships: Member, Adjudications Committee, ProKidney REACT Trial (WCG Clinical CRO) and Member, Safety and Clinical Events Committee for &#x201c;A Prospective, Multi-Center, Open-Label Assessment of Efficacy and Safety of Quanta SC+ for Home Hemodialysis&#x201d; Trial (Avania CRO). S. Zhao reports the following: Employer: Ardelyx and Google; and Ownership Interest: Ardelyx, Inc. and Google.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>9</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38323855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11146652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34067/KID.0000000000000387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">02200512-202405000-00015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Rastogi A, Bhatt N, Rossetti S, Beto J. Management of hyperphosphatemia in end-stage renal disease: a new paradigm. J Ren Nutr. 2021;31(1):21&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1053/j.jrn.2020.02.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.jrn.2020.02.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32386937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney Disease Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO). KDIGO clinical practice guideline for the diagnosis, evaluation, prevention, and treatment of chronic kidney disease&#x2013;mineral and bone disorder (CKD&#x2013;MBD). Kidney Int Suppl. 2009;76:S1&#x2013;S130. doi: 10.1038/ki.2009.188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ki.2009.188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19644521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young EW Akiba T Albert JM, et al. Magnitude and impact of abnormal mineral metabolism in hemodialysis patients in the Dialysis Outcomes and Practice Patterns Study (DOPPS). Am J Kidney Dis. 2004;44(5 suppl 2):34&#x2013;38. doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2004.08.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2004.08.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15486872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block GA, Klassen PS, Lazarus JM, Ofsthun N, Lowrie EG, Chertow GM. Mineral metabolism, mortality, and morbidity in maintenance hemodialysis. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2004;15(8):2208&#x2013;2218. doi: 10.1097/01.ASN.0000133041.27682.A2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.ASN.0000133041.27682.A2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15284307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tentori F Blayney MJ Albert JM, et al. Mortality risk for dialysis patients with different levels of serum calcium, phosphorus, and PTH: the Dialysis Outcomes and Practice Patterns Study (DOPPS). Am J Kidney Dis. 2008;52(3):519&#x2013;530. doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2008.03.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2008.03.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18514987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moe S Dr&#xfc;eke T Cunningham J, et al. Definition, evaluation, and classification of renal osteodystrophy: a position statement from Kidney Disease: improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO). Kidney Int. 2006;69(11):1945&#x2013;1953. doi: 10.1038/sj.ki.5000414</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ki.5000414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16641930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kestenbaum B Sampson JN Rudser KD, et al. Serum phosphate levels and mortality risk among people with chronic kidney disease. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2005;16(2):520&#x2013;528. doi: 10.1681/ASN.2004070602</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1681/ASN.2004070602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15615819</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney Disease Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO), CKD-MBD Update Work Group. KDIGO 2017 clinical practice guideline update for the diagnosis, evaluation, prevention, and treatment of chronic kidney disease-mineral and bone disorder (CKD-MBD). Kidney Int Suppl (2011). 2017;7(1):1&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.kisu.2017.04.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kisu.2017.04.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6340919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30675420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ketteler M Block GA Evenepoel P, et al. Executive summary of the 2017 KDIGO chronic kidney disease-mineral and bone disorder (CKD-MBD) guideline update: what's changed and why it matters. Kidney Int. 2017;92(1):26&#x2013;36. doi: 10.1016/j.kint.2017.04.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kint.2017.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28646995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isakova T Nickolas TL Denburg M, et al. KDOQI US commentary on the 2017 KDIGO clinical practice guideline update for the diagnosis, evaluation, prevention, and treatment of chronic kidney disease-mineral and bone disorder (CKD-MBD). Am J Kidney Dis. 2017;70(6):737&#x2013;751. doi: 10.1053/j.ajkd.2017.07.019</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2017.07.019</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28941764</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barreto FC, Barreto DV, Massy ZA, Dr&#xfc;eke TB. Strategies for phosphate control in patients with CKD. Kidney Int Rep. 2019;4(8):1043&#x2013;1056. doi: 10.1016/j.ekir.2019.06.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ekir.2019.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6698320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31440695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pergola PE. Phosphate frustration: treatment options to complement current therapies. Int J Nephrol. 2022;2022:9457440. doi: 10.1155/2022/9457440</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2022/9457440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9424003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36045900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forfang D, Edwards DP, Kalantar-Zadeh K. The impact of phosphorus management today on quality of life: patient perspectives. Kidney Med. 2022;4(4):100437. doi: 10.1016/j.xkme.2022.100437</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xkme.2022.100437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8971307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35372822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clegg DJ, Palmer BF. A new age for phosphate management: novel, non-binder therapies to combat diets high in hidden phosphates. Nephrol Renal Dis. 2022;7:1&#x2013;7. doi: 10.15761/NRD.1000194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15761/NRD.1000194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fissell RB Karaboyas A Bieber BA, et al. Phosphate binder pill burden, patient-reported non-adherence, and mineral bone disorder markers: findings from the DOPPS. Hemodial Int. 2016;20(1):38&#x2013;49. doi: 10.1111/hdi.12315</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hdi.12315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4644509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25975222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guedes M Bieber B Dasgupta I, et al. Serum phosphorus level rises in US hemodialysis patients over the past decade: a DOPPS special report. Kidney Med. 2023;5(2):100584. doi: 10.1016/j.xkme.2022.100584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.xkme.2022.100584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9871331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36704450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spencer AG Labonte ED Rosenbaum DP, et al. Intestinal inhibition of the Na+/H+ exchanger 3 prevents cardiorenal damage in rats and inhibits Na+ uptake in humans. Sci Transl Med. 2014;6(227):227ra36. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.3007790</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.3007790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24622516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King AJ Siegel M He Y, et al. Inhibition of sodium/hydrogen exchanger 3 in the gastrointestinal tract by tenapanor reduces paracellular phosphate permeability. Sci Transl Med. 2018;10(456):eaam6474. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.aam6474</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.aam6474</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6454550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30158152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs JW Leadbetter MR Bell N, et al. Discovery of tenapanor: a first-in-class minimally systemic inhibitor of intestinal Na<sup>+</sup>/H<sup>+</sup> exchanger isoform 3. ACS Med Chem Lett.
2022;13(7):1043&#x2013;1051. doi: 10.1021/acsmedchemlett.2c00037
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsmedchemlett.2c00037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9290029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35859876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block GA Rosenbaum DP Leonsson-Zachrisson M, et al. Effect of tenapanor on serum phosphate in patients receiving hemodialysis. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2017;28(6):1933&#x2013;1942. doi: 10.1681/ASN.2016080855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1681/ASN.2016080855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5461797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28159782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block GA, Rosenbaum DP, Yan A, Chertow GM. Efficacy and safety of tenapanor in patients with hyperphosphatemia receiving maintenance hemodialysis: a randomized phase 3 trial. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2019;30(4):641&#x2013;652. doi: 10.1681/ASN.2018080832</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1681/ASN.2018080832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6442342</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30846557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block GA Bleyer AJ Silva AL, et al. Safety and efficacy of tenapanor for long-term serum phosphate control in maintenance dialysis: a 52-week randomized phase 3 trial (PHREEDOM). Kidney360. 2021;2(10):1600&#x2013;1610. doi: 10.34067/KID.0002002021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34067/KID.0002002021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8785778</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35372979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pergola PE, Rosenbaum DP, Yang Y, Chertow GM. A randomized trial of tenapanor and phosphate binders as a dual-mechanism treatment for hyperphosphatemia in patients on maintenance dialysis (AMPLIFY). J Am Soc Nephrol. 2021;32(6):1465&#x2013;1473. doi: 10.1681/ASN.2020101398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1681/ASN.2020101398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8259655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33766811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenbaum DP, Yang Y, Silva AL, Hernandez GT. A Long-Term, Open-Label Study to Evaluate the Ability of Tenapanor (Alone or in Combination with Wevelamer) to Achieve Normal Serum Phosphorus in Patients with Chronic Kidney Disease on Dialysis (NORMALIZE) in Patients Treated for up to 2.5 Years. National Kideny Foundation Spring Clinical Meetings; 2022.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>