<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40232594</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8210</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>6</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Dermatology and therapy</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dermatol Ther (Heidelb)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Management of Challenging Psoriasis Clinical Scenarios.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1555</StartPage><EndPage>1567</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1555-1567</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13555-025-01393-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Psoriasis, a chronic inflammatory skin condition, can have a significant impact on patients' quality of life. Adoption of novel and emerging treatments has significantly improved psoriasis care in clinical practice, but challenges remain. The 'Bridging the Gaps in Challenging Psoriasis' meeting was held in October 2024 to discuss relevant evidence, knowledge gaps, and best practices pertaining to challenging presentations of psoriasis. This report captures important insights and practice impacting guidance gathered from the panel discussion on five topics. The meeting commenced with an in-depth discussion on managing psoriasis in high-impact areas (e.g., scalp, intertriginous regions, nails, and the palms and soles) followed by a discussion on the importance of identifying and addressing common comorbidities associated with psoriasis. The panel explored key considerations and unique challenges when treating psoriasis in patients with darker skin tones ('skin of color') and highlighted the need for tailored therapeutic approaches. A comprehensive dialogue ensued on strategies for managing primary and secondary treatment failures. The session concluded with a concise discussion on the future of psoriasis treatments and pharmacologic therapies currently being developed to manage psoriasis. While discussing various challenging psoriasis scenarios, the dermatology experts emphasized the need to approach psoriasis as a systemic disease and advocated for comprehensive management that addresses both the skin and the broader health of the patient.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stein Gold</LastName><ForeName>Linda</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henry Ford Health, Detroit, MI, USA. lstein1@hfhs.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexis</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weill Cornell Medicine, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glick</LastName><ForeName>Brad P</ForeName><Initials>BP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Larkin Community Hospital, Palm Springs Campus, Miami, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shahriari</LastName><ForeName>Mona</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Song</LastName><ForeName>Eingun James</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Frontier Dermatology, Mill Creek, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strober</LastName><ForeName>Bruce</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Yale University School of Medicine, New Haven, CT, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Watch</LastName><ForeName>Najat M</ForeName><Initials>NM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Henry Ford Health, Detroit, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Young</LastName><ForeName>Melodie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Mindful Dermatology, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Dermatol Ther (Heidelb)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101590450</NlmUniqueID></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Challenging cases</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Comorbidities</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-impact sites</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inadequate response to biologics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psoriasis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skin of color</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflicts of Interest: Linda Stein Gold is an investigator, consultant, and/or speaker for Abbvie, Arcutis, Amgen, Dermavant, Galderma, Incyte, LEO Pharma, Lilly, Pfizer, Regeneron, and Sanofi. Andrew Alexis is an investigator, consultant, and/or speaker for AbbVie, Amgen, LEO Pharma, Galderma, Arcutis, Dermavant, Castle, Incyte, Pfizer, Sanofi-Regeneron, Genzyme, Beiersdorf, Ortho, L&#x2019;Oreal, Bristol Myers Squibb, Bausch Health, UCB, Janssen, Allergan, Almirall, VisualDx, Eli Lilly and Company, Swiss American, Cutera, Cara Therapeutics, EPI, Incyte, Castle, Apogee, Canfield Scientific, Alphyn Biologics, Avita Medical, Genentech, Boehringer Ingelheim, Johnson and Johnson, Aerolase, Springer, Wiley-Blackwell, Wolters Kluwer Health, and Elsevier. Brad Glick is an investigator, consultant, speaker, and/or stakeholder for AbbVie, Amgen, Arcutis, AstraZeneca, Bellus Medical, Brickell Biotech, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cara Therapeutics, ChemoCentryx, CorEvitas Registry PSO, CorEvitas Registry AD, Dermavant, Dermira, Eli Lilly and Company, Galderma, Incyte, Janssen, LEO Pharma, Nimbus Lakshmi, Novartis, Ortho, Pfizer, PROSE Registry for AD, Regeneron, Sanofi-Genzyme, Sun Pharmaceutical Industries, Top MD, and UCB. Mona Shahriari is an investigator, consultant, and/or speaker for AbbVie, Amgen, Apogee, Arcutis, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cara Therapeutics, CorEvitas Registry PSO, CorEvitas Registry AD, Dermavant, Dermira, Galderma, Incyte, Janssen, LEO Pharma, Lilly USA, Mindera Health, Novartis, Pfizer, Sanofi-Genzyme, Regeneron, UCB, and Union Therapeutics. Eingun James Song is an investigator, consultant, and/or speaker for AbbVie, Alphyn Biologics, Amgen, Apogee, Arcutis, Bristol Myers Squibb, Boehringer Ingelheim, Dermavant, DermBiont, Galderma, Incyte, Janssen, LEO Pharma, MoonLake, Novartis, Ortho, Pfizer, Regeneron, Sanofi, Sun Pharmaceutical Industries, Timber Pharmaceuticals, and UCB. Bruce Strober is an investigator, consultant, speaker, and/or stockholder for AbbVie, Alumis, Almirall, Amgen, Arcutis, Boehringer Ingelheim, Bristol Myers Squibb, Capital One, Connect Biopharma, CorEvitas Registry PSO, Dermavant, Janssen, LEO Pharma, Eli Lilly and Company, Mindera Health, Maruho, Meiji Seika Pharma, Novartis, Oruka Therapeutics, Protagonist, Pfizer, Rapt, Regeneron, Sanofi-Genzyme, SG Cowen, Takeda, UCB, Union Therapeutics. Najat M. Watch and Melodie Young report no conflicts of interest. Ethical Approval: All experts who took part in this conference are the authors of this manuscript, therefore ethical approval was not required.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>29</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40232594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12092870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13555-025-01393-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13555-025-01393-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Armstrong AW, Mehta MD, Schupp CW, Gondo GC, Bell SJ, Griffiths CEM. Psoriasis prevalence in adults in the United States. JAMA Dermatol. 2021;157(8):940&#x2013;6. 10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.2007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.2007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8246333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34190957</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmets CA, Korman NJ, Prater EF, et al. Joint AAD-NPF guidelines of care for the management and treatment of psoriasis with topical therapy and alternative medicine modalities for psoriasis severity measures. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2021;84(2):432&#x2013;70. 10.1016/j.jaad.2020.07.087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.07.087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosca M, Hong J, Hadeler E, Brownstone N, Bhutani T, Liao W. Scalp psoriasis: a literature review of effective therapies and updated recommendations for practical management. Dermatol Ther (Heidelb). 2021;11(3):769&#x2013;97. 10.1007/s13555-021-00521-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13555-021-00521-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8163911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33893995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arcutis Biotherapeutics. Zoryve cream. Prescribing information. 2024. https://www.arcutis.com/wp-content/uploads/USPI-roflumilast-cream.pdf. Accessed 19 Nov 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arcutis Biotherapeutics. Zoryve foam. Prescribing information. 2023. https://www.arcutis.com/wp-content/uploads/zoryve-foam-pi-hcp.pdf. Accessed 19 Nov 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dermavant Sciences Inc. Vtama cream. Prescribing information. 2024. https://vtamahcp.com/PI/. Accessed 24 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson FC, Icen M, Crowson CS, McEvoy MT, Gabriel SE, Kremers HM. Incidence and clinical predictors of psoriatic arthritis in patients with psoriasis: a population-based study [published correction appears in Arthritis Rheum. 2010 Apr;62(4):574].&#xa0;Arthritis Rheum. 2009;61(2):233&#x2013;239. 10.1002/art.24172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3061343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19177544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papp K, Lebwohl M, Gottlieb A, et al. Bimekizumab for the treatment of moderate to severe plaque psoriasis with scalp, nail and palmoplantar involvement through 52 weeks: post-hoc analysis from the BE VIVID phase 3 trial. SKIN J Cutan Med. 2021;5(1):s18. 10.25251/skin.5.supp.18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25251/skin.5.supp.18</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merola JF, Conrad C, Hampton P, et al. Bimekizumab 3-year efficacy in high-impact areas in moderate to severe plaque psoriasis: pooled results from five phase 3/3b trials. SKIN J Cutan Med. 2024;8(1):s304. 10.25251/skin.8.supp.304.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25251/skin.8.supp.304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich K, Leonardi C, Lebwohl M, et al. Sustained response with ixekizumab treatment of moderate-to-severe psoriasis with scalp involvement: results from three phase 3 trials (UNCOVER-1, UNCOVER-2, UNCOVER-3). J Dermatol Treat. 2017;28(4):282&#x2013;7. 10.1080/09546634.2016.1249820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09546634.2016.1249820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27759463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piaserico S, Riedl E, Pavlovsky L, et al. Comparative effectiveness of biologics for patients with moderate-to-severe psoriasis and special area involvement: week 12 results from the observational psoriasis study of health outcomes (PSoHO). Front Med (Lausanne). 2023;10:1185523. 10.3389/fmed.2023.1185523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2023.1185523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10339811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37457564</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Law RM, Ngo MA, Maibach HI. Twenty clinically pertinent factors/observations for percutaneous absorption in humans. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2020;21(1):85&#x2013;95. 10.1007/s40257-019-00480-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-019-00480-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31677110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bristol Myers Squibb. Sotyktu. Prescribing information. 2022. https://packageinserts.bms.com/pi/pi_sotyktu.pdf. Accessed 19 Nov 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong AW, Gooderham M, Warren RB, et al. Deucravacitinib versus placebo and apremilast in moderate to severe plaque psoriasis: efficacy and safety results from the 52-week, randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled phase 3 POETYK PSO-1 trial. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2023;88(1):29&#x2013;39. 10.1016/j.jaad.2022.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2022.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35820547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebwohl M, Kircik LH, Moore A, et al. Roflumilast cream, a once-daily, potent phosphodiesterase-4 inhibitor, in chronic plaque psoriasis patients: efficacy and safety from DERMIS-1 and DERMIS-2 phase 3 trials. In: The 2024 European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology Spring Symposium, 25-28 Sept, Amsterdam. https://www.arcutis.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Roflumilast-cream-Study-301-302-EADV-presentation_FINAL.pdf. Accessed 24 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sofen H, Tyring S, Johnson SM, et al. Efficacy of tapinarof cream 1% once daily for the treatment of mild to severe intertriginous plaque psoriasis. SKIN J Cutan Med. 2023. 10.25251/skin.7.supp.235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25251/skin.7.supp.235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan C, Menter A, Guenther L, et al. Efficacy and safety of ixekizumab in a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled phase IIIb study of patients with moderate-to-severe genital psoriasis. Br J Dermatol. 2018;179(4):844&#x2013;52. 10.1111/bjd.16736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.16736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29747232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merola JF, Parish LC, Guenther L, et al. Efficacy and safety of apremilast in patients with moderate-to-severe genital psoriasis: results from DISCREET, a phase 3 randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2024;90(3):485&#x2013;93. 10.1016/j.jaad.2023.10.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2023.10.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37852306</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lebwohl M, Bukhalo M, Stein Gold L, et al. A randomized phase 3b study evaluating the safety and efficacy of risankizumab in adult patients with moderate-to-severe plaque psoriasis with non-pustular palmoplantar involvement. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2024;91(6):1150&#x2013;7. 10.1016/j.jaad.2024.07.1521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2024.07.1521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39208985</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb A, Sullivan J, van Doorn M, et al. Secukinumab shows significant efficacy in palmoplantar psoriasis: results from GESTURE, a randomized controlled trial. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;76(1):70&#x2013;80. 10.1016/j.jaad.2016.07.058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2016.07.058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27707593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muzumdar S, Leonardi C, Strober B. Tofacitinib for the treatment of refractory palmoplantar psoriasis: a case series. J Psoriasis Psoriatic Arthritis. 2021;6(2):93&#x2013;8. 10.1177/2475530321995516.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2475530321995516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11361534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39295821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dhillon S. Delgocitinib: first approval. Drugs. 2020;80(6):609&#x2013;15. 10.1007/s40265-020-01291-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40265-020-01291-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32166597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yamamoto T. Psoriasis and connective tissue diseases. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21(16):5803. 10.3390/ijms21165803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7460816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32823524</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mease PJ, Gladman DD, Papp KA, et al. Prevalence of rheumatologist-diagnosed psoriatic arthritis in patients with psoriasis in European/North American dermatology clinics. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2013;69(5):729&#x2013;35. 10.1016/j.jaad.2013.07.023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2013.07.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23981683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellinato F, Maurelli M, Geat D, Girolomoni G, Gisondi P. Managing the patient with psoriasis and metabolic comorbidities. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2024;25(4):527&#x2013;40. 10.1007/s40257-024-00857-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-024-00857-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11193697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38748391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin M, Lee EB, Tsai TF, Wu JJ. Psoriasis and co-morbidity. Acta Derm Venereol. 2020;100(3):adv00033. 10.2340/00015555-3387.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/00015555-3387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9128942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31971602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu JJ, Nguyen TU, Poon KY, Herrinton LJ. The association of psoriasis with autoimmune diseases. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2012;67(5):924&#x2013;30. 10.1016/j.jaad.2012.04.039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2012.04.039</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22664308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong A, Bohannan B, Mburu S, et al. Impact of psoriatic disease on quality of life: interim results of a global survey. Dermatol Ther (Heidelb). 2022;12(4):1055&#x2013;64. 10.1007/s13555-022-00695-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13555-022-00695-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8918421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35286611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Felix PAO, Sampaio AL, Silva BL, Viana ALP. Early intervention in psoriasis: where do we go from here? Front Med (Lausanne). 2022;9:1027347. 10.3389/fmed.2022.1027347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2022.1027347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9751903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36530901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takeshita J, Augustin M, de Jong EMGJ, et al. Health-related QOL differs by race/ethnicity in North American patients with psoriasis: results from PSOLAR. J Investig Dermatol. 2022;142(9):2528-31.e3. 10.1016/j.jid.2022.02.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jid.2022.02.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35304247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexis AF, Blackcloud P. Psoriasis in skin of color: epidemiology, genetics, clinical presentation, and treatment nuances. J Clin Aesthet Dermatol. 2014;7(11):16&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4255694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25489378</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lew W, Lee E, Krueger JG. Psoriasis genomics: analysis of proinflammatory (type 1) gene expression in large plaque (Western) and small plaque (Asian) psoriasis vulgaris. Br J Dermatol. 2004;150(4):668&#x2013;76. 10.1111/j.0007-0963.2004.05891.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0007-0963.2004.05891.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15099362</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Desai SR, Alexis AF, Jacobson A. Successful management of a black male with psoriasis and dyspigmentation treated with halobetasol propionate 0.01%/tazarotene 0.045% lotion: case report. J Drugs Dermatol. 2020;19(10):1000&#x2013;4. 10.36849/jdd.2020.5347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36849/jdd.2020.5347</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33026772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexis A, McMichael A, Bhutani T. et al. Visible cohort b: guselkumab demonstrates significant scalp clearance at week 16 in participants with moderate-to-severe scalp psoriasis across all skin tones. In: The 5th Annual San Diego Dermatology Symposium, 2&#x2013;4 February 2024, San Diego. https://www.dermrefoundation.org/uploads/1/2/6/2/126228942/ind_rowland.pdf. Accessed 22 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mufti A, Maliyar K, Walton L, Vender R, Yeung J. Guselkumab dosing interval optimization in adult patients with psoriasis: a retrospective, multicenter case series. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;83(6):1813&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.jaad.2020.04.025.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.04.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32289394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagit A, Maliyar K, Mansour M, et al. Effectiveness and safety of risankizumab dose optimization in adult patients with plaque psoriasis: an international multicentre retrospective cohort study. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2024. 10.1111/jdv.20373.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.20373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39403817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boswell ND, Singla S, Gordon KB. Sequencing of targeted therapy in psoriasis: does it matter. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2024;25(5):795&#x2013;810. 10.1007/s40257-024-00874-z.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-024-00874-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39003351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruggiero A, Picone B, Martora F, Fabbrocini G, Megna M. Guselkumab, risankizumab, and tildrakizumab in the management of psoriasis: a review of the real-world evidence. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2022;15:1649&#x2013;58. 10.2147/CCID.S364640.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CCID.S364640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9392468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35996400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reich K, Warren RB, Lebwohl M, et al. Bimekizumab versus secukinumab in plaque psoriasis. N Engl J Med. 2021;385:142&#x2013;52. 10.1056/NEJMoa2102383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2102383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33891380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gu&#xe9;nin S, Andrews E, Lebwohl MG. Safety and efficacy of dual tyrosine kinase 2 inhibitor and monoclonal antibody therapy for psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis. Br J Dermatol. 2024;190(3):451&#x2013;3. 10.1093/bjd/ljad473.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjd/ljad473</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38011328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bissonnette R, Pinter A, Ferris LK, et al. An oral interleukin-23-receptor antagonist peptide for plaque psoriasis. N Engl J Med. 2024;390(6):510&#x2013;21. 10.1056/NEJMoa2308713.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2308713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38324484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferris LK, Bagel J, Huang Y, et al. A phase 2b, long-term extension, dose-ranging study of oral JNJ-77242113 for treating moderate-to-severe plaque psoriasis: FRONTIER-2. In: The Congress of Clinical Rheumatology-West (CCR West 2024), 26-29 Sept 2024, San Diego. https://www.janssenscience.com/media/attestation/congresses/immunology/2024/ccr-west/a-phase-2b-longterm-extension-doseranging-study-of-oral-jnj77242113-for-the-treatment-of-moderatetos.pdf. Accessed 22 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Armstrong AW, Gooderham M, Lynde C, et al. Tyrosine kinase 2 inhibition with zasocitinib (TAK-279) in psoriasis: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Dermatol. 2024;160(10):1066&#x2013;74. 10.1001/jamadermatol.2024.2701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2024.2701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11339701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39167366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papp KA, Sofen H, Rubio RG, et al. Efficacy and safety of ESK-001, a highly selective oral TYK2 inhibitor, in a phase 2 study (STRIDE) and OLE study in adults with moderate-to-severe plaque psoriasis. In: The 2024 American Academy of Dermatology Annual Meeting, 27-31 March 2024, Denver. https://www.alumis.com/file.cfm/18/docs/alumis_pub_2_for_website_aad_pres_vf.pdf. Accessed 22 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blauvelt A, Kempers S, Hitraya E, et al. Efficacy and safety of ESK-001, a highly selective oral TYK2 inhibitor, in moderate to severe plaque psoriasis: phase 2 results through week 28. In: The 2024 European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology Congress, 25&#x2013;28 Sept 2024, Amsterdam. https://www.alumis.com/file.cfm/18/docs/eadv_late_breaker_presentation_final.pdf. Accessed 22 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwan B, Alam MM, Milligan J, et al. Characterization of ORKA-001, a novel extended half-life monoclonal antibody targeting IL-23 for the treatment of psoriasis. In: The 2024 European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology Congress, 25&#x2013;28 Sept 2024, Amsterdam. Abstract 4711. https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/m-anage.com.storage.eadv/abstracts_congress_2024/46185.pdf. Accessed 22 Jan 2025.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>