<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40235631</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2048-8505</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Clinical kidney journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Kidney J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>eGFR slope modelling predicts long-term clinical benefit with nefecon in a real-world IgAN population.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>sfae404</StartPage><MedlinePgn>sfae404</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">sfae404</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/ckj/sfae404</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Nefecon is an oral, targeted-release formulation of budesonide approved to reduce kidney function loss in patients with immunoglobulin A nephropathy (IgAN). In the phase 3 NefIgArd trial, 9 months of nefecon treatment preserved estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) and reduced urine protein-creatinine ratio versus placebo, for 15&#xa0;months post-treatment. A modelling analysis was conducted to predict nefecon's long-term benefits on clinical outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A published linear regression model was used to extrapolate nefecon's effect on the eGFR slope in NefIgArd to predict its effect on the clinical outcome of kidney failure, eGFR &lt;15&#xa0;ml/min/1.73&#xa0;m<sup>2</sup>, or sustained doubling of serum creatinine. This model was applied to registry data from patients with IgAN at Leicester General Hospital (LGH), whose records were matched to individual NefIgArd patients on the basis of their urine protein-creatinine ratio and eGFR values.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 1684 LGH-NeflgArd 'matched pairs' were obtained. Nefecon was predicted to delay the time to clinical outcome by 12.8 years (95% confidence interval 4.8-27.9), with median time to outcome of 9.6 years for patients receiving supportive care only versus 22.4 years for nefecon-treated patients. The NeflgArd 2-year eGFR slope yielded a log hazard ratio for the clinical outcome of 0.38 (95% confidence interval 0.21-0.63), a 62% risk reduction versus placebo. Of patients receiving only supportive care, 52% were modelled to have a clinical outcome within 10 years versus 24% of nefecon-treated patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This modelling analysis indicates that the eGFR benefit seen with nefecon predicts a substantial delay in progression to kidney failure.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the ERA.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barratt</LastName><ForeName>Jonathan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>College of Life Sciences, University of Leicester, Leicester, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stone</LastName><ForeName>Andrew M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Stone Biostatistics Ltd, Crewe, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reich</LastName><ForeName>Heather N</ForeName><Initials>HN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Division of Nephrology, University Health Network, University of Toronto, Toronto, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lafayette</LastName><ForeName>Richard A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Medicine, Stanford University, Stanford, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Kidney J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101579321</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2048-8505</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IgA nephropathy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">end-stage kidney disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">glomerular filtration rate</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">kidney failure</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proteinuria</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>J.B. is a consultant to Calliditas Therapeutics and reports grants and consultancy and personal fees from Calliditas Therapeutics, Everest Medicines, and STADA Arzneimittel. A.M.S. received support for the present manuscript from Calliditas Therapeutics and reports consulting fees from Calliditas Therapeutics outside the submitted work. H.N.R. received support to serve as a member of the steering committee of the present study and funding for its execution from Calliditas Therapeutics; has received grant support from the Canadian Institutes of Health Research and the Kidney Foundation of Canada (from John and Leslie Pearson); has received fellowship support from the Louise Fast Foundation; reports consulting fees, honoraria, or travel support from Calliditas Therapeutics, Chinook, Novartis, Omeros, Pfizer, and Travere Therapeutics; has served on advisory boards and steering committees for Chinook, Novartis, Omeros, Pfizer, and Travere Therapeutics; has been an investigator for Alnylam Pharmaceuticals, Calliditas Therapeutics, ChemoCentryx, Chinook, Omeros, and Pfizer; and is Director of the Glomerulonephritis Fellowship, funded by the Louise Fast Foundation. R.A.L. received support for the present manuscript from Calliditas Therapeutics; reports institutional grants from Calliditas Therapeutics, ChemoCentryx, Omeros, Otsuka, Pfizer, Roche, Travere Therapeutics, Vera Therapeutics, and Visterra; and has served on advisory boards for Cara Therapeutics.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40235631</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11997755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ckj/sfae404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">sfae404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wyatt RJ, Julian BA.. IgA nephropathy. N Engl J Med 2013;368:2402&#x2013;14. 10.1056/NEJMra1206793</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra1206793</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23782179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafayette R, Kristensen J, Stone Aet al. Efficacy and safety of a targeted-release formulation of budesonide in patients with primary IgA nephropathy (NefIgArd): 2-year results from a randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet 2023;402:859&#x2013;70. 10.1016/S0140-6736(23)01554-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(23)01554-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37591292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coppo R. The gut&#x2013;renal connection in IgA nephropathy. Semin Nephrol 2018;38:504&#x2013;12. 10.1016/j.semnephrol.2018.05.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semnephrol.2018.05.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30177022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barratt J, Rovin BH, Cattran Det al. Why target the gut to treat IgA nephropathy? Kidney Int Rep 2020;5:1620&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.ekir.2020.08.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ekir.2020.08.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7569689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33102954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitcher D, Braddon F, Hendry Bet al. Long-term outcomes in IgA nephropathy. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 2023;18:727&#x2013;38. 10.2215/CJN.0000000000000135</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.0000000000000135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10278810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37055195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai KN, Leung JC, Tang SC.. Recent advances in the understanding and management of IgA nephropathy. F1000Res 2016;5:161. 10.12688/f1000research.7352.1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/f1000research.7352.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4755398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26918170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moriyama T, Tanaka K, Iwasaki Cet al. Prognosis in IgA nephropathy: 30-year analysis of 1,012 patients at a single center in Japan. PLoS ONE 2014;9:e91756. 10.1371/journal.pone.0091756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0091756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3962373</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24658533</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Penfold RS, Prendecki M, McAdoo Set al. Primary IgA nephropathy: current challenges and future prospects. Int J Nephrol Renovasc Dis 2018;11:137&#x2013;48. 10.2147/IJNRD.S129227</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IJNRD.S129227</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5905843</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29695925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Manno C, Strippoli GF, D'Altri Cet al. A novel simpler histological classification for renal survival in IgA nephropathy: a retrospective study. Am J Kidney Dis 2007;49:763&#x2013;75. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2007.03.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2007.03.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17533019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schena FP. A retrospective analysis of the natural history of primary IgA nephropathy worldwide. Am J Med 1990;89:209&#x2013;15. 10.1016/0002-9343(90)90300-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0002-9343(90)90300-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2200265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kefale B, Alebachew M, Tadesse Yet al. Quality of life and its predictors among patients with chronic kidney disease: a hospital-based cross sectional study. PLoS ONE 2019;14:e0212184. 10.1371/journal.pone.0212184</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0212184</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6392259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30811447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levey AS, Gansevoort RT, Coresh Jet al. Change in albuminuria and GFR as end points for clinical trials in early stages of CKD: a scientific workshop sponsored by the National Kidney Foundation in collaboration with the US Food and Drug Administration and European Medicines Agency. Am J Kidney Dis 2020;75:84&#x2013;104. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2019.06.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2019.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31473020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levey AS, Inker LA, Matsushita Ket al. GFR decline as an end point for clinical trials in CKD: a scientific workshop sponsored by the National Kidney Foundation and the US Food and Drug Administration. Am J Kidney Dis 2014;64:821&#x2013;35. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2014.07.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2014.07.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25441437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inker LA, Heerspink HJL, Tighiouart Het al. Association of treatment effects on early change in urine protein and treatment effects on GFR slope in IgA nephropathy: an individual participant meta-analysis. Am J Kidney Dis 2021;78:340&#x2013;349.e1. 10.1053/j.ajkd.2021.03.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.ajkd.2021.03.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8384669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33775708</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafayette RA, Reich HN, Stone AMet al. One-year estimated GFR slope independently predicts clinical benefit in immunoglobulin A nephropathy. Kidney Int Rep 2022;7:2730&#x2013;3. 10.1016/j.ekir.2022.09.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ekir.2022.09.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9727523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36506237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inker LA, Heerspink HJL, Tighiouart Het al. GFR slope as a surrogate end point for kidney disease progression in clinical trials: a meta-analysis of treatment effects of randomized controlled trials. J Am Soc Nephrol 2019;30:1735&#x2013;45. 10.1681/ASN.2019010007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1681/ASN.2019010007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6727261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31292197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbour SJ, Coppo R, Zhang Het al. Evaluating a new international risk-prediction tool in IgA nephropathy. JAMA Intern Med 2019;179:942&#x2013;52. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2019.0600</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2019.0600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30980653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grams ME, Brunskill NJ, Ballew SHet al. The Kidney Failure Risk equation: evaluation of novel input variables including eGFR estimated using the CKD-EPI 2021 equation in 59 cohorts. J Am Soc Nephrol 2023;34:482&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10103205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36857500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du Y, Cheng T, Liu Cet al. IgA nephropathy: current understanding and perspectives on pathogenesis and targeted treatment. Diagnostics 2023;13:303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9857562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36673113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barratt J, Lafayette RA, Rovin BHet al. Budesonide delayed-release capsules to reduce proteinuria in adults with primary immunoglobulin A nephropathy. Expert Rev Clin Immunol 2023;19:699&#x2013;710. 10.1080/1744666X.2023.2206119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1744666X.2023.2206119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37103889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barratt J, Lafayette R, Kristensen Jet al. Results from part A of the multi-center, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled NefIgArd trial, which evaluated targeted-release formulation of budesonide for the treatment of primary immunoglobulin A nephropathy. Kidney Int 2023;103:391&#x2013;402. (supplementary appendix). 10.1016/j.kint.2022.09.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kint.2022.09.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36270561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>STADA Arzneimittel AG. Kinpeygo (budesonide) European Summary of Product Characteristics. 2023; https://www.ema.europa.eu/documents/product-information/kinpeygo-epar-product-information_en.pdf
(March 1, 2024, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calliditas Therapeutics AB. Tarpeyo (budesonide) US Prescribing Information. 2023; https://www.tarpeyo.com/prescribinginformation.pdf
(January 24, 2024, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ClinicalTrials.gov . Efficacy and safety of nefecon in patients with primary IgA (immunoglobulin A) nephropathy (NefIgArd). 2021; https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03643965
(March 3, 2023, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafayette R, Kristensen J, Stone Aet al. eGFR decline in patients with IgAN treated with Nefecon or placebo: results from the 2-year NefIgArd Phase 3 trial. Philadelphia, PA, USA: American Society of Nephrology (ASN), 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv J, Wong MG, Hladunewich MAet al. Effect of oral methylprednisolone on decline in kidney function or kidney failure in patients with IgA nephropathy: the TESTING randomized clinical trial. JAMA 2022;327:1888&#x2013;98. 10.1001/jama.2022.5368</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2022.5368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9115617</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rauen T, Wied S, Fitzner Cet al. After ten years of follow-up, no difference between supportive care plus immunosuppression and supportive care alone in IgA nephropathy. Kidney Int 2020;98:1044&#x2013;52. 10.1016/j.kint.2020.04.046</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kint.2020.04.046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32450154</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lafayette R, Kristensen J, Jones Ret al. NefIgArd open-label extension: efficacy and safety of nefecon in patients with IgAN who completed the 2-year Phase 3 trial. San Diego, CA, USA: American Society of Nephrology (ASN), 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngai C, Pesce G, Zaidi Set al. Results from a real-world case series of IgAN patients who received at least 9 months of TARPEYO. San Diego, CA, USA: American Society of Nephrology (ASN), 2024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson A, Carroll K, Inker LAet al. Proteinuria reduction as a surrogate end point in trials of IgA nephropathy. Clin J Am Soc Nephrol 2019;14:469&#x2013;81. 10.2215/CJN.08600718</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2215/CJN.08600718</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6419287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercer A, Carroll K, Conley Let al. Estimating delay in time to kidney failure or death for treatment effects on proteinuria in IgA nephropathy. Milan, Italy: European Renal Association (ERA), 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes Glomerular Diseases Work Group . KDIGO 2024 clinical practice guideline for the management of immunoglobulin A nephropathy (IgAN) and immunoglobulin A vasculitis (IgAV) public review draft. 2024; https://kdigo.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/KDIGO-2024-IgAN-IgAV-Guideline-Public-Review-Draft.pdf (January 24, 2025, date last accessed).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barratt J, Kristensen J, Stone Aet al. Nefecon treatment response in Asian and White patient populations with immunoglobulin A nephropathy: a 2-year analysis of the phase 3 NefIgArd trial. Tokyo, Japan: International Symposium on IgA Nephropathy (IIgANN), 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wimbury D, Muto M, Bhachu JSet al. Targeted-release budesonide modifies key pathogenic biomarkers in immunoglobulin A nephropathy: insights from the NEFIGAN trial. Kidney Int 2023;105:381&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.kint.2023.11.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.kint.2023.11.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38008160</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>