<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">40665146</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-1888</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of clinical dermatology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Clin Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Efficacy and Safety of Lebrikizumab in Adult and Adolescent Patients with Skin of Color and Moderate-to-Severe Atopic Dermatitis: Results from the Phase IIIb, Open-Label ADmirable Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>803</StartPage><EndPage>817</EndPage><MedlinePgn>803-817</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40257-025-00970-8</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Data are lacking to guide diagnosis and treatment in patients with skin of color and atopic dermatitis (AD), a population traditionally underrepresented in clinical trials.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to evaluate the efficacy and safety of lebrikizumab in adults and adolescents with skin of color and moderate-to-severe AD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In the open-label ADmirable trial, 90 adults and adolescents with moderate-to-severe AD, Fitzpatrick skin phototype IV-VI, and self-reported race other than White received lebrikizumab 250&#xa0;mg subcutaneously every 2 weeks (Q2W), following a 500-mg loading dose at baseline and Week 2, for 16 weeks. From Week 16 to Week 24, responders, defined as patients with at least 75% improvement in Eczema Area and Severity Index (EASI&#xa0;75) and/or Investigator's Global Assessment (IGA) score of 0/1 with at least a 2-point improvement from baseline, received lebrikizumab every 4 weeks (Q4W); inadequate responders continued lebrikizumab Q2W. The primary endpoint was the percentage of patients achieving EASI&#xa0;75 at Week 16. Secondary and exploratory efficacy endpoints and safety were assessed throughout. Data were analyzed as observed and using imputation, with Q2W and Q4W populations pooled for Weeks 16-24.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Mean age at baseline was 40.7 years; 43.3% were female; and 43.3%, 24.4%, and 32.2% had Fitzpatrick skin phototypes IV, V, and VI, respectively. Baseline mean EASI and Pruritus Numeric Rating Scale (NRS) scores were 26.4 and 7.0, respectively; 68.9% of patients had moderate disease (IGA&#xa0;=&#xa0;3). At Week 16 (number of patients with non-missing values [Nx] = 78), EASI&#xa0;75, EASI&#xa0;90 (&#x2265;&#xa0;90% improvement from baseline in EASI), and IGA&#xa0;0/1 (IGA response of clear or almost clear) were achieved by 69.2%, 44.9%, and 44.9% of patients, respectively; for Pruritus NRS (Nx&#xa0;=&#xa0;62), 58.1% of patients reported &#x2265; 4-point improvement. At Week 24 (Nx&#xa0;=&#xa0;74) (pooled treatment arms), EASI&#xa0;75, EASI&#xa0;90, and IGA&#xa0;0/1 were achieved by 78.4%, 47.3%, and 54.1% of patients, respectively. EASI&#xa0;75 was achieved by 62.9%, 88.2%, and 95.5% of patients with Fitzpatrick skin phototype IV (Nx&#xa0;=&#xa0;35), V (Nx&#xa0;=&#xa0;17), and VI (Nx&#xa0;=&#xa0;22), respectively, at Week 24. Most patients (64.4%) with baseline PDCA-Derm&#x2122;-assessed hyperpigmented areas showed reduced hyperpigmentation at Week 24. Most treatment-emergent adverse events were mild or moderate in severity; none were serious or led to discontinuation. One case of conjunctivitis was reported.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In this first lebrikizumab study in patients with skin of color (Fitzpatrick skin phototype IV, V, and VI) and moderate-to-severe AD, lebrikizumab improved signs and symptoms of AD and confirmed its favorable safety profile.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT05372419 (registered May 5, 2022).</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alexis</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Weill Cornell Medicine, Cornell University, New York, NY, USA. drandrewalexis@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moiin</LastName><ForeName>Ali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Comprehensive Dermatology Center, Detroit, MI, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waibel</LastName><ForeName>Jill</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Miami Dermatology and Laser Institute, Miami, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wallace</LastName><ForeName>Paul</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Wallace Skin Research Center, Los Angeles, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cohen</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Skin Care Physicians of Georgia, Macon, GA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laquer</LastName><ForeName>Vivian</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>First OC Dermatology Research, Fountain Valley, CA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kwong</LastName><ForeName>Pearl</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Solutions Through Advanced Research, Jacksonville, FL, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atwater</LastName><ForeName>Amber Reck</ForeName><Initials>AR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly and Company, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schuster</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly and Company, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Proper</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly and Company, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Silk</LastName><ForeName>Maria</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly and Company, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pierce</LastName><ForeName>Evangeline</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly and Company, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pillai</LastName><ForeName>Sreekumar</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly and Company, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rueda</LastName><ForeName>Maria Jose</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eli Lilly and Company, Indianapolis, IN, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moore</LastName><ForeName>Angela</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor University Medical Center, Dallas, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arlington Research Center, Arlington, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Arlington Center for Dermatology, Arlington, TX, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>ADmirable Investigators</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT05372419</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>New Zealand</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Clin Dermatol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100895290</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1175-0561</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>U9JLP7V031</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C561806">lebrikizumab</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000911">Antibodies, Monoclonal</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003879">Dermatologic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003876" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatitis, Atopic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007279" MajorTopicYN="N">Injections, Subcutaneous</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012880" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin Pigmentation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000911" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antibodies, Monoclonal</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003879" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dermatologic Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics Approval: The ADmirable clinical trial was conducted in accordance with ethical principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki, Council for International Organizations of Medical Sciences, and Good Clinical Practice guidelines. The ADmirable trial protocol was approved by the Advarra Institutional Review Board on 17 October 2022 (IRB #: Pro00066938). Additionally, Advarra approved the study at each participating center (Supplement 1, Table S1). All investigation sites received approval from the appropriate authorized institutional review board or ethics committee. The ADmirable study is registered on ClinicalTrials.gov (NCT05372419). Consent to Participate: Informed consent was obtained from all patients before study procedures were initiated. For patients considered to be minors, the written consent of the parent or legal guardian, as well as the assent of the minor, was obtained. Consent to Publish: The authors affirm that human research participants provided informed consent for publication of the images in Figures 3a, 3b, and 3c. Funding and Role of the Funder/Sponsor: This study was funded by Eli Lilly and Company. Eli Lilly and Company had a role in the design and conduct of the study; collection, management, analysis, and interpretation of the data; preparation, review, or approval of the manuscript; and decision to submit the manuscript for publication. Almirall, S.A. has licensed the rights to develop and commercialize lebrikizumab for the treatment of dermatology indications, including atopic dermatitis, in Europe. Lilly has exclusive rights for development and commercialization of lebrikizumab in the United States and the rest of the world outside of Europe. Competing Interests: Andrew Alexis has received grant support (funds to institution) from Leo, Amgen, Galderma, Arcutis, Dermavant, Abbvie, Castle Advisory board/Consulting: Leo, Galderma, Pfizer, Sanofi-Regeneron, Genzyme, Dermavant, Beiersdorf, Ortho, L&#x2019;Or&#xe9;al, BMS, Bausch health, UCB, Arcutis, Janssen, Allergan, Almirall, Abbvie, Amgen, VisualDx, Eli Lilly and Company, Swiss American, Cutera, Cara, EPI, Incyte, Castle, Apogee, Canfield, Alphyn, Avita Medical, Genentech; has served as a speaker for Regeneron, SANOFI-Genzyme, BMS, L&#x2019;Oreal, Janssen, and J&amp;J; has received royalties from Springer, Wiley-Blackwell, Wolters Kluwer Health; and has received equipment from Aerolase. Ali Moiin has received reimbursement for travel costs from and conducted clinical trials for Eli Lilly and Company. Jill Waibel has served as a consultant, investigator, and/or on scientific advisory boards for Allergan (Consultant), Amgen (Clinical Trial), ArgenX (Clinical Trial), Bellamia (Advisory Board), Bristol Myers Squibb (Clinical Trial), Candela (Speaker, Consultant, Advisory Board), Cytrellis Biosystems (Advisory Board, Consultant, Clinical Trial), Eli Lilly and Company (Clinical Trial, Speaker), Emblation (Clinical Trial), Galderma (Clinical Trial, Consultant), Horizon (Clinical Trial), Janssen/J&amp;J (Clinical Trial), Lumenis (Advisory Board, Consultant, Speaker), Neuronetics (Clinical Trial), Pfizer (Clinical Trial), P &amp; G (Consultant), RegenX (Clinical Consultant, Clinical Trial, Board of Directors), Sanofi (Clinical Trial), Skinceuticals (Clinical Trial, Consultant, Advisory Board), and Shanghai Biopharma, PWB (Clinical Trial); and has received a VA Merit Grant for Amputated Veterans. Paul Wallace has served as a principal investigator, advisor and/or speaker for Abbvie, Amgen, Arcutis, Biogen, Bristol Myers, Celgene, Centocor, Cynosure, Eli Lilly and Company, Genentech, GlaxoSmithKline, Merck, Novartis, Pfizer, Sanofi-Aventis, and UCB; and has received equipment (loan to institution) from Cynosure. David Cohen reports no financial conflicts of interest. Vivian Laquer conducts research for Abbvie, Acelyrin, Acrotech, Amgen, Argenx, Arcutis, Aslan, Biofrontera, Bristol Meyers Squibb, Cara, Dermavant, Eli Lilly and Company, Galderma, Horizon Therapeutics, Incyte, Janssen, Leo, Novartis, Padagis, Pfizer, Q32, Rapt, Sun, UCB, and Ventyx. Pearl Kwong is a principal investigator for Eli Lilly and Company, Pfizer, Dermavant, Incyte, Arcutis, Galderma, Novartis, Abbvie, CastleCreek Biosciences, Amgen, and UCB; a consultant/advisor for Leo, Galderma, Pfizer, Eli Lilly and Company, Incyte, EPI Health, Novan, Verrica, BMS, Sanofi-Regeneron, UCB, and Ortho; and a speaker for Abbvie, Regeneron Sanofi, Incyte, Verrica, Sun Pharma, Ortho, L&#x2019;Or&#xe9;al, EPI, and Arcutis. Amber Reck Atwater is a former employee of Eli Lilly and Company. Jennifer Proper, Evangeline Pierce, Christopher Schuster, Maria Silk, Sreekumar Pillai, and Maria Jose Rueda are employees and shareholders of Eli Lilly and Company. Angela Moore has received research grants or honoraria from Abbvie, Acrotech, Arcutis, Bristol Meyers Squibb, Cara, Eli Lilly and Company, Galderma, Incyte, Janssen J&amp;J, Pfizer, Rapt, and Sanofi-Regeneron. Authors&#x2019; Contribution: A. Alexis has contributed to conception of the study and interpretation of the data. A. Moiin has contributed to conception of the work. A. Moore, J. Waibel, and P. Wallace have contributed to acquisition and interpretation of data. D. Cohen and V. Laquer have contributed to acquisition of data. P. Kwong has contributed to interpretation of data. A. Atwater, M. Silk, E. Pierce, S. Pillai, and M.J. Rueda have contributed to study conception, design, analysis, and data interpretation. J. Proper has contributed to study analysis and interpretation. C. Schuster has contributed to data interpretation. All authors contributed to the drafting or critical review of the manuscript and give final approval of the manuscript. Prior Meeting Presentation: Initial baseline characteristics were presented at Maui Derm for Dermatologists, 22 January 2024, Maui, USA. An interim analysis of the results was presented at the American Academy of Dermatology Annual Meeting, 10 March 2024, San Diego, USA. Primary results were presented at the Fall Clinical Dermatology Conference, 24 October 2024, Las Vegas, USA. The 24-week results were presented at the Revolutionizing Atopic Dermatitis (RAD) Conference 2025, June 7, 2025, Nashville, USA. Data Availability: Lilly provides access to all individual participant data collected during the trial, after anonymization, with the exception of pharmacokinetic or genetic data. Data are available to request 6 months after the indication studied has been approved in the US and EU and after primary publication acceptance, whichever is later. No expiration date of data requests is currently set once data are made available. Access is provided after a proposal has been approved by an independent review committee identified for this purpose and after receipt of a signed data sharing agreement. Data and documents, including the study protocol, statistical analysis plan, clinical study report, and blank or annotated case report forms will be provided in a secure data sharing environment. For details on submitting a request, see the instructions provided at www.vivli.org . Code Availability: Not applicable.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>36</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40665146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12436573</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-025-00970-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40257-025-00970-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Langan SM, Irvine AD, Weidinger S. Atopic dermatitis. Lancet. 2020;396:345&#x2013;60. 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31286-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31286-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32738956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim J, Kim BE, Leung DYM. Pathophysiology of atopic dermatitis: clinical implications. Allergy Asthma Proc. 2019;40:84&#x2013;92. 10.2500/aap.2019.40.4202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2500/aap.2019.40.4202</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6399565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30819278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rerknimitr P, Otsuka A, Nakashima C, et al. The etiopathogenesis of atopic dermatitis: barrier disruption, immunological derangement, and pruritus. Inflamm Regen. 2017;37:14. 10.1186/s41232-017-0044-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41232-017-0044-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5725646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29259713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quan VL, Erickson T, Daftary K, et al. Atopic dermatitis across shades of skin. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2023;24(5):731&#x2013;51. 10.1007/s40257-023-00797-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40257-023-00797-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37336869</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg JI. Racial and ethnic disparities in atopic dermatitis. Curr Dermatol Rep. 2015;4(1):44&#x2013;8. 10.1007/s13671-014-0097-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13671-014-0097-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Czarnowicki T, He H, Krueger JG, et al. Atopic dermatitis endotypes and implications for targeted therapeutics. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2019;143(1):1&#x2013;11. 10.1016/j.jaci.2018.10.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2018.10.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30612663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexis A, Woolery-Lloyd H, Andriessen A, et al. Insights in skin of color patients with atopic dermatitis and the role of skincare in improving outcomes. J Drugs Dermatol. 2022;21(5):462&#x2013;70. 10.36849/jdd.6609.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36849/jdd.6609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35533036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Price KN, Hsiao JL, Shi VY. Race and ethnicity gaps in global hidradenitis suppurativa clinical trials. Dermatology. 2021;237(1):97&#x2013;102. 10.1159/000504911.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000504911</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31865334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen V, Akhtar S, Zheng C, et al. Assessment of changes in diversity in dermatology clinical trials between 2010&#x2013;2015 and 2015&#x2013;2020: a systematic review. JAMA Dermatol. 2022;158(3):288&#x2013;92. 10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.5596.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2021.5596</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8792791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35080592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Croce EA, Levy ML, Adamson AS, et al. Reframing racial and ethnic disparities in atopic dermatitis in Black and Latinx populations. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2021;148(5):1104&#x2013;11. 10.1016/j.jaci.2021.09.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaci.2021.09.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8578465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34600773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunner PM, Guttman-Yassky E. Racial differences in atopic dermatitis. Ann Allergy Asthma Immunol. 2019;122(5):449&#x2013;55. 10.1016/j.anai.2018.11.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anai.2018.11.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30465859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gottlieb S, Madkins K, Lio P. An Updated Scoping Review of Disparities in Pediatric Atopic Dermatitis. Pediatr Dermatol. 2025. 10.1111/pde.15914. (<b>Epub ahead of print. PMID: 40166858</b>).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pde.15914</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12118532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40166858</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebede T, Papier A. Disparities in dermatology educational resources. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2006;55(4):687&#x2013;90. 10.1016/j.jaad.2005.10.068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2005.10.068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17010750</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adelekun A, Onyekaba G, Lipoff JB. Skin color in dermatology textbooks: an updated evaluation and analysis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2021;84(1):194&#x2013;6. 10.1016/j.jaad.2020.04.084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.04.084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32335181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibraheim MK, Gupta R, Dao H, et al. Evaluating skin of color education in dermatology residency programs: data from a national survey. Clin Dermatol. 2022;40(2):228&#x2013;33. 10.1016/j.clindermatol.2021.11.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clindermatol.2021.11.015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34838657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kurtti A, Austin E, Jagdeo J. Representation of skin color in dermatology-related Google image searches. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2022;86(3):705&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.jaad.2021.03.036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2021.03.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33744357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao CY, Wijayanti A, Doria MC, et al. The reliability and validity of outcome measures for atopic dermatitis in patients with pigmented skin: a grey area. Int J Womens Dermatol. 2015;1(3):150&#x2013;4. 10.1016/j.ijwd.2015.05.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijwd.2015.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5418878</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28491979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silverberg JI, Guttman-Yassky E, Tha&#xe7;i D, et al. Two phase 3 trials of lebrikizumab for moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis. N Engl J Med. 2023;388(12):1080&#x2013;91. 10.1056/NEJMoa2206714.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2206714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36920778</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blauvelt A, Thyssen JP, Guttman-Yassky E, et al. Efficacy and safety of lebrikizumab in moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: 52-week results of two randomized double-blinded placebo-controlled phase III trials. Br J Dermatol. 2023;188(6):740&#x2013;8. 10.1093/bjd/ljad022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjd/ljad022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36994947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexis A, Ardern-Jones M, Chovatiya R, et al. Lebrikizumab demonstrates significant efficacy versus placebo across racial and ethnic subgroups in patients with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis. Br J Dermatol. 2024;190(Suppl 2):ii20&#x2013;1. 10.1093/bjd/ljad498.024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjd/ljad498.024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eichenfield LF, Tom WL, Chamlin SL, et al. Guidelines of care for the management of atopic dermatitis: diagnosis and assessment of atopic dermatitis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2014;70(2):338&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.jaad.2013.10.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2013.10.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4410183</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24290431</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki. ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA. 2013;310(20):2191&#x2013;4. 10.1001/jama.2013.281053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.281053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexis A, Pierce E, Cohee A, et al. Assessing post-inflammatory pigmentation in atopic dermatitis: reliability of the PDCA-Derm&#x2122;. J Skin. 2025;9(1):s514. 10.25251/skin.9.supp.514.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.25251/skin.9.supp.514</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stalder JF, Barbarot S, Wollenberg A, et al. Patient-Oriented SCORAD (PO-SCORAD): a new self-assessment scale in atopic dermatitis validated in Europe. Allergy. 2011;66(8):1114&#x2013;21. 10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02577.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1398-9995.2011.02577.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21414011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faye O, Meledie N&#x2019;Djong AP, Diadie S, et al. Validation of the Patient-Oriented SCORing for Atopic Dermatitis tool for black skin. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2020;34(4):795&#x2013;9. 10.1111/jdv.15999.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.15999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7154547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis DMR, Drucker AM, Alikhan A, et al. Executive summary: Guidelines of care for the management of atopic dermatitis in adults with phototherapy and systemic therapies. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2024;90(2):342&#x2013;5. 10.1016/j.jaad.2023.08.103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2023.08.103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37943241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narla S, Heath CR, Alexis A, et al. Racial disparities in dermatology. Arch Dermatol Res. 2023;315(5):1215&#x2013;23. 10.1007/s00403-022-02507-z. (<b>Ref #8 in this: Bureau UC. Projections of the size and composition of the U.S. population. In: Bureau UC, ed2015</b>).
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00403-022-02507-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9743121</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36508020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexis AF, Rendon M, Silverberg JI, et al. Efficacy of Dupilumab in Different Racial Subgroups of Adults With Moderate-to-Severe Atopic Dermatitis in Three Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Phase 3 Trials. J Drugs Dermatol. 2019;18(8):804&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31424712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson EL, Gooderham M, Wollenberg A, et al. Efficacy and safety of lebrikizumab in combination with topical corticosteroids in adolescents and adults with moderate-to-severe atopic dermatitis: a randomized clinical trial (ADhere). JAMA Dermatol. 2023;159(2):182&#x2013;91. 10.1001/jamadermatol.2022.5534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamadermatol.2022.5534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9857439</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36630140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaowattanapanit S, Silpa-Archa N, Kohli I, et al. Postinflammatory hyperpigmentation: a comprehensive overview: Treatment options and prevention. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;77(4):607&#x2013;21. 10.1016/j.jaad.2017.01.036.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.01.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28917452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alexis AF, Sergay AB, Taylor SC. Common dermatologic disorders in skin of color: a comparative practice survey. Cutis. 2007;80(5):387&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18189024</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maymone MBC, Neamah HH, Wirya SA, et al. The impact of skin hyperpigmentation and hyperchromia on quality of life: a cross-sectional study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;77(4):775&#x2013;8. 10.1016/j.jaad.2017.05.009.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.05.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28917465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor S, Grimes P, Lim J, et al. Postinflammatory hyperpigmentation. J Cutan Med Surg. 2009;13(4):183&#x2013;91. 10.2310/7750.2009.08077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2310/7750.2009.08077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19706225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mar K, Maazi M, Khalid B, et al. Prevention of post-inflammatory hyperpigmentation in skin of colour: a systematic review. Australas J Dermatol. 2025;66(3):119&#x2013;26. 10.1111/ajd.14432.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajd.14432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12062726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39953770</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markiewicz E, Karaman-Jurukovska N, Mammone T, et al. Post-inflammatory hyperpigmentation in dark skin: molecular mechanism and skincare implications. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2022;15:2555&#x2013;65. 10.2147/CCID.S385162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CCID.S385162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9709857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36466945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papa CM, Kligman AM. The behavior of melanocytes in inflammation. J Invest Dermatol. 1965;45(6):465&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/jid.1965.160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5847001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grayson C, Heath CR. Dupilumab Improves Atopic Dermatitis and Post-Inflammatory Hyperpigmentation in Patient With Skin of Color. J Drugs Dermatol. 2020;19(7):776&#x2013;8. 10.36849/JDD.2020.4937.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36849/JDD.2020.4937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32726553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn HJ, Shin MK. Improvement of Nonlesional Skin Tone and Skin Barrier in Severe Atopic Dermatitis after Dupilumab Treatment. Dermatol Ther. 2023;2023:6218587. 10.1155/2023/6218587.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2023/6218587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartford C, Alexis A, Wang Z, et al. Development of novel patient-reported outcome instruments to assess atopic dermatitis-associated dyspigmentation and xerosis in patients with skin of colour. Br J Dermatol. 2025;192(5):863&#x2013;73. 10.1093/bjd/ljae494.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bjd/ljae494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39792566</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgenstern M, Sargent JD, Hanewinkel R. Relation between socioeconomic status and body mass index: evidence of an indirect path via television use. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med. 2009;163(8):731&#x2013;8. 10.1001/archpediatrics.2009.78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpediatrics.2009.78</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3719170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19652105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anekwe CV, Jarrell AR, Townsend MJ, et al. Socioeconomics of obesity. Curr Obes Rep. 2020;9(3):272&#x2013;9. 10.1007/s13679-020-00398-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13679-020-00398-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7484407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32627133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware OR, Dawson JE, Shinohara MM, et al. Racial limitations of fitzpatrick skin type. Cutis. 2020;105(2):77&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32186531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dadzie OE, Sturm RA, Fajuyigbe D, et al. The Eumelanin Human Skin Colour Scale: a proof-of-concept study. Br J Dermatol. 2022;187(1):99&#x2013;104. 10.1111/bjd.21277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.21277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35349165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben-Gashir MA, Hay RJ. Reliance on erythema scores may mask severe atopic dermatitis in black children compared with their white counterparts. Br J Dermatol. 2002;147(5):920&#x2013;5. 10.1046/j.1365-2133.2002.04965.x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1365-2133.2002.04965.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12410701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>