<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36583934</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>16</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2368-7959</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR mental health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Ment Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Patient and Therapist Expectations for a Blended Cognitive Behavioral Therapy Program for Depression: Qualitative Exploratory Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e36806</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e36806</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e36806</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/36806</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Blended cognitive behavioral therapy (bCBT)-the combination of digital elements and face-to-face psychotherapy-has been proposed to alleviate challenges that patients and therapists face in conventional cognitive behavioral therapy. There is growing evidence that adding digital elements to face-to-face psychotherapy can contribute to better treatment outcomes. However, bCBT programs still show considerable shortcomings, and knowledge on how to improve digital apps using a bCBT protocol is limited.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to inductively identify functions and qualities that are expected from a bCBT treatment for depression in the eyes of patients and psychotherapists who were not currently receiving or practicing bCBT treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We used a qualitative exploratory study design and conducted 3 focus group interviews (n=6 in each) and 5 semistructured in-depth interviews with therapists as well as 11 individual interviews with patients with a primary diagnosis of depression and currently undergoing cognitive behavioral therapy treatment in Germany. Themes and categories were established inductively from transcribed interview records based on a rigorous coding method.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Both therapists and patients expected a digital app to provide patients with the opportunity to track their mood, work on therapeutic homework activities, easily access an intervention set for harder moments, and efficiently facilitate administrative tasks. The desire to be able to customize bCBT protocols to individual patient circumstances was evident in both patient and therapist interviews. Patients differed with respect to what content and the amount of material the app should focus on as well as the method of recording experiences. Therapists viewed digital apps as potentially aiding in their documentation work outside of sessions. Different attitudes surfaced on the topic of data security, with patients not as concerned as therapists.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Both patients and therapists had substantially positive attitudes toward the option of an integrated bCBT treatment. Our study presents novel findings on the expectations and attitudes of patients and therapists.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Ece Atik, Magnus Sch&#xfc;ckes, Jennifer Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen. Originally published in JMIR Mental Health (https://mental.jmir.org), 30.12.2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atik</LastName><ForeName>Ece</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1361-6301</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sch&#xfc;ckes</LastName><ForeName>Magnus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3059-0673</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for SME Research and Entrepreneurship, University of Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5755-9225</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Occupational, Social and Environmental Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Centre for Health and Society, Heinrich Heine University Dusseldorf, Dusseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Ment Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101658926</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2368-7959</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bCBT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blended cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">blended psychotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">internet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile app</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile phone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">user perspectives</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: EA worked as a part-time researcher for Elona Health, which aims to develop digital health apps in the field of mental health care, during the time when this study was conducted and reported. MS is a shareholder of Elona Health. JAH declares no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36583934</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/36806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v9i12e36806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Richards D. Prevalence and clinical course of depression: a review. Clin Psychol Rev. 2011 Nov;31(7):1117&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2011.07.004.S0272-7358(11)00112-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2011.07.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21820991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillham JE, Shatt&#xe9; AJ, Freres DR. Preventing depression: a review of cognitive-behavioral and family interventions. Appl Prev Psychol. 2000 Mar;9(2):63&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1016/s0962-1849(00)80007-4. doi: 10.1016/s0962-1849(00)80007-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0962-1849(00)80007-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Judd LL. The clinical course of unipolar major depressive disorders. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1997 Nov;54(11):989&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.1997.01830230015002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.1997.01830230015002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9366654</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;nig H, K&#xf6;nig HH, Konnopka A. The excess costs of depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2019 Apr 05;29:e30. doi: 10.1017/S2045796019000180. 
 
S2045796019000180</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S2045796019000180</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8061284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30947759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Cristea IA, Karyotaki E, Reijnders M, Huibers MJ. How effective are cognitive behavior therapies for major depression and anxiety disorders? A meta-analytic update of the evidence. World Psychiatry. 2016 Oct;15(3):245&#x2013;58. doi: 10.1002/wps.20346. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20346</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5032489</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27717254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haby MM, Donnelly M, Corry J, Vos T. Cognitive behavioural therapy for depression, panic disorder and generalized anxiety disorder: a meta-regression of factors that may predict outcome. Aust N Z J Psychiatry. 2006 Jan;40(1):9&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1080/j.1440-1614.2006.01736.x.ANP1736</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/j.1440-1614.2006.01736.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16403033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofmann SG, Asnaani A, Vonk IJ, Sawyer AT, Fang A. Erratum to: the efficacy of cognitive behavioral therapy: a review of meta-analyses. Cogn Ther Res. 2014 Jan 8;38(3):368. doi: 10.1007/s10608-013-9595-3. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10608-013-9595-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3584580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23459093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tolin DF. Is cognitive-behavioral therapy more effective than other therapies? A meta-analytic review. Clin Psychol Rev. 2010 Aug;30(6):710&#x2013;20. doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2010.05.003.S0272-7358(10)00089-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2010.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20547435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns DD, Nolen-Hoeksema S. Coping styles, homework compliance, and the effectiveness of cognitive-behavioral therapy. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1991 Apr;59(2):305&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1037//0022-006x.59.2.305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0022-006x.59.2.305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2030192</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haynes RB, McDonald HP, Garg AX. Helping patients follow prescribed treatment: clinical applications. JAMA. 2002 Dec 11;288(22):2880&#x2013;3. doi: 10.1001/jama.288.22.2880.jsr20017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.288.22.2880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12472330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazantzis N, Lampropoulos GK. Reflecting on homework in psychotherapy: what can we conclude from research and experience? J Clin Psychol. 2002 May;58(5):577&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1002/jclp.10034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.10034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11967882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helbig S, Fehm L. Problems with homework in CBT: rare exception or rather frequent? Behav Cogn Psychother. 2004 Jun 14;32(3):291&#x2013;301. doi: 10.1017/s1352465804001365. doi: 10.1017/s1352465804001365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s1352465804001365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns DD, Spangler DL. Does psychotherapy homework lead to improvements in depression in cognitive-behavioral therapy or does improvement lead to increased homework compliance? J Consult Clin Psychol. 2000 Feb;68(1):46&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1037//0022-006x.68.1.46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037//0022-006x.68.1.46</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10710839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazantzis N, Deane FP, Ronan KR. Homework assignments in cognitive and behavioral therapy: a meta-analysis. Clin Psychol Sci Pract. 2000 Jun;7(2):189&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1093/clipsy.7.2.189. doi: 10.1093/clipsy.7.2.189.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/clipsy.7.2.189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazantzis N, Deane FP, Ronan KR. Assessing compliance with homework assignments: review and recommendations for clinical practice. J Clin Psychol. 2004 Jun;60(6):627&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1002/jclp.10239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.10239</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15141396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazantzis N, Whittington C, Zelencich L, Kyrios M, Norton PJ, Hofmann SG. Quantity and quality of homework compliance: a meta-analysis of relations with outcome in cognitive behavior therapy. Behav Ther. 2016 Sep;47(5):755&#x2013;72. doi: 10.1016/j.beth.2016.05.002.S0005-7894(16)30029-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beth.2016.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27816086</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojnarowski C, Firth N, Finegan M, Delgadillo J. Predictors of depression relapse and recurrence after cognitive behavioural therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Behav Cogn Psychother. 2019 Sep;47(5):514&#x2013;29. doi: 10.1017/S1352465819000080.S1352465819000080</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1352465819000080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30894231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbe D, Eichert H, Riper H, Ebert DD. Blending face-to-face and internet-based interventions for the treatment of mental disorders in adults: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2017 Sep 15;19(9):e306. doi: 10.2196/jmir.6588. 
 
v19i9e306</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright JH, Mishkind M, Eells TD, Chan SR. Computer-assisted cognitive-behavior therapy and mobile apps for depression and anxiety. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2019 Jun 27;21(7):62. doi: 10.1007/s11920-019-1031-2.10.1007/s11920-019-1031-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11920-019-1031-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31250242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Kleiboer A, Karyotaki E, Riper H. Internet and mobile interventions for depression: opportunities and challenges. Depress Anxiety. 2017 Jul;34(7):596&#x2013;602. doi: 10.1002/da.22641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28471479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenter RM, van de Ven PM, Cuijpers P, Koole G, Niamat S, Gerrits RS, Willems M, van Straten A. Costs and effects of Internet cognitive behavioral treatment blended with face-to-face treatment: results from a naturalistic study. Internet Interv. 2015 Mar;2(1):77&#x2013;83. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2015.01.001. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2015.01.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2015.01.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang W, Kreindler D. Supporting homework compliance in cognitive behavioural therapy: essential features of mobile apps. JMIR Ment Health. 2017 Jun 08;4(2):e20. doi: 10.2196/mental.5283. 
 
v4i2e20</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mental.5283</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5481663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacmon J, Malouff JM, Taylor N. Treatment of major depression: effectiveness of cognitive-behavioural therapy with an internet course as a central component. E J Appl Psychol. 2009 Jan 03;5(2):1&#x2013;8. doi: 10.7790/ejap.v5i2.153. doi: 10.7790/ejap.v5i2.153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7790/ejap.v5i2.153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooistra LC, Wiersma JE, Ruwaard J, Neijenhuijs K, Lokkerbol J, van Oppen P, Smit F, Riper H. Cost and effectiveness of blended versus standard cognitive behavioral therapy for outpatients with depression in routine specialized mental health care: pilot randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2019 Oct 29;21(10):e14261. doi: 10.2196/14261. 
 
v21i10e14261</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6914243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31663855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster R, Laireiter AR, Berger T, Moritz S, Meyer B, Hohagen F, Klein JP. Immediate and long-term effectiveness of adding an Internet intervention for depression to routine outpatient psychotherapy: subgroup analysis of the EVIDENT trial. J Affect Disord. 2020 Sep 01;274:643&#x2013;51. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2020.05.122.S0165-0327(19)33632-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2020.05.122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wentzel J, van der Vaart R, Bohlmeijer ET, van Gemert-Pijnen JE. Mixing online and face-to-face therapy: how to benefit from blended care in mental health care. JMIR Ment Health. 2016 Feb 09;3(1):e9. doi: 10.2196/mental.4534. 
 
v3i1e9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mental.4534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4764785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26860537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haug T, Nordgreen T, &#xd6;st LG, Kvale G, Tangen T, Andersson G, Carlbring P, Heiervang ER, Havik OE. Stepped care versus face-to-face cognitive behavior therapy for panic disorder and social anxiety disorder: predictors and moderators of outcome. Behav Res Ther. 2015 Aug;71:76&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2015.06.002.S0005-7967(15)00101-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2015.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26081010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein AA, Slaymaker VJ, Dugosh KL, McKay JR. Computerized continuing care support for alcohol and drug dependence: a preliminary analysis of usage and outcomes. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2012 Jan;42(1):25&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2011.07.002.S0740-5472(11)00130-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2011.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6498848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Krieger T, Sude K, Meyer B, Maercker A. Evaluating an e-mental health program ("deprexis") as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J Affect Disord. 2018 Feb;227:455&#x2013;62. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021.S0165-0327(17)31255-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe5;nsson KN, Skagius Ruiz E, Gervind E, Dahlin M, Andersson G. Development and initial evaluation of an Internet-based support system for face-to-face cognitive behavior therapy: a proof of concept study. J Med Internet Res. 2013 Dec 10;15(12):e280. doi: 10.2196/jmir.3031. 
 
v15i12e280</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3868964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24326065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Paganini S, Sander LB, Lin J, Schlicker S, Terhorst Y, Moshagen M, Bengel J, Lehr D, Ebert DD. Effectiveness of a guided Internet- and mobile-based intervention for patients with chronic back pain and depression (WARD-BP): a multicenter, pragmatic randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2021;90(4):255&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1159/000511881.000511881</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000511881</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33321501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Berger T, Schr&#xf6;der J, Sp&#xe4;th C, Meyer B, Caspar F, Lutz W, Arndt A, Greiner W, Gr&#xe4;fe V, Hautzinger M, Fuhr K, Rose M, Nolte S, L&#xf6;we B, Anderssoni G, Vettorazzi E, Moritz S, Hohagen F. Effects of a psychological internet intervention in the treatment of mild to moderate depressive symptoms: results of the EVIDENT study, a randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2016;85(4):218&#x2013;28. doi: 10.1159/000445355. 
 
000445355</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000445355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thase ME, Wright JH, Eells TD, Barrett MS, Wisniewski SR, Balasubramani GK, McCrone P, Brown GK. Improving the efficiency of psychotherapy for depression: computer-assisted versus standard CBT. Am J Psychiatry. 2018 Mar 01;175(3):242&#x2013;50. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2017.17010089. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2017.17010089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5848497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28969439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly KH, Topooco N, Cederlund H, Wallin A, Bergstr&#xf6;m J, Molander O, Carlbring P, Andersson G. Smartphone-supported versus full behavioural activation for depression: a randomised controlled trial. PLoS One. 2015 May 26;10(5):e0126559. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0126559. 
 
PONE-D-14-40400</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0126559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4444307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26010890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez JC, Fern&#xe1;ndez O, C&#xe1;ceres C, Carrasco &#xc1;E, Moessner M, Bauer S, Espinosa-Duque D, Gloger S, Krause M. An adjunctive internet-based intervention to enhance treatment for depression in adults: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Ment Health. 2021 Dec 16;8(12):e26814. doi: 10.2196/26814. 
 
v8i12e26814</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/26814</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8726028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34927594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasing SP, Stikkelbroek YA, den Hollander W, Riper H, Dekovi&#x107; M, Nauta MH, Creemers DH, Immink MC, Spuij M, Bodden DH. Pragmatic quasi-experimental controlled trial evaluating the outcomes of blended CBT compared to face-to-face CBT and treatment as usual for adolescents with depressive disorders. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021 Mar 17;18(6):3102. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18063102. 
 
ijerph18063102</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18063102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8002752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33802913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thase ME, McCrone P, Barrett MS, Eells TD, Wisniewski SR, Balasubramani GK, Brown GK, Wright JH. Improving cost-effectiveness and access to cognitive behavior therapy for depression: providing remote-ready, computer-assisted psychotherapy in times of crisis and beyond. Psychother Psychosom. 2020;89(5):307&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1159/000508143. 
 
000508143</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000508143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7483890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32396917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langergaard A, Mathiasen K, S&#xf8;ndergaard J, S&#xf8;rensen SS, Laursen SL, Xylander AA, Lichtenstein MB, Ehlers LH. Economic evaluation alongside a randomized controlled trial of blended cognitive-behavioral therapy for patients suffering from major depressive disorder. Internet Interv. 2022 Apr;28:100513. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2022.100513. 
 
S2214-7829(22)00020-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2022.100513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8886051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35242594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etzelmueller A, Radkovsky A, Hannig W, Berking M, Ebert DD. Patient's experience with blended video- and internet based cognitive behavioural therapy service in routine care. Internet Interv. 2018 Jun;12:165&#x2013;75. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.003. 
 
S2214-7829(17)30089-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096318</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooistra LC, Ruwaard J, Wiersma JE, van Oppen P, van der Vaart R, van Gemert-Pijnen JE, Riper H. Development and initial evaluation of blended cognitive behavioural treatment for major depression in routine specialized mental health care. Internet Interv. 2016 May;4:61&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2016.01.003. 
 
S2214-7829(16)00003-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2016.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titzler I, Saruhanjan K, Berking M, Riper H, Ebert DD. Barriers and facilitators for the implementation of blended psychotherapy for depression: a qualitative pilot study of therapists' perspective. Internet Interv. 2018 Jun;12:150&#x2013;64. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.002. 
 
S2214-7829(17)30090-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gumz A, Boettcher J. Digitale interventionen in der Psychotherapie. Psychotherapeut. 2021 Aug 30;66(5):369&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1007/s00278-021-00531-4. doi: 10.1007/s00278-021-00531-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00278-021-00531-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stoff-Ahnis S. Digitale gesundheitsanwendungen &#x2013; das erste jahr aus sicht der gesetzlichen krankenversicherung. MedR. 2022 Apr 12;40(4):285&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1007/s00350-022-6161-6. doi: 10.1007/s00350-022-6161-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00350-022-6161-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kitzinger J. Qualitative research. Introducing focus groups. BMJ. 1995 Jul 29;311(7000):299&#x2013;302. doi: 10.1136/bmj.311.7000.299. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.311.7000.299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2550365</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7633241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malagon-Maldonado G. Qualitative research in health design. HERD. 2014;7(4):120&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1177/193758671400700411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/193758671400700411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25303432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun Tie Y, Birks M, Francis K. Grounded theory research: a design framework for novice researchers. SAGE Open Med. 2019 Jan 2;7:2050312118822927. doi: 10.1177/2050312118822927. 
 
10.1177_2050312118822927</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2050312118822927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6318722</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30637106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corbin J, Strauss A. Basics of Qualitative Research: Techniques and Procedures for Developing Grounded Theory. 4th edition. Thousand Oaks, CA, USA: Sage Publications; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glaser BG, Strauss AL. Discovery of Grounded Theory: Strategies for Qualitative Research. Chicago, IL, USA: Aldine Publishing Company; 1967.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care. 2007 Dec;19(6):349&#x2013;57. doi: 10.1093/intqhc/mzm042.mzm042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzm042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Vaart R, Witting M, Riper H, Kooistra L, Bohlmeijer ET, van Gemert-Pijnen LJ. Blending online therapy into regular face-to-face therapy for depression: content, ratio and preconditions according to patients and therapists using a Delphi study. BMC Psychiatry. 2014 Dec 14;14:355. doi: 10.1186/s12888-014-0355-z. 
 
s12888-014-0355-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-014-0355-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4271498</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25496393</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerga-Pashoja A, Doukani A, Gega L, Walke J, Araya R. Added value or added burden? A qualitative investigation of blending internet self-help with face-to-face cognitive behaviour therapy for depression. Psychother Res. 2020 Nov;30(8):998&#x2013;1010. doi: 10.1080/10503307.2020.1720932.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10503307.2020.1720932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32024447</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster R, Topooco N, Keller A, Radvogin E, Laireiter AR. Advantages and disadvantages of online and blended therapy: replication and extension of findings on psychotherapists' appraisals. Internet Interv. 2020 Sep;21:100326. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2020.100326. 
 
S2214-7829(20)30015-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2020.100326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7251770</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32477885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beattie A, Shaw A, Kaur S, Kessler D. Primary-care patients' expectations and experiences of online cognitive behavioural therapy for depression: a qualitative study. Health Expect. 2009 Mar;12(1):45&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1111/j.1369-7625.2008.00531.x. 
 
HEX531</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1369-7625.2008.00531.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5060477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19250152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bendelin N, Hesser H, Dahl J, Carlbring P, Nelson KZ, Andersson G. Experiences of guided internet-based cognitive-behavioural treatment for depression: a qualitative study. BMC Psychiatry. 2011 Jun 30;11:107. doi: 10.1186/1471-244X-11-107. 
 
1471-244X-11-107</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-244X-11-107</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3142491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21718523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert MJ, Barley DE. Research summary on the therapeutic relationship and psychotherapy outcome. Psychother Theory Res Pract Train. 2001;38(4):357&#x2013;61. doi: 10.1037/0033-3204.38.4.357. doi: 10.1037/0033-3204.38.4.357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-3204.38.4.357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leach MJ. Rapport: a key to treatment success. Complement Ther Clin Pract. 2005 Nov;11(4):262&#x2013;5. doi: 10.1016/j.ctcp.2005.05.005.S1744-3881(05)00071-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctcp.2005.05.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16290897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marziali E, Alexander L. The power of the therapeutic relationship. Am J Orthopsychiatry. 1991 Jul;61(3):383&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1037/h0079268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0079268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1951645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Meyer B, Lutz W, Hautzinger M, Sp&#xe4;th C, Eichenberg C, Klein JP, Moritz S. Attitudes towards internet interventions among psychotherapists and individuals with mild to moderate depression symptoms. Cogn Ther Res. 2017 Apr 22;41(5):745&#x2013;56. doi: 10.1007/s10608-017-9850-0. doi: 10.1007/s10608-017-9850-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10608-017-9850-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster R, Pokorny R, Berger T, Topooco N, Laireiter AR. The advantages and disadvantages of online and blended therapy: survey study amongst licensed psychotherapists in Austria. J Med Internet Res. 2018 Dec 18;20(12):e11007. doi: 10.2196/11007. 
 
v20i12e11007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6315274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>