<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">25722504</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">0253-7176</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>37</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2015</Year><Season>Jan-Mar</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Indian journal of psychological medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Indian J Psychol Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Insight in schizophrenia: relationship to positive, negative and neurocognitive dimensions.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>5</StartPage><EndPage>11</EndPage><MedlinePgn>5-11</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/0253-7176.150797</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Impairment of insight is considered as the hallmark of schizophrenia. Substantial proportion of patients with schizophrenia has either poor or absent insight. Insight is a multidimensional and dynamic construct which appears to have intricate links with other symptom dimensions of the psychotic illness. A better appreciation of the association that insight shares with other symptom clusters in psychosis could help us in gaining knowledge about aetiology, prognosis and treatment-related facets of the disorder. This is likely to have critical implications in the understanding and therapeutics of schizophrenia.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Joseph</LastName><ForeName>Boban</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatric Social Work, Schizophrenia Clinic, Translational Psychiatry Laboratory, Bangalore, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Narayanaswamy</LastName><ForeName>Janardhanan C</ForeName><Initials>JC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences, Bangalore, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venkatasubramanian</LastName><ForeName>Ganesan</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, National Institute of Mental Health and Neurosciences, Bangalore, Karnataka, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Indian J Psychol Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7910727</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0253-7176</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insight</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">negative symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurocognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">positive symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">schizophrenia</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest:</b> None.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2015</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25722504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4341311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0253-7176.150797</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">IJPsyM-37-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Amador XS, editor. 2nd ed. New York: Oxford; 2004. Awareness of Illness in Schizophrenia and Related Disorders.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>David AS. Insight and psychosis. Br J Psychiatry. 1990;156:798&#x2013;808.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2207510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young DA, Davila R, Scher H. Unawareness of illness and neuropsychological performance in chronic schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 1993;10:117&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8398943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenfeld D, Strauss JS, Bowers MB, Mandelkern M. Insight and interpretation of illness in recovery from psychosis. Schizophr Bull. 1989;15:245&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2749187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter WT, Jr, Strauss JS, Bartko JJ. Flexible system for the diagnosis of schizophrenia: Report from the WHO International Pilot Study of Schizophrenia. Science. 1973;182:1275&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4752222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartko G, Herczeg I, Zador G. Clinical symptomatology and drug compliance in schizophrenic patients. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1988;77:74&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2894746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>David A, van Os J, Jones P, Harvey I, Foerster A, Fahy T. Insight and psychotic illness. Cross-sectional and longitudinal associations. Br J Psychiatry. 1995;167:621&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8564318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pyne JM, Bean D, Sullivan G. Characteristics of patients with schizophrenia who do not believe they are mentally ill. J Nerv Ment Dis. 2001;189:146&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11277350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pijnenborg GH, van Donkersgoed RJ, David AS, Aleman A. Changes in insight during treatment for psychotic disorders: A meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2013;144:109&#x2013;17.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23305612</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baier M. Insight in schizophrenia: A review. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2010;12:356&#x2013;61.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20526897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amador XF, Strauss DH. New York: Columbia University and New York State Psychiatric Institute; 1990. The Scale to Assess Unawareness of Mental Disorder (SUMD)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Baruch E, Balter JM, Steer RA, Warman DM. A new instrument for measuring insight: The Beck Cognitive Insight Scale. Schizophr Res. 2004;68:319&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15099613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McGorry PD, McConville SB. Insight in psychosis: An elusive target. Compr Psychiatry. 1999;40:131&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10080260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markova IS, Berrios GE. Insight in clinical psychiatry. A new model. J Nerv Ment Dis. 1995;183:743&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8522935</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osatuke K, Ciesla J, Kasckow JW, Zisook S, Mohamed S. Insight in schizophrenia: A review of etiological models and supporting research. Compr Psychiatry. 2008;49:70&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18063044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan B, Jacob KS, Johnson S, Prince M, Bhugra D, David AS. Belief models in first episode schizophrenia in South India. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2007;42:446&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17502975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan B, Jacob KS, Johnson S, Prince M, Bhugra D, David AS. Assessing insight in schizophrenia: East meets West. Br J Psychiatry. 2007;190:243&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17329745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saravanan B, David A, Bhugra D, Prince M, Jacob KS. Insight in people with psychosis: The influence of culture. Int Rev Psychiatry. 2005;17:83&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16194776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shad MU, Muddasani S, Keshavan MS. Prefrontal subregions and dimensions of insight in first-episode schizophrenia--a pilot study. Psychiatry Res. 2006;146:35&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16361089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Drake RJ, Lewis SW. Insight and neurocognition in schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2003;62:165&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12765757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siever LJ, Kalus OF, Keefe RS. The boundaries of schizophrenia. Psychiatr Clin North Am. 1993;16:217&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8332562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amador XF, Flaum M, Andreasen NC, Strauss DH, Yale SA, Clark SC, et al. Awareness of illness in schizophrenia and schizoaffective and mood disorders. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1994;51:826&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7944872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baier M, DeShay E, Owens K, Robinson M, Lasar K, Peterson K, et al. The relationship between insight and clinical factors for persons with schizophrenia. Arch Psychiatr Nurs. 2000;14:259&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11144413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collins AA, Remington GJ, Coulter K, Birkett K. Insight, neurocognitive function and symptom clusters in chronic schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 1997;27:37&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9373893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritsner MS, Blumenkrantz H. Predicting domain-specific insight of schizophrenia patients from symptomatology, multiple neurocognitive functions, and personality related traits. Psychiatry Res. 2007;149:59&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17137634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Hert MA, Simon V, Vidovic D, Franic T, Wampers M, Peuskens J, et al. Evaluation of the association between insight and symptoms in a large sample of patients with schizophrenia. Eur Psychiatry. 2009;24:507&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19540728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stefanopoulou E, Lafuente AR, Saez Fonseca JA, Huxley A. Insight, global functioning and psychopathology amongst in-patient clients with schizophrenia. Psychiatr Q. 2009;80:155&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19526340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuesta MJ, Peralta V, Zarzuela A. Psychopathological dimensions and lack of insight in schizophrenia. Psychol Rep. 1998;83(3 Pt 1):895&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9923164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mintz AR, Addington J, Addington D. Insight in early psychosis: A 1-year follow-up. Schizophr Res. 2004;67:213&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14984880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monteiro LC, Silva VA, Louza MR. Insight, cognitive dysfunction and symptomatology in schizophrenia. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2008;258:402&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18437275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon AE, Berger GE, Giacomini V, Ferrero F, Mohr S. Insight, symptoms and executive functions in schizophrenia. Cogn Neuropsychiatry. 2006;11:437&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17354080</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TE, Hull JW, Israel LM, Willson DF. Insight, symptoms, and neurocognition in schizophrenia and schizoaffective disorder. Schizophr Bull. 2000;26:193&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10755681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danki D, Dilbaz N, Okay IT, Telci S. Insight in schizophrenia: Relationship to family history, and positive and negative symptoms. Turk Psikiyatri Derg. 2007;18:129&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17566878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aleman A, Agrawal N, Morgan KD, David AS. Insight in psychosis and neuropsychological function: Meta-analysis. Br J Psychiatry. 2006;189:204&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16946354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Putten T, Crumpton E, Yale C. Drug refusal in schizophrenia and the wish to be crazy. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1976;33:1443&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">999448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mintz AR, Dobson KS, Romney DM. Insight in schizophrenia: A meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2003;61:75&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12648738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lincoln TM, Lullmann E, Rief W. Correlates and long-term consequences of poor insight in patients with schizophrenia. A systematic review. Schizophr Bull. 2007;33:1324&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2779879</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17289653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amador XF, Gorman JM. Psychopathologic domains and insight in schizophrenia. Psychiatr Clin North Am. 1998;21:27&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9551489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nieto L, Cobo J, Pousa E, Blas-Navarro J, Garcia-Pares G, Palao D, et al. Insight, symptomatic dimensions, and cognition in patients with acute-phase psychosis. Compr Psychiatry. 2012;53:502&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22036010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekinci O, Ekinci A. Association between insight, cognitive insight, positive symptoms and violence in patients with schizophrenia. Nord J Psychiatry. 2013;67:116&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22616874</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tirupati S, Padmavati R, Thara R, McCreadie RG. Insight and psychopathology in never-treated schizophrenia. Compr Psychiatry. 2007;48:264&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17445521</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim Y, Sakamoto K, Kamo T, Sakamura Y, Miyaoka H. Insight and clinical correlates in schizophrenia. Compr Psychiatry. 1997;38:117&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9056131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchy L, Torres IJ, Liddle PF, Woodward TS. Symptomatic determinants of insight in schizophrenia spectrum disorders. Compr Psychiatry. 2009;50:578&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19840598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedrelli P, McQuaid JR, Granholm E, Patterson TL, McClure F, Beck AT, et al. Measuring cognitive insight in middle-aged and older patients with psychotic disorders. Schizophr Res. 2004;71:297&#x2013;305.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15474900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engh JA, Friis S, Birkenaes AB, Jonsdottir H, Klungsoyr O, Ringen PA, et al. Delusions are associated with poor cognitive insight in schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2010;36:830&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2894586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19176474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiffen BD, Rabinowitz J, Lex A, David AS. Correlates, change and &#x2018;state or trait&#x2019; properties of insight in schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2010;122:94&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20382507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceskova E, Radovan P, Tomas K, Hana K. One-year follow-up of patients with first-episode schizophrenia (comparison between remitters and non-remitters) Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2007;3:153&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19300545</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanchard JJ, Kring AM, Horan WP, Gur R. Toward the next generation of negative symptom assessments: The collaboration to advance negative symptom assessment in schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2011;37:291&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3044636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20861151</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wible CG, Anderson J, Shenton ME, Kricun A, Hirayasu Y, Tanaka S, et al. Prefrontal cortex, negative symptoms, and schizophrenia: An MRI study. Psychiatry Res. 2001;108:65&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2845854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11738541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventura J, Hellemann GS, Thames AD, Koellner V, Nuechterlein KH. Symptoms as mediators of the relationship between neurocognition and functional outcome in schizophrenia: A meta-analysis. Schizophr Res. 2009;113:189&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2825750</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19628375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy BP, Chung YC, Park TW, McGorry PD. Pharmacological treatment of primary negative symptoms in schizophrenia: A systematic review. Schizophr Res. 2006;88:5&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16930948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinberger DR, Aloia MS, Goldberg TE, Berman KF. The frontal lobes and schizophrenia. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 1994;6:419&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7841813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voruganti LN, Heslegrave RJ, Awad AG. Neurocognitive correlates of positive and negative syndromes in schizophrenia. Can J Psychiatry. 1997;42:1066&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9469239</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buckley PF, Hasan S, Friedman L, Cerny C. Insight and schizophrenia. Compr Psychiatry. 2001;42:39&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11154714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Debowska G, Grzywa A, Kucharska-Pietura K. Insight in paranoid schizophrenia--its relationship to psychopathology and premorbid adjustment. Compr Psychiatry. 1998;39:255&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9777276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mutsatsa SH, Joyce EM, Hutton SB, Barnes TR. Relationship between insight, cognitive function, social function and symptomatology in schizophrenia: The West London first episode study. Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2006;256:356&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16902732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemp RA, Lambert TJ. Insight in schizophrenia and its relationship to psychopathology. Schizophr Res. 1995;18:21&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8929757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gharabawi GM, Lasser RA, Bossie CA, Zhu Y, Amador X. Insight and its relationship to clinical outcomes in patients with schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder receiving long-acting risperidone. Int Clin Psychopharmacol. 2006;21:233&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16687995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wittorf A, Jakobi U, Bechdolf A, Muller B, Sartory G, Wagner M, et al. The influence of baseline symptoms and insight on the therapeutic alliance early in the treatment of schizophrenia. Eur Psychiatry. 2009;24:259&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19200695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fenton WS, Blyler CR, Heinssen RK. Determinants of medication compliance in schizophrenia: Empirical and clinical findings. Schizophr Bull. 1997;23:637&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9366000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kao YC, Liu YP. Compliance and schizophrenia: The predictive potential of insight into illness, symptoms, and side effects. Compr Psychiatry. 2010;51:557&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20965300</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mingrone C, Rocca P, Castagna F, Montemagni C, Sigaudo M, Scalese M, et al. Insight in stable schizophrenia: Relations with psychopathology and cognition. Compr Psychiatry. 2013;54:484&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23332554</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Meer L, de Vos AE, Stiekema AP, Pijnenborg GH, van Tol MJ, Nolen WA, et al. Insight in schizophrenia: Involvement of self-reflection networks? Schizophr Bull. 2013;39:1288&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3796073</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23104865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boyer L, Cermolacce M, Dassa D, Fernandez J, Boucekine M, Richieri R, et al. Neurocognition, insight and medication nonadherence in schizophrenia: A structural equation modeling approach. PloS One. 2012;7:e47655.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3483287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23144705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goodman C, Knoll G, Isakov V, Silver H. Insight into illness in schizophrenia. Compr Psychiatry. 2005;46:284&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16175760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmer BW, Dawes SE, Heaton RK. What do we know about neuropsychological aspects of schizophrenia? Neuropsychol Rev. 2009;19:365&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2745531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19639412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan KD, David ASIIaPne. Neuropsychological studies of insight in patients with psychotic disorders. In: David XF, editor. Insight and Psychosis. 2nd ed. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2004. pp. 177&#x2013;93.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Subotnik KL, Nuechterlein KH, Irzhevsky V, Kitchen CM, Woo SM, Mintz J. Is unawareness of psychotic disorder a neurocognitive or psychological defensiveness problem? Schizophr Res. 2005;75:147&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15885506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simon V, De Hert M, Wampers M, Peuskens J, van Winkel R. The relation between neurocognitive dysfunction and impaired insight in patients with schizophrenia. Eur Psychiatry. 2009;24:239&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19070996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donohoe G, Corvin A, Robertson IH. Are the cognitive deficits associated with impaired insight in schizophrenia specific to executive task performance? J Nerv Ment Dis. 2005;193:803&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16319702</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohamed S, Fleming S, Penn DL, Spaulding W. Insight in schizophrenia: Its relationship to measures of executive functions. J Nerv Ment Dis. 1999;187:525&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10496507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shad MU, Muddasani S, Prasad K, Sweeney JA, Keshavan MS. Insight and prefrontal cortex in first-episode Schizophrenia. Neuroimage. 2004;22:1315&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15219603</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantakopoulos G, Ploumpidis D, Oulis P, Patrikelis P, Nikitopoulou S, Papadimitriou GN, et al. The relationship between insight and theory of mind in schizophrenia. Schizophr Res. 2014;152:217&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24321712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bora E, Sehitoglu G, Aslier M, Atabay I, Veznedaroglu B. Theory of mind and unawareness of illness in schizophrenia: Is poor insight a mentalizing deficit? Eur Arch Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2007;257:104&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17171312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langdon R, Ward P. Taking the perspective of the other contributes to awareness of illness in schizophrenia. Schizophr Bull. 2009;35:1003&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18495647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keshavan MS, Rabinowitz J, DeSmedt G, Harvey PD, Schooler N. Correlates of insight in first episode psychosis. Schizophr Res. 2004;70:187&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15329295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchy L, Czechowska Y, Chochol C, Malla A, Joober R, Pruessner J, et al. Toward a model of cognitive insight in first-episode psychosis: Verbal memory and hippocampal structure. Schizophr Bull. 2010;36:1040&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2930348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19346315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quee PJ, van der Meer L, Krabbendam L, de Haan L, Cahn W, Wiersma D, et al. Insight change in psychosis: Relationship with neurocognition, social cognition, clinical symptoms and phase of illness. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2014;129:126&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23600752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lysaker PH, Dimaggio G, Daroyanni P, Buck KD, LaRocco VA, Carcione A, et al. Assessing metacognition in schizophrenia with the Metacognition Assessment Scale: Associations with the Social Cognition and Object Relations Scale. Psychol Psychother. 2010;83(Pt 3):303&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20170602</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>