<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38684135</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>23</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-7385</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>103</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>American journal of physical medicine &amp; rehabilitation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparative Effects of Exercise Interventions and Mindfulness-Based Interventions for Cognitive Impairment and Quality of Life in Breast Cancer Survivors During or After Cancer Treatment: A Systematic Review and Bayesian Network Meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>777</StartPage><EndPage>788</EndPage><MedlinePgn>777-788</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002531</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this network meta-analysis was to compare the improvement effects of various exercise interventions and mindfulness-based interventions to determine the best interventions for the improvement of cognitive impairment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN">Seven databases were searched to screen randomized controlled trials of exercise interventions and mindfulness-based interventions to improve cognitive impairment. The network meta-analysis was performed using Revman 5.3, R 4.2.1 and ADDIS 1.16.8 software.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Thirty-four randomized controlled trials involving 14 interventions were included in the study. In terms of cognitive function, except for mindfulness-based stress reduction, all interventions showed significantly greater improvement in cognitive function compared with conventional therapy. Physical activity and Qigong showed better effect in improving executive function. In terms of improving verbal memory, compensatory cognitive training, neurofeedback training, Qigong, and sham Qigong were more effective than other interventions. On performing surface under the cumulative ranking curve analysis, acceptance and commitment therapy, neurofeedback training, Qigong, and mediation had the best effects on cognitive function, quality of life, executive function, and processing speed, respectively.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Mindfulness-based interventions were found to be more effective than exercise interventions for alleviating cognitive impairment. More robust randomized controlled trials focusing on acceptance and commitment therapy for cognitive impairment are required to support the current evidence.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeng</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>From the School of Nursing, Lanzhou University, Lanzhou, Gansu, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Li</LastName><ForeName>Caiyue</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yu</LastName><ForeName>Tana</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Hongchen</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D003160">Comparative Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000099094">Network Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Am J Phys Med Rehabil</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8803677</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0894-9115</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064866" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mindfulness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast Neoplasms</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073116" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cancer Survivors</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001499" MajorTopicYN="N">Bayes Theorem</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Conflict of interest statement: There are none conflicts of interest for each other. Financial disclosure statements have been obtained, and no conflicts of interest have been reported by the authors or by any individuals in control of the content of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38684135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PHM.0000000000002531</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002060-202409000-00003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Nardin S, Mora E, Varughese FM, et al.: Breast cancer survivorship, quality of life, and late toxicities. Front Oncol 2020;10:864</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller KD, Nogueira L, Mariotto AB, et al.: Cancer treatment and survivorship statistics, 2019. CA Cancer J Clin 2019;69:363&#x2013;85</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dijkshoorn ABC, van Stralen HE, Sloots M, et al.: Prevalence of cognitive impairment and change in patients with breast cancer: a systematic review of longitudinal studies. Psychooncology 2021;30:635&#x2013;48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whittaker AL, George RP, O'Malley L: Prevalence of cognitive impairment following chemotherapy treatment for breast cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Sci Rep 2022;12:2135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vardy J, Tannock I: Cognitive function after chemotherapy in adults with solid tumours. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol 2007;63:183&#x2013;202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mounier NM, Abdel-Maged AE, Wahdan SA, et al.: Chemotherapy-induced cognitive impairment (CICI): an overview of etiology and pathogenesis. Life Sci 2020;258:118071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koppelmans V, Breteler MM, Boogerd W, et al.: Neuropsychological performance in survivors of breast cancer more than 20 years after adjuvant chemotherapy. J Clin Oncol 2012;30:1080&#x2013;6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence JA, Griffin L, Balcueva EP, et al.: A study of donepezil in female breast cancer survivors with self-reported cognitive dysfunction 1 to 5 years following adjuvant chemotherapy. J Cancer Surviv 2016;10:176&#x2013;84</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakamura ZM, Deal AM, Park EM, et al.: A phase II single-arm trial of memantine for prevention of cognitive decline during chemotherapy in patients with early breast cancer: feasibility, tolerability, acceptability, and preliminary effects. Cancer Med 2023;12:8172&#x2013;83</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mar Fan HG, Clemons M, Xu W, et al.: A randomised, placebo-controlled, double-blind trial of the effects of d-methylphenidate on fatigue and cognitive dysfunction in women undergoing adjuvant chemotherapy for breast cancer. Support Care Cancer 2008;16:577&#x2013;83</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang Z, Shi Y, Bao P, et al.: Associations of dietary intake and supplement use with post-therapy cognitive recovery in breast cancer survivors. Breast Cancer Res Treat 2018;171:189&#x2013;98</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ren X, Wang X, Sun J, et al.: Effects of physical exercise on cognitive function of breast cancer survivors receiving chemotherapy: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Breast 2022;63:113&#x2013;22</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns SA, Von Ah D, Brown LF, et al.: Randomized controlled pilot trial of mindfulness-based stress reduction for breast and colorectal cancer survivors: effects on cancer-related cognitive impairment. J Cancer Surviv 2016;10:437&#x2013;48</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Von Ah D, Carpenter JS, Saykin A, et al.: Advanced cognitive training for breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat 2012;135:799&#x2013;809</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt ME, Wiskemann J, Armbrust P, et al.: Effects of resistance exercise on fatigue and quality of life in breast cancer patients undergoing adjuvant chemotherapy: a randomized controlled trial. Int J Cancer 2015;137:471&#x2013;80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galiano-Castillo N, Cantarero-Villanueva I, Fern&#xe1;ndez-Lao C, et al.: Telehealth system: a randomized controlled trial evaluating the impact of an internet-based exercise intervention on quality of life, pain, muscle strength, and fatigue in breast cancer survivors. Cancer 2016;122:3166&#x2013;74</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mijwel S, Backman M, Bolam KA, et al.: Adding high-intensity interval training to conventional training modalities: optimizing health-related outcomes during chemotherapy for breast cancer: the OptiTrain randomized controlled trial. Breast Cancer Res Treat 2018;168:79&#x2013;93</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steindorf K, Schmidt ME, Klassen O, et al.: Randomized, controlled trial of resistance training in breast cancer patients receiving adjuvant radiotherapy: results on cancer-related fatigue and quality of life. Ann Oncol 2014;25:2237&#x2013;43</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasyar N, Barshan Tashnizi N, Mansouri P, et al.: Effect of yoga exercise on the quality of life and upper extremity volume among women with breast cancer related lymphedema: a pilot study. Eur J Oncol Nurs 2019;42:103&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell KL, Kam JWY, Neil-Sztramko SE, et al.: Effect of aerobic exercise on cancer-associated cognitive impairment: a proof-of-concept RCT. Psychooncology 2018;27:53&#x2013;60</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myers JS, Mitchell M, Krigel S, et al.: Qigong intervention for breast cancer survivors with complaints of decreased cognitive function. Support Care Cancer 2019;27:1395&#x2013;403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mihuta ME, Green HJ, Shum DHK: Web-based cognitive rehabilitation for survivors of adult cancer: a randomised controlled trial. Psychooncology 2018;27:1172&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larkey LK, Roe DJ, Smith L, et al.: Exploratory outcome assessment of Qigong/Tai Chi easy on breast cancer survivors. Complement Ther Med 2016;29:196&#x2013;203</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kesler S, Hadi Hosseini SM, Heckler C, et al.: Cognitive training for improving executive function in chemotherapy-treated breast cancer survivors. Clin Breast Cancer 2013;13:299&#x2013;306</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Damholdt MF, Mehlsen M, O'Toole MS, et al.: Web-based cognitive training for breast cancer survivors with cognitive complaints&#x2014;a randomized controlled trial. Psychooncology 2016;25:1293&#x2013;300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneghan AM, Becker H, Harrison ML, et al.: A randomized control trial of meditation compared to music listening to improve cognitive function for breast cancer survivors: feasibility and acceptability. Complement Ther Clin Pract 2020;41:101228</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milbury K, Chaoul A, Biegler K, et al.: Tibetan sound meditation for cognitive dysfunction: results of a randomized controlled pilot trial. Psychooncology 2013;22:2354&#x2013;63</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gokal K, Munir F, Ahmed S, et al.: Does walking protect against decline in cognitive functioning among breast cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy? Results from a small randomised controlled trial. PloS One 2018;13:e0206874</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson RJ, Sigmon ST, Pritchard AJ, et al.: A randomized trial of videoconference-delivered cognitive behavioral therapy for survivors of breast cancer with self-reported cognitive dysfunction. Cancer 2016;122:1782&#x2013;91</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman SJ, Nelson SH, Myers E, et al.: Randomized controlled trial of increasing physical activity on objectively measured and self-reported cognitive functioning among breast cancer survivors: the memory &amp; motion study. Cancer 2018;124:192&#x2013;202</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shari NI, Zainal NZ, Ng CG: Effects of brief acceptance and commitment therapy (ACT) on subjective cognitive impairment in breast cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy. J Psychosoc Oncol 2021;39:695&#x2013;714</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Henneghan AM, Becker H, Phillips C, et al.: Sustained effects of mantra meditation compared to music listening on neurocognitive outcomes of breast cancer survivors: a brief report of a randomized control trial. J Psychosom Res 2021;150:110628</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galiano-Castillo N, Arroyo-Morales M, Lozano-Lozano M, et al.: Effect of an Internet-based telehealth system on functional capacity and cognition in breast cancer survivors: a secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial. Support Care Cancer 2017;25:3551&#x2013;9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vadiraja HS, Rao MR, Nagarathna R, et al.: Effects of yoga program on quality of life and affect in early breast cancer patients undergoing adjuvant radiotherapy: a randomized controlled trial. Complement Ther Med 2009;17(5&#x2013;6):274&#x2013;80</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duval A, Davis CG, Khoo EL, et al.: Mindfulness-based stress reduction and cognitive function among breast cancer survivors: a randomized controlled trial. Cancer 2022;128:2520&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li Z, Hao X, Lei P, et al.: Patients with breast cancer receiving chemotherapy: effects of multisensory stimulation training on cognitive impairment. Clin J Oncol Nurs 2022;26:71&#x2013;7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh B, Butow PN, Mullan BA, et al.: Effect of medical Qigong on cognitive function, quality of life, and a biomarker of inflammation in cancer patients: a randomized controlled trial. Support Care Cancer 2012;20:1235&#x2013;42</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyant S: Feasibility and acceptability of a computerized working memory training in breast cancer survivors. Feasibility &amp; acceptability of a computerized working memory training in breast cancer survivors 2017:1&#x2013;1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Northey JM, Pumpa KL, Quinlan C, et al.: Cognition in breast cancer survivors: a pilot study of interval and continuous exercise. J Sci Med Sport 2019;22:580&#x2013;5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perrault AA, Pomares FB, Smith D, et al.: Effects of cognitive behavioral therapy for insomnia on subjective and objective measures of sleep and cognition. Sleep medicine 2022;97:13&#x2013;26</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liou KT, Root JC, Garland SN, et al.: Effects of acupuncture versus cognitive behavioral therapy on cognitive function in cancer survivors with insomnia: a secondary analysis of a randomized clinical trial. Cancer 2020;126:3042&#x2013;52</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Hernandez E, Romero R, Campos D, et al.: Cognitively-Based Compassion Training (CBCT&#xae;) in breast cancer survivors: a randomized clinical trial study. Integr Cancer Ther 2018;17:684&#x2013;96</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferguson RJ, McDonald BC, Rocque MA, et al.: Development of CBT for chemotherapy-related cognitive change: results of a waitlist control trial. Psychooncology 2012;21:176&#x2013;86</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarvghadi P, Ghaffari A, Rostami HR: The effects of neurofeedback training on short-term memory and quality of life in women with breast cancer. Int J Ther Rehabil 2019;26:1&#x2013;8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Park JH, Jung YS, Kim KS, et al.: Effects of compensatory cognitive training intervention for breast cancer patients undergoing chemotherapy: a pilot study. Support Care Cancer 2017;25:1887&#x2013;96</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ding Y, Sun Z, Wu W: Effect of mindfulness based music therapy on cognitive function and emotion of patients with breast cancer undergoing chemotherapy. Chin J Gen Pract 2017;15:1798&#x2013;801</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodds SE, Pace TW, Bell ML, et al.: Feasibility of cognitively-based compassion training (CBCT) for breast cancer survivors: a randomized, wait list controlled pilot study. Support Care Cancer 2015;23:3599&#x2013;608</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Treanor CJ, McMenamin UC, O'Neill RF, et al.: Non-pharmacological interventions for cognitive impairment due to systemic cancer treatment. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2016;2016:Cd011325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mackenzie L, Marshall K: Effective non-pharmacological interventions for cancer related cognitive impairment in adults (excluding central nervous system or head and neck cancer): systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 2022;58:258&#x2013;70</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng Y, Dong J, Huang M, et al.: Nonpharmacological interventions for cancer-related cognitive impairment in adult cancer patients: a network meta-analysis. Int J Nurs Stud 2020;104:103514</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh P-J, Kim JH: The effects of nonpharmacologic interventions on cognitive function in patients with cancer: a meta-analysis. Oncol Nurs Forum 2016;43:E205&#x2013;17</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alwi SMS, Narayanan V, Din NC, et al.: Cognitive rehabilitation programs for survivors of breast cancer treated with chemotherapy: a systematic review. Rehabil Oncol 2021;39:155&#x2013;67</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>