<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35270919</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1424-8220</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>22</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>24</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Sensors (Basel, Switzerland)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sensors (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Hough Transform Proposal and Simulations for Particle Track Recognition for LHC Phase-II Upgrade.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1768</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/s22051768</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In the near future, LHC experiments will continue future upgrades by overcoming the technological obsolescence of the detectors and the readout capabilities. Therefore, after the conclusion of a data collection period, CERN will have to face a long shutdown to improve overall performance, by updating the experiments, and implementing more advanced technologies and infrastructures. In particular, the largest LHC experiment, i.e., ATLAS, will upgrade parts of the detector, the trigger, and the data acquisition system. In addition, the ATLAS experiment will complete the implementation of new strategies, algorithms for data handling, and transmission to the final storage apparatus. This paper presents an overview of an upgrade planned for the second half of this decade for the ATLAS experiment. In particular, we show a study of a novel pattern recognition algorithm used in the trigger system, which is a device designed to provide the information needed to select physical events from unnecessary background data. The idea is to use a well known mathematical transform, the Hough transform, as the algorithm for the detection of particle trajectories. The effectiveness of the algorithm has already been validated in the past, regardless of particle physics applications, to recognize generic shapes within images. On the contrary, here, we first propose a software emulation tool, and a subsequent hardware implementation of the Hough transform, for particle physics applications. Until now, the Hough transform has never been implemented on electronics in particle physics experiments, and since a hardware implementation would provide benefits in terms of overall Latency, we complete the studies by comparing the simulated data with a physical system implemented on a Xilinx hardware accelerator (FELIX-II card). In more detail, we have implemented a low-abstraction RTL design of the Hough transform on Xilinx UltraScale+ FPGAs as target devices for filtering applications.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gabrielli</LastName><ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5346-7841</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INFN Bologna, Viale Berti Pichat 6/2, 40127 Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physics and Astronomy Department, University of Bologna, 40126 Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Alfonsi</LastName><ForeName>Fabrizio</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INFN Bologna, Viale Berti Pichat 6/2, 40127 Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Del Corso</LastName><ForeName>Francesca</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7799-577X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>INFN Bologna, Viale Berti Pichat 6/2, 40127 Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Physics and Astronomy Department, University of Bologna, 40126 Bologna, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Sensors (Basel)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101204366</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1424-8220</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FPGAs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hough transform</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high energy physics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">particle recognition</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>15</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35270919</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8914620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s22051768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">s22051768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Apollinari G., Bejar Alonso I., Bruning O., Fessia P., Lamont M., Rossi L., Tavian L. High-Luminosity Large Hadron Collider (HL-LHC): Technical Design Report V. 0.1. Cern Yellow Rep. Monogr. 2017;4:599.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perkins D.H. Introduction to High Energy Physics. Cambridge University Press; Cambridge, UK: 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abeling K., on behalf of the ATLAS Collaboration Expected tracking performance with the HL-LHC ATLAS detector; Proceedings of the European Physical Society Conference on High Energy Physics; Ghent, Belgium. 10&#x2013;17 July 2019; p. 177.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Backhaus M. The Upgrade of the CMS Inner Tracker at HL-LHC. JINST. 2019;14:C10017. doi: 10.1088/1748-0221/14/10/C10017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1088/1748-0221/14/10/C10017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryd A., Skinnari L. Tracking Triggers for the HL-LHC. Annu. Rev. Nucl. Part. Sci. 2020;70:171&#x2013;195. doi: 10.1146/annurev-nucl-020420-093547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-nucl-020420-093547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanein A.S., Mohammad S., Sameer S., Ragab M.E. A survey on Hough Transform, Theory, Techniques and Applications. Int. J. Comput. Sci. 2015;12:32&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mukhopadhyay P., Chaudhuria B.B. A survey of Hough Transform. Pattern Recognit. 2015;48:993&#x2013;1010. doi: 10.1016/j.patcog.2014.08.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.patcog.2014.08.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabrielli A., Alfonsi F., Annovi A., Camplani A., Cerri A. Hardware Implementation Study of Particle Tracking Algorithm on FPGAs. Electronics. 2021;10:2546. doi: 10.3390/electronics10202546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics10202546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabrielli A., Alfonsi F., Corso F.D. Simulated Hough Transform Model Optimized for Straight-Line Recognition Using Frontier FPGA Devices. Electronics. 2022;11:517. doi: 10.3390/electronics11040517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics11040517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramesh N., Purdy G., Purdy C., Smith J. A Hardware Implementation of Hough Transform Based on Parabolic Duality; Proceedings of the 2014 IEEE 57th International Midwest Symposium on Circuits and Systems (MWSCAS); College Station, TX, USA. 3&#x2013;6 August 2014; pp. 145&#x2013;148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston J., Ngo H. Real-Time Image Processing and Deep Learning. Volume 11736 International Society for Optics and Photonics; Bellingham, WA, USA: 2021. Design of an embedded system for real-time lane detection based on the linear Hough transform.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandelli B. The Pixel Detector of the ATLAS Experiment for the Run 2 at the Large Hadron Collider. Nucl. Part. Phys. Proc. 2016;273&#x2013;275:1166&#x2013;1172. doi: 10.1016/j.nuclphysbps.2015.09.183.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nuclphysbps.2015.09.183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller J.S. The ATLAS ITk strip detector system for the High Luminosity LHC upgrade. Nucl. Instrum. Methods Phys. Res. Sect. A. 2020;958:1166&#x2013;1172. doi: 10.1016/j.nima.2019.04.007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nima.2019.04.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baranov S. High Level Synthesis of Digital Systems: For Data Path and Control Dominated Systems. ACM Digital Library; New York, NY, USA: 2018. p. 207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xilinx. UltraFast DesignMethodology Guide forXilinx FPGAs and SoCs. UG949 (v2021.1) 2020.  [(accessed on 1 December 2021)]. p. 327. Available online:  https://www.xilinx.com/support/documentation/sw_manuals/xilinx2020_1/ug949-vivado-design-methodology.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J., Ma J., Yan Z. Identification of Pipeline Circuit Design. Electron. Signal Process. 2015;97:71&#x2013;76.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vasques W.P. FELIX: The new detector interface for ATLAS. EPJ Web Conf. 2020;245:01037.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xilinx. UltraScale and UltraScale+ GTY Transceivers. UltraScale Architecture GTY Transceivers UG578. 2017.  [(accessed on 1 December 2021)]. p. 446. Available online:  https://www.xilinx.com/support/documentation/user_guides/ug578-ultrascale-gty-transceivers.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang C., Li P., Sun G., Guan Y., Xiao B., Cong J. Optimizing fpga-based accelerator design for deep convolutional neural networks; Proceedings of the 2015 ACM/SIGDA International Symposium on Field-Programmable Gate Arrays; Monterey, CA, USA. 22&#x2013;24 February 2015; pp. 161&#x2013;170.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim T., Park S., Cho Y. Study on the Implementation of a Simple and Effective Memory System for an AI Chip. Electronics. 2021;10:1399. doi: 10.3390/electronics10121399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics10121399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He D., He J., Liu J., Yang J., Yan Q., Yang Y. An FPGA-Based LSTM Acceleration Engine for Deep Learning Frameworks. Electronics. 2021;10:681. doi: 10.3390/electronics10060681.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/electronics10060681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>