<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38794894</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2047-7163</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>107</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Season>Apr-Jun</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Science progress</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Sci Prog</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Theoretical analysis of <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>J</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>-transform decomposition method with applications of nonlinear ordinary differentialequations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>368504241256864</StartPage><MedlinePgn>368504241256864</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">00368504241256864</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/00368504241256864</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>One of the most noteworthy differential equations of the first order is the Riccati differential equation. It is applied in various branches of mathematics, including algebraic geometry, physics, and conformal mapping theory. The <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>J</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>-transform Adomian decomposition method is employed in the current study to find exact solutions for different kinds of nonlinear differential equations. We give thorough detailed proofs for new theorems related to the <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>J</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>-transform technique. The Adomian decomposition method and the <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>J</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>-transform method serve as the foundation for this technique. For certain differential equations, the theoretical analysis of the <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>J</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>-transform Adomian decomposition method is examined and is computed using readily computed terms. Our findings are contrasted with exact solutions found in the literature that were produced using alternative techniques. The significant features of the <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>J</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>-transform Adomian decomposition method are described in the article. It has been shown that the <mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mml:mrow><mml:mrow><mml:mi>J</mml:mi></mml:mrow></mml:mrow></mml:math>-transform Adomian decomposition method is very efficient, useful, and adaptable to a broad variety of linear and nonlinear differential equations. Most of the symbolic and numerical calculations were performed using Mathematica.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Obeidat</LastName><ForeName>Nazek A</ForeName><Initials>NA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0008-6367-0737</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Statistics, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">37251</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rawashdeh</LastName><ForeName>Mahmoud Saleh</ForeName><Initials>MS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1543-7443</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Statistics, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">37251</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al Smadi</LastName><ForeName>Mohammad N</ForeName><Initials>MN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Statistics, Jordan University of Science and Technology, Irbid, Jordan.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">37251</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Sci Prog</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0411361</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0036-8504</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">44A10</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">44A15</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">44A20</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">44A30</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">44A35</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">AMS Classification Codes</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Adomian decomposition method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">J-transform method</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Riccati differential equation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fixed point theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nonlinear differential equations</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of conflicting interestsThe author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest for the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>54</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38794894</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11320701</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/00368504241256864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Agwa HA, Ali FM, K&#x131;l&#x131;&#xe7;man A. A new integral transform on time scales and its applications. Adv Differ Equat 2012; 2012: 1&#x2013;14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atangana A. A note on the triple Laplace transform and its applications to some kind of third-order differential equation. In <i>Abstract and Applied Analysis</i>. (Vol. 2013). Hindawi, 2013, January.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atangana A, Alkaltani BST. A novel double integral transform and its applications. J Nonlinear Sci Appl 2016; 9: 424&#x2013;434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asiru MA. Sumudu transform and the solution of integral equations of convolution type. Int J Math Educ Sci Technol 2001; 32: 906&#x2013;910.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belgacem FBM, Karaballi AA, Kalla SL. Analytical investigations of the Sumudu transform and applications to integral production equations. Math Probl Eng 2003; 2003: 103&#x2013;118.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belgacem FBM, Karaballi AA. Sumudu transform fundamental properties investigations and applications. Int J Stoch Anal 2006; 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belgacem FBM, Silambarasan R. Theory of natural transform. Math Engg Sci Aeros 2012; 3: 99&#x2013;124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan ZH, Khan WA. N-transform properties and applications. NUST J Eng Sci 2008; 1: 127&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies B. Integral transforms and their applications (vol. 41). Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dattoli G, Martinelli MR, Ricci PE. On new families of integral transforms for the solution of partial differential equations. Integr Transf Spec Funct 2005; 16: 661&#x2013;667.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buschman RG. Integral transformations, operational calculus, and generalized functions (vol. 377). Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel MR. Laplace transforms (p. 249). New York: McGraw-Hill, 1965.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watugala GK. Sumudu transform: a new integral transform to solve differential equations and control engineering problems. Integr Educ 1993; 24: 35&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wazwaz AM. Partial differential equations and solitary waves theory. Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adomian G. Solving frontier problems of physics: the decomposition method (vol. 60). Springer Science &amp; Business Media, 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adomian G. A review of the decomposition method in applied mathematics. J Math Anal Appl 1988; 135: 501&#x2013;544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adomian G. A new approach to nonlinear partial differential equations. J Math Anal Appl 1984; 102: 420&#x2013;434.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Sayed SM. The decomposition method for studying the Klein&#x2013;Gordon equation. Chaos, Soliton Fract 2003; 18: 1025&#x2013;1030.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miah MM, Seadawy AR, Ali HS, et al. Abundant closed form wave solutions to some nonlinear evolution equations in mathematical physics. J Ocean Eng Sci 2020; 5: 269&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basak KC, Ray PC, Bera RK. Solution of non-linear Klein&#x2013;Gordon equation with a quadratic non-linear term by Adomian decomposition method. Commun Nonlin Sci Numer Simul 2009; 14: 718&#x2013;723.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obeidat NA, Rawashdeh MS. On theories of natural decomposition method applied to system of nonlinear differential equations in fluid mechanics. Adv Mech Eng 2023; 15: 16878132221149835.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawashdeh M. Improved approximate solutions for nonlinear evolutions equations in mathematical physics using the reduced differential transform method. J Appl Math Bioinform 2013; 3: 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawashdeh M. Using the reduced differential transform method to solve nonlinear PDEs arises in biology and physics. World Appl Sci J 2013; 23: 1037&#x2013;1043.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawashdeh M, Obeidat NA. On finding exact and approximate solutions to some PDEs using the reduced differential transform method. Appl Math Inform Sci 2014; 8: 2171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawashdeh M. Approximate solutions for coupled systems of nonlinear PDES using the reduced differential transform method. Math Comput Appl 2014; 19: 161&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#x15e; Y&#xfc;zba&#x15f;&#x131;. An operational method for solutions of Riccati type differential equations with functional arguments. J Taibah Univ Sci 2020; 14: 661&#x2013;669.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>bin Rasedee AFN, Sathar MHA, Ishak N, et al. Numerical approximation of Riccati type differential equations. ASM Sci J 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghadimi NA, Keshavarz M. Solving the interval Riccati differential equation by wavelet operational matrix method. J Fuzzy Set Valued Anal 2016; 118&#x2013;130.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Odibat Z, Momani S. A reliable treatment of homotopy perturbation method for Klein&#x2013;Gordon equations. Phys Lett A 2007; 365: 351&#x2013;357.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maitama S, Zhao W. Beyond Sumudu transform and natural transform: J-transform properties and applications. J Appl Anal Comput 2020; 10: 1223&#x2013;1241.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spiegel MR. Theory and problems of complex variables with an introduction to conformal mapping and its applications. New York, 1964.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kalla IL. Convergence of Adomian&#x2019;s method applied to a class of Volterra type integro-differential equations. Int J Differ Equ Appl 2005; 10: 225&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>