<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">35393734</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1467-789X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>23</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Aug</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Obesity reviews : an official journal of the International Association for the Study of Obesity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Obes Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The impact of the interplay of the intestinal microbiome and diet on the metabolomic and health outcomes of bariatric surgery.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13455</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13455</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/obr.13455</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Obesity has evolved into a global epidemic. Bariatric surgery, the most effective treatment for obesity, keeps many comorbidities of obesity at bay for a prolonged period of time. However, complications, including metabolic alterations, are inherent in bariatric surgery. Surgical intervention in the structure of the digestive tract, especially during bariatric bypass procedures, also causes significant changes in the composition of the microbiome, which may affect the composition and quantity of various metabolites produced by intestinal bacteria. The composition of the intestinal microbiome is connected to human metabolism via metabolites that are produced and secreted by bacterial cells into the intestinal lumen and then absorbed into the host's bloodstream. Bariatric surgery causes changes in the composition and quantity of many circulating metabolites. Metabolic disorders may be affected after bariatric surgery by changes in the composition of the microbiome and metabolites produced by bacteria.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2022 World Obesity Federation.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mika</LastName><ForeName>Adriana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2877-5652</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Biochemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janczy</LastName><ForeName>Agata</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Nutrition, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Waleron</LastName><ForeName>Krzysztof</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Microbiology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Szymanski</LastName><ForeName>Michal</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0215-9213</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General, Endocrine and Transplant Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaska</LastName><ForeName>Lukasz</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of General, Endocrine and Transplant Surgery, Faculty of Medicine, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sledzinski</LastName><ForeName>Tomasz</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9028-3790</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Biochemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Obes Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100897395</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1467-7881</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bariatric Surgery</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004032" MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000069196" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Microbiome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017063" MajorTopicYN="N">Outcome Assessment, Health Care</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bariatric surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fatty acids</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microbiome</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>15</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35393734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/obr.13455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Vance DE, Vance JE. Biochemistry of Lipids, Lipoproteins, and Membranes. Elsevier; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swierczynski, Julian, Sledzinski T. The role of adipokines and gastrointestinal tract hormones in obesity. In: Principles of Metabolic Surgery. Springer; 2012:53-79. doi:10.1007/978-3-642-02411-5_6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koulas SG, Stefanou CK, Stefanou SK, et al. Gut microbiota in patients with morbid obesity before and after bariatric surgery: a ten-year review study (2009-2019). Obes Surg. 2021;31(1):317-326. doi:10.1007/s11695-020-05074-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose C, Parker A, Jefferson B, Cartmell E. The characterization of feces and urine: A review of the literature to inform advanced treatment technology. Crit Rev Environ Sci Technol. 2015;45(17):1827-1879. doi:10.1080/10643389.2014.1000761</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gentileschi P. Laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy as a primary operation for morbid obesity: experience with 200 patients. Gastroenterol Res Pract. 2012;2012:801325 doi:10.1155/2012/801325</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carbajo M, Luque-de-Le&#xf3;n E, Jim&#xe9;nez J, Ortiz-de-Sol&#xf3;rzano J, P&#xe9;rez-Miranda M, Castro-Alija M. Laparoscopic one-anastomosis gastric bypass: technique, results, and long-term follow-up in 1200 patients. Obes Surg. 2017;27(5):1153-1167. doi:10.1007/s11695-016-2428-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal W, Zagzoog MM, Sait SH, et al. Initial outcomes of one anastomosis gastric bypass at a single institution. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. 2019;12:35-41. doi:10.2147/DMSO.S180111</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fisher B. Comparison of recovery time after open and laparoscopic gastric bypass and laparoscopic adjustable banding. Obes Surg. 2004;14(1):67-72. doi:10.1381/096089204772787310</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seetharamaiah S, Tantia O, Goyal G, et al. LSG vs OAGB-1 year follow-up data-a randomized control trial. Obes Surg. 2016;27(4):948-954. doi:10.1007/s11695-016-2403-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Milone M, di Minno M, Leongito M, et al. Bariatric surgery and diabetes remission: sleeve gastrectomy or mini-gastric bypass? World J Gastroenterol. 2013;19(39):6590-6597. doi:10.3748/wjg.v19.i39.6590</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsilingiris D, Koliaki C, Kokkinos A. Remission of type 2 diabetes mellitus after bariatric surgery: fact or fiction? Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(17):3171 doi:10.3390/ijerph16173171</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vigilante A, Signorini F, Marani M, et al. Impact on dyslipidemia after laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy. Obes Surg. 2018;28(10):3111-3115. doi:10.1007/s11695-018-3343-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu Z, Sun J, Li R, et al. A comprehensive comparison of LRYGB and LSG in obese patients including the effects on QoL, comorbidities, weight loss, and complications: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obes Surg. 2019;30(3):819-827. doi:10.1007/s11695-019-04306-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corcelles R, Boules M, Froylich D, et al. Total weight loss as the outcome measure of choice after Roux-en-Y Gastric bypass. Obes Surg. 2016;26(8):1794-1798. doi:10.1007/s11695-015-2022-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peterli R, W&#xf6;lnerhanssen BK, Peters T, et al. Effect of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy vs laparoscopic Roux-en-Y Gastric bypass on weight loss in patients with morbid obesity: the SM-BOSS randomized clinical trial. Jama. 2018;319(3):255-265. doi:10.1001/jama.2017.20897</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poublon N, Chidi I, Bethlehem M, et al. One anastomosis gastric bypass vs. Roux-en-Y gastric bypass, remedy for insufficient weight loss and weight regain after failed restrictive bariatric surgery. Obes Surg. 2020;30(9):3287-3294. doi:10.1007/s11695-020-04536-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musella M, Susa A, Manno E, et al. Complications following the mini/one anastomosis gastric bypass (MGB/OAGB): a multi-institutional survey on 2678 patients with a mid-term (5 years) follow-up. Obes Surg. 2017;27(11):2956-2967. doi:10.1007/s11695-017-2726-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adduci AJ, Phillips CH, Harvin H. Prospective diagnosis of marginal ulceration following Roux-en-Y gastric bypass with computed tomography. Radiol Case Reports. 2015;10(2):1063.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musella M, Vitiello A, Berardi G, Velotti N, Pesce M, Sarnelli G. Evaluation of reflux following sleeve gastrectomy and one anastomosis gastric bypass: 1-year results from a randomized open-label controlled trial. Surg Endosc. 2020;1:1-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merrouche M, Sabat&#xe9; JM, Jouet J, et al. Gastro-esophageal reflux and esophageal motility disorders in morbidly obese patients before and after bariatric surgery. Obes Surg. 2007;17(7):894-900. doi:10.1007/s11695-007-9166-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rutte PWJ, Smulders JF, de Zoete JP, Nienhuijs SW. Outcome of sleeve gastrectomy as a primary bariatric procedure. Br J Surg. 2014;101(6):661-668. doi:10.1002/bjs.9447</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagner M, Deitel M, Erickson A, Crosby R. Survey on laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy (LSG) at the fourth international consensus summit on sleeve gastrectomy. Obes Surg. 2013;23(12):2013-2017. doi:10.1007/s11695-013-1040-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabl C, Peeva S, Prado K, et al. Early and late abdominal bleeding after Roux-en-Y gastric bypass: sources and tailored therapeutic strategies. Obes Surg. 2011;21(4):413-420. doi:10.1007/s11695-011-0354-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jammu GS, Sharma R. A 7-year clinical audit of 1107 cases comparing sleeve gastrectomy, Roux-En-Y gastric bypass, and mini-gastric bypass, to determine an effective and safe bariatric and metabolic procedure. Obes Surg. 2016;26(5):926-932. doi:10.1007/s11695-015-1869-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper TC, Simmons EB, Webb K, Burns JL, Kushner RF. Trends in weight regain following Roux-en-Y gastric bypass (RYGB) bariatric surgery. Obes Surg. 2015;25(8):1474-1481. doi:10.1007/s11695-014-1560-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory DM, Twells LK, Lester KK, et al. Preoperative and postoperative assessments of biochemical parameters in patients with severe obesity undergoing laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy. Obes Surg. 2018;28(8):2261-2271. doi:10.1007/s11695-017-3007-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antoniewicz A, Kalinowski P, Kotulecka KJ, et al. Nutritional deficiencies in patients after Roux-en-Y gastric bypass and sleeve gastrectomy during 12-month follow-up. Obes Surg. 2019;29(10):3277-3284. doi:10.1007/s11695-019-03985-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hakeam HA, ORegan PJ, Salem AM, Bamehriz FY, Eldali AM. Impact of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy on iron indices: 1 year follow-up. Obes Surg. 2009;19(11):1491-1496. doi:10.1007/s11695-009-9919-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Engebretsen KV, Blom-H&#xf8;gest&#xf8;l IK, Hewitt S, et al. Anemia following Roux-en-Y gastric bypass for morbid obesity; a 5-year follow-up study. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2018;53(8):917-922. doi:10.1080/00365521.2018.1489892</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad A, Kornrich B, Krasner H, et al. Prevalence of dumping syndrome after laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy and comparison with laparoscopic Roux-en-Y Gastric bypass. Obes Surg. 2019;29(5):1506-1513. doi:10.1007/s11695-018-03699-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laurenius A, Olbers T, N&#xe4;slund I, Karlsson J. Dumping syndrome following gastric bypass: validation of the dumping symptom rating scale. Obes Surg. 2013;23(6):740-755. doi:10.1007/s11695-012-0856-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angrisani L, Santonicola A, Iovino P, et al. Bariatric surgery and endoluminal procedures: IFSO worldwide survey 2014. Obes Surg. 2017;27(9):2279-2289. doi:10.1007/s11695-017-2666-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Estimate of Bariatric Surgery Numbers, 2011-2019|American Society for Metabolic and Bariatric Surgery.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yehoshua RT, Eidelman LA, Stein M, et al. Laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy-volume and pressure assessment. Obes Surg. 2008;18(9):1083-1088. doi:10.1007/s11695-008-9576-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannelli A, Dainese R, Piche T, Facchiano E, Gugenheim J. Laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy for morbid obesity. World J Gastroenterol. 2008;14(6):821-827. doi:10.3748/wjg.14.821</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Luca M, Tie T, Ooi G, et al. Mini gastric bypass-one anastomosis gastric bypass (MGB-OAGB)-IFSO position statement. Obes Surg. 2018;28(5):1188-1206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arterburn D, Telem D, Kushner R, Courcoulas A. Benefits and risks of bariatric surgery in adults: a review. Jama. 2020;324(9):879-887. doi:10.1001/jama.2020.12567</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li JV, Ashrafian H, Bueter M, et al. Metabolic surgery profoundly influences gut microbial-host metabolic cross-talk. Gut. 2011;60(9):1214-1223. doi:10.1136/gut.2010.234708</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacharoulis D, Sioka E, Papamargaritis D, et al. Influence of the learning curve on safety and efficiency of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy. Obes Surg. 2012;22(3):411-415. doi:10.1007/s11695-011-0436-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carandina S, Montana L, Danan M, Zulian V, Nedelcu M, Barrat C. Laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy learning curve: clinical and economical impact. Obes Surg. 2019;29(1):143-148. doi:10.1007/s11695-018-3486-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catheline J, Fysekidis M, Dbouk R, et al. Weight loss after sleeve gastrectomy in super superobesity. J Obes. 2012;2012:1-4. doi:10.1155/2012/959260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iannelli A, Facchiano E, Gugenheim J. Internal hernia after laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass for morbid obesity. Obes Surg. 2006;16(10):1265-1271. doi:10.1381/096089206778663689</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauti M, Kularatna M, Hill A, MacCormick A. Weight Regain Following Sleeve Gastrectomy-a Systematic Review. Obes Surg. 2016;26(6):1326-1334. doi:10.1007/s11695-016-2152-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain M, Tantia O, Goyal G, et al. LSG vs MGB-OAGB: 5-year follow-up data and comparative outcome of the two procedures over long term-results of a randomised control trial. Obes Surg. 2021;31(3):1223-1232. doi:10.1007/s11695-020-05119-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soong T, Lee M, Lee W, et al. Long-term efficacy of bariatric surgery for the treatment of super-obesity: comparison of SG, RYGB, and OAGB. Obes Surg. 2021;31(8):3391-3399. doi:10.1007/s11695-021-05464-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahawar K, Reed A, Graham Y. Marginal ulcers after one anastomosis (mini) gastric bypass: a survey of surgeons. Clin Obes. 2017;7(3):151-156. doi:10.1111/cob.12186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos A, Chevallier J, Mahawar K, et al. IFSO (International Federation for Surgery of Obesity and Metabolic Disorders) consensus conference statement on one-anastomosis gastric bypass (OAGB-MGB): results of a modified delphi study. Obes Surg. 2020;30(5):1625-1634. doi:10.1007/s11695-020-04519-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chevallier JM, Arman GA, Guenzi M, et al. One thousand single anastomosis (omega loop) gastric bypasses to treat morbid obesity in a 7-year period: outcomes show few complications and good efficacy. Obes Surg. 2015;25(6):951-958. doi:10.1007/s11695-014-1552-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rheinwalt K, Plamper A, R&#xfc;ckbeil M, Kroh A, Neumann U, Ulmer T. One anastomosis gastric bypass-mini-gastric bypass (OAGB-MGB) versus Roux-en-Y Gastric Bypass (RYGB)-a mid-term cohort study with 612 patients. Obes Surg. 2020;30(4):1230-1240. doi:10.1007/s11695-019-04250-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robert M, Espalieu P, Pelascini E, et al. Efficacy and safety of one anastomosis gastric bypass versus Roux-en-Y gastric bypass for obesity (YOMEGA): a multicentre, randomised, open-label, non-inferiority trial. Lancet. 2019;393(10178):1299-1309. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(19)30475-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashrafi D, Osland E, Memon MA. Bariatric surgery and gastroesophageal reflux disease. Ann Transl Med. 2020;8(Suppl 1):S11. doi:10.21037/atm.2019.09.15</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mou D, DeVries C, Pater N, et al. BODY-Q patient-reported outcomes measure (PROM) to assess sleeve gastrectomy vs. Roux-en-Y gastric bypass: eating behavior, eating-related distress, and eating-related symptoms. Surg Endosc. 2021;35(8):4609-4617. doi:10.1007/s00464-020-07886-w</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Steenackers N, Van Der Schueren B, Mertens A, et al. Iron deficiency after bariatric surgery: What is the real problem? Proc Nutr Soc. 2018;77(4):445-455. doi:10.1017/S0029665118000149</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerrier JB, Dietch ZC, Schirmer BD, Hallowell PT. Laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy is associated with lower 30-day morbidity versus laparoscopic gastric bypass: an analysis of the American College of Surgeons NSQIP. Obes Surg. 2018;28(11):3567-3572. doi:10.1007/s11695-018-3396-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bevilacqua LA, Obeid NR, Yang J, et al. Incidence of GERD, esophagitis, Barretts esophagus, and esophageal adenocarcinoma after bariatric surgery. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2020;16(11):1828-1836. doi:10.1016/j.soard.2020.06.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altinoz A, Maasher A, Jouhar F, et al. Diagnostic laparoscopy is more accurate than Computerized Tomography for internal hernia after Roux-en-Y gastric bypass. Am J Surg. 2020;220(1):214-216. doi:10.1016/j.amjsurg.2019.10.034</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scarpellini E, Arts J, Karamanolis G, et al. International consensus on the diagnosis and management of dumping syndrome. Nat Rev Endocrinol. 2020;16(8):448-466. doi:10.1038/s41574-020-0357-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohapatra S, Gangadharan K, Pitchumoni CS. Malnutrition in obesity before and after bariatric surgery. Dis Mon. 2020;66(2):100866 doi:10.1016/j.disamonth.2019.06.008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Rutte PWJ, Aarts EO, Smulders JF, Nienhuijs SW. Nutrient deficiencies before and after sleeve gastrectomy. Obes Surg. 2014;24(10):1639-1646. doi:10.1007/s11695-014-1225-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Dahmani KM, Kayyal YM, Gariballa S. Transient severe hypercholesterolemia following bariatric surgery treated successfully with increased food intake. Nutrition. 2016;32(3):394-396. doi:10.1016/j.nut.2015.10.016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Osdol AD, Grover BT, Borgert AJ, Kallies KJ, Kothari SN. Impact of laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass versus sleeve gastrectomy on postoperative lipid values. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2017;13(3):399-403. doi:10.1016/j.soard.2016.09.031</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaska L, Sledzinski T, Chomiczewska A, Dettlaff-Pokora A, Swierczynski J. Improved glucose metabolism following bariatric surgery is associated with increased circulating bile acid concentrations and remodeling of the gut microbiome. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22(39):8698-8719. doi:10.3748/wjg.v22.i39.8698</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molinero N, Ruiz L, S&#xe1;nchez B, Margolles A, Delgado S. Intestinal bacteria interplay with bile and cholesterol metabolism: implications on host physiology. Front Physiol. 2019;10:185 doi:10.3389/fphys.2019.00185</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mika A, Kaska L, Proczko-Stepaniak M, et al. Evidence that the length of bile loop determines serum bile acid concentration and glycemic control after bariatric surgery. Obes Surg. 2018;28(11):3405-3414. doi:10.1007/s11695-018-3314-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mika A, Stepnowski P, Kaska L, et al. A comprehensive study of serum odd- and branched-chain fatty acids in patients with excess weight. Obesity. 2016;24(8):1669-1676. doi:10.1002/oby.21560</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakiet A, Wilczynski M, Rostkowska O, et al. The effect of one anastomosis gastric bypass on branched-chain fatty acid and branched-chain amino acid metabolism in subjects with morbid obesity. Obes Surg. 2020;30(1):304-312. doi:10.1007/s11695-019-04157-z</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin C, V&#xe5;ge V, Mj&#xf8;s SA, Kvalheim OM. Changes in serum fatty acid levels during the first year after bariatric surgery. Obes Surg. 2016;26(8):1735-1742. doi:10.1007/s11695-015-1980-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pakiet A, Hali&#x144;ski &#x141;P, Rostkowska O, et al. The effects of one-anastomosis gastric bypass on fatty acids in the serum of patients with morbid obesity. Obes Surg. 2021. Published online July 13, 2021:1-8;31(10):4264-4271. doi:10.1007/s11695-021-05531-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mika A, Sledzinski T. Alterations of specific lipid groups in serum of obese humans: a review. Obes Rev. 2017;18(2):247-272. doi:10.1111/obr.12475</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cronan JE, Thomas J. Chapter 17 bacterial fatty acid synthesis and its relationships with polyketide synthetic pathways. Methods Enzymol. 2009;459(B):395-433. doi:10.1016/S0076-6879(09)04617-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace M, Green CR, Roberts LS, et al. Enzyme promiscuity drives branched-chain fatty acid synthesis in adipose tissues. Nat Chem Biol. 2018;14(11):1021-1031. doi:10.1038/s41589-018-0132-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tremaroli V, Karlsson F, Werling M, et al. Roux-en-Y gastric bypass and vertical banded gastroplasty induce long-term changes on the human gut microbiome contributing to fat mass regulation. Cell Metab. 2015;22(2):228-238. doi:10.1016/j.cmet.2015.07.009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rios-Covian D, Gonz&#xe1;lez S, Nogacka AM, et al. An overview on fecal branched short-chain fatty acids along human life and as related with body mass index: associated dietary and anthropometric factors. Front Microbiol. 2020;11:973. doi:10.3389/fmicb.2020.00973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sledzinski T, Mika A, Stepnowski P, et al. Identification of cyclopropaneoctanoic acid 2-hexyl in human adipose tissue and serum. Lipids. 2013;48(8):839-848. doi:10.1007/s11745-013-3806-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mika A, Stepnowski P, Chmielewski M, et al. Increased serum level of cyclopropaneoctanoic acid 2-hexyl in patients with hypertriglyceridemia-related disorders. Lipids. 2016;51(7):867-873. doi:10.1007/s11745-016-4141-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lolli V, DallAsta M, del Rio D, Caligiani A. Identification of cyclopropane fatty acids in human plasma after controlled dietary intake of specific foods. Nutrients. 2020;12(11):1-10. doi:10.3390/nu12113347</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grogan DW, Cronan JE Jr. Cyclopropane ring formation in membrane lipids of bacteria. Microbiol Mol Biol Rev. 1997;61(4):429-441.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliphant K, Allen-Vercoe E. Macronutrient metabolism by the human gut microbiome: major fermentation by-products and their impact on host health. Microbiome. 2019;7(1):91. doi:10.1186/s40168-019-0704-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan KK, Tremaroli V, Clemmensen C, et al. FXR is a molecular target for the effects of vertical sleeve gastrectomy. Nature. 2014;509(7499):183-188. doi:10.1038/nature13135</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaji I, Karaki SI, Kuwahara A. Short-chain fatty acid receptor and its contribution to glucagon-like peptide-1 release. Digestion. 2014;89(1):31-36. doi:10.1159/000356211</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen HK, Gudmundsdottir V, Nielsen HB, et al. Human gut microbes impact host serum metabolome and insulin sensitivity. Nature. 2016;535(7612):376-381. doi:10.1038/nature18646</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galarregui C, Cantero I, Marin-Alejandre BA, et al. Dietary intake of specific amino acids and liver status in subjects with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: fatty liver in obesity (FLiO) study. Eur J Nutr. 2021;60(4):1769-1780. doi:10.1007/s00394-020-02370-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao J, Xu K, Liu H, et al. Impact of the gut microbiota on intestinal immunity mediated by tryptophan metabolism. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2018;8:13. doi:10.3389/fcimb.2018.00013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, Young K. Indole production by the tryptophanase TnaA in Escherichia coli is determined by the amount of exogenous tryptophan. Microbiology. 2013;159(Pt_2):402-410. doi:10.1099/mic.0.064139-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shoar S, Saber AA. Long-term and midterm outcomes of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy versus Roux-en-Y gastric bypass: a systematic review and meta-analysis of comparative studies. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2017;13(2):170-180. doi:10.1016/j.soard.2016.08.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luijten JCHBM, Vugts G, Nieuwenhuijzen GAP, Luyer MDP. The importance of the microbiome in bariatric surgery: a systematic review. Obes Surg. 2019;29(7):2338-2349. doi:10.1007/s11695-019-03863-y</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oduro-Donkor D, Turner MC, Farnaud S, et al. Modification of fecal microbiota as a mediator of effective weight loss and metabolic benefits following bariatric surgery. Expert Rev Endocrinol Metab. 2020;15(5):363-373. doi:10.1080/17446651.2020.1801412</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ju&#xe1;rez-Fern&#xe1;ndez M, Rom&#xe1;n-Sag&#xfc;illo S, Porras D, et al. Long-term effects of bariatric surgery on gut microbiota composition and faecal metabolome related to obesity remission. Nutrients. 2021;13(8):2519. doi:10.3390/nu13082519</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu D, Shu XO, Howard EF, Long J, English WJ, Flynn CR. Fecal metagenomics and metabolomics reveal gut microbial changes after bariatric surgery. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2020;16(11):1772-1782. doi:10.1016/j.soard.2020.06.032</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen N, Caix&#xe0;s A, Ahlers M, et al. Longitudinal changes of microbiome composition and microbial metabolomics after surgical weight loss in individuals with obesity. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2019;15(8):1367-1373. doi:10.1016/j.soard.2019.05.038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crovesy L, Masterson D, Rosado EL. Profile of the gut microbiota of adults with obesity: a systematic review. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2020;74(9):1251-1262. doi:10.1038/s41430-020-0607-6</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deb&#xe9;dat J, Cl&#xe9;ment K, Aron-Wisnewsky J. Gut microbiota dysbiosis in human obesity: impact of bariatric surgery. Curr Obes Rep. 2019;8(3):229-242. doi:10.1007/s13679-019-00351-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Izhak M, Eshel A, Cohen R, et al. Projection of gut microbiome pre- and post-bariatric surgery to predict surgery outcome. mSystems. 2021;6(3):e0136720. doi:10.1128/mSystems.01367-20. e01367-20</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee CJ, Florea L, Sears CL, et al. Changes in gut microbiome after bariatric surgery versus medical weight loss in a pilot randomized trial. Obes Surg. 2019;29(10):3239-3245. doi:10.1007/s11695-019-03976-4</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S&#xe1;nchez-Alcoholado L, Guti&#xe9;rrez-Repiso C, G&#xf3;mez-P&#xe9;rez AM, Garc&#xed;a-Fuentes E, Tinahones FJ, Moreno-Indias I. Gut microbiota adaptation after weight loss by Roux-en-Y gastric bypass or sleeve gastrectomy bariatric surgeries. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2019;15(11):1888-1895. doi:10.1016/j.soard.2019.08.551</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kong LC, Tap J, Aron-Wisnewsky J, et al. Gut microbiota after gastric bypass in human obesity: increased richness and associations of bacterial genera with adipose tissue genes. Am J Clin Nutr. 2013;98(1):16-24. doi:10.3945/ajcn.113.058743</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campisciano G, Cason C, Palmisano S, Comar M. Bariatric surgery drives major rearrangements of the intestinal microbiota including the biofilm composition. Front Biosci (Elite Ed). 2018;10(3):495-505. doi:10.2741/e836</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitlik SD, Koren O. How holobionts get sick-toward a unifying scheme of disease. Microbiome. 2017;5(1):64. doi:10.1186/s40168-017-0281-7</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulker I, Yildiran H. The effects of bariatric surgery on gut microbiota in patients with obesity: a review of the literature. Biosci Microbiota, Food Heal. 2019;38(1):3-9. doi:10.12938/bmfh.18-018</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ilhan ZE, DiBaise JK, Dautel SE, et al. Temporospatial shifts in the human gut microbiome and metabolome after gastric bypass surgery. NPJ Biofilms Microbiomes. 2020;6(1):12. doi:10.1038/s41522-020-0122-5</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palleja A, Kashani A, Allin KH, et al. Roux-en-Y gastric bypass surgery of morbidly obese patients induces swift and persistent changes of the individual gut microbiota. Genome Med. 2016;8(1):67. doi:10.1186/s13073-016-0312-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams TD, Davidson LE, Litwin SE, et al. Weight and metabolic outcomes 12 years after gastric bypass. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(12):1143-1155. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1700459</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen L, Roager HM, Astrup A, Hjorth MF. Microbial enterotypes in personalized nutrition and obesity management. Am J Clin Nutr. 2018;108(4):645-651. doi:10.1093/ajcn/nqy175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Y, Ma N, Song P, et al. Grape seed proanthocyanidin affects lipid metabolism via changing gut microflora and enhancing propionate production in weaned pigs. J Nutr. 2019;149(9):1523-1532. doi:10.1093/jn/nxz102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m L, Lindroos A-K, Peltonen M, et al. Lifestyle, diabetes, and cardiovascular risk factors 10 years after bariatric surgery. N Engl J Med. 2004;351(26):2683-2693. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa035622</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Costea PI, Hildebrand F, Manimozhiyan A, et al. Enterotypes in the landscape of gut microbial community composition. Nat Microbiol. 2017;3(1):8-16. doi:10.1038/s41564-017-0072-8</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ley RE, Turnbaugh PJ, Klein S, Gordon JI. Human gut microbes associated with obesity. Nat Cell Biol. 2006;444(7122):1022-1023. doi:10.1038/4441022a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ojeda P, Bobe A, Dolan K, Leone V, Martinez K. Nutritional modulation of gut microbiota - the impact on metabolic disease pathophysiology. J Nutr Biochem. 2016;28:191-200. doi:10.1016/j.jnutbio.2015.08.013</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook J, Lehne C, Weiland A, et al. Gut microbiota, probiotics and psychological states and behaviors after bariatric surgery-a systematic review of their interrelation. Nutrients. 2020;12(8):1-21. doi:10.3390/nu12082396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu G, Song M. Recent advances in the mechanisms underlying the beneficial effects of bariatric and metabolic surgery. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2021;17(1):231-238. doi:10.1016/j.soard.2020.08.028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palmisano S, Campisciano G, Silvestri M, et al. Changes in gut microbiota composition after bariatric surgery: a new balance to decode. J Gastrointest Surg. 2020;24(8):1736-1746. doi:10.1007/s11605-019-04321-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karami R, Kermansaravi M, Pishgahroudsari M, Talebi M, Mohammadzadeh N, Pazouki A. Changes in gut microbial flora after Roux-en-Y gastric bypass and sleeve gastrectomy and their effects on post-operative weight loss. Updates Surg. 2021;73(4):1493-1499. doi:10.1007/s13304-020-00900-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aron-Wisnewsky J, Prifti E, Belda E, et al. Major microbiota dysbiosis in severe obesity: fate after bariatric surgery. Gut. 2019;68(1):70-82. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2018-316103</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rivera-Piza A, Lee SJ. Effects of dietary fibers and prebiotics in adiposity regulation via modulation of gut microbiota. Appl Biol Chem. 2020;63(1):2. doi:10.1186/s13765-019-0482-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rinott E, Youngster I, Yaskolka Meir A, et al. Effects of diet-modulated autologous fecal microbiota transplantation on weight regain. Gastroenterology. 2021;160(1):158-173.e10. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2020.08.041</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bach Knudsen K, Laerke H, Hedemann M, et al. Impact of diet-modulated butyrate production on intestinal barrier function and inflammation. Nutrients. 2018;10(10):1499. doi:10.3390/nu10101499</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez J, Hiel S, Delzenne NM. Metformin: old friend, new ways of action-implication of the gut microbiome? Curr Opin Clin Nutr Metab Care. 2018;21(4):294-301. doi:10.1097/MCO.0000000000000468</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ballini A, Scacco S, Boccellino M, Santacroce L, Arrigoni R. Microbiota and obesity: where are we now? Biology (Basel). 2020;9(12):415. doi:10.3390/biology9120415</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan SS, Goldenshluger A, Globus I, et al. Nutritional recommendations for adult bariatric surgery patients: clinical practice. Adv Nutr. 2017;8(2):382-394. doi:10.3945/an.116.014258</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun L, Ma L, Ma Y, Zhang F, Zhao C, Nie Y. Insights into the role of gut microbiota in obesity: pathogenesis, mechanisms, and therapeutic perspectives. Protein Cell. 2018;9(5):397-403. doi:10.1007/s13238-018-0546-3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein J, Stier C, Raab H, Weiner R. Review article: the nutritional and pharmacological consequences of obesity surgery. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2014;40(6):582-609. doi:10.1111/apt.12872</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Q, Liang Q, Balakrishnan B, Belobrajdic DP, Feng QJ, Zhang W. Role of dietary nutrients in the modulation of gut microbiota: a narrative review. Nutrients. 2020;12(2):381. doi:10.3390/nu12020381</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tap J, Furet J-P, Bensaada M, et al. Gut microbiota richness promotes its stability upon increased dietary fibre intake in healthy adults. Environ Microbiol. 2015;17(12):4954-4964. doi:10.1111/1462-2920.13006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sonnenburg E, Sonnenburg J. Starving our microbial self: the deleterious consequences of a diet deficient in microbiota-accessible carbohydrates. Cell Metab. 2014;20(5):779-786. doi:10.1016/j.cmet.2014.07.003</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garc&#xed;a-Peris P, Velasco C, Lozano M, et al. Effect of a mixture of inulin and fructo-oligosaccharide on Lactobacillus and Bifidobacterium intestinal microbiota of patients receiving radiotherapy: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Nutr Hosp. 2012;27(6):1908-1915. doi:10.3305/nh.2012.27.6.5992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carvalho-Wells A, Helmolz K, Nodet C, et al. Determination of the in vivo prebiotic potential of a maize-based whole grain breakfast cereal: a human feeding study. Br J Nutr. 2010;104(9):1353-1356. doi:10.1017/S0007114510002084</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gill HK, Wu GY. Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and the metabolic syndrome: Effects of weight loss and a review of popular diets. Are low carbohydrate diets the answer? World J Gastroenterol. 2006;12(3):345-353. doi:10.3748/wjg.v12.i3.345</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moiz&#xe9; VL, Pi-Sunyer X, Mochari H, Vidal J. Nutritional pyramid for post-gastric bypass patients. Obes Surg. 2010;20(8):1133-1141. doi:10.1007/s11695-010-0160-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolters M, Ahrens J, Roman&#xed;-P&#xe9;rez M, et al. Dietary fat, the gut microbiota, and metabolic health-a systematic review conducted within the MyNewGut project. Clin Nutr. 2019;38(6):2504-2520. doi:10.1016/j.clnu.2018.12.024</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos-Marcos JA, Haro C, Vega-Rojas A, et al. Sex differences in the gut microbiota as potential determinants of gender predisposition to disease. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2019;63(7):e1800870. doi:10.1002/mnfr.201800870</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farr&#xe0;s M, Martinez-Gili L, Portune K, et al. Modulation of the gut microbiota by olive oil phenolic compounds: implications for lipid metabolism, immune system, and obesity. Nutrients. 2020;12(8):2200. doi:10.3390/nu12082200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellenger J, Bellenger S, Escoula Q, Bidu C, Narce M. N-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids: an innovative strategy against obesity and related metabolic disorders, intestinal alteration and gut microbiota dysbiosis. Biochimie. 2019;159:66-71. doi:10.1016/j.biochi.2019.01.017</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanick JI, Apovian C, Brethauer S, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for the perioperative nutrition, metabolic, and nonsurgical support of patients undergoing bariatric procedures-2019 update: cosponsored by American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists/American College of Endocrinology, The Obesity Society, American Society for Metabolic &amp; Bariatric Surgery, Obesity Medicine Association, and American Society of Anesthesiologists. Surg Obes Relat Dis. 2020;16(2):175-247. doi:10.1016/j.soard.2019.10.025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong TS, Luu K, Lagishetty V, et al. A high protein calorie restriction diet alters the gut microbiome in obesity. Nutrients. 2020;12(10):3221. doi:10.3390/nu12103221</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sprong R, Schonewille A, van der Meer R. Dietary cheese whey protein protects rats against mild dextran sulfate sodium-induced colitis: role of mucin and microbiota. J Dairy Sci. 2010;93(4):1364-1371. doi:10.3168/jds.2009-2397</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McAllan L, Skuse P, Cotter P, et al. Protein quality and the protein to carbohydrate ratio within a high fat diet influences energy balance and the gut microbiota in C57BL/6J mice. PLoS ONE. 2014;9(2):e88904. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0088904</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruzzi M, Duboc H, Gronnier C, et al. Long-term evaluation of biliary reflux after experimental one-anastomosis gastric bypass in rats. Obes Surg. 2017;27(4):1119-1122. doi:10.1007/s11695-017-2577-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aggarwal S, Bhambri A, Singla V, Dash N, Sharma A. Adenocarcinoma of oesophagus involving gastro-oesophageal junction following mini-gastric bypass/one anastomosis gastric bypass. J Minim Access Surg. 2020;16(2):175-178. doi:10.4103/jmas.JMAS_320_18</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner NRF, Ramos MRZ, de Oliveira Carlos L, et al. Effects of probiotics supplementation on gastrointestinal symptoms and SIBO after Roux-en-Y gastric bypass: a prospective, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Obes Surg. 2020;31(1):143-150. doi:10.1007/s11695-020-04900-x</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>