<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39318407</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1758-5732</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Shoulder &amp; elbow</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Shoulder Elbow</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>ChatGPT is capable of providing satisfactory responses to frequently asked questions regarding total shoulder arthroplasty.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>407</StartPage><EndPage>412</EndPage><MedlinePgn>407-412</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/17585732241246560</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The rising prominence of artificial intelligence in healthcare has revolutionized patient access to medical information. This cross-sectional study sought to assess if ChatGPT could satisfactorily address common patient questions about total shoulder arthroplasty (TSA).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ten commonly encountered questions in TSA practice were selected and posed to ChatGPT. Each response was assessed for accuracy and clarity using the Mika et al. scoring system, which ranges from "excellent response not requiring clarification" to "unsatisfactory response requiring substantial clarification," and a modified DISCERN score. The readability was further evaluated using the Flesch Reading Ease Score and the Flesch-Kincaid Grade Level.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The mean Mika et al. score was 2.93, corresponding to an overall subjective rating of "satisfactory but requiring moderate clarification." The mean DISCERN score was 46.60, which is considered "fair." The readability analysis suggested that the responses were at a college-graduate level, higher than the recommended level for patient educational materials.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Our results suggest that ChatGPT has the potential to supplement the collaborative decision-making process between patients and experienced orthopedic surgeons for TSA-related inquiries. Ultimately, while tools like ChatGPT can enhance traditional patient education methods, they should not replace direct consultations with medical professionals.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yeramosu</LastName><ForeName>Teja</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7263-6134</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Virginia Commonwealth University School of Medicine, Richmond, VA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">6886</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johns</LastName><ForeName>William L</ForeName><Initials>WL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rothman Institute Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Thomas Jefferson University Hospital, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">542915</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Onor</LastName><ForeName>Gabriel</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rothman Institute Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Thomas Jefferson University Hospital, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">542915</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menendez</LastName><ForeName>Mariano E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Oregon Shoulder Institute, Medford, OR, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Namdari</LastName><ForeName>Surena</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rothman Institute Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Thomas Jefferson University Hospital, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">542915</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hammoud</LastName><ForeName>Sommer</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Rothman Institute Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Thomas Jefferson University Hospital, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">542915</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>17</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Shoulder Elbow</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101506589</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1758-5732</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ChatGPT</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anatomic</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">frequently asked questions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reverse</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total shoulder arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors of the manuscript have no conflicts of interest for the contents of this current work. The authors listed below have the following disclosures listed which can be found on the AAOS website. SH: American Orthopaedic Society for Sports Medicine Board or committee member; Arthrex, Inc: Paid consultant; Orthopaedic Learning Center: Board or committee member; Perry Initiative: Board or committee member. SN: ACI Clinical: Paid Consultant; Aevumed: IP royalties, Stock or stock options; Arthrex, Inc: Research support; Biederman Motech: Paid consultant, paid presenter or speaker; CLEI Diagnostics, stock or stock options; Coracoid Solutions, stock or stock options; DePuy, A John &amp; Johnson Company, research support; Enovis, IP royalties, paid consultant, pai presenter or speaker, research support; HealthExl, stock or stock options; Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery-American, editorial or governing board; MediFlix, IP royalties, stock or stock options; Philadelphia Orthopaedic Society, Board or committee member; Roche, research support; Parvizi Surgical Innovations, stock or stock options; Saunders/Mosby-Elsevier, publishing royalties, financial or material support; Shoulder &amp;Elbow, editor or governing board; SLACK Incorporated, publishing royalties, financial or material support; Smith &amp; Nephew, research support; Stryker, research support; SurgiWipe, stock or stock options; Synthes, paid consultant; Tangen, stock or stock options; Tigon, IP royalties; Wolters Kluwer Health &#x2013; Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, publishing royalties, financial or material support; Zimmer, research support.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>4</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39318407</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11418678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/17585732241246560</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_17585732241246560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Groot OQ, Ogink PT, Lans A, et al. Machine learning prediction models in orthopedic surgery: a systematic review in transparent reporting. J Orthop Res 2022; 40: 475&#x2013;483.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9290012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33734466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mika AP, Martin JR, Engstrom SM, et al. Assessing ChatGPT responses to common patient questions regarding total hip arthroplasty. J Bone Joint Surg Am 2023; 105: 1519&#x2013;1526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37459402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns WL, Kellish A, Farronato D, et al. ChatGPT can offer satisfactory responses to common patient questions regarding elbow ulnar collateral ligament reconstruction. Arthrosc Sports Med Rehabil 2024; 6: 100893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10875189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38375341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns WL, Martinazzi BJ, Miltenberg B, et al. ChatGPT provides unsatisfactory responses to frequently asked questions regarding Anterior Cruciate Ligament reconstruction. Arthroscopy 2024; S0749-8063(24): 00061-000666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38311261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurley ET, Crook BS, Lorentz SG, et al. Evaluation high-quality of information from ChatGPT (Artificial Intelligence-Large Language Model) artificial intelligence on shoulder stabilization surgery. Arthroscopy 2024; 40: 726&#x2013;731.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37567487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warren E, Jr, Hurley ET, Park CN, et al. Evaluation of information from artificial intelligence on rotator cuff repair surgery. JSES Int 2024; 8: 53&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10837709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38312282</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charnock D, Shepperd S, Needham G, et al. DISCERN: an instrument for judging the quality of written consumer health information on treatment choices. J Epidemiol Community Health 1999; 53: 105&#x2013;111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1756830</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10396471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weil AG, Bojanowski MW, Jamart J, et al. Evaluation of the quality of information on the internet available to patients undergoing cervical spine surgery. World Neurosurg 2014; 82: e31&#x2013;e39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23142585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flesch RF, Gould AJ. The art of readable writing. 1st ed. New York, NY: Harper, 1949.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh TM, Volsko TA. Readability assessment of internet-based consumer health information. Respir Care 2008; 53: 1310&#x2013;1315.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18811992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawrence C, Lazarus M, Abboud J, et al. Prospective comparative study of preoperative expectations and postoperative outcomes in anatomic and reverse shoulder arthroplasty. Joints 2019; 7: 159&#x2013;164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8253618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34235380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razmjou H, Christakis M, Nam D, et al. Assessing appropriateness for shoulder arthroplasty using a shared decision-making process. J Shoulder Elb Arthroplast 2023; 7: 24715492231167104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10064165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37008201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCormick JR, Kruchten MC, Mehta N, et al. Internet search analytics for shoulder arthroplasty: what questions are patients asking? Clin Shoulder Elb 2023; 26: 55&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10030990</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36919508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stelzer JW, Wellington IJ, Trudeau MT, et al. Readability assessment of patient educational materials for shoulder arthroplasty from top academic orthopedic institutions. JSES Int 2022; 6: 44&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8811415</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35141675</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Puzzitiello RN, Colliton EM, Swanson DP, et al. Patients with limited health literacy have worse preoperative function and pain control and experience prolonged hospitalizations following shoulder arthroplasty. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2022; 31: 2473&#x2013;2480.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35671931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiss BD. Health literacy and patient safety: help patients understand. 2nd ed. Chicago, IL: American Medical Association Foundation, 2007.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>