<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">40299104</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2161-3311</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>29</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Current nutrition reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Curr Nutr Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>New Approaches to the Treatment of Severe Obesity-Prehabilitation as the Key to Success.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>64</StartPage><MedlinePgn>64</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13668-025-00652-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Bariatric surgery (BS) has emerged as a crucial and effective treatment for severe obesity (SO), providing significant and sustained weight loss and improving comorbidities. Optimizing perioperative careparticularly through structured prehabilitation is crucial for improving surgical outcomes and long-term weight management. This review examines the role of prehabilitation, nutrition, psychological support, physical activity, and pharmacologic treatment in improving the effectiveness of BS.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Despite the benefits of prehabilitation, there are significant differences in the way it is implemented in different healthcare centers. Protocols vary widely in terms of duration, components and intensity, leading to inconsistencies in patient preparation and postoperative recovery. Many patients still do not receive multidisciplinary support from dietitians, psychologists or physiotherapists prior to surgery, which can affect long-term outcomes. Barriers to effective prehabilitation include a lack of standardized guidelines, insufficient healthcare resources and limited patient adherence due to lack of awareness, low motivation or logistical constraints. Despite its proven benefits, structured prehabilitation lasting at least 3-6&#xa0;months is not available to all patients, as access remains unequal and suboptimal in many healthcare settings. Prehabilitation is an important but underutilized component of BS preparation. Standardizing protocols and ensuring multidisciplinary, patient-centered support are essential to maximizing surgical benefit. Overcoming barriers such as healthcare system limitations, patient motivation and knowledge gaps is critical to integrating prehabilitation into routine bariatric care. This review emphasizes the need for evidence-based, multimodal prehabilitation strategies to improve perioperative care and long-term outcomes for BS patients.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Budny</LastName><ForeName>Aleksandra</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8478-0224</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hypertension and Diabetology, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Janczy</LastName><ForeName>Agata</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8504-6213</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Food Commodity Science, Faculty of Health Sciences With the Institute of Maritime and Tropical Medicine, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mika</LastName><ForeName>Adriana</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2877-5652</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Environmental Analytics, Faculty of Chemistry, University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland. adriana.mika@gumed.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Biochemistry, Medical University of Gdansk, Gdansk, Poland. adriana.mika@gumed.edu.pl.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>Young Creator of Science: 01/65034/01/643/501/0005281</GrantID><Agency>Medical University of Gdansk</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2021/43/B/NZ5/00039</GrantID><Agency>National Science Centre of Poland</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>29</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Curr Nutr Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101587480</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2161-3311</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D050110" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bariatric Surgery</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009767" MajorTopicYN="Y">Obesity, Morbid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Loss</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Preoperative Care</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bariatric surgery</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diet</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunonutrition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacotherapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prehabilitation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40299104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13668-025-00652-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13668-025-00652-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><ReferenceList><Title>Papers of particular interest, published recently, have been highlight</Title><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO European regional obesity report 2022. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wharton S, Lau DCW, Vallis M, Sharma AM, Biertho L, Campbell-Scherer D, et al. Obesity in adults: a clinical practice guideline. CMAJ [Internet]. 2020 [cited 2024 May 3];192:E875&#x2013;91. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32753461/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Durrer Schutz D, Busetto L, Dicker D, Farpour-Lambert N, Pryke R, Toplak H, et al. European Practical and Patient-Centred Guidelines for Adult Obesity Management in Primary Care. Obes Facts [Internet]. 2019 [cited 2024 May 3];12:40&#x2013;66. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/30673677/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stenberg E, F DRFL, O&#x2019;Kane M, Liem R, Pournaras DJ, Salminen P, et al. Guidelines for perioperative care in bariatric surgery: Enhanced recovery after surgery (ERAS) society recommendations: A 2021 Update. World J Surg [Internet]. 2022;46. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34984504 .&#xa0;Accessed 18&#xa0;Apr 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lobo DN, Pavel Sko&#x159;epa, Gomez D, Greenhaff PL. Prehabilitation: high-quality evidence is still required. Br J Anaesth [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Mar 3];130:9&#x2013;14. Available from: https://www.bjanaesthesia.org/action/showFullText?pii=S0007091222005517</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banasiewicz T, Kobiela J, Cwali&#x144;ski J. Recommendations on the use of prehabilitation, i.e. comprehensive preparation of the patient for surgery. Polish Journal of Surgery [Internet]. 2023;95:62&#x2013;91. Available from: https://ppch.pl/gicid/01.3001.0053.8854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sibley D, Chen M, West MA, Matthew AG, Mina DS, Randall I. Potential mechanisms of multimodal prehabilitation effects on surgical complications: a narrative review. Applied Physiology, Nutrition and Metabolism [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Mar 3];48:639&#x2013;56. Available from: https://www.researchgate.net/publication/371010421_Potential_mechanisms_of_multimodal_prehabilitation_effects_on_surgical_complications_a_narrative_review</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budzy&#x144;ski A, Major P, G&#x142;uszek S, Kaseja K, Koszutski T, Le&#x15b;niak S, et al. Polskie rekomendacje w zakresie chirurgii bariatrycznej i metabolicznej. 2016 [cited 2024 May 5]; Available from: https://ruj.uj.edu.pl/xmlui/handle/item/139211</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanick JI, Apovian C, Brethauer S, Garvey WT, Joffe AM, Kim J, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for the perioperative nutrition, metabolic, and nonsurgical support of patients undergoing bariatric procedures - 2019 update: cosponsored by American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists/American College of Endocrinology, The Obesity Society, American Society for Metabolic &amp; Bariatric Surgery, Obesity Medicine Association, and American Society of Anesthesiologists. Surg Obes Relat Dis [Internet]. 2020;16. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31917200</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchwald H, Avidor Y, Braunwald E, Jensen MD, Pories W, Fahrbach K, et al. Bariatric surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA [Internet]. 2004;292. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15479938</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m L, Peltonen M, Jacobson P, Sj&#xf6;str&#xf6;m CD, Karason K, Wedel H, et al. Bariatric surgery and long-term cardiovascular events. JAMA [Internet]. 2012 [cited 2024 May 3];307:56&#x2013;65. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/22215166/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiggins T, Guidozzi N, Welbourn R, Ahmed AR, Markar SR. Association of bariatric surgery with all-cause mortality and incidence of obesity-related disease at a population level: A systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS Med [Internet]. 2020 [cited 2024 May 3];17. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32722673/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glazer S, Biertho L. Bariatric Surgery: Selection &amp; Preoperative Workup [Internet]. 2020. Available from: https://obesitycanada.ca/guidelines/preop .&#xa0;Accessed 18 Apr 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorell A, MacCormick AD, Awad S, Reynolds N, Roulin D, Demartines N, et al. Guidelines for Perioperative Care in Bariatric Surgery: Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) Society Recommendations. World J Surg [Internet]. 2016;40. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26943657</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz M, Acheson AG, Auerbach M, Besser M, Habler O, Kehlet H, et al. International consensus statement on the peri-operative management of anaemia and iron deficiency. Anaesthesia [Internet]. 2017;72. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27996086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klek S, Rymarowicz J, Sobocki J, Banasiewicz T, P&#x119;dziwiatr M, Dziki A, et al. Recommendations for modern perioperative care for elective surgery: consensus of panel of exerts. Pol Przegl Chir [Internet]. 2023;95. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36808061</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho C, Samwil SNM, Kahairudin Z. Pre-habilitation with exercise and high whey-protein-based meal replacement therapy promotes weight loss and preserve muscle mass before bariatric surgery. Asian J Surg [Internet]. 2023;46:3716&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.asjsur.2023.03.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36931924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M CB, Bilic-Curcic I, Mrzljak A, S CV, Cigrovski V. Prehabilitation of overweight and obese patients with dysglycemia awaiting bariatric surgery: Predicting the success of obesity treatment. World J Diabetes [Internet]. 2022;13. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36578866</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herrera-Santelices A, Arg&#xfc;ello-Florencio G, Westphal G, N NJ, Zamun&#xe9;r AR. Effects of Supervised Physical Exercise as Prehabilitation on Body Composition, Functional Capacity and Quality of Life in Bariatric Surgery Candidates: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. J Clin Med [Internet]. 2022;11. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36079027</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeske P, Wojtera B, Banasiewicz T. Prehabilitation &#x2013; Current Role in Surgery. Polish Journal of Surgery [Internet]. 2022;94:64&#x2013;72. Available from: https://ppch.pl/gicid/pdf/01.3001.0015.7340</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weimann A, Braga M, Carli F, Higashiguchi T, H&#xfc;bner M, Klek S, et al. ESPEN practical guideline: Clinical nutrition in surgery. Clin Nutr [Internet]. 2021;40. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34242915</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mastino D, Robert M, Betry C, Laville M, Gouillat C, Disse E. Bariatric Surgery Outcomes in Sarcopenic Obesity. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2016;26. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26926186</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kabata P. Wp&#x142;yw suplementacji &#x17c;ywieniowej na przygotowanie pacjenta do zabiegu u chorych bez klinicznych cech niedo&#x17c;ywienia - badanie prospektywne randomizowane. 2013; Available from: https://pbc.gda.pl/dlibra/doccontent?id=33561</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry R, Herbert G, Atkinson C, England C, Northstone K, Baos S, et al. Pre-admission interventions (prehabilitation) to improve outcome after major elective surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open [Internet]. 2021;11. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34593498</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown Jennifer CC. Canadian Adult Obesity Clinical Practice Guidelines: Medical Nutrition Therapy in Obesity Management [Internet]. obesitycanada.ca/guidelines; 2022. Available from: https://obesitycanada.ca/guidelines/nutrition/ .&#xa0;Accessed 18 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#x105;k-Sosnowska M, Bogda&#x144;ski P, Chomiuk T, Ga&#x142;&#x105;zka-Sobotka M, Holecki M, BM. Zalecenia kliniczne dotycz&#x105;ce post&#x119;powania u chorych na oty&#x142;o&#x15b;&#x107; 2022&#x2013;stanowisko Polskiego Towarzystwa Leczenia Oty&#x142;o&#x15b;ci. Medycyna Praktyczna [Internet]. 2022; Available from: https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=pl&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=WS+5%2F2022+Medycyna+Praktyczna%3A+Zalecenia+kliniczne+dotycz%C4%85ce+post%C4%99powania+u+chorych+na+oty%C5%82o%C5%9B%C4%87+2022+&amp;btnG =</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabesh MR, Eghtesadi M, Abolhasani M, Maleklou F, Ejtehadi F, Alizadeh Z. Nutrition, Physical Activity, and Prescription of Supplements in Pre- and Post-bariatric Surgery Patients: An Updated Comprehensive Practical Guideline. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2023;33:2557&#x2013;72. Available from: https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-023-06703-2</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naseer F, Shabbir A, Livingstone B, Price R, Syn NL, Flannery O. The Efficacy of Energy-Restricted Diets in Achieving Preoperative Weight Loss for Bariatric Patients: a Systematic Review. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2018;28. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30121854</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bettini S, Belligoli A, Fabris R, Busetto L. Diet approach before and after bariatric surgery. Rev Endocr Metab Disord [Internet]. 2020;21. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32734395</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holderbaum M, Casagrande DS, Sussenbach S, Buss C. Effects of very low calorie diets on liver size and weight loss in the preoperative period of bariatric surgery: a systematic review. Surg Obes Relat Dis [Internet]. 2018;14. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29239795</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J van W, Bakker N, Doodeman HJ, Jansma EP, Bonjer HJ, Houdijk AP. Preoperative Methods to Reduce Liver Volume in Bariatric Surgery: a Systematic Review. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2016;26. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26123526</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jastrz&#x119;bska W, Boniecka I, Szostak-W&#x119;gierek D. Validity and efficacy of diets used for preoperative weight reduction among patients qualified for bariatric surgery. Pol Przegl Chir [Internet]. 2021;93. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33949320</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alger-Mayer S, Polimeni JM, Malone M. Preoperative weight loss as a predictor of long-term success following Roux-en-Y gastric bypass. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2008;18. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18392899</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Edholm D, Kullberg J, Haenni A, Karlsson FA, Ahlstr&#xf6;m A, Hedberg J, et al. Preoperative 4-week low-calorie diet reduces liver volume and intrahepatic fat, and facilitates laparoscopic gastric bypass in morbidly obese. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2011;21. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21181291</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonz&#xe1;lez-P&#xe9;rez J, S&#xe1;nchez-Leenheer S, Delgado AR, Gonz&#xe1;lez-Vargas L, D&#xed;az-Zamudio M, Montejo G, et al. Clinical impact of a 6-week preoperative very low calorie diet on body weight and liver size in morbidly obese patients. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2013;23. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23681317</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isom KA, Andromalos L, Ariagno M, Hartman K, Mogensen KM, Stephanides K, et al. Nutrition and metabolic support recommendations for the bariatric patient. Nutr Clin Pract [Internet]. 2014;29. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25288251</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nielsen L V, Nielsen MS, Schmidt JB, Pedersen SD, Sj&#xf6;din A. Efficacy of a liquid low-energy formula diet in achieving preoperative target weight loss before bariatric surgery. J Nutr Sci [Internet]. 2016;5. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27293559</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yumuk V, Tsigos C, Fried M, Schindler K, Busetto L, Micic D, et al. European Guidelines for Obesity Management in Adults. Obes Facts [Internet]. 2015;8. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26641646</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salminen pklaaklmnapgbewkps. Consensus on definitions and clinical practice guidelines for patients considering metabolic-bariatric surgery. nternational Federation for the Surgery of Obesity and metabolic disorders; 2023. Available from: https://bariatriarf.ru/wp-content/uploads/2023/10/IFSO-CONSENSUS-CONFERENCE-2023-BOOK.pdf .&#xa0;Accessed 18 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenberg D, Shikora SA, Aarts E, Aminian A, Angrisani L, Cohen R V., et al. 2022 American Society of Metabolic and Bariatric Surgery (ASMBS) and International Federation for the Surgery of Obesity and Metabolic Disorders (IFSO) Indications for Metabolic and Bariatric Surgery. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2024 May 3];33:3&#x2013;14. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36336720/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Osland E, Powlesland H, Guthrie T, Lewis CA, Memon MA. Micronutrient management following bariatric surgery: the role of the dietitian in the postoperative period. Ann Transl Med [Internet]. 2020;8. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32309413</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lupoli R, Lembo E, Saldalamacchia G, Avola CK, Angrisani L, Capaldo B. Bariatric surgery and long-term nutritional issues. World J Diabetes [Internet]. 2017;8. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29204255</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A AM, Shakoor H, Ali HI, Feehan J, S ADA, L CI, et al. The Effects of Bariatric Surgery on Vitamin B Status and Mental Health. Nutrients [Internet]. 2021;13. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33923999</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busetto L, Dicker D, Azran C, Batterham RL, Farpour-Lambert N, Fried M, et al. Practical Recommendations of the Obesity Management Task Force of the European Association for the Study of Obesity for the Post-Bariatric Surgery Medical Management. Obes Facts [Internet]. 2017;10. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29207379</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscogiuri G, M EG, Colao A, Hassapidou M, Yumuk V, Busetto L. European Guidelines for Obesity Management in Adults with a Very Low-Calorie Ketogenic Diet: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Obes Facts [Internet]. 2021;14. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33882506</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albanese A, Prevedello L, Markovich M, Busetto L, Vettor R, Foletto M. Pre-operative Very Low Calorie Ketogenic Diet (VLCKD) vs. Very Low Calorie Diet (VLCD): Surgical Impact. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2019;29. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30251088</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leonetti F, Campanile FC, Coccia F, Capoccia D, Alessandroni L, Puzziello A, et al. Very low-carbohydrate ketogenic diet before bariatric surgery: prospective evaluation of a sequential diet. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2015;25. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25005809</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colangeli L, Gentileschi P, Sbraccia P, Guglielmi V. Ketogenic Diet for Preoperative Weight Reduction in Bariatric Surgery: A Narrative Review. Nutrients [Internet]. 2022;14. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36079867</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Correa LL, Moretti A, M de SPA, Dinis L, F de SM, Tostes I, et al. Effectiveness and Safety of a Very Low-Calorie Ketogenic Diet on Weight Regain Following Bariatric Surgery. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2021;31. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34558025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>S SD, Goldenshluger A, Globus I, Schweiger C, Kessler Y, G KS, et al. Nutritional Recommendations for Adult Bariatric Surgery Patients: Clinical Practice. Adv Nutr [Internet]. 2017;8. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28298280</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherf-Dagan S, Sinai T, Goldenshluger A, Globus I, Kessler Y, Schweiger C, et al. Nutritional Assessment and Preparation for Adult Bariatric Surgery Candidates: Clinical Practice. Adv Nutr [Internet]. 2021;12. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33040143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscogiuri G, Verde L, Sulu C, Katsiki N, Hassapidou M, Frias-Toral E, et al. Mediterranean Diet and Obesity-related Disorders: What is the Evidence? Curr Obes Rep [Internet]. 2022;11. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36178601</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erdem NZ, Ozelgun D, Taskin HE, Avsar FM. Comparison of a pre-bariatric surgery very low-calorie ketogenic diet and the Mediterranean diet effects on weight loss, metabolic parameters, and liver size reduction. Sci Rep [Internet]. 2022;12. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36450844</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gastaldo I, Casas R, Moiz&#xe9; V. Clinical Impact of Mediterranean Diet Adherence before and after Bariatric Surgery: A Narrative Review. Nutrients [Internet]. 2022;14. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/35057574</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrea L, Verde L, Schiavo L, Sarno G, Camajani E, Iannelli A, et al. Very Low-Calorie Ketogenic Diet (VLCKD) as Pre-Operative First-Line Dietary Therapy in Patients with Obesity Who Are Candidates for Bariatric Surgery. Nutrients [Internet]. 2023;15. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/37111126</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Gu Y, Guo T, Li Y, Cai H. Perioperative immunonutrition for gastrointestinal cancer: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Surg Oncol [Internet]. 2012;21. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22317969</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cerantola Y, H&#xfc;bner M, Grass F, Demartines N, Sch&#xe4;fer M. Immunonutrition in gastrointestinal surgery. Br J Surg [Internet]. 2011;98. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/20931620</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz-Tovar J, Zubiaga L, Diez M, Murcia A, Boix E, Mu&#xf1;oz JL, et al. Preoperative Regular Diet of 900 kcal/day vs Balanced Energy High-Protein Formula vs Immunonutrition Formula: Effect on Preoperative Weight Loss and Postoperative Pain, Complications and Analytical Acute Phase Reactants After Laparoscopic Sleeve Gastrectomy. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2016;26. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26358120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schiavo L, Scalera G, Sergio R, G DS, Pilone V, Barbarisi A. Clinical impact of Mediterranean-enriched-protein diet on liver size, visceral fat, fat mass, and fat-free mass in patients undergoing sleeve gastrectomy. Surg Obes Relat Dis [Internet]. 2015;11. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26052081</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>C&#x4d1;toi AF, Vodnar DC, Corina A, Nikolic D, Citarrella R, P&#xe9;rez-Mart&#xed;nez P, et al. Gut Microbiota, Obesity and Bariatric Surgery: Current Knowledge and Future Perspectives. Curr Pharm Des [Internet]. 2019;25. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31298152</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pascale A, Marchesi N, Marelli C, Coppola A, Luzi L, Govoni S, et al. Microbiota and metabolic diseases. Endocrine [Internet]. 2018;61. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29721802</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ciob&#xe2;rc&#x103; D, C&#x103;toi AF, Cop&#x103;escu C, Miere D, Cri&#x219;an G. Bariatric Surgery in Obesity: Effects on Gut Microbiota and Micronutrient Status. Nutrients [Internet]. 2020;12. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31963247</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Astrup A, B&#xfc;gel S. Overfed but undernourished: recognizing nutritional inadequacies/deficiencies in patients with overweight or obesity. Int J Obes (Lond) [Internet]. 2019;43. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29980762</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buchwald H. The evolution of metabolic/bariatric surgery. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2014;24. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25008469</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodard GA, Encarnacion B, Downey JR, Peraza J, Chong K, Hernandez-Boussard T, et al. Probiotics improve outcomes after Roux-en-Y gastric bypass surgery: a prospective randomized trial. J Gastrointest Surg [Internet]. 2009;13. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/19381735</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Y, Zheng Y, Kuang L, Yang K, Xie J, Liu X, et al. Effects of probiotics in patients with morbid obesity undergoing bariatric surgery: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Int J Obes (Lond) [Internet]. 2023;47. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/37674033</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Toole PW, Marchesi JR, Hill C. Next-generation probiotics: the spectrum from probiotics to live biotherapeutics. Nat Microbiol [Internet]. 2017;2. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28440276</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azad MAK, Sarker M, Li T, Yin J. Probiotic Species in the Modulation of Gut Microbiota: An Overview. Biomed Res Int [Internet]. 2018;2018. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29854813</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner NRF, Zaparolli MR, Cruz MRR, Schieferdecker MEM, Campos ACL. postoperative changes in intestinal microbiota and use of probiotics in Roux-EN-Y Gastric bypass and sleeve vertical gastrectomy: an integrative review. Arq Bras Cir Dig [Internet]. 2018;31. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30539975</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherf-Dagan S, Zelber-Sagi S, Zilberman-Schapira G, Webb M, Buch A, Keidar A, et al. Probiotics administration following sleeve gastrectomy surgery: a randomized double-blind trial. Int J Obes (Lond) [Internet]. 2018;42. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28852205</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang PJ, Lee WJ, Tseng PH, Lee PH, Lin MT, Yang WS. Bariatric surgery decreased the serum level of an endotoxin-associated marker: lipopolysaccharide-binding protein. Surg Obes Relat Dis [Internet]. 2014;10. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24713521</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X, Zhang P, Zhang X. Probiotics Regulate Gut Microbiota: An Effective Method to Improve Immunity. Molecules [Internet]. 2021;26. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34641619</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galyean S, Sawant D, Shin AC. Immunometabolism, Micronutrients, and Bariatric Surgery: The Use of Transcriptomics and Microbiota-Targeted Therapies. Mediators Inflamm [Internet]. 2020;2020. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33281501</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos JM, Mathew MS, Shah N, Pajuelo-Vasquez R, Mistry AM, Heindl SE. Pre and Post-Operative Alterations of the Gastrointestinal Microbiome Following Bariatric Surgery. Cureus [Internet]. 2021;13. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33680599</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagliardi A, Totino V, Cacciotti F, Iebba V, Neroni B, Bonfiglio G, et al. Rebuilding the Gut Microbiota Ecosystem. Int J Environ Res Public Health [Internet]. 2018;15. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30087270</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cambi MPC, Baretta GAP. BARIATRIC DIET GUIDE: PLATE MODEL TEMPLATE FOR BARIATRIC SURGERY PATIENTS. Arq Bras Cir Dig [Internet]. 2018;31. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29972403</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moiz&#xe9; VL, Pi-Sunyer X, Mochari H, Vidal J. Nutritional Pyramid for Post-gastric Bypass Patients. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2010;20:1133&#x2013;41. Available from: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11695-010-0160-9</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mechanick JI, Apovian C, Brethauer S, Garvey WT, Joffe AM, Kim J, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for the perioperative nutrition, metabolic, and nonsurgical support of patients undergoing bariatric procedures - 2019 update: cosponsored by American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists/American College of Endocrinology, The Obesity Society, American Society for Metabolic &amp; Bariatric Surgery, Obesity Medicine Association, and American Society of Anesthesiologists. Surg Obes Relat Dis [Internet]. 2020 [cited 2024 May 3];16:175&#x2013;247. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31917200/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parrott JM, Craggs-Dino L, Faria SL, O&#x2019;Kane M. The Optimal Nutritional Programme for Bariatric and Metabolic Surgery. Curr Obes Rep [Internet]. 2020;9. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32451780</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endevelt R, Ben-Assuli O, Klain E, Zelber-Sagi S. The role of dietician follow-up in the success of bariatric surgery. Surg Obes Relat Dis [Internet]. 2013 [cited 2024 Jun 5];9:963&#x2013;8. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/23499190/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushner R. HD. Bariatric surgery: Postoperative nutritional management - UpToDate [Internet]. 2024. Available from: https://www-1uptodate-1com-1i8qj42tj015f.han.gumed.edu.pl/contents/bariatric-surgery-postoperative-nutritional-management/print?sectionName=DIET%20AND%20TEXTURE%20PROGRESSION&amp;search=Bariatric%20surgery:%20Postoperative%20nutritional%20management&amp;topicRef=88610&amp;anchor=H4&amp;source=see_link .&#xa0;Accessed 18&#xa0;Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouwels S, Stokmans RA, Willigendael EM, Nienhuijs SW, Rosman C, B van R, et al. Preoperative exercise therapy for elective major abdominal surgery: a systematic review. Int J Surg [Internet]. 2014;12. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24325942</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pouwels S, Department of Surgery Eindhoven the Netherlands CH, Department of Epidemiology Maastricht University Maastricht the Netherlands CRS, Wit M, Department of Physiotherapy Eindhoven the Netherlands CH, Teijink JAW, et al. Aspects of Exercise before or after Bariatric Surgery: A Systematic Review. Obes Facts [Internet]. 2024;8:132&#x2013;46. Available from: https://karger.com/ofa/article-pdf/8/2/132/3302501/000381201.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bull FC, Al-Ansari SS, Biddle S, Borodulin K, Buman MP, Cardon G, et al. World Health Organization 2020 guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. Br J Sports Med [Internet]. 2020;54. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33239350</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fried M, Yumuk V, Oppert JM, Scopinaro N, Torres A, Weiner R, et al. Interdisciplinary European guidelines on metabolic and bariatric surgery. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2014 [cited 2024 May 3];24:42&#x2013;55. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/24081459/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seku&#x142;a M, Kwiatkowski A, Pa&#x15b;nik K. Znaczenie przedoperacyjnej oceny psychologicznej chorych na oty&#x142;o&#x15b;&#x107; olbrzymi&#x105; leczonych chirurgicznie. 2020; Available from: https://repozytorium.wim.mil.pl/handle/20.500.12564/198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Usubini AG, Cattivelli R, Villa V, Varallo G, Granese V, Pietrabissa G, et al. Psychological Considerations for Bariatric Surgery. 2020; Available from: https://www.intechopen.com/chapters/73992</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sogg S, Lauretti J, West-Smith L. Recommendations for the presurgical psychosocial evaluation of bariatric surgery patients. Surg Obes Relat Dis [Internet]. 2016;12. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/27179400</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralph AF, Brennan L, Byrne S, Caldwell B, Farmer J, Hart LM, et al. Management of eating disorders for people with higher weight: clinical practice guideline. J Eat Disord [Internet]. 2022;10. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/35978344</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keski-Rahkonen A. Epidemiology of binge eating disorder: prevalence, course, comorbidity, and risk factors. Curr Opin Psychiatry [Internet]. 2021;34. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34494972</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarwer DB, Allison KC, Wadden TA, Ashare R, Spitzer JC, McCuen-Wurst C, et al. Psychopathology, disordered eating, and impulsivity as predictors of outcomes of bariatric surgery. Surg Obes Relat Dis [Internet]. 2019;15. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/30858009</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shiau Judy BL. Bariatric Surgery: Postoperative Management [Internet]. Canadian Adult Obesity Clinical Practice Guidelines. https://obesitycanada.ca/guidelines/postop .; 2020. Available from: https://obesitycanada.ca/guidelines/postop/ .&#xa0;Accessed 18 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salminen P, Kow L, Aminian A, Kaplan LM, Nimeri A, Prager G, et al. IFSO Consensus on Definitions and Clinical Practice Guidelines for Obesity Management-an International Delphi Study. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2024 [cited 2024 May 3];34:30&#x2013;42. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37999891/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Lancet Diabetes Endocrinology. Redefining obesity: advancing care for better lives. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol [Internet]. 2025 [cited 2025 Mar 5]; Available from: http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/39826562</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chakhtoura M, Haber R, Ghezzawi M. Pharmacotherapy of obesity: an update on the available medications and drugs under investigation. EClinicalMedicine [Internet]. 2023;58. Available from: http://dx.doi.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole TJ, Lobstein T. Extended international (IOTF) body mass index cut-offs for thinness, overweight and obesity. Pediatr Obes [Internet]. 2012;7. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/22715120</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jeong D, Priefer R. Anti-obesity weight loss medications: Short-term and long-term use. Life Sci [Internet]. 2022;306. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/35870619</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A USFD. Orange Book: Approved drug products with therapeutic equivalence evaluations [Internet]. 2014. Available from: https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cder/ob/results_product.cfm?Appl_Type=N&amp;Appl_No=206321#32118 .&#xa0;Accessed 18 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A USFD. FDA Approves New Drug Treatment for Chronic Weight Management, First Since 2014 | FDA [Internet]. 2021. Available from: https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-approves-new-drug-treatment-chronic-weight-management-first-2014 .&#xa0;Accessed 18 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agency EM. European public assessment report for wegovy [Internet]. EMA; 2022. Available from: https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/wegovy .&#xa0;Accessed 18 Apr 2025</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mounjaro | European Medicines Agency (EMA) [Internet]. [cited 2025 Mar 2]. Available from: https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/mounjaro</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Muscogiuri G, Cignarelli A, Giorgino F, Prodam F, Santi D, Tirabassi G, et al. GLP-1: benefits beyond pancreas. J Endocrinol Invest [Internet]. 2014;37. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25107343</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heppner KM, Kirigiti M, Secher A, Paulsen SJ, Buckingham R, Pyke C, et al. Expression and distribution of glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor mRNA, protein and binding in the male nonhuman primate (Macaca mulatta) brain. Endocrinology [Internet]. 2015;156. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25380238</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bansal AB, Y AK. Orlistat. n: StatPearls [Internet] Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing [Internet]. 2022; Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31194359</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Billes SK, Sinnayah P, Cowley MA. Naltrexone/bupropion for obesity: an investigational combination pharmacotherapy for weight loss. Pharmacol Res [Internet]. 2014;84. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24754973</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenway FL, Whitehouse MJ, Guttadauria M, Anderson JW, Atkinson RL, Fujioka K, et al. Rational design of a combination medication for the treatment of obesity. Obesity (Silver Spring) [Internet]. 2009;17. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/18997675</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussain A, Farzam K. Setmelanotide. 2023; Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jordan J, Astrup A, Engeli S, Narkiewicz K, Day WW, Finer N. Cardiovascular effects of phentermine and topiramate: a new drug combination for the treatment of obesity. J Hypertens [Internet]. 2014;32. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24621808</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haws R, Brady S, Davis E, Fletty K, Yuan G, Gordon G, et al. Effect of setmelanotide, a melanocortin-4 receptor agonist, on obesity in Bardet-Biedl syndrome. Diabetes Obes Metab [Internet]. 2020;22. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32627316</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inoue K, Maeda N, Fujishima Y, Fukuda S, Nagao H, Yamaoka M, et al. Long-term impact of liraglutide, a glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) analogue, on body weight and glycemic control in Japanese type 2 diabetes: an observational study. Diabetol Metab Syndr [Internet]. 2014;6. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25237400</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller TD, Finan B, Bloom SR, D&#x2019;Alessio D, Drucker DJ, Flatt PR, et al. Glucagon-like peptide 1 (GLP-1). Mol Metab [Internet]. 2019;30. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31767182</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kastin AJ, Akerstrom V, Pan W. Interactions of glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1) with the blood-brain barrier. J Mol Neurosci [Internet]. 2002;18. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/11931352</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holst JJ. On the physiology of GIP and GLP-1. Hormone and Metabolic Research [Internet]. 2004 [cited 2025 Mar 7];36:747&#x2013;54. Available from: http://www.thieme-connect.com/products/ejournals/html/ https://doi.org/10.1055/s-2004-826158</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Block C, Bailey C, Wysham C, Hemmingway A, Allen SE, Peleshok J. Tirzepatide for the treatment of adults with type 2 diabetes: An endocrine perspective. Diabetes Obes Metab [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Mar 7];25:3&#x2013;17. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/35929488/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller TD, Bl&#xfc;her M, Tsch&#xf6;p MH, DiMarchi RD. Anti-obesity drug discovery: advances and challenges. Nat Rev Drug Discov [Internet]. 2022;21. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34815532</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yuya Fujishima NM. Chapter 15 - Effect of Glucagon-Like Peptide 1 Receptor Agonists on Visceral Fat Adiposity, Appetite, and Food Preference,. In: Watson RR, editor. Nutrition in the Prevention and Treatment of Abdominal Obesity [Internet]. Academic Press; 2014. p. 167&#x2013;76. Available from: http://dx.doi.org/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rao RS, Kini S. GIP and bariatric surgery. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2011 [cited 2025 Mar 7];21:244&#x2013;52. Available from: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11695-010-0305-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu QK. Mechanisms of action and therapeutic applications of GLP-1 and dual GIP/GLP-1 receptor agonists. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) [Internet]. 2024 [cited 2025 Mar 7];15. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/39114288/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>le Roux CW, Zhang S, Aronne LJ, Kushner RF, Chao AM, Machineni S, et al. Tirzepatide for the treatment of obesity: Rationale and design of the SURMOUNT clinical development program. Obesity (Silver Spring) [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Mar 7];31:96&#x2013;110. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36478180/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino DM, Greenway FL, Khalid U, O&#x2019;Neil PM, Rosenstock J, S&#xf8;rrig R, et al. Effect of Weekly Subcutaneous Semaglutide vs Daily Liraglutide on Body Weight in Adults With Overweight or Obesity Without Diabetes: The STEP 8 Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA [Internet]. 2022;327. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/35015037</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deng Y, Park A, Zhu L, Xie W, Pan CQ. Effect of semaglutide and liraglutide in individuals with obesity or overweight without diabetes: a systematic review. Ther Adv Chronic Dis [Internet]. 2022;13. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/35813188</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadden TA, Chao AM, Moore M, Tronieri JS, Gilden A, Amaro A, et al. The Role of Lifestyle Modification with Second-Generation Anti-obesity Medications: Comparisons, Questions, and Clinical Opportunities. Curr Obes Rep [Internet]. 2023;12. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/38041774</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xed;as JP, Davies MJ, Rosenstock J, P&#xe9;rez Manghi FC, Fern&#xe1;ndez Land&#xf3; L, Bergman BK, et al. Tirzepatide versus Semaglutide Once Weekly in Patients with Type 2 Diabetes. New England Journal of Medicine [Internet]. 2021 [cited 2025 Mar 9];385:503&#x2013;15. Available from: https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2107519</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jastreboff AM, Aronne LJ, Ahmad NN, Wharton S, Connery L, Alves B, et al. Tirzepatide Once Weekly for the Treatment of Obesity. New England Journal of Medicine [Internet]. 2022 [cited 2025 Mar 9];387:205&#x2013;16. Available from: https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2206038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrichsen M, Breitschaft A, Tadayon S, Wizert A, Skovgaard D. The effect of semaglutide 2.4 mg once weekly on energy intake, appetite, control of eating, and gastric emptying in adults with obesity. Diabetes Obes Metab [Internet]. 2021;23. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33269530</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>J van C, Sloth B, Jensen CB, Flint A, Blaak EE, Saris WH. Effects of the once-daily GLP-1 analog liraglutide on gastric emptying, glycemic parameters, appetite and energy metabolism in obese, non-diabetic adults. Int J Obes (Lond) [Internet]. 2014;38. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23999198</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knudsen LB, Lau J. The Discovery and Development of Liraglutide and Semaglutide. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) [Internet]. 2019;10. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/31031702</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaman AM, Bain SC, Bakris GL, Buse JB, Idorn T, Mahaffey KW, et al. Effect of the Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 Receptor Agonists Semaglutide and Liraglutide on Kidney Outcomes in Patients With Type 2 Diabetes: Pooled Analysis of SUSTAIN 6 and LEADER. Circulation [Internet]. 2022;145. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34903039</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blundell J, Finlayson G, Axelsen M, Flint A, Gibbons C, Kvist T, et al. Effects of once-weekly semaglutide on appetite, energy intake, control of eating, food preference and body weight in subjects with obesity. Diabetes Obes Metab [Internet]. 2017;19. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28266779</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gabery S, Salinas CG, Paulsen SJ, Ahnfelt-R&#xf8;nne J, Alanentalo T, Baquero AF, et al. Semaglutide lowers body weight in rodents via distributed neural pathways. JCI Insight [Internet]. 2020;5. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/32213703</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell W, Song X, Mohamed Y, Walsh D, Parks EJ, McMahon TM, et al. Medications and conditions associated with weight loss in patients prescribed semaglutide based on real-world data. Obesity (Silver Spring) [Internet]. 2023;31. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/37593896</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jastreboff AM, Aronne LJ, Ahmad NN, Wharton S, Connery L, Alves B, et al. Tirzepatide Once Weekly for the Treatment of Obesity. New England Journal of Medicine [Internet]. 2022 [cited 2025 Mar 7];387:205&#x2013;16. Available from: https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMoa2206038</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>le Roux CW, Hankosky ER, Wang D, Malik R, Yu M, Hickey A, et al. Tirzepatide 10 and 15 mg compared with semaglutide 2.4 mg for the treatment of obesity: An indirect treatment comparison. Diabetes Obes Metab [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Mar 7];25:2626&#x2013;33. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37344384/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>W le RC, Astrup A, Fujioka K, Greenway F, Lau DCW, L VG, et al. 3 years of liraglutide versus placebo for type 2 diabetes risk reduction and weight management in individuals with prediabetes: a randomised, double-blind trial. Lancet [Internet]. 2017;389. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28237263</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wharton S, Batterham RL, Bhatta M, Buscemi S, Christensen LN, Frias JP, et al. Two-year effect of semaglutide 2.4 mg on control of eating in adults with overweight/obesity: STEP 5. Obesity (Silver Spring) [Internet]. 2023;31. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36655300</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vilsb&#xf8;ll T, Lindahl C&#xd8;, Nielsen NF, Tikkanen CK. Real-world impact of once-weekly subcutaneous semaglutide after 2 years of follow-up: Results from a nationwide observational study in people with type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab [Internet]. 2023;25. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36809678</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies MJ, Bergenstal R, Bode B, Kushner RF, Lewin A, Skj&#xf8;th T V, et al. Efficacy of Liraglutide for Weight Loss Among Patients With Type 2 Diabetes: The SCALE Diabetes Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA [Internet]. 2015;314. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26284720</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilding JPH, Batterham RL, Davies M, F VGL, Kandler K, Konakli K, et al. Weight regain and cardiometabolic effects after withdrawal of semaglutide: The STEP 1 trial extension. Diabetes Obes Metab [Internet]. 2022;24. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/35441470</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grunvald E, Shah R, Hernaez R, Chandar AK, Pickett-Blakely O, Teigen LM, et al. AGA Clinical practice guideline on pharmacological interventions for adults with obesity. Gastroenterology. 2022;163:1198&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2022.08.045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36273831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammedi K, Belhatem N, Berentzen TL, Catarig AM, Potier L. Once-weekly semaglutide use in patients with type 2 diabetes: Results from the SURE France multicentre, prospective, observational study. Diabetes Obes Metab [Internet]. 2023;25. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/36869853</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubino D, Abrahamsson N, Davies M, Hesse D, Greenway FL, Jensen C, et al. Effect of Continued Weekly Subcutaneous Semaglutide vs Placebo on Weight Loss Maintenance in Adults With Overweight or Obesity: The STEP 4 Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA [Internet]. 2021;325. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/33755728</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pi-Sunyer X, Astrup A, Fujioka K, Greenway F, Halpern A, Krempf M, et al. A Randomized, Controlled Trial of 3.0 mg of Liraglutide in Weight Management. N Engl J Med [Internet]. 2015;373. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26132939</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadden TA, Butryn ML, Wilson C. Lifestyle modification for the management of obesity. Gastroenterology [Internet]. 2007;132. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17498514</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorgojo-Mart&#xed;nez JJ, Mezquita-Raya P, Carretero-G&#xf3;mez J, Castro A, Cebri&#xe1;n-Cuenca A, de Torres-S&#xe1;nchez A, et al. Clinical Recommendations to Manage Gastrointestinal Adverse Events in Patients Treated with Glp-1 Receptor Agonists: A Multidisciplinary Expert Consensus. J Clin Med [Internet]. 2022 [cited 2025 Mar 7];12. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/36614945/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad NN, Robinson S, Kennedy-Martin T, Poon JL, Kan H. Clinical outcomes associated with anti-obesity medications in real-world practice: A systematic literature review. Obes Rev [Internet]. 2021;22. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/34423889</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lautenbach A, Kantowski T, Wagner J, Mann O, Stoll F, Aberle J. Sustained weight loss with semaglutide once weekly in patients without type 2 diabetes and post-bariatric treatment failure. Clin Obes [Internet]. 2023;13. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/37364260</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal M, Qasem W, Hamshari F, Dsouza C, Alqallaf N, Otiku P, et al. Effectiveness and tolerability of liraglutide for the management of weight regain following sleeve gastrectomy. Obes Sci Pract [Internet]. 2023;10. Available from: https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/38259354</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jamal M, Alhashemi M, Dsouza C, Al-hassani S, Qasem W, Almazeedi S, et al. Semaglutide and Tirzepatide for the Management of Weight Recurrence After Sleeve Gastrectomy: A Retrospective Cohort Study. Obes Surg [Internet]. 2024 [cited 2025 Mar 8];34:1324&#x2013;32. Available from: https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11695-024-07137-0</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Society of Anesthesiologists Consensus-Based Guidance on Preoperative Management of Patients (Adults and Children) on Glucagon-Like Peptide-1 (GLP-1) Receptor Agonists | American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) [Internet]. [cited 2025 Mar 8]. Available from: https://www.asahq.org/about-asa/newsroom/news-releases/2023/06/american-society-of-anesthesiologists-consensus-based-guidance-on-preoperative</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van der Velde M, van der Leeden M, Geleijn E, Veenhof C, Valkenet K. What moves patients to participate in prehabilitation before major surgery? A mixed methods systematic review. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act [Internet]. 2023 [cited 2025 Mar 5];20. Available from: https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/37344902/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>A Healthy Weight for Ireland: Obesity Policy and Action Plan [Internet]. Available from: https://www.hse.ie/eng/about/who/cspd/ncps/obesity/ .&#xa0;Accessed 18 Apr 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specialized obesity centers (CSO) | Sant&#xe9;.fr [Internet]. [cited 2025 Mar 5]. Available from: https://www.sante.fr/les-centres-specialises-obesite-cso</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medicines and surgery | Overweight and obesity management | Guidance | NICE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oty&#x142;o&#x15b;&#x107;. Skala zjawiska i konsekwencje. Za&#x142;o&#x17c;enia do stworzenia planu strategicznego redukcji oty&#x142;o&#x15b;ci w Polsce [Internet]. [cited 2025 Mar 7]. Available from: https://izwoz.lazarski.pl/projekty-badawcze/otylosc-skala-zjawiska-i-konsekwencje-zalozenia-do-stworzenia-planu-strategicznego-redukcji-otylosci-w-polsce/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podatek cukrowy - Inspekcja Jako&#x15b;ci Handlowej Artyku&#x142;&#xf3;w Rolno-Spo&#x17c;ywczych - Portal Gov.pl [Internet]. [cited 2025 Mar 7]. Available from: https://www.gov.pl/web/ijhars/podatek-cukrowy</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Sugar Tax in Italy - Fiscal Solutions [Internet]. [cited 2025 Mar 5]. Available from: https://www.fiscal-requirements.com/news/1574%20(dost%C4%99p%2018.08.2022%20r .).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Specialized obesity centers (CSO) | Sant&#xe9;.fr [Internet]. (2025). Available from: https://www.sante.fr/les-centres-specialises-obesite-cso &#xa0;</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medicines and surgery | Overweight and obesity management | Guidance | NICE.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oty&#x142;o&#x15b;&#x107;. Skala zjawiska i konsekwencje. Za&#x142;o&#x17c;enia do stworzenia planu strategicznego redukcji oty&#x142;o&#x15b;ci w Polsce [Internet]. 2025. Available from:&#xa0; https://izwoz.lazarski.pl/projekty-badawcze/otylosc-skala-zjawiska-i-konsekwencje-zalozenia-do-stworzenia-planu-strategicznego-redukcji-otylosci-w-polsce/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podatek cukrowy - Inspekcja Jako&#x15b;ci Handlowej Artyku&#x142;&#xf3;w Rolno-Spo&#x17c;ywczych - Portal Gov.pl [Internet]. 2025. Available from: https://www.gov.pl/web/ijhars/podatek-cukrowy</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Sugar Tax in Italy - Fiscal Solutions [Internet]. 2025. Available from: https://www.fiscal-requirements.com/news/1574%20(dost%C4%99p%2018.08.2022%20r</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>