<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40690110</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1869-6953</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>16</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Diabetes therapy : research, treatment and education of diabetes and related disorders</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Diabetes Ther</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Real-World Effectiveness of My Dose Coach&#x2122;-Assisted Basal Insulin Titration in People with Type 2 Diabetes in Saudi Arabia and Kuwait.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1829</StartPage><EndPage>1840</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1829-1840</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13300-025-01772-1</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">My Dose Coach (MDC) is a digital smartphone application approved in multiple countries, including Saudi Arabia and Kuwait, to help people with type 2 diabetes (T2D) titrate their basal insulin as per their clinician-guided, individualized diabetes care plan.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective, observational cohort analysis was conducted on MDC user data collected from 1 January 2021 to 1 June 2023 in Saudi Arabia and Kuwait. Primary outcome was change in fasting blood glucose (FBG). Key secondary outcomes included time to achieve FBG and HbA<sub>1c</sub> targets, and time to first hypoglycemia event. Outcomes were analyzed by FBG target status and frequency of MDC usage (high:&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;3 days per week; moderate:&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;1-&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;3 days per week; low:&#x2009;&#x2264;&#x2009;1 day per week).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Among all users (N&#x2009;=&#x2009;494), mean&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;SD FBG decrease was&#x2009;-44.4&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;72.5 mg/dL. Mean&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;SD time to achieve FBG target was 14.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;20.9 days and 12.8&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;18.8, 29.1&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;28.0, and 43.5&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;41.7 days for high-, moderate-, and low-frequency MDC users, respectively. Individualized FBG targets were achieved by 276 (55.9%) users, and high-frequency of MDC use was associated with better target achievement (p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.01). Mean&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;SD time to achieve HbA<sub>1c</sub> target was 48.0&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;40.5 days. Reduction in HbA<sub>1c</sub> was more in high-frequency MDC users (18.3%) than low-frequency MDC users (6.3%). Mean&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;SD time to the first hypoglycemia event was 4.86&#x2009;&#xb1;&#x2009;4.8 days. Hypoglycemia events were reported in only seven (1.4%) participants and not significantly correlated with MDC use frequency (p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.1431).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Current findings show that using MDC is associated with improved glycemic control in people with T2D in Saudi Arabia and Kuwait, with greater benefits observed with higher frequency MDC usage.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Sofiani</LastName><ForeName>Mohammed E</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4420-9378</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Endocrinology Unit, Internal Medicine Department, College of Medicine, King Saud University, 11461, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia. malsofiani@ksu.edu.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology, Diabetes, &amp; Metabolism, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA. malsofiani@ksu.edu.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Almehthel</LastName><ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>King Fahad Medical City, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al Ozairi</LastName><ForeName>Ebaa</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dasman Diabetes Institute, Dasman, Kuwait City, Kuwait.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sadik</LastName><ForeName>Jamaa</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sanofi, Dubai, United Arab Emirates.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hao</LastName><ForeName>Lichen</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sanofi, Bridgewater, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Akil</LastName><ForeName>Yasser</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Sanofi, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Diabetes Ther</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101539025</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1869-6961</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fasting blood glucose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoglycemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mobile applications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">My Dose Coach</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-monitoring blood glucose</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Conflict of Interest: Mohammed E. Al-Sofiani has served on an advisory panel for Abbott, Medtronic, Insulet, VitalAire, and Sanofi and has received honoraria for speaking and consultancy from Abbott, Eli Lilly, Medtronic, Novo Nordisk, Sanofi, and VitalAire; Mohamed Almehthel and Ebaa Al Ozairi have no conflicts of interest to declare; Jamaa Sadik, Lichen Hao, and Yasser Akil are employees of Sanofi and may hold Sanofi shares and/or stock. Ethical Approval: MDC users agreed to allow their anonymized data to be used retrospectively as part of the registration process. The study was approved by the Institutional Review Board of King Saud University (ref. no. 22/0251 /IRB), Saudi Arabia and Kuwait.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>20</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40690110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12399482</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13300-025-01772-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13300-025-01772-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>IDF Diabetes Atlas 11th Edition. Brussels, Belgium: International Diabetes Federation; 2025. IDF Diabetes Atlas | Global Diabetes Data &amp; Statistics. Accessed 9 April 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moradinazar M, Babakhani M, Rostami R, Shakiba M, Moradi A, Shakiba E. Epidemiological status of type 2 diabetes mellitus in the Middle East and North Africa, 1990&#x2013;2019. East Mediterr Health J. 2022;28(7):478&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35959663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>El-Kebbi IM, Bidikian NH, Hneiny L, Nasrallah MP. Epidemiology of type 2 diabetes in the Middle East and North Africa: challenges and call for action. World J Diabetes. 2021;12(9):1401&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8472500</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34630897</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alhagawy AJ, Yafei S, Hummadi A, et&#xa0;al. Barriers and attitudes of primary healthcare physicians to insulin initiation and intensification in Saudi Arabia. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2022;19(24):16794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9779059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36554673</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsuliman MA, Alotaibi SA, Zhang Q, Durgampudi PK. A systematic review of factors associated with uncontrolled diabetes and meta-analysis of its prevalence in Saudi Arabia since 2006. Diabetes Metab Res Rev. 2021;37(3): e3395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33448636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badedi M, Solan Y, Darraj H, et&#xa0;al. Factors associated with long-term control of type 2 diabetes mellitus. J Diabetes Res. 2016;2016:2109542.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5206435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28090538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdullah A, Alkandari A, Longenecker JC, et&#xa0;al. Glycemic control in Kuwaiti diabetes patients treated with glucose-lowering medication. Prim Care Diabetes. 2020;14(4):311&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31911041</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association. Glycemic targets: standards of medical care in diabetes, chapter 6. Diabetes Care. 2022;45(Suppl 1):S83&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34964868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell-Jones D, Pouwer F, Khunti K. Identification of barriers to insulin therapy and approaches to overcoming them. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2018;20(3):488&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5836933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29053215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polonsky WH, Arsenault J, Fisher L, et&#xa0;al. Initiating insulin: How to help people with type 2 diabetes start and continue insulin successfully. Int J Clin Pract. 2017;71(8): e12973.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5601201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28735508</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshoalah QM, Alfaraj NA, Krishanani MK, Khamis AH. Primary care physicians&#x2019; barriers to initiate insulin in Type 2 diabetes mellitus. A survey from the Eastern Province, Saudi Arabia. World Family Med. 2018;16(7):4&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peyrot M, Barnett AH, Meneghini LF, Schumm-Draeger PM. Insulin adherence behaviours and barriers in the multinational global attitudes of patients and physicians in insulin therapy study. Diabet Med. 2012;29(5):682&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3433794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22313123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulrhim S, Sankaralingam S, Ibrahim MIM, et&#xa0;al. Collaborative care model for diabetes in primary care settings in Qatar: a qualitative exploration among healthcare professionals and patients who experienced the service. BMC Health Serv Res. 2021;21(1):192.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7927378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33653324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balla SA, Shaaban KMA, Abdelaziz SI, Abeldafia NMA. Structural quality of diabetes services at primary health care in Khartoum state 2013: health centers versus specialized diabetes centers. Med Sci Healthcare J. 2015;10(8):41&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jabbar A, Abdallah K, Hassoun A, et&#xa0;al. Patterns and trends in insulin initiation and intensification among patients with Type 2 diabetes mellitus in the Middle East and North Africa region. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2019;149:18&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30653994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghafoor E, Masood S, Belkhadir J, et&#xa0;al. Availability and accessibility of diabetes-related technologies in IDF-MENA region. J Diabetol. 2022;13(5):81&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr D, Edelman S, Vespasiani G, Khunti K. New digital health technologies for insulin initiation and optimization for people with type 2 diabetes. Endocr Pract. 2022;28(8):811&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35452813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food and Drug Administration. My Dose Coach FDA approval. 2017. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/cdrh_docs/pdf16/K163099.pdf. Accessed 6 Sep 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kingdom of Saudi Arabia Food and Drug Authority, Medical Device Marketing Authorization, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>State of Kuwait Ministry of Health. Pharmaceutical and Herbal Medicines Registration and Control Administration. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al-Nozha OM, Alshareef EK, Aljawi AF, et&#xa0;al. Diabetic patients&#x2019; perspective about new technologies used in managing diabetes mellitus in Saudi Arabia: a cross-sectional study. Cureus. 2022;14(5): e25038.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9198967</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35719798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unnikrishnan AG, Viswanathan V, Zhou FL, et&#xa0;al. Impact of My Dose Coach app frequency of use on clinical outcomes in type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Ther. 2022;13(5):983&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8938735</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35316509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai X, Zhang F, Lin C, et&#xa0;al. Achieving effective and efficient basal insulin optimal management by using mobile health application (APP) for type 2 diabetes patients in China. Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. 2020;13:1327&#x2013;38.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7185643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32368124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franc S, Joubert M, Daoudi A, et&#xa0;al. Efficacy of two telemonitoring systems to improve glycaemic control during basal insulin initiation in patients with type 2 diabetes: The TeleDiab-2 randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2019;21(10):2327&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6771866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elshebiny A, Alali H, Alamer Z, et&#xa0;al. The incidence of hypoglycemia and its risk factors among diabetic patients in the Eastern Province of Saudi Arabia. Int J Med Dev Countries. 2021;5:614&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>AlKhaldi YM, AlKhaldi AY, AlQahtani AS, Al-Shahrani BS, Meshawi EA, Albishri BM. Incidence of hypoglycemia and its risk factors among diabetics during Ramadan in Abha city, Aseer Region. KSA J Family Med Prim Care. 2019;8(9):2793&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6820420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31681644</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies MJ, Aroda VR, Collins BS, et&#xa0;al. Management of hyperglycaemia in type 2 diabetes, 2022. A consensus report by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) and the European Association for the Study of Diabetes (EASD). Diabetologia. 2022;65(12):1925&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9510507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36151309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell-Jones D, Dauchy A, Delgado E, et&#xa0;al. Take control: a randomized trial evaluating the efficacy and safety of self-versus physician-managed titration of insulin glargine 300 U/mL in patients with uncontrolled type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2019;21(7):1615&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6767413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30851006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Al Slamah T, Nicholl BI, Alslail FY, Harris L, Melville CA, Kinnear D. Cultural adaptation of self-management of type 2 diabetes in Saudi Arabia (qualitative study). PLoS ONE. 2020;15(7): e0232904.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7386581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32722666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rafiullah M, David SK. Health apps usage and preferences among Saudi patients with diabetes: a survey. Int J Clin Pract. 2019;73(5): e13345.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30884059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alanzi T, Istepanian R, Philip N. Design and usability evaluation of social mobile diabetes management system in the Gulf Region. JMIR Res Protoc. 2016;5(3): e93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5057064</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27670696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abduo H, Curtain C, Othman N. Use of smartphone applications for diabetes management in Kuwait: a pilot study. J Consumer Health Internet. 2020;24(2):111&#x2013;25.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>