<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">36602040</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>01</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1932-2968</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>18</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Jul</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of diabetes science and technology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Diabetes Sci Technol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Evaluation of a Digital Health Tool for Titration of Basal Insulin in People With Type 2 Diabetes: Rationale and Design of a Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>946</StartPage><EndPage>955</EndPage><MedlinePgn>946-955</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/19322968221148756</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Optimal insulin titration is essential in helping people with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) to achieve adequate glycemic control. Barriers of people with diabetes to implementation of titration include lack of self-efficiency and self-management skills, increased diabetes-related distress, low treatment satisfaction, poor well-being, as well as concerns about hypoglycemia and insulin overdose. My Dose Coach is a digital health tool for optimizing titration of basal insulin that combines a smartphone app for patients with T2DM and a Web portal for healthcare professionals.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS/DESIGN" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This is a prospective, open-label, multicenter, randomized controlled parallel study conducted in approximately 50 centers in Germany that are specialized in the treatment of diabetes. Patients in the intervention group will use the titration app and will be registered on the Web portal by their treating physician. Control group patients will continue their current basal insulin titration without using the app. The primary outcome is the mean change in HbA1c levels at the 12-week follow-up. The secondary outcome measures include patient-reported outcomes such as diabetes-related distress, self-management, empowerment, self-efficacy, treatment satisfaction, and psychological well-being as well as fasting blood glucose values.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This digital health tool has been previously implemented in several independent pilot studies. The findings from this multicenter randomized controlled trial can provide further evidence supporting the effectiveness of this tool in patients with T2DM and serve as a basis for its clinical integration.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">German Register for Clinical Studies-DRKS-ID: DRKS00024861.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hermanns</LastName><ForeName>Norbert</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2903-2677</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute Diabetes Academy Mergentheim, Bad Mergentheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, University of Bamberg, Bamberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Center Mergentheim, Bad Mergentheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ehrmann</LastName><ForeName>Dominic</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute Diabetes Academy Mergentheim, Bad Mergentheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, University of Bamberg, Bamberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finke-Gr&#xf6;ne</LastName><ForeName>Katharina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute Diabetes Academy Mergentheim, Bad Mergentheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roos</LastName><ForeName>Timm</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute Diabetes Academy Mergentheim, Bad Mergentheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freckmann</LastName><ForeName>Guido</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0406-9529</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Forschungs- und Entwicklungsgesellschaft mbH an der Universit&#xe4;t Ulm, Institut f&#xfc;r Diabetes-Technologie, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kulzer</LastName><ForeName>Bernhard</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute Diabetes Academy Mergentheim, Bad Mergentheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, University of Bamberg, Bamberg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Center Mergentheim, Bad Mergentheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Diabetes Sci Technol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101306166</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1932-2968</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D001786">Blood Glucose</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006442">Glycated Hemoglobin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="C517652">hemoglobin A1c protein, human</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007004">Hypoglycemic Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D007328">Insulin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001786" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Glucose</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003924" MajorTopicYN="Y">Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000097" MajorTopicYN="N">blood</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000097103" MajorTopicYN="N">Digital Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006442" MajorTopicYN="N">Glycated Hemoglobin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007004" MajorTopicYN="N">Hypoglycemic Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007328" MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063731" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mobile Applications</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000068997" MajorTopicYN="N">Smartphone</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017216" MajorTopicYN="N">Telemedicine</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015337" MajorTopicYN="N">Multicenter Studies as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">basal insulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital application</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">insulin titration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting InterestsThe author(s) declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: N.H. has received fees for Advisory Board Participation from Abbott. He also received fees for lectures from Berlin Chemie, Sanofi, and Novo Nordisk. He also reports research support from Sanofi, Berlin Chemie, Roche, and mySugr. D.E. has received fees for Advisory Board participation from Dexcom, Roche Diabetes Care, mySugr, and Medtronic. He also received fees for lectures from Dexcom and Berlin-Chemie AG. K.F.G has no conflict of interest. T.R has no conflict of interest. G.F. is general manager of the Institut f&#xfc;r Diabetes-Technologie Forschungs- und Entwicklungsgesellschaft mbH an der Universit&#xe4;t Ulm (IfDT, Ulm, Germany), which carries out clinical studies on the evaluation of BG meters and medical devices for diabetes therapy on its own initiative and on behalf of various companies. G.F./IfDT has received grants, speakers&#x2019; honoraria, or consulting fees from Abbott, Agamatrix, Ascensia, Berlin-Chemie, Beurer, Boydsens, CRF Health, Dexcom, i-SENS, LifeScan, Lilly, Metronom Health, Medtronic, Menarini, mySugr, Novo Nordisk, PharmaSens, Roche, Sanofi, Sensile, and Ypsomed. B.K. reports grants from AstraZeneca, Berlin-Chemie, Roche Diabetes Care, Abbott Diabetes Care, AstraZeneca, Dexcom, and Ypsomed, and personal fees from Berlin-Chemie, Roche Diabetes Care, Novo Nordisk, Medtronic, Ascensia Diabetes Care, Abbott Diabetes Care, and Eli Lilly.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36602040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11307223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19322968221148756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Diabetes Association. 2. Classification and diagnosis of diabetes: standards of medical care in diabetes&#x2014;2021. Diabetes Care. 2021;44(suppl 1):S15-S33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33298413</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garber AJ, Handelsman Y, Grunberger G, et al. Consensus statement by the American Association of Clinical Endocrinologists and American College of Endocrinology on the comprehensive type 2 diabetes management algorithm-2020 executive summary. Endocr Pract. 2020;26(1):107-139.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32022600</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sieber J, Weinheimer M, Kongable G, Riddle S, Chang YY, Flacke F. In silico examination of initiation of long-acting insulin analogs toujeo compared to lantus under 3 dosing titration rules in virtual type 2 diabetes subjects. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2020;14(5):898-907.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7753861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31288531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauricio D, Meneghini L, Seufert J, et al. Glycaemic control and hypoglycaemia burden in patients with type 2 diabetes initiating basal insulin in Europe and the USA. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2017;19(8):1155-1164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5573947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K, Nikolajsen A, Thorsted BL, Andersen M, Davies MJ, Paul SK. Clinical inertia with regard to intensifying therapy in people with type 2 diabetes treated with basal insulin. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2016;18(4):401-409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5067688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26743666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polonsky W. Psychological insulin resistance: the patient perspective. Diabetes Educ. 2007;33(suppl 7):241S-244S.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17656740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polonsky WH, Fisher L, Guzman S, Villa-Caballero L, Edelman SV. Psychological insulin resistance in patients with type 2 diabetes: the scope of the problem. Diabetes Care. 2005;28(10):2543-2545.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16186296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polonsky WH, Hajos TR, Dain MP, Snoek FJ. Are patients with type 2 diabetes reluctant to start insulin therapy? an examination of the scope and underpinnings of psychological insulin resistance in a large, international population. Curr Med Res Opin. 2011;27(6):1169-1174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21469914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polonsky WH, Jackson RA. What&#x2019;s so tough about taking insulin? addressing the problem of psychological insulin resistance in type 2 diabetes. Clin Diabetes. 2004;22(3):147-150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies MJ, Gagliardino JJ, Gray LJ, Khunti K, Mohan V, Hughes R. Real-world factors affecting adherence to insulin therapy in patients with Type 1 or Type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. Diabet Med. 2013;30(5):512-524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23323988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cramer JA. A systematic review of adherence with medications for diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2004;27(5):1218-1224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15111553</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes-Truscott E, Skinner TC, Pouwer F, Speight J. Negative appraisals of insulin therapy are common among adults with Type 2 diabetes using insulin: results from diabetes MILES-Australia cross-sectional survey. Diabet Med. 2015;32(10):1297-1303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25683652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K, Millar-Jones D. Clinical inertia to insulin initiation and intensification in the UK: a focused literature review. Prim Care Diabetes. 2017;11(1):3-12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27727005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polinski JM, Smith BF, Curtis BH, et al. Barriers to insulin progression among patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review. Diabetes Educ. 2013;39(1):53-65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23192599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermanns N, Mahr M, Kulzer B, Skovlund SE, Haak T. Barriers towards insulin therapy in type 2 diabetic patients: results of an observational longitudinal study. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2010;8:113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2959097</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20920319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermanns N, Kulzer B, Krichbaum M, Kubiak T, Haak T. Affective and anxiety disorders in a German sample of diabetic patients: prevalence, comorbidity and risk factors. Diabet Med. 2005;22(3):293-300.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15717877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell-Jones D, Dauchy A, Delgado E, et al. Take control: a randomized trial evaluating the efficacy and safety of self- versus physician-managed titration of insulin glargine 300 U/mL in patients with uncontrolled type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2019;21(7):1615-1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6767413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30851006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies M, Bain S, Charpentier G, et al. A randomized controlled, treat-to-target study evaluating the efficacy and safety of insulin glargine 300 U/mL (Gla-300) administered using either device-supported or routine titration in people with type 2 diabetes. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2019;13(5):881-889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6955447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30646755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergenstal RM, Johnson M, Passi R, et al. Automated insulin dosing guidance to optimise insulin management in patients with type 2 diabetes: a multicentre, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2019;393(10176):1138-1148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6715130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30808512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamez-P&#xe9;rez HE, Cantu-Santos OM, Gutierrez-Gonzalez D, Gonzalez-Facio R, Romero-Ibarguengoitia ME. Effect of digital-tool-supported basal insulin titration algorithm in reaching glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes in Mexico. J Diabetes Sci Technol. 2022;16:1513-1520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9631525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34323110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Modi KD, Jha S, Panda MSR, et al. 138-LB: digital-tool-sup ported basal insulin (BI) titration: real-world effectiveness of my dose coach in India. Diabetes. 2019;68:138-LB.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw S. App-based approach to basal insulin titration: initial results of the my dose coach pilot in India. The 12th IDF Western Pacific Region Congress; 2018. The 12th IDF Western Pacific Region Congress; 22. Nov. 2018 - 25. Nov.2018; Kuala Lumpur 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermanns N, Kulzer B, Krichbaum M, Kubiak T, Haak T. How to screen for depression and emotional problems in patients with diabetes: comparison of screening characteristics of depression questionnaires, measurement of diabetes-specific emotional problems and standard clinical assessment. Diabetologia. 2006;49(3):469-477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16432706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt A, Gahr A, Hermanns N, Kulzer B, Haak T. Der diabetes self-management questionnaire (DSMQ): psychometrische analyse eines neuen fragebogeninventars zur G&#x2022; te der diabetes-selbstbehandlung. Diabetologie Und Stoffwechsel. 2013;8(suppl 1):FV35.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt A., Kulzer B., Ehrmann D., Haak T., Hermanns N. (2022). A Self-Report Measure of Diabetes Self-Management for Type 1 and Type 2 Diabetes: The Diabetes Self-Management Questionnaire-Revised (DSMQ-R) -Clinimetric Evidence From Five Studies. Front. Clin. Diabetes Healthc. 2: 823046. doi: 10.3389/fcdhc.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10012087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36994332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergis N, Ehrmann D, Hermanns N, Kulzer B, Haak T. L&#xe4;sst sich Empowerment bei Menschen mit Diabetes messen? [Is empowerment measurable in persons with diabetes?]. Diabetologie Und Stoffwechsel. 2012;7(suppl 1):P9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergis-Jurgan N, Hermanns N, Kulzer B, Ehrmann D, Haak T. Einfluss der selbstwirksamkeit auf die glykaemische kontrolle bei typ-1 und typ-2-diabetikern mit einer intensivierten insulintherapie [Influence of self-efficacy on glycemic control in people with type 1 and type 2 diabetes with an intensified insulin therapy]. Diabetologie Und Stoffwechsel. 2013;8(suppl 1):P134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulzer B, Bauer U, Hermanns N, Bergis KH. Entwicklung eines problemfragebogens fuer diabetiker zur identifikation von schwierigkeiten im umgang mit der krankheit [Development of a questionnaire for the assessment of diabetes related problems and satisfaction with insulin treatment]. Verhaltenstherapie. 1995;5(suppl 1):A72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;hler E, M&#xfc;hlan H, Albani C, Schmidt S. Teststatistische pr&#xfc;fung und normierung der deutschen versionen des EUROHIS-QOL lebensqualit&#xe4;t-Index und des WHO-5 wohlbefindens-index. Diagnostica. 2007;53(2):83-96.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>