<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35936976</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>11</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2523-3246</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cybersecurity</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cybersecur (Singap)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle><i>Sarve</i>: synthetic data and local differential privacy for private frequency estimation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>26</StartPage><MedlinePgn>26</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s42400-022-00129-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The collection of user attributes by service providers is a double-edged sword. They are instrumental in driving statistical analysis to train more accurate predictive models like recommenders. The analysis of the collected user data includes frequency estimation for categorical attributes. Nonetheless, the users deserve privacy guarantees against inadvertent identity disclosures. Therefore algorithms called frequency oracles were developed to randomize or perturb user attributes and estimate the frequencies of their values. We propose <i>Sarve</i>, a frequency oracle that used Randomized Aggregatable Privacy-Preserving Ordinal Response (RAPPOR) and Hadamard Response (HR) for randomization in combination with fake data. The design of a service-oriented architecture must consider two types of complexities, namely computational and communication. The functions of such systems aim to minimize the two complexities and therefore, the choice of privacy-enhancing methods must be a calculated decision. The variant of RAPPOR we had used was realized through bloom filters. A bloom filter is a memory-efficient data structure that offers time complexity of O(1). On the other hand, HR has been proven to give the best communication costs of the order of log(b) for b-bits communication. Therefore, <i>Sarve</i> is a step towards frequency oracles that exhibit how privacy provisions of existing methods can be combined with those of fake data to achieve statistical results comparable to the original data. <i>Sarve</i> also implemented an adaptive solution enhanced from the work of Arcolezi et al. The use of RAPPOR was found to provide better privacy-utility tradeoffs for specific privacy budgets in both high and general privacy regimes.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Varma</LastName><ForeName>Gatha</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Amity Institute of Information Technology, Amity University, Noida, India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.444644.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1805 0217</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chauhan</LastName><ForeName>Ritu</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Computational Biology and Bioinformatics, Amity University, Noida, India.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.444644.2</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 1805 0217</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Dhananjay</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Electronics Engineering, HUFS, Seoul, Korea.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="GRID">grid.440932.8</Identifier><Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2375 5180</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Singapore</Country><MedlineTA>Cybersecur (Singap)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918284166606676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2523-3246</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Differential privacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frequency estimation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Frequency oracle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Privacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Synthetic data</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Competing interestsThe authors declare that they do not have any known competing financial interests, or any personal relationships that appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>55</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35936976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9345740</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s42400-022-00129-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Ahamad D, Alam Hameed S, Akhtar M. A multi-objective privacy preservation model for cloud security using hybrid Jaya-based shark smell optimization. J King Saud Univ Comput Inf Sci. 2020 doi: 10.1016/J.JKSUCI.2020.10.015.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JKSUCI.2020.10.015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arcolezi HH, Couchot JF, Al Bouna B, Xiao X. Random sampling plus fake data: multidimensional frequency estimates with local differential privacy. Int Conf Inf Knowl Manag Proc. 2021 doi: 10.1145/3459637.3482467.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/3459637.3482467</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Balle B, Barthe G, Gaboardi M. Privacy amplification by subsampling: tight analyses via couplings and divergences. Adv Neural Inf Process Syst. 2018;2018:6277&#x2013;6287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Basat R, Chen X, Einziger G, Rottenstreich O. Designing heavy-hitter detection algorithms for programmable switches. IEEE/ACM Trans Netw. 2020;28(3):1172&#x2013;1185. doi: 10.1109/TNET.2020.2982739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNET.2020.2982739</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulanger M. Scraping the bottom of the barrel: Why it is no surprise that data scrapers can have access to public profiles on linkedIn. Sci Technol Law Rev. 2018;21(1):77.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell M. Synthetic data: how AI is transitioning from data consumer to data producer and why that&#x2019;s important. Computer. 2019;52:89&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1109/MC.2019.2930097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MC.2019.2930097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheu A, Smith A, Ullman J, Zeber D, Zhilyaev M. Distributed differential privacy via shuffling. Lect Notes Comput Sci. 2019 doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-17653-2_13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-17653-2_13</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djenouri Y, Belhadi A, Fournier-Viger P. Extracting useful knowledge from event logs: a frequent itemset mining approach. Knowl Based Syst. 2018;139:132&#x2013;148. doi: 10.1016/J.KNOSYS.2017.10.016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.KNOSYS.2017.10.016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Djenouri Y, Djenouri D, Belhadi A, Cano A. Exploiting GPU and cluster parallelism in single scan frequent itemset mining. Inf Sci (NY) 2019;496:363&#x2013;377. doi: 10.1016/J.INS.2018.07.020.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.INS.2018.07.020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emam KE, Mosquera L, Zheng C. Optimizing the synthesis of clinical trial data using sequential trees. J Am Med Inform Assoc. 2021;28(1):3&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1093/jamia/ocaa249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jamia/ocaa249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7810457</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33186440</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlingsson &#xda;, Pihur V, Korolova A. RAPPOR: randomized aggregatable privacy-preserving ordinal response. Proc ACM Conf Comput Commun Secur. 2014 doi: 10.1145/2660267.2660348.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/2660267.2660348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hittmeir M, Ekelhart A, Mayer R. Utility and privacy assessments of synthetic data for regression tasks. Proc IEEE Int Conf Big Data. 2019;2019:5763&#x2013;5772. doi: 10.1109/BIGDATA47090.2019.9005476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/BIGDATA47090.2019.9005476</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoffmann J, Bar-Sinai Y, Lee LM, Andrejevic J, Mishra S, Rubinstein SM, Rycroft CH. Machine learning in a data-limited regime: augmenting experiments with synthetic data uncovers order in crumpled sheets. Sci Adv. 2019 doi: 10.1126/SCIADV.AAU6792/SUPPL_FILE/AAU6792_SM.PDF.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/SCIADV.AAU6792/SUPPL_FILE/AAU6792_SM.PDF</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6486215</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31032399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Joseph M, Roth A, Ullman J, Waggoner B. Local differential privacy for evolving data. J Priv Confid. 2018;10:1&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kacha L, Zitouni A, Djoudi M. KAB: a new k-anonymity approach based on black hole algorithm. J King Saud Univ Comput Inf Sci. 2021 doi: 10.1016/J.JKSUCI.2021.04.014.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JKSUCI.2021.04.014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kairouz P, Oh S, Viswanath P. Extremal mechanisms for local differential privacy. J Mach Learn Res. 2016;17(1):492&#x2013;542.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirsch MS. Do-not-track: revising the EU&#xe2;??s data protection framework to require meaningful consent for behavioral advertising. Richmond J Law Technol. 2011;18:1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee J, Clifton C. How much is enough? Choosing &#xce;&#xb5; for differential privacy. Lect Notes Comput Sci. 2011;7001:325&#x2013;340. doi: 10.1007/978-3-642-24861-0_22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-642-24861-0_22</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li S, Mu N, Le J, Liao X. Privacy preserving frequent itemset mining: maximizing data utility based on database reconstruction. Comput Secur. 2019;84:17&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1016/J.COSE.2019.03.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.COSE.2019.03.008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luna JM, Fournier-Viger P, Ventura S. Frequent itemset mining: a 25 years review. Wiley Interdiscip Rev Data Min Knowl Discov. 2019;9(6):e1329. doi: 10.1002/WIDM.1329.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/WIDM.1329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mahanti R. Data governance and compliance. Data Gov Compliance. 2021 doi: 10.1007/978-981-33-6877-4_5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-33-6877-4_5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehta BB, Rao UP. Improved l-diversity: scalable anonymization approach for privacy preserving big data publishing. J King Saud Univ - Comput Inf Sci. 2019 doi: 10.1016/J.JKSUCI.2019.08.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.JKSUCI.2019.08.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Memon I, Shaikh RA, Fazal H, Hanif Tunio M, Arain QA. The world of hacking: a survey. Univ Sindh J Inf Commun Technol. 2020;4(1):31&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pekar A, Duque-Torres A, Seah WKG, Caicedo O. Knowledge discovery: can it shed new light on threshold definition for heavy-hitter detection? J Netw Syst Manag. 2021;29(3):1&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1007/S10922-021-09593-W.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S10922-021-09593-W</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quick H. Generating Poisson-distributed differentially private synthetic data. J R Stat Soc Ser A. 2021;184:1093&#x2013;1108. doi: 10.1111/RSSA.12711.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/RSSA.12711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rouane O, Belhadef H, Bouakkaz M. Combine clustering and frequent itemsets mining to enhance biomedical text summarization. Expert Syst Appl. 2019;135:362&#x2013;373. doi: 10.1016/J.ESWA.2019.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.ESWA.2019.06.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snoke J, Raab GM, Nowok B, Dibben C, Slavkovic A. General and specific utility measures for synthetic data. J Res Stat Soc Ser A. 2018;181:663&#x2013;688. doi: 10.1111/RSSA.12358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/RSSA.12358</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sordello M, Bu Z, Dong J. Privacy amplification via iteration for shuffled and online PNSGD. Lect Notes Comput Sci. 2021;12976:796&#x2013;813. doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-86520-7_49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-86520-7_49</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanwar G, Chauhan R, Singh M, Singh D. Pre-emption of affliction severity using HRV measurements from a smart wearable; case-study on SARS-Cov-2 symptoms. Sensors. 2020;20(24):7068. doi: 10.3390/s20247068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s20247068</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7764028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33321780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanwar G, Chauhan R, Singh D. User privacy in smart systems: recent findings and countermeasures. SSRN Electron J. 2020 doi: 10.2139/ssrn.3565901.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2139/ssrn.3565901</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanwar G, Chauhan R, Yafi E. ARTYCUL: a privacy-preserving ML-driven framework to determine the popularity of a cultural exhibit on display. Sensors. 2021;21(4):1527. doi: 10.3390/s21041527.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/s21041527</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7926548</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33671822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tu Z, Zhao K, Xu F, Li Y, Su L, Jin D. Protecting trajectory from semantic attack considering ${k} $-anonymity, ${l} $-diversity, and ${t} $-closeness. IEEE Trans Netw Serv Manage. 2018;16(1):264&#x2013;278. doi: 10.1109/TNSM.2018.2877790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TNSM.2018.2877790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang Z, Ma P, Wang R, Zhang J, Chi Y, Ma Y, Yang T. Secure medical data collection via local differential privacy. IEEE Int Conf Comput Commun ICCC. 2018;2018:2446&#x2013;2450. doi: 10.1109/COMPCOMM.2018.8780925.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/COMPCOMM.2018.8780925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Zhao J, Hu Z, Yang X, Ren X, Lam KY. Local differential privacy for data collection and analysis. Neurocomputing. 2021;426:114&#x2013;133. doi: 10.1016/J.NEUCOM.2020.09.073.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.NEUCOM.2020.09.073</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Li N, Jha S. Locally differentially private heavy hitter identification. IEEE Trans Dependable Secur Comput. 2021;18(2):982&#x2013;993. doi: 10.1109/TDSC.2019.2927695.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TDSC.2019.2927695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warner SL. Randomized response: a survey technique for eliminating evasive answer bias. J Am Stat Assoc. 1965;60:63&#x2013;69. doi: 10.1080/01621459.1965.10480775.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01621459.1965.10480775</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12261830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiong X, Liu S, Li D, Cai Z, Niu X. A comprehensive survey on local differential privacy. Secur Commun Netw. 2020 doi: 10.1155/2020/8829523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/8829523</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Q, Zhu Y. Mean estimation over numeric data with personalized local differential privacy. Front Comput Sci. 2022;163(16):1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1007/S11704-020-0103-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S11704-020-0103-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xue Q, Zhu Y, Wang J. Joint distribution estimation and na&#xef;ve bayes classification under local differential privacy. IEEE Trans Emerg Top Comput. 2021;9(4):2053&#x2013;2063. doi: 10.1109/TETC.2019.2959581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TETC.2019.2959581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ye Y, Zhang M, Feng D, Li H, Chi J. Multiple privacy regimes mechanism for local differential privacy. Lect Notes Comput Sci. 2019;11447:247&#x2013;263. doi: 10.1007/978-3-030-18579-4_15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-030-18579-4_15</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao D, Chen H, Zhao S, Zhang X, Li C, Liu R. Local differential privacy with k-anonymous for frequency estimation. Proc IEEE Int Conf Big Data. 2019;2019:5819&#x2013;5828. doi: 10.1109/BIGDATA47090.2019.9006022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/BIGDATA47090.2019.9006022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao D, Zhao S, Chen H, Liu R, Li C, Liang W. Efficient protocols for heavy hitter identification with local differential privacy. Front Comput Sci. 2022;16(5):1&#x2013;11. doi: 10.1007/S11704-021-0412-Y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/S11704-021-0412-Y</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng H, Hu H, Han Z. Preserving user privacy for machine learning: local differential privacy or federated machine learning? IEEE Intell Syst. 2020;35:5&#x2013;14. doi: 10.1109/MIS.2020.3010335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/MIS.2020.3010335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X, Yan K, Duan J, Tang W, Tian L. Histogram publication over numerical values under local differential privacy. Wirel Commun Mobile Comput. 2021 doi: 10.1155/2021/8886255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2021/8886255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abay NC, Zhou Y, Kantarcioglu M, Thuraisingham B, Sweeney L (2018) Privacy preserving synthetic data release using deep learning. In: Joint European conference on machine learning and knowledge discovery in databases, Springer, Cham, pp 510&#x2013;526</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya J, Sun Z, Zhang H (2018) Hadamard response: estimating distributions privately, efficiently, and with little communication. In: AISTATS 2019&#x2014;22nd international conference on artificial intelligence and statistics</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acharya J, Canonne C L, Freitag C, Tyagi H (2019) Test without trust: optimal locally private distribution testing</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhalifah T, Wang H, Ovcharenko O (2021) MLReal: bridging the gap between training on synthetic data and real data applications in machine learning, pp 1&#x2013;5. 10.3997/2214-4609.202113262/CITE/REFWORKS</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arcolezi HH, Couchot JF, Baala O, Contet JM, Al Bouna B, Xiao X, Al B (2021b) Mobility modeling through mobile data: generating an optimized and open dataset respecting privacy</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bautista P, Inventado PS (2021) Protecting student privacy with&amp;nbsp;synthetic data from generative adversarial networks, pp 66&#x2013;70. 10.1007/978-3-030-78270-2_11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cao X, Jia J, Gong N Z (2019) Data poisoning attacks to local differential privacy protocols. In: Proceedings of 30th USENIX security symposium, pp 947&#x2013;964</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen W N, Kairouz P, &#xd6;zg&#xfc;r A (2020) Breaking the communication-privacy-accuracy trilemma.&amp;nbsp;arXiv preprint arXiv:2007.11707.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheu A, Smith A, Ullman J (2019b) Manipulation attacks in local differential privacy. In: Proceedings of IEEE symposium on security and privacy, 2021-May, pp 883&#x2013;900. 10.1109/SP40001.2021.00001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormode G, Kulkarni T, Srivastava D (2018) Marginal release under local differential privacy. In: Proceedings of 2018 international conference on management of data, vol 16. 10.1145/3183713</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cormode G, Maddock S, Maple C (2021) Frequency estimation under local differential privacy [experiments, analysis and benchmarks]. In: Proceedings of VLDB Endow, vol 14, pp 2046&#x2013;2058. 10.14778/3476249.3476261</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dong J, Roth A, Su WJ (2019) Gaussian differential privacy.&amp;nbsp;arXiv preprint arXiv:1905.02383</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwork C, Rothblum GN, Vadhan S (2010a) Boosting and differential privacy. In: 2010a IEEE 51st annual symposium on foundations of computer science, IEEE, pp 51&#x2013;60</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwork C, Naor M, Pitassi T, Rothblum G N (2010b) Differential privacy under continual observation. In: Proceedings of the forty-second ACM symposium on theory of computing, pp 715&#x2013;724</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlingsson &#xda;, Feldman V, Mironov I, Raghunathan A, Talwar K, Thakurta A (2019) Amplification by shuffling: from local to central differential privacy via anonymity. In: Proceedings, pp 2468&#x2013;2479. 10.1137/1.9781611975482.151</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman V, Mironov I, Talwar K, Thakurta A (2018) Privacy amplification by iteration. In: Proceedings of annual IEEE symposium foundations of computer science. FOCS 2018-Octob, pp 521&#x2013;532. 10.1109/FOCS.2018.00056</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman V, Audra A, Apple M, Apple KT (2020) Hiding among the clones: a simple and nearly optimal analysis of privacy amplification by shuffling</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatha, Chauhan R, Singh D (2020a) Ensuring privacy-aware data release: an analysis of applicability of privacy enhancing techniques to real-world datasets. In: ICRITO 2020a&#x2014;IEEE 8th international conference on reliability, infocom technologies and optimization (trends and future directions). 10.1109/ICRITO48877.2020a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gatha, Chauhan R, Singh D (2020b) Ensuring privacy-aware data release: an analysis of applicability of privacy enhancing techniques to real-world datasets. 10.1109/ICRITO48877.2020b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghalebikesabi S, Wilde H, Jewson J, Doucet A, Vollmer S, Holmes C (2021) Bias mitigated learning from differentially private synthetic data: a cautionary tale.&amp;nbsp;arXiv preprint arXiv:2108.10934</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grafenstein M, Heum&#xfc;ller J, Belgacem E, Jakobi T, Smiesko P (2021) Effective regulation through design&#x2014;aligning the eprivacy regulation with the EU general data protection regulation (GDPR): tracking technologies in personalised internet content and the data protection by design approach. SSRN Electron J. 10.2139/SSRN.3945471</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe4;rting M, Partgmbb R, Niko H (2017) Study on the impact of the proposed ePrivacy regulation centre for information policy leadership 30 St Mary Axe London, EC3A 8EP</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hittmeir M, Mayer R, Ekelhart A (2020) A baseline for attribute disclosure risk in synthetic data. In: CODASPY 2020&#x2014;proceedings of the tenth ACM conference on data and application security and privacy, pp 133&#x2013;143. 10.1145/3374664.3375722</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang SY, Ban T (2020) Monitoring social media for vulnerability-threat prediction and topic analysis. In: Proceedings of 2020 IEEE 19th international conference on trust, security and privacy in computing and communications 2020, pp 1771&#x2013;1776. 10.1109/TRUSTCOM50675.2020.00243</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jia J, Gong NZ (2019) Calibrate: frequency estimation and heavy hitter identification with local differential privacy via incorporating prior knowledge. In: Proceedings of IEEE INFOCOM 2019-April: 2008&#x2013;2016. 10.1109/INFOCOM.2019.8737527</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kairouz P, Bonawitz K, Ramage D (2016a) Discrete distribution estimation under local privacy</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenthapadi K, Mironov I, Thakurta AG (2019) Privacy-preserving data mining in industry. In: WSDM 2019&#x2014;Proceedings of 12th ACM international conference on web search data mining, pp 840&#x2013;841. 10.1145/3289600.3291384</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kifer D, Messing S, Roth A, Thakurta A, Zhang D (2020) Guidelines for implementing and auditing differentially private systems</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohavi R (1996) Scaling up the accuracy of naive-bayes classifiers: a decision-tree hybrid. In: Kdd, vol 96, pp 202&#x2013;207</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le BD, Zia T (2021) Discrete distribution estimation with local differential privacy: a comparative analysis. In: 2021 IEEE International conference on pervasive computing and communications, PerCom Work, pp 692&#x2013;697. 10.1109/PerComWorkshops51409.2021.9431028</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li N, Qardaji W, Su D (2012) On sampling, anonymization, and differential privacy or, k-anonymization meets differential privacy. In: ASIACCS 2012&#x2014;7th ACM symposium information computer and communications security, pp 32&#x2013;33. 10.1145/2414456.2414474</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li M, Tian Y, Zhang J, Fan D, Zhao D (2021) The trade-off between privacy and utility in local differential privacy. In: 2021 International conference on network application, pp 373&#x2013;378. 10.1109/NANA53684.2021.00071</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin BC, Wu S , Tsou YT, Huang Y (2018) PPDCA: privacy-preserving crowdsensing data collection and analysis with randomized response. In: IEEE wireless communications and networking conference WCNC 2018-April, pp 1&#x2013;6. 10.1109/WCNC.2018.8377050</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Bai X, Ma X, Cui L (2020) Frequent itemset mining with hadamard response under local differential privacy. In: ICEIEC 2020&#x2014;proceedings of 2020 IEEE 10th International conference on electronic information, emerging communication, pp 49&#x2013;5210.1109/ICEIEC49280.2020.9152248</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopuha&#xe4;-Zwakenberg M, &#x160;kori&#x107; B, Li N (2019) Information-theoretic metrics for local differential privacy protocols</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopuha&#xe4;-Zwakenberg M, Li Z, Skoric B, Li N (2020) Improving frequency estimation under local differential privacy. In: WPES 2020&#x2014;Proceedings of 19th workshop on privacy in the electronic society, pp 123&#x2013;135. 10.1145/3411497.3420215</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naor M, Pinkas B, Ronen E (2019) How to (not) share a password: Privacy preserving protocols for finding heavy hitters with adversarial behavior. In: Proceedings of the 2019 ACM SIGSAC conference on computer and communications security, pp 1369&#x2013;1386</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguy&#xea;n TT, Xiao X, Yang Y, Hui SC, Shin H, Shin J (2016) Collecting and analyzing data from smart device users with local differential privacy.&amp;nbsp;arXiv preprint arXiv:1606.05053.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olave M, Rajkovic V (1989) Administration, M.B.-E.S. In: An application for admission in public school systems. kt.ijs.si</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rahimian S, Orekondy T, Fritz M (2020) Sampling attacks: amplification of membership inference attacks by repeated queries</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Regulation with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) Tracking technologies in personalised internet content and the data protection by design approach. SSRN Electron J. 10.2139/SSRN.3945471</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenblatt L, Liu X, Pouyanfar S, de Leon E, Desai A, Allen J (2020) A differentially private synthetic data: applied evaluations and enhancements. development, M.A., Program</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snoke J, Slavkovi&#x107; A (2018) pMSE mechanism: differentially private synthetic data with maximal distributional similarity. Lect Notes Comput Sci 11126 LNCS:138&#x2013;159. 10.1007/978-3-319-99771-1_10</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stadler T, Oprisanu B, Troncoso C (2022) Synthetic data&#x2014;anonymisation groundhog day</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vietri G, Tian G, Bun M, Steinke T, Wu Z S (2020) New Oracle-efficient algorithms for private synthetic data release</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagenseil P (2020) Zoom security issues: here's everything that's gone wrong (so far).&amp;nbsp;Toms guide, pp 1&#x2013;3</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Huang L, Wang P, Nie Y, Xu H, Yang W, Li XY, Qiao C (2016) Mutual information optimally local private discrete distribution estimation</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Blocki J, Li N, Jha S (2017) Locally differentially private protocols for frequency estimation. In: 26th {USENIX} security symposium ({USENIX} security 17), pp 729&#x2013;745</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Li N, Jha S (2018b) Locally differentially private frequent itemset mining. In: Proceedings of IEEE symposium on security and Privacy 2018b-May, pp 127&#x2013;143. 10.1109/SP.2018b</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang N, Xiao X, Yang Y, Zhao J, Hui S C, Shin H, Shin J, Yu G (2019a) Collecting and analyzing multidimensional data with local differential privacy. In: Proceedings&#x2014;international conference on data engineering, pp 638&#x2013;649. 10.1109/ICDE.2019a</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Ding B, Zhou J, Hong C, Huang Z, Li N, Jha S (2019b) Answering multi-dimensional analytical queries under local differential privacy. In: Proceedings of ACM SIGMOD international conference on management of data, pp 159&#x2013;176. 10.1145/3299869.3319891</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang T, Ding B, Zhou J, Hong C, Huang Z, Li N, Jha S (2019c) Answering multi-dimensional analytical queries under local differential privacy. In: Proceedings of 2019c international conference on management of data, vol 18. 10.1145/3299869</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu M, Ding B, Wang T, Zhou J (2020) Collecting and analyzing data jointly from multiple services under local differential privacy. Proc VLDB Endow 13:2760&#x2013;2772. 10.14778/3407790.3407859</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Lyu L, Zhao J, Zhu T, Lam KY (2020) Local differential privacy and its applications: a comprehensive survey</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang M, Tjuawinata I, Lam K-Y, Zhu T, Zhao J (2021) Fair and differentially private distributed frequency estimation. 10.48550/arxiv.2104.05974</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Z, Wang T, Li N, He S, Chen J (2018) CALM: consistent adaptive local marginal for marginal release under local differential privacy. In: Proceedings of 2018 ACM SIGSAC conference on computer and communications security, vol 18. 10.1145/3243734</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu W, Kairouz P, McMahan B, Sun H, Li W (2020) Federated heavy hitters discovery with differential privacy. In: International conference on artificial intelligence and statistics, PMLR, pp 3837&#x2013;3847</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>