<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39114551</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2542-4823</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>8</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of Alzheimer's disease reports</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Alzheimers Dis Rep</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Long-Term Effects of the Multicomponent Program BrainProtect<sup>&#xae;</sup> on Cognitive Function: One-Year Follow-Up in Healthy Adults.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1069</StartPage><EndPage>1087</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1069-1087</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3233/ADR-230199</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Age-related neuronal changes impact cognitive integrity, which is a major contributor to health and quality of life. The best strategy to prevent cognitive decline and Alzheimer's disease is still debated.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To investigate the long-term effects of the eight-week multicomponent training program BrainProtect<sup>&#xae;</sup> on cognitive abilities compared to general health counseling (GHC) in cognitively healthy adults in Germany.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Healthy adults (age &#x2265;50 years) previously randomized to either GHC (<i>n</i>&#x200a;=&#x200a;72) or BrainProtect (intervention group, IG, <i>n</i>&#x200a;=&#x200a;60) for eight-weeks (once weekly, 90 minutes, group-based) underwent a comprehensive neuropsychological test battery and health-related quality of life (HRQoL) evaluation 3- and 12-months after intervention end.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Dropout rates were <i>n</i>&#x200a;=&#x200a;8 after 3 months and <i>n</i>&#x200a;=&#x200a;19 after 12 months. No significant long-term effect of BrainProtect was observed for the primary endpoint Consortium to Establish a Registry for Alzheimer's Disease (CERAD-Plus) total score. Logical reasoning was significantly improved (<i>p</i>&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.024) 12 months after completion of the training program in IG participants compared to the GHC group independent of sex, age, education, diet, and physical activity. In IG participants, thinking flexibility (<i>p</i>&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.019) and confrontational naming (<i>p</i>&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.010) were improved 3 months after completing the intervention compared to the GHC group, however, after conservative Bonferroni adjustment, significance was lost.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">BrainProtect<sup>&#xae;</sup> independently improved logical reasoning compared to GHC up to 12 months after cognitive training's end in healthy adults. To uncover the long-term clinical significance of multicomponent cognitive training in healthy adults, studies with larger sample size and frequent follow up visits are necessary.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 &#x2013; The authors. Published by IOS Press.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kunkler</LastName><ForeName>Michelle Celine</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ageing Clinical Research, Department II of Internal Medicine and Center for Molecular Medicine Cologne, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Falkenreck</LastName><ForeName>Julia Maria</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ageing Clinical Research, Department II of Internal Medicine and Center for Molecular Medicine Cologne, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ophey</LastName><ForeName>Anja</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies &amp; Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Interventions (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dencker</LastName><ForeName>Katharina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ageing Clinical Research, Department II of Internal Medicine and Center for Molecular Medicine Cologne, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friese</LastName><ForeName>Andrea</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AF Gehirntraining, Bedburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jahr</LastName><ForeName>Petra</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>C Plus, Krefeld, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalbe</LastName><ForeName>Elke</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies &amp; Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Interventions (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nelles</LastName><ForeName>Gereon</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Neuromed-Campus Hohenlind, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polidori</LastName><ForeName>M Cristina</ForeName><Initials>MC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ageing Clinical Research, Department II of Internal Medicine and Center for Molecular Medicine Cologne, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cologne Excellence Cluster on Cellular Stress Response in Aging-Associated Diseases (CECAD), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Alzheimers Dis Rep</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101705500</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2542-4823</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive integrity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive training</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dementia prevention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">long-term effects</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>M. Cristina Polidori is an Editorial Board Member of the Journal of Alzheimer&#x2019;s Disease. M. Cristina Polidori is a member of the advisory board of memodio (multidomain app for the treatment of MCI) and an Editorial Board Member of Aging Research Reviews and of the &#x2018;Deutsche Medizinische Wochenschrift&#x2019;. M. Cristina Polidori receives the royalties for the publication of two books: the latest edition of &#x2018;Paziente Anziano - Paziente Geriatrico - Medicina della Complessit&#x2018;a&#x2019;, EdiSES 2020 and &#x2018;Ratgeber Altern - Es ist nie zu sp&#xe4;t&#x2019;, Elsevier 2021. M. Cristina Polidori is a member of the supervisory board and curatorship of Diakonie Michaelshoven e.V. M. Cristina Polidori and Elke Kalbe are members of the scientific advisory board of the Bundesverband Ged&#xe4;chtnistraining e.V. Elke Kalbe has received grants from the German Ministry of Education and Research, Brandau-Laibach Stiftung, Germany, RheinEnergie Stiftung, Germany, consulting fees from Memodio GmbH, Germany, Kyowa Kirin Services Ltd, UK, lecture fees from Biogen GmbH, Germany, EISAI GmbH, Germany, Abbvie GmbH, Germany, KoJ Geh&#xf6;rtraining, Switzerland, licence fees from Prolog GmbH, Germany; all outside the submitted work. Gereon Nelles is a board member of the Berufsverband Deutscher Nerven&#xe4;rzte (BVDN) e.V. Gereon Nelles is a member of the advisory board of memodio (multidomain app for the treatment of MCI). Petra Jahr is the regional manager &#x2018;Nordrhein-Westfalen West&#x2018; of the Bundesverband Ged&#xe4;chtnistraining e.V. Andrea Friese is the former educational manager of the Bundesverband Ged&#xe4;chtnistraining e.V. Anja Ophey received grants of the Koeln Fortune Program (grant-no. 329/2021), Faculty of Medicine, University of Cologne, and the &#x201c;Novartis-Stiftung f&#xfc;r therapeutische Forschung&#x201d; and speaking honoraria of ProLog Wissen GmbH, all outside the submitted work. Julia Maria Falkenreck is a member of the Bundesverband Ged&#xe4;chtnistraining e.V. The other authors have no conflict of interest to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39114551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11305852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/ADR-230199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">ADR230199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Tipton PW and Graff-Radford NR. Prevention of late-life dementia: What works and what does not. Pol Arch Intern Med 2018; 128: 310&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29768391</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson ND. State of the science on mild cognitive impairment (MCI). CNS Spectr 2019; 24: 78&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30651152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rostamzadeh A, Bohr L, Wagner M, et al. Progression of subjective cognitive decline to MCI or dementia in relation to biomarkers for Alzheimer disease: A meta-analysis. Neurology 2022; 99: e1866&#x2013;e1874.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36028322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veronese N, Soysal P, Demurtas J, et al. Physical activity and exercise for the prevention and management of mild cognitive impairment and dementia: A collaborative international guideline. Eur Geriatr Med 2023; 14: 925&#x2013;952.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10587099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37768499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ellouze I, Sheffler J, Nagpal R, et al. Dietary patterns and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: An updated review linking nutrition to neuroscience. Nutrients 2023; 15: 3204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10384681</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37513622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hughes ML, Agrigoroaei S, Jeon M, et al. Change in cognitive performance from midlife into old age: Findings from the Midlife in the United States (MIDUS) study. J Int Neuropsychol Soc 2018; 24: 805&#x2013;820.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6170692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30019663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polidori MC, Nelles G, Senin U, et al. Cognitive decline. In: Roller-Wirnsberger R, Singler K and Polidori MC (eds) Learning Geriatric Medicine Practical Issues in Geriatrics. Springer, Cham, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell NL, Unverzagt F, LaMantia MA, et al. Risk factors for the progression of mild cognitive impairment to dementia. Clin Geriatr Med 2013; 29: 873&#x2013;893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5915285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24094301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton S, Matthews FE, Barnes DE, et al. Potential for primary prevention of Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease: An analysis of population-based data. Lancet Neurol 2014; 13: 788&#x2013;794.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25030513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polidori MC, Stahl W, Griffiths HR. Nutritional cognitive neuroscience of aging: Focus on carotenoids and cognitive frailty. Redox Biol 2021; 44: 101996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8212151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34090844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstrom E, Neukam S, Kalin L, et al. Physical activity and healthy aging. Clin Geriatr Med 2020; 36: 671&#x2013;683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33010902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer AM, Podolski N, Pickert L, et al. Strategies to prevent age-related cognitive decline. Dtsch Med Wochenschr 2020; 145:(3) 146&#x2013;150.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32018286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngandu T, Lehtisalo J, Solomon A, et al. A 2 year multidomain intervention of diet, exercise, cognitive training, and vascular risk monitoring versus control to prevent cognitive decline in at-risk elderly people (FINGER): A randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2015; 385: 2255&#x2013;2263.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivipelto M, Mangialasche F, Ngandu T. Lifestyle interventions to prevent cognitive impairment, dementia and Alzheimer disease. Nat Rev Neurol 2018; 14: 653&#x2013;666.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30291317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavelin HM, Lampit A, Hallock H, et al. Cognition-oriented treatments for older adults: A systematic overview of systematic reviews. Neuropsychol Rev 2020; 30: 167&#x2013;193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7305099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32266520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li T, Yao Y, Cheng Y, et al. Cognitive training can reduce the rate of cognitive aging: A neuroimaging cohort study. BMC Geriatr 2016; 16: 12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4712458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26762334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn S, Chung JW, Crane MK, et al. The effects of multi-domain interventions on cognition: A systematic review. West J Nurs Res 2021; 1939459211032272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34261376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global status report on the public health response to dementia. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ben Hassen C, Fayosse A, Landr&#xe9; B, et al. Association between age at onset of multimorbidity and incidence of dementia: 30 year follow-up in Whitehall II prospective cohort study. BMJ 2022; 376: e068005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9086721</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35110302</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Falkenreck JM, Roheger M, Weigert H, et al. BrainProtect<sup>&#xae;</sup> - A cognitive training program with nutritional and physical counseling components: A retrospective analysis of its effects in healthy individuals. Geriatric Care
2020; 6:(4): 10.4081/gc.2020.9328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4081/gc.2020.9328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falkenreck JM, Kunkler MC, Ophey A, et al. Effects of the multicomponent cognitive training program BrainProtect in cognitively healthy adults: A randomized controlled trial. J Alzheimers Dis 2023; 94: 1013&#x2013;1034.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37393493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nasreddine ZS, Phillips NA, B&#xe9;dirian V, et al. The Montreal Cognitive Assessment, MoCA: A brief screening tool for mild cognitive impairment. J Am Geriatr Soc 2005; 53: 695&#x2013;699.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15817019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck AT, Ward CH, Mendelson M, et al. An inventory for measuring depression. Arch Gen Psychiatry 1961; 4: 561&#x2013;571.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13688369</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid NS, Ehrensperger MM, Berres M, et al. The extension of the German CERAD neuropsychological assessment battery with tests assessing subcortical, executive and frontal functions improves accuracy in dementia diagnosis. Dement Geriatr Cogn Dis Extra 2014; 4: 322&#x2013;334.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4176468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25298776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawton MP and Brody EM. Assessment of older people: Self-maintaining and instrumental activities of daily living. Gerontologist 1969; 9: 179&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5349366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz S, Ford AB, Moskowitz RW, et al. Studies of illness in the aged. The index of ADL: A standardized measure of biological and psychosocial function. JAMA 1963; 185: 914&#x2013;919.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14044222</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubenstein LZ, Harker JO, Salv&#xe0; A, et al. Screening for undernutrition in geriatric practice: Developing the short-form mini-nutritional assessment (MNA-SF). J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 2001; 56: M366&#x2013;372.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11382797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Herdman M, Gudex C, Lloyd A, et al. Development and preliminary testing of the new five-level version of EQ-5D (EQ-5D-5L). Qual Life Res 2011; 20: 1727&#x2013;1736.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3220807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21479777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Risk Reduction of Cognitive Decline and Dementia: WHO Guidelines. Geneva: World Health Organization, 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31219687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berres M, Zehnder A, Bl&#xe4;si S, et al. Evaluation of diagnostic scores with adjustment for covariates. Stat Med 2008; 27: 1777&#x2013;1790.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17968872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aebi C. Validierung der Neuropsychologischen Testbatterie CERAD-NP: Eine Multi-Center Studie. Universit&#xe4;t Basel, Schweiz: Doktorarbeit, 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lillig R, Ophey A, Schulz JB, et al. A new CERAD total score with equally weighted z-scores and additional executive and non-amnestic &#x201c;CERAD-Plus&#x201d; tests enhances cognitive diagnosis in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: Evidence from the LANDSCAPE study. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 2021; 90: 90&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34418761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences. Hillsdale, NJ, USA: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern Y, Arenaza-Urquijo EM, Bartr&#xe9;s-Faz D, et al. Whitepaper: Defining and investigating cognitive reserve, brain reserve, and brain maintenance. Alzheimers Dement 2020; 16: 1305&#x2013;1311.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6417987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30222945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stern Y. Cognitive reserve in ageing and Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Lancet Neurol 2012; 11: 1006&#x2013;1012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3507991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23079557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg A, Mangialasche F, Ngandu T, et al. Multidomain interventions to prevent cognitive impairment, alzheimer&#x2019;s disease, and dementia: From FINGER to World-Wide FINGERS. J Prev Alzheimers Dis 2020; 7: 29&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7222931</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32010923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kivipelto M, Mangialasche F, Snyder HM, et al. World-Wide FINGERS Network: A global approach to risk reduction and prevention of dementia. Alzheimers Dement 2020; 16: 1078&#x2013;1094.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9527644</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32627328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen SY, Feng Z, Yi X. A general introduction to adjustment for multiple comparisons. J Thorac Dis 2017; 9: 1725&#x2013;1729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28740688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cristofori I, Cohen-Zimerman S and Grafman J. Executive functions. Handb Clin Neurol 2019; 163: 197&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31590731</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rebok GW, Ball K, Guey LT, et al. Ten-year effects of the advanced cognitive training for independent and vital elderly cognitive training trial on cognition and everyday functioning in older adults. J Am Geriatr Soc 2014; 62: 16&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4055506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24417410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiu HL, Chu H, Tsai JC, et al. The effect of cognitive-based training for the healthy older people: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. PLoS One 2017; 12: e0176742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5411084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28459873</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsang HL, Lee TM. The effect of ageing on confrontational naming ability. Arch Clin Neuropsychol 2003; 18: 81&#x2013;89.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14591480</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedden T and Gabrieli JD. Insights into the ageing mind: A view from cognitive neuroscience. Nat Rev Neurosci 2004; 5: 87&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14735112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;vd&#xe9;n M, Fratiglioni L, Glymour MM, et al. Education and cognitive functioning across the life span. Psychol Sci Public Interest 2020; 21: 6&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7425377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772803</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg A, Ngandu T, Rusanen M, et al. Multidomain lifestyle intervention benefits a large elderly population at risk for cognitive decline and dementia regardless of baseline characteristics: The FINGER trial. Alzheimers Dement 2018; 14: 263&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29055814</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lampit A, Hallock H and Valenzuela M. Computerized cognitive training in cognitively healthy older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis of effect modifiers. PLoS Med 2014; 11: e1001756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4236015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25405755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mewborn CM, Lindbergh CA and Stephen Miller L. Cognitive interventions for cognitively healthy, mildly impaired, and mixed samples of older adults: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized-controlled trials. Neuropsychol Rev 2017; 27: 403&#x2013;439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28726168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pitkala KH, Routasalo P, Kautiainen H, et al. Effects of socially stimulating group intervention on lonely, older people&#x2019;s cognition: A randomized, controlled trial. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry 2011; 19: 654&#x2013;663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21709611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan RM, Lynch MF, Vansteenkiste M, et al. Motivation and autonomy in counseling, psychotherapy, and behavior change: A look at theory and practice. Couns Psychol 2011; 39: 193&#x2013;260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer AM, Bartram MP, Antczak P, et al. A tailored discharge program improves frailty and mood in patients undergoing usual rehabilitative care: A randomized controlled trial. J Am Med Dir Assoc 2022; 23: 1962.e1961&#x2013;1962.e1913.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36228662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalbe E, Rohere M, Paluszak K, et al. Effects of a cognitive training with and without additional physical activity in healthy older adults: A follow-up 1 year after a randomized controlled trial. Front Aging Neurosci 2018; 10: 407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6305338</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng ST. Cognitive reserve and the prevention of dementia: The role of physical and cognitive activities. Curr Psychiatry Rep 2016; 18: 85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4969323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27481112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dominguez LJ, Veronese N, Vernuccio L, et al. Nutrition, physical activity, and other lifestyle factors in the prevention of cognitive decline and dementia. Nutrients 2021; 13: 4080.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8624903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34836334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin LA, Smart CM and Amariglio RE. Subjective cognitive decline in preclinical Alzheimer&#x2019;s disease. Annu Rev Clin Psychol 2017; 13: 369&#x2013;396.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28482688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krivanek TJ, Gale SA, McFeeley BM, et al. Promoting successful cognitive aging: A ten-year update. J Alzheimers Dis 2021; 81: 871&#x2013;920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8293659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33935078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jessen F, Amariglio RE, Buckley RF, et al. The characterisation of subjective cognitive decline. Lancet Neurol 2020; 19: 271&#x2013;278.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7062546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31958406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang L, Zhang Z, McArdle JJ, et al. Investigating ceiling effects in longitudinal data analysis. Multivariate Behav Res 2009; 43: 476&#x2013;496.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2778494</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19924269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett AG, van der Pols JC, Dobson AJ. Regression to the mean: What it is and how to deal with it. Int J Epidemiol 2005; 34: 215&#x2013;220.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15333621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smole&#x144; T, Jastrzebski J, Estrada E, et al. Most evidence for the compensation account of cognitive training is unreliable. Memory Cogn 2018; 46: 1315&#x2013;1330.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6290662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30117114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gates NJ, Rutjes AW, Di Nisio M, et al. Computerised cognitive training for 12 or more weeks for maintaining cognitive function in cognitively healthy people in late life. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2020; 2: CD012277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7045394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32104914</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crivelli L, Palmer K, Calandri I, et al. Changes in cognitive functioning after COVID-19: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Alzheimers Dement 2022; 18: 1047&#x2013;1066.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9073922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35297561</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>