<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">42173348</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-8414</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of cardiac failure</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Card Fail</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Baroreflex activation therapy in heart failure - the Barostim-Enabled Neurohormonal Intervention for Improving Treatment of Heart Failure (BENEFIT-HF) trial rationale and design.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1071-9164(26)00249-6</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cardfail.2026.04.023</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Baroreflex activation therapy (BAT) using an implanted neurostimulator enhances functional status and quality of life in patients with symptomatic heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF). Nonetheless, its influence on mortality, heart failure morbidity, and optimal patient subgroups requires further study.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">BENEFIT-HF is a prospective, randomized, open-label trial recruiting patients with left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt;50% who remain symptomatic despite guideline-directed medical and device therapies. A total of 2500 eligible ambulatory patients with stable heart failure will be randomized 2:1 to BAT implantation (Barostim System, CVRx, Inc., Minneapolis, MN, USA) plus standard care (Treatment Group) or standard care alone (Control Group). The primary efficacy endpoint is a 24-month composite of all-cause mortality, left ventricular assist device implantation or heart transplantation, and recurrent heart failure events. Secondary endpoints encompass changes in health status via the Minnesota Living with Heart Failure Questionnaire, 6-minute hall walk distance, days lost due to death or hospitalization, N-terminal pro-B-type natriuretic peptide levels, and all-cause mortality.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">BENEFIT-HF represents the largest device-based trial evaluating BAT as a neurohormonal modulator in a diverse cohort of HFrEF and heart failure with mildly reduced ejection fraction (HFmrEF) patients, aimed at determining its effects on morbidity, mortality, health status, and functional capacity.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sheikh</LastName><ForeName>Farooq H</ForeName><Initials>FH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MedStar Heart and Vascular Institute/Georgetown University School of Medicine, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abraham</LastName><ForeName>William T</ForeName><Initials>WT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Medicine, Davis Heart and Lung Research Institute, The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adamson</LastName><ForeName>Philip B</ForeName><Initials>PB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CVRx, Inc., Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anker</LastName><ForeName>Stefan D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology (CVK) of German Heart Center Charit&#xe9;; German Centre for Cardiovascular Research (DZHK) partner site Berlin, Charit&#xe9; Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Bright Research, Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Butler</LastName><ForeName>Javed</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor Scott and White Research Institute, Dallas, Texas, USA; University of Mississippi, Jackson, Mississippi, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Friede</LastName><ForeName>Tim</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Statistics, University Medical Centre G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lindenfeld</LastName><ForeName>JoAnn</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Nashville, Tennessee, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Perez-Izquierdo</LastName><ForeName>Manuel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Vascular Surgery, Health First, Melbourne, Florida, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sears</LastName><ForeName>Samuel F</ForeName><Initials>SF</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>East Carolina University, East Carolina Heart Institute, Greenville, North Carolina, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilks</LastName><ForeName>Seth J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CVRx, Inc., Minneapolis, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zannad</LastName><ForeName>Faiez</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; de Lorraine, Inserm, Centre d'Investigations Cliniques, - Plurith&#xe9;matique 14-33, and Inserm U1116, CHRU Nancy, F-CRIN INI-CRCT (Cardiovascular and Renal Clinical Trialists), Nancy, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zile</LastName><ForeName>Michael R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Medicine, Medical University of South Carolina and RHJ Department of Veterans Affairs, Charleston, South Carolina, USA. Electronic address: zilem@musc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Card Fail</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9442138</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1071-9164</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure with mildly reduced ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">heart failure with reduced ejection fraction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurohormonal activation</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Discolosures FHS has received consulting fees from Abbott, Alnylam, XVIVO, Astra Zeneca, BridgeBio, CVRx and Pfizer, research support from Abbott, Alnylam, Astra Zeneca, and Intellia, and advisory board fees from Abbott and Procyrion. WTA has received personal fees from Abbott, AquaPass, Cordio Medical, CVRx, Innoventric, Sensible Medical, Vectorious Medical Technologies, WhiteSwell, and Zoll Respicardia; speaker honoraria from Impulse Dynamics; and has/had leadership or fiduciary roles at JNJ V-Wave, Cardiac Dimensions, BioVentrix, and formerly at scPharmaceuticals. SDA has received grants from CSL/Vifor and Abbott Laboratories, and personal fees for consultancies, trial committee work and/or lectures from Actimed, Alleviant, Astra Zeneca, Bayer, Berlin Heals, BiMyo, Boehringer Ingelheim, Brahms, Cardiac Dimensions, Cardior, Cordio, Corvia, CSL/Vifor, CVRx, Cytokinetics, Edwards, Impulse Dynamics, Lilly, Mankind Pharma, Novo Nordisk, Occlutech, Pfizer, Pulnovo, Regeneron, Relaxera, Repairon, Scirent, Sensible Medical, Vectorious, Veru, Viscardia, Vivus, and V-Wave; is a named co-inventor of two patent applications regarding MR-proANP (DE 102007010834 &amp; DE 102007022367), but does not benefit personally from the related issued patents. SB is an employee of Bright Research and serves as a paid consultant to CVRx. JB has been a consultant for Abbott, Adaptyx, Amgen, Anumana, AskBio, AstraZeneca, Bayer, Berlin Heals, Boehringer Ingelheim, Boston Scientific, BridgeBio, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardiac Dimension, CSL Vifor, Chiugai, CVRx, Cytokinetics, Daichi Sankyo, Daxor, Diastol, Eccogene, Edgewise, Edwards, Eikonizo, Element Sciences, Faraday, Idorsia, Impulse Dynamics, Imbria, Intellia, Inventiva, Levator, Lexicon, Eli Lilly, Kardigan, Mankind, Medtronic, Merck, Novartis, NovoNordisk, Pfizer, Pharmacosmos, Pharmain, Prolaio, Pulnovo, Recordati, Regeneron, Renibus, Reprieve, Roche, Rycarma, Saillent, Salamandra, Salubris, SC Pharma, Servier, SQ Innovation, Scirent, Secretome, Sequanna, Transmural, TekkunLev, Tenex, Thryv, Tricog, Ultromic, Vera, Zealand Pharma, and Zoll. TF reported receiving institutional grants from the German Research Foundation, the Federal Joint Committee, and the European Commission; receiving personal fees for statistical consultancies including data monitoring committees from Actimed Therapeutics, Apellis, argenx, Aslan, AstraZeneca, Bayer, BerlinHeals, Boehringer Ingelheim, Biogen, BiosenseWebster, Bristol Myers Squibb, Cardior, CSL Behring, CVRx, Daiichi Sankyo, eCovery, Enanta Pharmaceuticals, Fresenius Kabi, Galapagos, IQVIA, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Novartis, PINK! Aktiv gegen Brustkrebs, PPD, Priothera, Recardio Inc, Recordati, Relaxera, Roche, Sarfez, UpstreamBio, Viatris Inc, VICO Therapeutics and Vifor. JL has received consulting fees from Abbott, Abiomed, Alleviant, AskBio, Boston Scienfific, Cordio, CVRx, Edwards Lifesciences, Kestra, Medtronic, Merck, Orchestra BioMed, Vectorious, V-Wave, and WhiteSwell; has received grants from Volumetrix and NIH. MP has received consulting fees from CVRx. SFS serves as a research consultant on quality of life to Medtronic, Abbott, Solid Biosciences, Philips, and Milestone Pharmaceuticals; has received a research grant from CVRx and Thryv that is paid to East Carolina University; has received speaker honorarium from Medtronic, IRhythm, and Zoll Medical in the last year. FZ reports personal fees from Alnylam, Bayer, Biopeutics, Boehringer, Cellprothera, Centrix, Cereno, Centrix Corteria, CVRx, Lilly, Lupin, Merck, NovoNordisk, Opalia Recordati, Owkin, Polygon, Ribocure, Roche, Viatris, stock options or equities at Cereno pharmaceutical, founder of Cardiovascular Clinical Trialists (CVCT). MRZ has received consulting contracts for advisory committees with Abbott, Adona Medical, Alleviant, Aria CV, Avery Therapeutics, Bayer, CVRx, Diasol, EBR, Edwards Lifesciences, Lilly, GenKardia, Innoventrics, Medtronic, Novartis, Pulnovo, Salubris Biotherapeutics, Sonata, sRNAlytics, V-Wave, Vectorious, and WhiteSwell. PBA and SJW are paid employees of CVRx.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>37</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>19</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">42173348</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cardfail.2026.04.023</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1071-9164(26)00249-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>