<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">27230863</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2017</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1423-0348</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>85</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychotherapy and psychosomatics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychother Psychosom</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effects of a Psychological Internet Intervention in the Treatment of Mild to Moderate Depressive Symptoms: Results of the EVIDENT Study, a Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>218</StartPage><EndPage>228</EndPage><MedlinePgn>218-28</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000445355</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Mild to moderate depressive symptoms are common but often remain unrecognized and treated inadequately. We hypothesized that an Internet intervention in addition to usual care is superior to care as usual alone (CAU) in the treatment of mild to moderate depressive symptoms in adults.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This trial was controlled, randomized and assessor-blinded. Participants with mild to moderate depressive symptoms (Patient Health Questionnaire, PHQ-9, score 5-14) were recruited from clinical and non-clinical settings and randomized to either CAU or a 12-week Internet intervention (Deprexis) adjunctive to usual care. Outcomes were assessed at baseline, 3 months (post-assessment) and 6 months (follow-up). The primary outcome measure was self-rated depression severity (PHQ-9). The main analysis was based on the intention-to-treat principle and used linear mixed models.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 1,013 participants were randomized. Changes in PHQ-9 from baseline differed signixFB01;cantly between groups (t825 = 6.12, p &lt; 0.001 for the main effect of group). The post-assessment between-group effect size in favour of the intervention was d = 0.39 (95% CI: 0.13-0.64). It was stable at follow-up, with d = 0.32 (95% CI: 0.06-0.69). The rate of participants experiencing at least minimally clinically important PHQ-9 change at the post-assessment was higher in the intervention group (35.6 vs. 20.2%) with a number needed to treat of 7 (95% CI: 5-10).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The Internet intervention examined in this trial was superior to CAU alone in reducing mild to moderate depressive symptoms. The magnitude of the effect is clinically important and has public health implications.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2016 S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klein</LastName><ForeName>Jan Philipp</ForeName><Initials>JP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berger</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schr&#xf6;der</LastName><ForeName>Johanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sp&#xe4;th</LastName><ForeName>Christina</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyer</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caspar</LastName><ForeName>Franz</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lutz</LastName><ForeName>Wolfgang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Arndt</LastName><ForeName>Alice</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Greiner</LastName><ForeName>Wolfgang</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gr&#xe4;fe</LastName><ForeName>Viola</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hautzinger</LastName><ForeName>Martin</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fuhr</LastName><ForeName>Kristina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rose</LastName><ForeName>Matthias</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nolte</LastName><ForeName>Sandra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>L&#xf6;we</LastName><ForeName>Bernd</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Anderssoni</LastName><ForeName>Gerhard</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vettorazzi</LastName><ForeName>Eik</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moritz</LastName><ForeName>Steffen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hohagen</LastName><ForeName>Fritz</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>27</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Psychother Psychosom</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0024046</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0033-3190</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015928" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005858" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Germany</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020407" MajorTopicYN="N">Internet</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000706" MajorTopicYN="Y">statistics &amp; numerical data</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016015" MajorTopicYN="N">Logistic Models</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011569" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychiatric Status Rating Scales</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>J.P.K. has received payments for presentations, workshops and books on psychotherapy for chronic depression and on psychiatric emergencies. B.M. is employed as research director at GAIA AG, the company that developed, owns and operates the Internet intervention investigated in this trial. All the other authors report no relationships with commercial interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2015</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2016</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2016</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230863</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000445355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000445355</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Murray CJ, Vos T, Lozano R, et al. Disability-adjusted life years (DALYs) for 291 diseases and injuries in 21 regions, 1990-2010: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. Lancet. 2012;380:2197&#x2013;2223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch MA, Maske UE, Ryl L, Schlack R, Hapke U. [Prevalence of depressive symptoms and diagnosed depression among adults in Germany: results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey for Adults (DEGS1)] Bundesgesundheitsblatt Gesundheitsforschung Gesundheitsschutz. 2013;56:733&#x2013;739.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23703492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fournier JC, DeRubeis RJ, Hollon SD, Dimidjian S, Amsterdam JD, Shelton RC, Fawcett J. Antidepressant drug effects and depression severity: a patient-level meta-analysis. JAMA. 2010;303:47&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3712503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20051569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirsch I, Deacon BJ, Huedo-Medina TB, Scoboria A, Moore TJ, Johnson BT. Initial severity and antidepressant benefits: a meta-analysis of data submitted to the Food and Drug Administration. PLoS Med. 2008;5:e45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2253608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18303940</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richards D, Richardson T. Computer-based psychological treatments for depression: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Psychol Rev. 2012;32:329&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22466510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Paxling B, Roch-Norlund P, Ostman G, Norgren A, Almlov J, Georen L, Breitholtz E, Dahlin M, Cuijpers P, Carlbring P, Silverberg F. Internet-based psychodynamic versus cognitive behavioral guided self-help for generalized anxiety disorder: a randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2012;81:344&#x2013;355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22964540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kok G, Burger H, Riper H, Cuijpers P, Dekker J, van MH, Smit F, Beck A, Bockting CL. The three-month effect of mobile internet-based cognitive therapy on the course of depressive symptoms in remitted recurrently depressed patients: results of a randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2015;84:90&#x2013;99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25721915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berle D, Starcevic V, Milicevic D, Hannan A, Dale E, Brakoulias V, Viswasam K. Do patients prefer face-to-face or internet-based therapy? Psychother Psychosom. 2015;84:61&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25547039</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bower P, Kontopantelis E, Sutton A, Kendrick T, Richards DA, Gilbody S, Knowles S, Cuijpers P, Andersson G, Christensen H, Meyer B, Huibers M, Smit F, van SA, Warmerdam L, Barkham M, Bilich L, Lovell K, Liu ET. Influence of initial severity of depression on effectiveness of low intensity interventions: meta-analysis of individual patient data. BMJ. 2013;346:f540.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3582703</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23444423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson R, Andersson G. Internet-based psychological treatments for depression. Expert Rev Neurother. 2012;12:861&#x2013;869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22853793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Donker T, Johansson R, Mohr DC, van SA, Andersson G. Self-guided psychological treatment for depressive symptoms: a meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2011;6:e21274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3119687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21712998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Hammerli K, Gubser N, Andersson G, Caspar F. Internet-based treatment of depression: a randomized controlled trial comparing guided with unguided self-help. Cogn Behav Ther. 2011;40:251&#x2013;266.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22060248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Schilling L, Hauschildt M, Schr&#xf6;der J, Treszl A. A randomized controlled trial of internet-based therapy in depression. Behav Res Ther. 2012;50:513&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbody S, Littlewood E, Hewitt C, Brierley G, Tharmanathan P, Araya R, Barkham M, Bower P, Cooper C, Gask L, Kessler D, Lester H, Lovell K, Parry G, Richards DA, Andersen P, Brabyn S, Knowles S, Shepherd C, Tallon D, White D. Computerised cognitive behaviour therapy (cCBT) as treatment for depression in primary care (REEACT trial): large scale pragmatic randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2015;351:h5627.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4641883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26559241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kordy H, Wolf M, Aulich K, Burgy M, Hegerl U, Husing J, Puschner B, Rummel-Kluge C, Vedder H, Backenstrass M. Internet-delivered disease management for recurrent depression: a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2016;85:91&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26808817</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Berger T, Caspar F, Beevers CG, Andersson G, Weiss M. Effectiveness of a novel integrative online treatment for depression (Deprexis): randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2009;11:e15&#x2013;e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19632969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoifodt RS, Lillevoll KR, Griffiths KM, Wilsgaard T, Eisemann M, Waterloo K, Kolstrup N. The clinical effectiveness of web-based cognitive behavioral therapy with face-to-face therapist support for depressed primary care patients: randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2013;15:e153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3742404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23916965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Berger T, Schr&#xf6;der J, Sp&#xe4;th C, Meyer B, Lutz W, Hautzinger M, Rose M, Gr&#xe4;fe V, Hohagen F, Andersson G, Vettorrazi E, Moritz S. The EVIDENT-trial: protocol and rationale of a multicenter randomized controlled trial testing the effectiveness of an online-based psychological intervention. BMC Psychiatry. 2013;13:239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3850933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24074299</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JB. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16:606&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Bierbrodt J, Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Beevers CG, Weiss M, Jacob G, Sp&#xe4;th C, Andersson G, Lutz W, Hautzinger M, L&#xf6;we B, Rose M, Hohagen F, Caspar F, Greiner W, Moritz S, Klein JP. Effects of an Internet intervention (Deprexis) on severe depression symptoms: randomized controlled trial. Internet Interventions. 2015:48&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe B, Unutzer J, Callahan CM, Perkins AJ, Kroenke K. Monitoring depression treatment outcomes with the Patient Health Questionnaire-9. Med Care. 2004;42:1194&#x2013;1201.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15550799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stauffer JM, Mendoza JL. The proper sequence for correcting correlation coefficients for range restriction and unreliability. Psychometrika. 2001;66:63&#x2013;68.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton M. A rating scale for depression. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 1960;23:56&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC495331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14399272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rush AJ, Trivedi MH, Ibrahim HM, Carmody TJ, Arnow B, Klein DN, Markowitz JC, Ninan PT, Kornstein S, Manber R, Thase ME, Kocsis JH, Keller MB. The 16-Item Quick Inventory of Depressive Symptomatology (QIDS), clinician rating (QIDS-C), and self-report (QIDS-SR): a psychometric evaluation in patients with chronic major depression. Biol Psychiatry. 2003;54:573&#x2013;583.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12946886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan DV, Lecrubier Y, Sheehan KH, Amorim P, Janavs J, Weiller E, Hergueta T, Baker R, Dunbar GC. The Mini-International Neuropsychiatric Interview (M.I.N.I.): the development and validation of a structured diagnostic psychiatric interview for DSM-IV and ICD-10. J Clin Psychiatry. 1998;9((suppl 20)):22&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9881538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ware J, Jr, Kosinski M, Keller SD. A 12-Item Short-Form Health Survey: construction of scales and preliminary tests of reliability and validity. Med Care. 1996;34:220&#x2013;233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8628042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutz W, Sch&#xfc;rch E, Stulz N, B&#xf6;hnke , JR, Sch&#xf6;ttke H, Rogner J, Wiedl KH. Entwicklung und psychometrische Kennwerte des Fragebogens zur Evaluation von Psychotherapieverl&#xe4;ufen (FEP) Diagnostica. 2009;55:106&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gueorguieva R, Krystal JH. Move over ANOVA: progress in analyzing repeated-measures data and its reflection in papers published in the Archives of General Psychiatry. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2004;61:310&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14993119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vickers AJ, Altman DG. Statistics notes: Analysing controlled trials with baseline and follow up measurements. BMJ. 2001;323:1123&#x2013;1124.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1121605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11701584</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bell ML, Fiero M, Horton NJ, Hsu CH. Handling missing data in RCTs; a review of the top medical journals. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2014;14:118.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4247714</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25407057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van HL, Schoevers RA, Dekker J. Predicting the outcome of antidepressants and psychotherapy for depression: a qualitative, systematic review. Harv Rev Psychiatry. 2008;16:225&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18661365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E, Kleiboer A, Smit F, Turner DT, Pastor AM, Andersson G, Berger T, Botella C, Breton JM, Carlbring P, Christensen H, de GE, Griffiths K, Donker T, Farrer L, Huibers MJ, Lenndin J, Mackinnon A, Meyer B, Moritz S, Riper H, Spek V, Vernmark K, Cuijpers P. Predictors of treatment dropout in self-guided web-based interventions for depression: an &#x2018;individual patient data&#x2019; meta-analysis. Psychol Med. 2015;45:2717&#x2013;2726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25881626</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fava GA. Rational Use of Antidepressant Drugs. Psychother Psychosom. 2014;83:197&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24969962</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guidi J, Fava GA, Fava M, Papakostas GI. Efficacy of the sequential integration of psychotherapy and pharmacotherapy in major depressive disorder: a preliminary meta-analysis. Psychol Med. 2011;41:321&#x2013;331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20444307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute., for Clinical Excellence Depression: Management of depression in primary and secondary care. London, The British Psychological Society and The Royal College of Psychiatrists. 2004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spek V, Nyklicek I, Smits N, Cuijpers P, Riper H, Keyzer J, Pop V. Internet-based cognitive behavioural therapy for subthreshold depression in people over 50 years old: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Psychol Med. 2007;37:1797&#x2013;1806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17466110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan AJ, Jorm AF, Mackinnon AJ. Email-based promotion of self-help for subthreshold depression: Mood Memos randomised controlled trial. Br J Psychiatry. 2012;200:412&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22442102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hallgren M, Kraepelien M, Ojehagen A, Lindefors N, Zeebari Z, Kaldo V, Forsell Y. Physical exercise and Internet-based cognitive behavioural therapy in the treatment of depression: randomised controlled trial. Br J Psychiatry. 2015;207:227&#x2013;234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26089305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lintvedt OK, Griffiths KM, Sorensen K, Ostvik AR, Wang CE, Eisemann M, Waterloo K. Evaluating the effectiveness and efficacy of unguided internet-based self-help intervention for the prevention of depression: a randomized controlled trial. Clin Psychol Psychother. 2013;20:10&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21887811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buntrock C, Ebert D, Lehr D, Riper H, Smit F, Cuijpers P, Berking M. Effectiveness of a web-based cognitive behavioural intervention for subthreshold depression: pragmatic randomised controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2015;84:348&#x2013;358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26398885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, van SA, Warmerdam L, Smits N. Characteristics of effective psychological treatments of depression: a metaregression analysis. Psychother Res. 2008;18:225&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18815968</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J, Br&#xfc;ckner K, Fischer A, Lindenau M, K&#xf6;ther U, Vettorazzi E, Moritz S. Efficacy of a psychological online intervention for depression in people with epilepsy: A randomized controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55:2069&#x2013;2076.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25410633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Schr&#xf6;der J, Vettorazzi E, Wolf OT, P&#xf6;ttgen J, Lau S, Heesen C, Moritz S, Gold SM. An online programme to reduce depression in patients with multiple sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. The Lancet Psychiatry. 2015;2:217&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warlow C. Advanced issues in the design and conduct of randomized clinical trials: the bigger the better? Stat Med. 2002;21:2797&#x2013;2805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12325095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental A, Andersson G, Boettcher J, Ebert DD, Cuijpers P, Knaevelsrud C, Lj&#xf3;tsson B, Kaldo V, Titov N, Carlbring P. Consensus statement on defining and measuring negative effects of internet interventions. Internet Interventions. 2014;1:12&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titov N, Andrews G, Kemp A, Robinson E. Characteristics of adults with anxiety or depression treated at an internet clinic: comparison with a national survey and an outpatient clinic. PLoS One. 2010;5:e10885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2878335</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20526371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>