<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">32159711</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1809-452X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>42</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Revista brasileira de psiquiatria (Sao Paulo, Brazil : 1999)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Braz J Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of an internet-based self-guided program to treat depression in a sample of Brazilian users: a study protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>322</StartPage><EndPage>328</EndPage><MedlinePgn>322-328</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1590/1516-4446-2019-0582</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Although psychological treatments for depressive disorders are available, they are often expensive or inaccessible for many. Web-based interventions that require minimal or no contact with therapists have been shown effective. To the best of our knowledge, no study using this treatment format has been conducted in Brazil. The Deprexis program was designed using empirically established principles of cognitive-behavioral therapy to reduce depressive symptoms. The objective of this study was to evaluate the effectiveness of Deprexis in Brazil. This randomized controlled trial will include 128 Brazilians with clinically significant depression symptoms or who have been diagnosed with depressive disorder (major depressive disorder or dysthymia), recruited over the internet (Brazilian forums, social networks, or e-mail lists). Individuals with other psychiatric diagnoses that require significant attention (e.g., bipolar disorder, psychosis) will not be included in the trial. Participants will be randomly assigned to 1) treatment as usual plus immediate access to Deprexis or 2) treatment as usual plus delayed access to Deprexis (after 8 weeks). Participants will be able to obtain other treatment types in addition to the online intervention. If found effective, this web-based intervention would increase the evidence-based care options for depression treatment in Brazil. RBR-6kk3bx, UTN U1111-1212-8998.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lopes</LastName><ForeName>Rodrigo T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6579-3043</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Cat&#xf3;lica de Petr&#xf3;polis, RJ, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Meyer</LastName><ForeName>Bj&#xf6;rn</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1100-0260</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Gaia Group, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berger</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2432-7791</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Svacina</LastName><ForeName>Maria A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3151-7534</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universidade Cat&#xf3;lica de Petr&#xf3;polis, RJ, Brazil.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Brazil</Country><MedlineTA>Braz J Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100895975</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1516-4446</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001938" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Brazil</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015928" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="Y">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003865" MajorTopicYN="N">Major Depressive Disorder</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000079382" MajorTopicYN="Y">Internet-Based Intervention</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011569" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychiatric Status Rating Scales</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>BM is employed as a research director at the GAIA Group, the company that developed, owns and operates the Internet intervention investigated in this trial (Deprexis). He is not involved in data collection or analysis. The other authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2019</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32159711</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1516-4446-2019-0582</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1516-44462020005005201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>American Psychiatric Association . Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, Fifth Edition (DSM-5) Arlington: American Psychiatric Publishing; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrari AJ, Charlson FJ, Norman RE, Patten SB, Freedman G, Murray CJ, et al. Burden of depressive disorders by country, sex, age, and year: findings from the global burden of disease study 2010. PLoS Med. 2013;10:e1001547.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3818162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24223526</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murray CJ, Lopez AD. Global mortality, disability, and the contribution of risk factors: Global Burden of Disease Study. Lancet. 1997;349:1436&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9164317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;st&#xfc;n TB, Ayuso-Mateos JL, Chatterji S, Mathers C, Murray CJL. Global burden of depressive disorders in the year 2000. Br J Psychiatry. 2004;184:386&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15123501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollon SD, Thase ME, Markowitz JC. Treatment and prevention of depression. Psychol Sci Public Interest. 2002;3:39&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26151569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg PE, Kessler RC, Birnbaum HG, Leong SA, Lowe SW, Berglund PA, et al. The economic burden of depression in the United States: how did it change between 1990 and 2000? J Clin Psychiatry. 2003;64:1465&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14728109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews PW, Thomson JA., Jr The bright side of being blue: depression as an adaptation for analyzing complex problems. Psychol Rev. 2009;116:620&#x2013;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2734449</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19618990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roness A, Mykletun A, Dahl AA. Help-seeking behaviour in patients with anxiety disorder and depression. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2005;111:51&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15636594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Schr&#xf6;der J, Meyer B, Hauschildt M. The more it is needed, the less it is wanted: attitudes toward face-to-face intervention among depressed patients undergoing online treatment. Depress Anxiety. 2013;30:157&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930656</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes A, Strunk D. Research-supported psychological treatments for depression [Internet]. [cited 2020 Jan 17]  https://www.div12.org/diagnosis/depression/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Driessen E, Hollon SD, Bockting CL, Cuijpers P, Turner EH. Does publication bias inflate the apparent efficacy of psychological treatment for major depressive disorder? A systematic review and meta-analysis of US national institutes of health-funded trials. PloS One. 2015;10:e0137864.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4589340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26422604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Andersson G, Donker T, van Straten A. Psychological treatment of depression: results of a series of meta-analyses. Nord J Psychiatry. 2011;65:354&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21770842</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lopes RT, Gon&#xe7;alves MM, Fassnacht DB, Machado PP, Sousa I. Long-term effects of psychotherapy on moderate depression: a comparative study of narrative therapy and cognitive-behavioral therapy. J Affect Disord. 2014;167:64&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25082116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kazdin AE. Addressing the treatment gap: a key challenge for extending evidence-based psychosocial interventions. Behav Res Ther. 2017;88:7&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28110678</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr DC, Ho J, Duffecy J, Baron KG, Lehman KA, Jin L, et al. Perceived barriers to psychological treatments and their relationship to depression. J Clin Psychol. 2010;66:394&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2907887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20127795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xf6;ller-Leimk&#xfc;hler AM. Barriers to help-seeking by men: a review of sociocultural and clinical literature with particular reference to depression. J Affect Disord. 2002;71:1&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12167495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang PS, Berglund P, Olfson M, Pincus HA, Wells KB, Kessler RC. Failure and delay in initial treatment contact after first onset of mental disorders in the National Comorbidity Survey Replication. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005;62:603&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15939838</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnyder N, Panczak R, Groth N, Schultze-Lutter F. Association between mental health-related stigma and active help-seeking: systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Psychiatry. 2017;210:261&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28153928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambless DL, Baker-Ericzen, Baucom DH, Beutler LE, Calhoun KS, Crits-Christoph P, et al. Update on empirically validated therapies II. Clin Psychol. 1998;51:3&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambless DL, Hollon SD. Defining empirically supported therapies. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1998;66:7&#x2013;18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9489259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall PC. Empirically supported psychological therapies. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1998;66:3&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9489258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kendall PC, Holmbeck G, Verduin T. Methodology, design, and evaluation in psychotherapy research. In: Lambert MJ, editor. Bergin and Garfield&#x2019;s handbook of psychotherapy and behavior change. 5th ed. New York: Wiley; 2004. pp. p. 16&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Kemper J, St&#xfc;rmer C. Public acceptability of e-mental health treatment services for psychological problems: a scoping review. JMIR Ment Health. 2017;4:e10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5394261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28373153</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barak A, Grohol JM. Current and future trends in internet-supported mental health interventions. J Technol Hum Serv. 2011;29:155&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Carlbring P, Berger T, Alml&#xf6;v J, Cuijpers P. What makes internet therapy work? Cogn Behav Ther. 2009;38(Supll 1):55&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19675956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Hesser H, Hummerdal D, Bergman-Nordgren L, Carlbring P. A 3.5-year follow-up of Internet-delivered cognitive behavior therapy for major depression. J Ment Health. 2013;22:155&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21957933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Caspar F, Richardson R, Kneub&#xfc;hler B, Sutter D, Andersson G. Internet-based treatment of social phobia: a randomized controlled trial comparing unguided with two types of guided self-help. Behav Res Ther. 2011;49:158&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21255767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Andersson G. Internet-based treatments &#x2013; experiences from Sweden: an interview with Gerhard Andersson. Verhaltenstherapie. 2013;23:211&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, H&#xe4;mmerli K, Gubser N, Andersson G, Caspar F. Internet-based treatment of depression: a randomized controlled trial comparing guided with unguided self-help. Cogn Behav Ther. 2011;40:251&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22060248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Messerli-B&#xfc;rgy N, Barth J, Berger T. The InterHerz project &#x2013; a web-based psychological treatment for cardiac patients with depression: study protocol of a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2012;13:245.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3551787</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23273042</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Donker T, van Straten A, Li J, Andersson G. Is guided self-help as effective as face-to-face psychotherapy for depression and anxiety disorders? A systematic review and meta-analysis of comparative outcome studies. Psychol Med. 2010;40:1943&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20406528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hedman E, Andersson G, Lj&#xf3;tsson B, Andersson E, R&#xfc;ck C, M&#xf6;rtberg E, et al. Internet-based cognitive behavior therapy vs. cognitive behavioral group therapy for social anxiety disorder: a randomized controlled non-inferiority trial. PLoS One. 2011;6:e18001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3070741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21483704</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E, Riper H, Twisk J, Hoogendoorn A, Kleiboer A, Mira A, et al. Efficacy of self-guided internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy in the treatment of depressive symptoms: a meta-analysis of individual participant data. JAMA Psychiatry. 2017;74:351&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28241179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical power analysis for the behavioral sciences. 2nd ed. Hillsdale: Erlbaum; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Twomey C, O&#x2019;Reilly G, B&#xfc;ltmann O, Meyer B. Effectiveness of a tailored, integrative Internet intervention (deprexis) for depression: updated meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2020;15:e0228100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992171</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31999743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conselho Federal de Psicologia  . Resolu&#xe7;&#xe3;o CFP n&#xb0; 011/2018: Regulamenta a presta&#xe7;&#xe3;o de servi&#xe7;os psicol&#xf3;gicos realizados por meios de tecnologias da informa&#xe7;&#xe3;o e da comunica&#xe7;&#xe3;o e revoga a Resolu&#xe7;&#xe3;o CFP n&#xb0; 11/2012.   http://site.cfp.org.br/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/RESOLU%C3%87%C3%83O-N%C2%BA-11-DE-11-DE-MAIO-DE-2018.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pieta MAM, Gomes WB. Psicoterapia pela internet: vi&#xe1;vel ou invi&#xe1;vel? Psicol Cienc Prof. 2014;34:18&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T, Krieger T, Sude K, Meyer B, Maercker A. Evaluating an e-mental health program (&#x201c;deprexis&#x201d;) as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J Affect Disord. 2018;227:455&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xfc;cker L, Bierbrodt J, Hand I, Wittekind C, Moritz S. Effects of a depression-focused internet intervention in slot machine gamblers: a randomized controlled trial. PloS One. 2018;13:e0198859.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5993308</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29883479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuhr K, Fahse B, Hautzinger M, Gulewitsch MD. Erste Erfahrungen zur Implementierbarkeit einer internet-basierten Selbsthilfe zur &#xdc;berbr&#xfc;ckung der Wartezeit auf eine ambulante Psychotherapie. Psychother Psych Med. 2018;68:234&#x2013;41.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29351710</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zwerenz R, Becker J, Knickenberg RJ, Siepmann M, Hagen K, Beutel ME. Online self-help as an add-on to inpatient psychotherapy: efficacy of a new blended treatment approach. Psychother Psychosom. 2017;86:341&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29131090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Berger T, Caspar F, Beevers CG, Andersson G, Weiss M. Effectiveness of a novel integrative online treatment for depression (deprexis): randomized controlled trial. J Med Internet Res. 2009;11:e15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19632969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fischer A, Schr&#xf6;der J, Vettorazzi E, Wolf OT, P&#xf6;ttgen J, Lau S, et al. An online programme to reduce depression in patients with multiple sclerosis: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet Psychiatry. 2015;2:217&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26359900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein JP, Berger T, Schr&#xf6;der J, Sp&#xe4;th C, Meyer B, Caspar F, et al. Effects of a psychological internet intervention in the treatment of mild to moderate depressive symptoms: results of the EVIDENT study, a randomized controlled trial. Psychother Psychosom. 2016;85:218&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer B, Bierbrodt J, Schr&#xf6;der J, Berger T, Beevers CG, Weiss M, et al. Effects of an Internet intervention (deprexis) on severe depression symptoms: randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. 2015;2:48&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moritz S, Schilling L, Hauschildt M, Schr&#xf6;der J, Treszl A. A randomized controlled trial of internet-based therapy in depression. Behav Res Ther. 2012;50:513&#x2013;21.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J, Br&#xfc;ckner K, Fischer A, Lindenau M, K&#xf6;ther U, Vettorazzi E, et al. Efficacy of a psychological online intervention for depression in people with epilepsy: a randomized controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55:2069&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25410633</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beevers CG, Pearson R, Hoffman JS, Foulser AA, Shumake J, Meyer B. Effectiveness of an internet intervention (deprexis) for depression in a united states adult sample: a parallel-group pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2017;85:367&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28230390</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santos IS, Tavares BF, Munhoz TN, de Almeida LSP, da Silva NTB, Tams BD, et al. Sensibilidade e especificidade do Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) entre adultos da popula&#xe7;&#xe3;o geral. Cad Saude Publica. 2013;29:1533&#x2013;43.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24005919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JB. Validation and utility of a self-report version of PRIME-MD: the PHQ primary care study. Primary Care Evaluation of Mental Disorders. Patient Health Questionnaire. JAMA. 1999;282:1737&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10568646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mo&#x15b;cicki EK, Clarke DE, Kuramoto SJ, Kraemer HC, Narrow WE, Kupfer DJ, et al. Testing DSM-5 in routine clinical practice settings: feasibility and clinical utility. Psychiatr Serv. 2013;64:952&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23852272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narrow WE, Clarke DE, Kuramoto SJ, Kraemer HC, Kupfer DJ, Greiner L, et al. DSM-5 field trials in the United States and Canada, Part III: development and reliability testing of a cross-cutting symptom assessment for DSM-5. Am J Psychiatry. 2013;170:71&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23111499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraguas R, Jr, Henriques SG, Jr, De Lucia MS, Iosifescu DV, Schwartz FH, Menezes PR, et al. The detection of depression in medical setting: a study with PRIME-MD. J Affect Disord. 2006;91:11&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16427132</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morilha A, Karagulian S, Lotufo PA, Santos IS, Bense&#xf1;or IM, Goulart AC. Abuso de &#xe1;lcool ap&#xf3;s s&#xed;ndrome coronariana aguda: avalia&#xe7;&#xe3;o prospectiva no estudo ERICO. Arq Bras Cardiol. 2015;104:457&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4484678</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26131701</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva M de M e, Mercer PBS, Witt MCZ, Pessoa RGR, Viveiros CP, Gazola BB, et al. Testes de rastreio para altera&#xe7;&#xf5;es psiqui&#xe1;tricas em esclerose m&#xfa;ltipla &#x2013; revis&#xe3;o sistem&#xe1;tica com metan&#xe1;lise. J Bras Psiquiatr. 2018;67:255&#x2013;63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Lima Os&#xf3;rio F, Vilela Mendes A, Crippa JA, Loureiro SR. Study of the discriminative validity of the PHQ-9 and PHQ-2 in a sample of Brazilian women in the context of primary health care. Perspect Psychiatr Care. 2009;45:216&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19566694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Evans C, Connell J, Barkham M, Margison F, McGrath G, Mellor-Clark J, et al. Towards a standardised brief outcome measure: psychometric properties and utility of the CORE-OM. Br J Psychiatry. 2002;180:51&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11772852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santana MRM, da Silva MM, de Moraes DS, Fukuda CC, Freitas LH, Ramos ME, et al. Brazilian Portuguese version of the CORE-OM: cross-cultural adaptation of an instrument to assess the efficacy and effectiveness of psychotherapy. Trends Psychiatry Psychother. 2015;37:227&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689392</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attkisson CC, Zwick R. The client satisfaction questionnaire. Psychometric properties and correlations with service utilization and psychotherapy outcome. Eval Program Plann. 1982;5:233&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10259963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attkisson CC, Greenfield TK. The UCSF client satisfaction scales: I. The client satisfaction questionnaire-8. In: Maruish ME, editor. The use of psychological testing for treatment planning and outcomes assessment: instruments for adults. Vol. 3. 3th ed. Mahwah: Lawrence Erlbaum Associates Publishers; 2004. pp. p. 799&#x2013;811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krieger T, Meyer B, Sude K, Urech A, Maercker A, Berger T. Evaluating an e-mental health program (&#x201c;deprexis&#x201d;) as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: design of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. BMC Psychiatry. 2014;14:285.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4195959</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25298158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eysenbach G, Consort-Ehealth Group CONSORT-EHEALTH: improving and standardizing evaluation reports of Web-based and mobile health interventions. J Med Internet Res. 2011;13:e126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3278112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22209829</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Schulz KF, Altman D. CONSORT Group (Consolidated Standards of Reporting Trials). The CONSORT statement: revised recommendations for improving the quality of reports of parallel-group randomized trials. JAMA. 2001;285:1987&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11308435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobson NS, Truax P. Clinical significance: a statistical approach to defining meaningful change in psychotherapy research. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1991;59:12&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2002127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conselho Federal de Psicologia  . C&#xf3;digo de &#xc9;tica Profissional do Psic&#xf3;logo [Internet]. 2005.  [cited 2014 Sep 30].  http://site.cfp.org.br/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/codigo_etica1.pdf.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>