<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41619247</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1423-0348</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>31</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychotherapy and psychosomatics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychother Psychosom</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Blended Cognitive Behavioral Therapy versus Standard Cognitive Behavioral Therapy for Unipolar Depression: A Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1</StartPage><EndPage>14</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1-14</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1159/000550820</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study evaluated the effectiveness of blended cognitive behavioral therapy (bCBT) with a digital health application (elona therapy) compared to standard cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) for unipolar depression in outpatient care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This multicenter, randomized, two-arm controlled trial recruited 283 adult patients with unipolar depression in Germany. Patients were randomized to receive either standard face-to-face CBT combined with the digital health application (bCBT group) or standard face-to-face CBT alone. Symptoms of depression and anxiety, along with other patient-related characteristics, were assessed at baseline (T0: week 0) and post-intervention (T1: week 12).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Patients in the bCBT group showed greater improvements in depressive symptoms (primary outcome: d = 0.62, p &lt; 0.001), anxiety (d = 0.61, p &lt; 0.001), quality of life (d = 0.42, p &lt; 0.001), perceived self-efficacy (d = 0.41, p = 0.003), depression literacy (d = 0.66, p &lt; 0.001) and overall disease severity outcomes (d = 0.45-0.60, ps &lt; 0.005) compared with patients in the CBT group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study provides evidence supporting the effectiveness of bCBT in patients diagnosed with unipolar depressive disorder across a broad range of clinically relevant outcomes. The discussion addresses important limitations of this trial.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2026 The Author(s). Published by S. Karger AG, Basel.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalde</LastName><ForeName>Jan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Psychology, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany, jan.kalde@hhu.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atik</LastName><ForeName>Ece</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Psychotherapy, Georg Elias M&#xfc;ller Institute of Psychology, University of G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stricker</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Psychology, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sch&#xfc;ckes</LastName><ForeName>Magnus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for SME Research and Entrepreneurship, University of Mannheim, Mannheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Neudeck</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology, Technical University Chemnitz, Chemnitz, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abel</LastName><ForeName>Pamela</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>AVT-Akademie f&#xfc;r Verhaltenstherapie, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hollank</LastName><ForeName>Johanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>MoVA Institut f&#xfc;r Moderne Verhaltenstherapie, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pittig</LastName><ForeName>Andre</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Psychotherapy, Georg Elias M&#xfc;ller Institute of Psychology, University of G&#xf6;ttingen, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pietrowsky</LastName><ForeName>Reinhard</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Experimental Psychology, Heinrich Heine University D&#xfc;sseldorf, D&#xfc;sseldorf, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Psychother Psychosom</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0024046</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0033-3190</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blended cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital therapeutics</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>E.A. is a part-time employee at Elona Health alongside her academic responsibilities. J.S. and A.P. have worked as consultants for Elona Health. M.S. and P.N. are shareholders of Elona Health. J.K., P.H., J.H., and R.P. did not have any conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>13</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41619247</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13008395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000550820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">000550820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gillham JE, Shatt&#xe9; AJ, Freres DR. Preventing depression: a review of cognitive-behavioral and family interventions. Appl Prev Psychol. 2000;9(2):63&#x2013;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2019 Diseases and Injuries Collaborators . Global burden of 369 diseases and injuries in 204 countries and territories, 1990-2019: a systematic analysis for the global burden of disease study 2019. Lancet. 2020;396(10258):1204&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7567026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
APA (American Psychological Association) . Clinical practice guideline for the treatment of depression across three age cohorts. 2019. https://www.apa.org/depression-guideline/guideline.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hofmann SG, Asnaani A, Vonk IJ, Sawyer AT, Fang A. The efficacy of cognitive behavioral therapy: a review of meta-analyses. Cognit Ther Res. 2012;36(5):427&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3584580</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23459093</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
NICE (National Institute for Health and Care Excellence) . Depression in adults: treatment and management. 2009. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng222</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35977056</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helbig S, Fehm L. Problems with homework in CBT: rare exception or rather frequent? Behav Cogn Psychother. 2004;32(3):291&#x2013;301.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shafran R, Clark DM, Fairburn CG, Arntz A, Barlow DH, Ehlers A, et al. Mind the gap: improving the dissemination of CBT. Behav Res Ther. 2009;47(11):902&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19664756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Miguel C, Harrer M, Plessen CY, Ciharova M, Ebert D, et al. Cognitive behavior therapy vs. control conditions, other psychotherapies, pharmacotherapies and combined treatment for depression: a comprehensive meta-analysis including 409 trials with 52,702 patients. World Psychiatry. 2023;22(1):105&#x2013;15.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36640411</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wojnarowski C, Firth N, Finegan M, Delgadillo J. Predictors of depression relapse and recurrence after cognitive behavioural therapy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Behav Cogn Psychother. 2019;47(5):514&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30894231</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G, Titov N. Advantages and limitations of Internet-based interventions for common mental disorders. World Psychiatry. 2014;13(1):4&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3918007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24497236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbe D, Eichert H-C, Riper H, Ebert DD. Blending face-to-face and internet-based interventions for the treatment of mental disorders in adults: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2017;19(9):e306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G. Internet-delivered psychological treatments. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2016;12(1):157&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26652054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster R, Laireiter A-R, Berger T, Moritz S, Meyer B, Hohagen F, et al. Immediate and long-term effectiveness of adding an Internet intervention for depression to routine outpatient psychotherapy: subgroup analysis of the EVIDENT trial. J Affect Disord. 2020;274:643&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Kleiboer A, Karyotaki E, Riper H. Internet and mobile interventions for depression: opportunities and challenges. Depress Anxiety. 2017;34(7):596&#x2013;602.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28471479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrao Nunes-Zlotkowski K, Shepherd HL, Beatty L, Butow P, Shaw JM. Blended psychological therapy for the treatment of psychological disorders in adult patients: systematic review and meta-analysis. Interact J Med Res. 2024;13:e49660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11558224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39470720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacmon J, Malouff JM, Taylor N. Treatment of major depression: effectiveness of cognitive-behavioural therapy with an internet course as a central component. E-J Appl Psychol. 2009;5(2):1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thase ME, Wright JH, Eells TD, Barrett MS, Wisniewski SR, Balasubramani GK, et al. Improving the efficiency of psychotherapy for depression: computer-assisted versus standard CBT. Am J Psychiatry. 2018;175(3):242&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5848497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28969439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly KH, Topooco N, Cederlund H, Wallin A, Bergstr&#xf6;m J, Molander O, et al. Smartphone-supported versus full behavioural activation for depression: a randomised controlled trial. PLoS One. 2015;10(5):e0126559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4444307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26010890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez JC, Fern&#xe1;ndez O, C&#xe1;ceres C, Carrasco &#xc1;E, Moessner M, Bauer S, et al. An adjunctive internet-based intervention to enhance treatment for depression in adults: randomized controlled trial. JMIR Ment Health. 2021;8(12):e26814.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8726028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34927594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalde J, Atik E, Stricker J, Sch&#xfc;ckes M, Neudeck P, Pittig A, et al. Enhancing the effectiveness of CBT for patients with unipolar depression by integrating digital interventions into treatment: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Psychother Res. 2024;34(8):1131&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37922395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tang W, Kreindler D. Supporting homework compliance in cognitive behavioural therapy: essential features of mobile apps. JMIR Ment Health. 2017;4(2):e20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5481663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atik E, Sch&#xfc;ckes M, Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J. Patient and therapist expectations for a blended cognitive behavioral therapy program for depression: qualitative exploratory study. JMIR Ment Health. 2022;9(12):e36806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9840101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36583934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun P, Atik E, Guthardt L, Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Sch&#xfc;ckes M. Barriers to and facilitators of a blended cognitive behavioral therapy program for depression and anxiety based on experiences of university students: qualitative interview study. JMIR Form Res. 2023;7:e45970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10134026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37043272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atik E, Stricker J, Sch&#xfc;ckes M, Pittig A. Efficacy of a brief blended cognitive behavioral therapy program for the treatment of depression and anxiety in university students: uncontrolled intervention study. JMIR Ment Health. 2023;10:e44742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10492172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37624631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margraf J, Cwik JC, Pflug V, Schneider S. Strukturierte klinische Interviews zur Erfassung psychischer St&#xf6;rungen &#xfc;ber die Lebensspanne: G&#xfc;tekriterien und Weiterentwicklungen der DIPS-Verfahren [Structured clinical interviews for mental disorders across the lifespan: psychometric quality and further developments of the DIPS Open Access interviews]. Zeitschrift f&#xfc;r Klinische Psychologie und Psychotherapie. 2017;46(3):176&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weltgesundheitsorganisation . Taschenf&#xfc;hrer zur ICD-10-Klassifikation psychischer St&#xf6;rungen: Mit Glossar und diagnostischen Kriterien sowie Referenztabellen: ICD-10 vs. ICD-9 und ICD-10 vs. DSM-IV-TR (9. ed.) [Pocket guide to the ICD-10 classification of mental disorders: with glossary and diagnostic criteria and reference tables: ICD-10 vs. ICD-9 and ICD-10 vs. DSM-IV-TR]. Dilling H, Freyberger HJ, Cooper JE, eds. 9th ed. Bern: Hogrefe; 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K, Spitzer RL, Williams JBW. The PHQ-9: validity of a brief depression severity measure. J Gen Intern Med. 2001;16(9):606&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1495268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11556941</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;we B, Spitzer RL, Zipfel S, Herzog W. Gesundheitsfragebogen f&#xfc;r Patienten (PHQ-D). Manual und Testunterlagen: Vol. (2. Auflage). Karlsruhe: Pfizer; 2002.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gr&#xe4;fe K, Zipfel S, Herzog W, L&#xf6;we B. Screening psychischer St&#xf6;rungen mit dem &#x201c;Gesundheitsfragebogen f&#xfc;r Patienten (PHQ-D)&#x201d;: Ergebnisse der deutschen Validierungsstudie [Screening for psychiatric disorders with the Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ). Results from the German validation study]. Diagnostica. 2004;50(4):171&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spitzer RL, Kroenke K, Williams JBW, L&#xf6;we B. A brief measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder: the GAD-7. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(10):1092&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16717171</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>L&#xf6;we B, Decker O, M&#xfc;ller S, Br&#xe4;hler E, Schellberg D, Herzog W, et al. Validation and standardization of the generalized anxiety disorder screener (GAD-7) in the general population. Med Care. 2008;46(3):266&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18388841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skevington SM, Lotfy M, O&#x2019;Connell KA, WHOQOL Group . The world health organization&#x2019;s WHOQOL-BREF quality of life assessment: psychometric properties and results of the international field trial. A report from the WHOQOL group. Qual Life Res. 2004;13(2):299&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15085902</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WHO . World health organization: WHOQOL-BREF: Introduction, administration, scoring and generic version of the assessment&#x2014;Field trial version. 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R, Jerusalem M. Generalized self-efficacy scale. In: Weinheim J, Wright S, Johnston M, eds. Measures in health psychology: a user&#x2019;s portfolio. Causal and control beliefs. Windsor, UK: NFER-Nelson; 1995. p. 35&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R, Mueller J, Greenglass E. Assessment of perceived general self-efficacy on the internet: data collection in cyberspace. Anxiety Stress Coping. 1999;12(2):145&#x2013;61.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R, Jerusalem M. Skalen zur Erfassung von Lehrer-und Sch&#xfc;lermerkmalen. Dokumentation der psychometrischen Verfahren im Rahmen der Wissenschaftlichen Begleitung des Modellversuchs Selbstwirksame Schulen. Berlin: Freie Universit&#xe4;t Berlin; 1999.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freitag S, Stolzenburg S, Schomerus G, Schmidt S. Depressionswissen &#x2013; Deutsche &#xdc;bersetzung und Testung der Depression Literacy Scale. Psychiatr Prax. 2018;45(8):412&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29237194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andrews G, Basu A, Cuijpers P, Craske MG, McEvoy P, English CL, et al. Computer therapy for the anxiety and depression disorders is effective, acceptable and practical health care: an updated meta-analysis. J Anxiety Disord. 2018;55:70&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29422409</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister H, Gr&#xe4;ssle C, Ebert D, Kr&#xe4;mer L. Blended Psychotherapy &#x2013; verzahnte Psychotherapie: Das Beste aus zwei Welten? Psychother Dialog. 2018;19(4):33&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe5;nsson KN, Skagius Ruiz E, Gervind E, Dahlin M, Andersson G. Development and initial evaluation of an internet-based support system for face-to-face cognitive behavior therapy: a proof of concept study. J Med Internet Res. 2013;15(12):e280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3868964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24326065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guy W. ECDEU assessment manual for psychopharmacology, revised. Rockville: US Department of Health, Education, and Welfare Publication (ADM). National Institute of Mental Health; 1976.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Collegium Internationale Psychiatriae Scalarum (CIPS) (Hrsg.) . (1996). Internationale Skalen f&#xfc;r Psychiatrie (4., &#xfc;berarb. u. erw. Aufl.). Weinheim: Beltz.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinshausen N. Hierarchical testing of variable importance. Biometrika. 2008;95(2):265&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israel JA. Remission in depression: definition and initial treatment approaches. J Psychopharmacol. 2006;20(3 Suppl):5&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16644766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller MB. Past, present, and future directions for defining optimal treatment outcome in depression: remission and beyond. JAMA. 2003;289(23):3152&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12813121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMillan D, Gilbody S, Richards D. Defining successful treatment outcome in depression using the PHQ-9: a comparison of methods. J Affect Disord. 2010;127(1&#x2013;3):122&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20569992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang A-G, Buchner A. G*Power 3: a flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39(2):175&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17695343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper AA, Conklin LR. Dropout from individual psychotherapy for major depression: a meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials. Clin Psychol Rev. 2015;40:57&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26067572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter JR, Roger JH, Kenward MG. Analysis of longitudinal trials with protocol deviation: a framework for relevant, accessible assumptions, and inference via multiple imputation. J Biopharm Stat. 2013;23(6):1352&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24138436</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB. Multiple imputation for nonresponse in surveys. 1st ed.New York: Wiley; 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Turner EH, Koole SL, van Dijke A, Smit F. What is the threshold for a clinically relevant effect? The case of major depressive disorders. Depress Anxiety. 2014;31(5):374&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24677535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topp R, Greenstein J, Etnoyer-Slaski J. The effect of a mobile health app on treatment adherence and revenue at physical health clinics: retrospective record review. JMIR Rehabil Assist Technol. 2023;10:e43507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10131932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36889337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiecek E, Torres-Robles A, Cutler RL, Benrimoj SI, Garcia-Cardenas V. Impact of a multicomponent digital therapeutic mobile app on medication adherence in patients with chronic conditions: retrospective analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2020;22(8):e17834.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7450368</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32784183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fan S, Jain RC, Kankanhalli MS. A comprehensive picture of factors affecting user willingness to use mobile health applications. ACM Trans Comput Healthc. 2024;5(1):1&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippi P, Baumeister H, Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J, Ebert DD, Hennemann S, Kott L, et al. Acceptance towards digital health interventions - model validation and further development of the unified theory of acceptance and use of technology. Internet Interv. 2021;26:100459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8463857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34603973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Howarth J. How many people own smartphones? (2025-2029). 2025. Retrieved 17/10/25 from: https://explodingtopics.com/blog/smartphone-stats</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mueller A, Segal DL. Structured versus semistructured versus unstructured interviews. In: Cautin RL, Lilienfeld SO, eds. The encyclopedia of clinical psychology. Hoboken: John Wiley and Sons, Inc; 2015. p. 1&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>