<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">38457150</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>16</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1877-718X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14</Volume><Issue>s1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of Parkinson's disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Parkinsons Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Can Physical Exercise Be Considered as a Promising Enhancer of Global Cognition in People with Parkinson's Disease? Results of a Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>S115</StartPage><EndPage>S133</EndPage><MedlinePgn>S115-S133</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3233/JPD-230343</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Physical exercise interventions are known to improve quality of life, motor and non-motor symptoms in people with Parkinson's disease (PD). However, systematic reviews and meta-analyses on cognitive outcomes are rare.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To perform a systematic review and meta-analysis of physical exercise intervention effects compared with passive and active control groups (CGs) on global cognition in people with PD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A literature search was performed for randomized controlled trials (RCTs) on physical exercise interventions in PD using nine databases. We included RCTs reporting global cognition outcomes. A meta-analysis was performed using random-effects models and standardized mean differences (SMDs) with 95% confidence intervals (CIs). Bias was assessed with the revised Cochrane Risk of Bias tool and the certainty of evidence was rated using the GRADE approach.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Seventeen studies (ten with passive, seven with active CGs) were included in the systematic review. Exercise interventions varied considerably between studies. The meta-analysis included nine studies with 236 people with PD (seven with passive, two with active CGs). The SMD was 0.33 (95% CI 0.00; 0.65) demonstrating a small effect (p&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.05) in favor of physical exercise. Compared with passive CGs, physical exercise had a small non-significant effect (SMD&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.22, 95% CI -0.14;0.58, p&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.24). Compared with active CGs, physical exercise had a medium significant effect (SMD&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.72, 95% CI 0.12;1.33, p&#x200a;=&#x200a;0.02).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Physical exercise may increase global cognition in people with PD, but the evidence is very uncertain. Further large-scale RCTs are needed to confirm this finding and to identify the most effective type of physical exercise for improving cognition.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Folkerts</LastName><ForeName>Ann-Kristin</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies &amp; Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ernst</LastName><ForeName>Moritz</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Public Health, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gollan</LastName><ForeName>Romina</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies &amp; Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Deakin University, Institute for Physical Activity and Nutrition (IPAN), School of Exercise and Nutrition Sciences, Geelong, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cryns</LastName><ForeName>Nora</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Public Health, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monsef</LastName><ForeName>Ina</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Public Health, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Skoetz</LastName><ForeName>Nicole</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Public Health, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalbe</LastName><ForeName>Elke</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies &amp; Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention (CeNDI), Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D000078182">Systematic Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Parkinsons Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101567362</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1877-7171</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005081" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000534" MajorTopicYN="N">rehabilitation</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson&#x2019;s disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mental status and dementia tests</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuropsychology</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical exercise</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>AKF has received grants from the German Parkinson Society, the German Alzheimer&#x2019;s Society, the German Parkinson Foundation, STADAPHARM GmbH and the General Joint Committee Germany as well as honoraria from Springer Medizin Verlag GmbH, Heidelberg, Germany; Springer-Verlag GmbH, Berlin; ProLog Wissen GmbH, Cologne, Germany; Seminar- und Fortbildungszentrum Rheine, Germany; LOGOMANIA, Fendt &amp; Sax GbR, Munich, Germany; LOGUAN, Ulm, Germany; dbse.V., Moers, Germany; STADAPHARM GmbH, Bad Vilbel, Germany; NEUROPSY, St. Konrad, Austria; Multiple Sclerosis Society Vienna, Vienna, Austria; and Gossweiler Foundation, Bern, Switzerland. AKF is one of the authors of the cognitive intervention series &#x201c;NEUROvitalis&#x201d; but receives no corresponding honoraria. EK has received grants from the German Ministry of Education and Research, General Joint Committee, Germany, the German Parkinson Society, and STADAPHARM GmbH; honoraria from AbbVie GmbH Germany; memodio GmbH Germany; license fees from Prolog GmbH, Germany. EK is one of the authors of the cognitive intervention series &#x201c;NEUROvitalis&#x201d; but receives no corresponding honoraria. All other authors have no conflict of interest to report.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38457150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11380223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JPD-230343</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">JPD230343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Svenningsson P, Westman E, Ballard C, Aarsland D (2012) Cognitive impairment in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: Diagnosis, biomarkers, and treatment. Lancet Neurol 11, 697&#x2013;707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Severiano Sousa EC, Alarc&#xe3;o J, Pav&#xe3;o Martins I, Ferreira JJ (2022) Frequency of dementia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Neurol Sci 432, 120077.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34896923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aarsland D, Kurz MW (2010) The epidemiology of dementia associated with Parkinson disease. J Neurol Sci 289, 18&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19733364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saredakis D, Collins-Praino LE, Gutteridge DS, Stephan BCM, Keage HAD (2019) Conversion to MCI and dementia in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Parkinsonism Relat Disord 65, 20&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31109727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang N, Ju Y, Ren J, Wang H, Li P, Ning H, Tao J, Liu W (2022) Prevalence and affective correlates of subjective cognitive decline in patients with de novo Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Acta Neurol Scand 146, 276&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9545461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35722712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalbe E, Rehberg SP, Heber I, Kronenbuerger M, Schulz JB, Storch A, Linse K, Schneider C, Gr&#xe4;ber S, Liepelt-Scarfone I, Berg D, Dams J, Balzer-Geldsetzer M, Hilker R, Oberschmidt C, Witt K, Schmidt N, Mollenhauer B, Trenkwalder C, Spottke A, Roeske S, Wittchen HU, Riedel O, Dodel R (2016) Subtypes of mild cognitive impairment in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: Evidence from the LANDSCAPE study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 87, 1099&#x2013;1105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27401782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aarsland D, Batzu L, Halliday GM, Geurtsen GJ, Ballard C, Ray Chaudhuri K, Weintraub D (2021) Parkinson disease-associated cognitive impairment. Nat Rev Dis Primers 7, 47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun C, Armstrong M (2021) Treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with cognitive impairment: Current approaches and future directions. Behav Sci (Basel) 11, 54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33920698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogosian A, Rixon L, Hurt CS (2020) Prioritising target non-pharmacological interventions for research in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: Achieving consensus from key stakeholders. Res Involv Engagem 6, 35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7315468</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32595982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gavelin HM, Domell&#xf6;f ME, Leung I, Neely AS, Launder NH, Nategh L, Finke C, Lampit A (2022) Computerized cognitive training in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Ageing Res Rev 80, 101671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35714854</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung IH, Walton CC, Hallock H, Lewis SJ, Valenzuela M, Lampit A (2015) Cognitive training in Parkinson disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurology 85, 1843&#x2013;1851.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4662707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26519540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petzinger GM, Fisher BE, McEwen S, Beeler JA, Walsh JP, Jakowec MW (2013) Exercise-enhanced neuroplasticity targeting motor and cognitive circuitry in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Lancet Neurol 12, 716&#x2013;726.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3690528</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23769598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson H, Hagstr&#xf6;mer M, Grooten WJA, Franz&#xe9;n E (2020) Exercise-induced neuroplasticity in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A metasynthesis of the literature. Neural Plast 2020, 8961493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7079218</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32256559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Picelli A, Varalta V, Melotti C, Zatezalo V, Fonte C, Amato S, Saltuari L, Santamato A, Fiore P, Smania N (2016) Effects of treadmill training on cognitive and motor features of patients with mild to moderate Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A pilot, single-blind, randomized controlled trial. Funct Neurol 31, 25&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4819815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27027891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Altmann LJ, Stegem&#xf6;ller E, Hazamy AA, Wilson JP, Bowers D, Okun MS, Hass CJ (2016) Aerobic exercise improves mood, cognition, and language function in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: Results of a controlled study. J Int Neuropsychol Soc 22, 878&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27655232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solla P, Cugusi L, Bertoli M, Cereatti A, Della Croce U, Pani D, Fadda L, Cannas A, Marrosu F, Defazio G, Mercuro G (2019) Sardinian folk dance for individuals with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A randomized controlled pilot trial. J Altern Complement Med 25, 305&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30624952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gollan R, Ernst M, Lieker E, Caro-Valenzuela J, Monsef I, Dresen A, Roheger M, Skoetz N, Kalbe E, Folkerts AK (2022) Effects of resistance training on motor- and non-motor symptoms in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. J Parkinsons Dis 12, 1783&#x2013;1806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35754291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marotta N, Calafiore D, Curci C, Lippi L, Ammendolia V, Ferraro F, Invernizzi M, de Sire A (2022) Integrating virtual reality and exergaming in cognitive rehabilitation of patients with Parkinson disease: A systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Eur J Phys Rehabil Med 58, 818&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10081485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36169933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang K, Li K, Zhang P, Ge S, Wen X, Wu Z, Yao X, Jiao B, Sun P, Lv P, Lu L (2021) Mind-body exercises for non-motor symptoms of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Front Aging Neurosci 13, 770920.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9549381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36226304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Wang G, Zhang S, Wang H, Zhou W, Ren F, Liang H, Wu D, Ji X, Hashimoto M, Wei J (2022) Efficacy and evaluation of therapeutic exercises on adults with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. BMC Geriatr 22, 813.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9587576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36271367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernst M, Folkerts AK, Gollan R, Lieker E, Caro-Valenzuela J, Adams A, Cryns N, Monsef I, Dresen A, Roheger M, Eggers C, Skoetz N, Kalbe E (2023) Physical exercise for people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 1, CD013856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9815433</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36602886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, Shamseer L, Tetzlaff JM, Akl EA, Brennan SE, Chou R, Glanville J, Grimshaw JM, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Lalu MM, Li T, Loder EW, Mayo-Wilson E, McDonald S, McGuinness LA, Stewart LA, Thomas J, Tricco AC, Welch VA, Whiting P, Moher D (2021) The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 372, n71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8005924</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33782057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strauss E, Sherman EMS, Spreen O (2006) A Compendium of Neuropsychological Tests: Administration, Norms, and Commentary (3rd ed.). Oxford University Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sterne JA, Savovi&#x107; J, Page MJ, Elbers RG, Blencowe NS, Boutron I, Cates CJ, Cheng HY, Corbett MS, Eldridge SM, Emberson JR, Hern&#xe1;n MA, Hopewell S, Hr&#xf3;bjartsson A, Junqueira DR, J&#xfc;ni P, Kirkham JJ, Lasserson T, Li T, McAleenan A, Reeves BC, Shepperd S, Shrier I, Stewart LA, Tilling K, White IR, Whiting PF, Higgins JPT (2019) RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 366, l4898.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston M, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA (2023) Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions (Version 6.4),https://training.cochrane.org/handbook.Last updated 22
August, 2023, Accessed October 2nd, 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J (1988) Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences (Second Edition). Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Hillsdale, NJ.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sch&#xfc;nemann H, Bro&#x17c;ek J, Guyatt G, Oxman A, editors (2013) GRADE Handbook for Grading Quality of Evidence and Strength of Recommendations. Updated October 2013. The GRADE Working Group.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santesso N, Glenton C, Dahm P, Garner P, Akl EA, Alper B, Brignardello-Petersen R, Carrasco-Labra A, De Beer H, Hultcrantz M, Kuijpers T, Meerpohl J, Morgan R, Mustafa R, Skoetz N, Sultan S, Wiysonge C, Guyatt G, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ GRADE Working Group (2020) GRADE guidelines 26: Informative statements to communicate the findings of systematic reviews of interventions. J Clin Epidemiol 119, 126&#x2013;135.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31711912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheung C, Bhimani R, Wyman JF, Konczak J, Zhang L, Mishra U, Terluk M, Kartha RV, Tuite P (2018) Effects of yoga on oxidative stress, motor function, and non-motor symptoms in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Pilot Feasibility Stud 4, 162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6198358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30377537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harvey M, Weston KL, Gray WK, O&#x2019;Callaghan A, Oates LL, Davidson R, Walker RW (2019) High-intensity interval training in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A randomized, controlled feasibility trial. Clin Rehabil 33, 428&#x2013;438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30514114</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pohl P, Dizdar N, Hallert E (2013) The Ronnie Gardiner Rhythm and Music Method &#x2013;A feasibility study in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Disabil Rehabil 35, 2197&#x2013;204.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23480646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silveira CRA, Roy EA, Intzandt BN, Almeida QJ (2018) Aerobic exercise is more effective than goal-based exercise for the treatment of cognition in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Brain Cogn 122, 1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29331916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Oliveira RT, Felippe LA, Gobbi LTB, Barbieri FA, Christofoletti G (2017) Benefits of exercise on the executive functions in people with Parkinson disease. J Phys Med Rehabil 96, 301&#x2013;306.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27584142</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avenali M, Picascia M, Tassorelli C, Sinforiani E, Bernini S (2021) Evaluation of the efficacy of physical therapy on cognitive decline at 6-month follow-up in Parkinson disease patients with mild cognitive impairment: A randomized controlled trial. Aging Clin Exp Res 33, 3275&#x2013;3284.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33978924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youm C, Kim Y, Noh B, Lee M, Kim J, Cheon SM (2020) Impact of trunk resistance and stretching exercise on fall-related factors in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A randomized controlled pilot study. Sensors (Basel) 20, 4106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7435366</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32717956</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pohl P, Wressle E, Lundin F, Enthoven P, Dizdar N (2020) Group-based music intervention in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease &#x2013;Findings from a mixed-methods study. Clin Rehabil 34, 533&#x2013;544.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7132435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32070122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasegawa N, Shah VV, Harker G, Carlson-Kuhta P, Nutt JG, Lapidus JA, Jung SH, Barlow N, King LA, Horak FB, Mancini M (2020) Responsiveness of objective vs. clinical balance domain outcomes for exercise intervention in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Front Neurol 11, 940.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7545952</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33101161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson H, Freidle M, Ekman U, Schalling E, Leavy B, Svenningsson P, Hagstr&#xf6;mer M, Franz&#xe9;n E (2020) Feasibility aspects of exploring exercise-induced neuroplasticity in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Parkinsons Dis 2020, 2410863.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7132585</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32300475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michels K, Dubaz O, Hornthal E, Bega D (2018) &#x201c;Dance Therapy&#x201d; as a psychotherapeutic movement intervention in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Complement Ther Med 40, 248&#x2013;252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30219460</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gobbi LTB, Pelicioni PHS, Lahr J, Lirani-Silva E, Teixeira-Arroyo C, Santos PCRD (2021) Effect of different types of exercises on psychological and cognitive features in people with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A randomized controlled trial. Ann Phys Rehabil Med 64, 101407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32561505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva-Batista C, Corcos DM, Kanegusuku H, Piemonte MEP, Gobbi LTB, de Lima-Pardini AC, de Mello MT, Forjaz CLM, Ugrinowitsch C (2018) Balance and fear of falling in subjects with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease is improved after exercises with motor complexity. Gait Posture 61, 90&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310015</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albrecht F, Pereira JB, Mijalkov M, Freidle M, Johansson H, Ekman U, Westman E, Franz&#xe9;n E (2021) Effects of a highly challenging balance training program on motor function and brain structure in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Parkinsons Dis 11, 2057&#x2013;2071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8673526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34511513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnan K, Rossetti H, Hynan LS, Carter K, Falkowski J, Lacritz L, Cullum CM, Weiner M (2017) Changes in Montreal Cognitive Assessment Scores over time. Assessment 24, 772&#x2013;777.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6757333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27318033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang X, Zhao X, Li B, Cai Y, Zhang S, Wan Q, Yu F (2022) Comparative efficacy of various exercise interventions on cognitive function in patients with mild cognitive impairment or dementia: A systematic review and network meta-analysis. J Sport Health Sci 11, 212&#x2013;223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9068743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34004389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li G, You Q, Hou X, Zhang S, Du L, Lv Y, Yu L (2023) The effect of exercise on cognitive function in people with multiple sclerosis: A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Neurol 270, 2908&#x2013;2923.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36864256</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johansson ME, Cameron IGM, Van der Kolk NM, de Vries NM, Klimars E, Toni I, Bloem BR, Helmich RC (2022) Aerobic exercise alters brain function and structure in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: A randomized controlled trial. Ann Neurol 91, 203&#x2013;216.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9306840</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34951063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Petzinger GM, Fisher BE, Van Leeuwen JE, Vukovic M, Akopian G, Meshul CK, Holschneider DP, Nacca A, Walsh JP, Jakowec MW (2010) Enhancing neuroplasticity in the basal ganglia: The role of exercise in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord 25 Suppl 1, S141&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4111643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20187247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jasim N, Balakirishnan D, Zhang H, Steiner-Lim GZ, Karamacoska D, Yang GY (2023) Effects and mechanisms of Tai Chi on mild cognitive impairment and early-stage dementia: A scoping review. Syst Rev 12, 200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10612170</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37891692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litvan I, Goldman JG, Tr&#xf6;ster AI, Schmand BA, Weintraub D, Petersen RC, Mollenhauer B, Adler CH, Marder K, Williams-Gray CH, Aarsland D, Kulisevsky J, Rodriguez-Oroz MC, Burn DJ, Barker RA, Emre M (2012) Diagnostic criteria for mild cognitive impairment in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: Movement Disorder Society Task Force guidelines. Mov Disord 27, 349&#x2013;356.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3641655</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22275317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Emre M, Aarsland D, Brown R, Burn DJ, Duyckaerts C, Mizuno Y, Broe GA, Cummings J, Dickson DW, Gauthier S, Goldman J, Goetz C, Korczyn A, Lees A, Levy R, Litvan I, McKeith I, Olanow W, Poewe W, Quinn N, Sampaio C, Tolosa E, Dubois B (2007) Clinical diagnostic criteria for dementia associated with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mov Disord 22, 1689&#x2013;1707; quiz 1837.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17542011</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>