<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41032653</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1877-718X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><Issue>8</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of Parkinson's disease</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Parkinsons Dis</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prevention of cognitive impairment and dementia in people with Parkinson's disease: A call-to-action.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1353</StartPage><EndPage>1366</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1353-1366</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/1877718X251365769</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Mild cognitive impairment and dementia are common symptoms in people with Parkinson's disease (PwPD) that impair the quality of life of those affected. However, PD-specific concepts for the prevention of cognitive decline are rarely incorporated into routine care. Here, we provide key data on cognitive impairment in PwPD and a framework for primary, secondary, and tertiary prevention in this context. The importance of cognitive reserve as a protective buffer for cognitive decline in PwPD is highlighted. Relevant lifestyle and health-related factors, including cognitive aspects, physical and social activity, diet, hearing loss, and cardiovascular factors, are discussed. Evidence on the efficacy of possible cognition-enhancing interventions in PwPD-pharmacological, cognitive, physical, nutritional, and multidomain interventions-is summarized. On this basis, and the recommendations of the European Task Force for Brain Health Services, a proposal is developed outlining options for preventing cognitive impairment in PwPD that could be implemented in routine care, as well as further developments needed to achieve a best-case scenario. The main pillars of a strategic agenda for this purpose include: (i) regular assessment of cognitive state, overall risk, and risk factors for cognitive decline; (ii) risk communication and education concerning modifiable risk factors with standardized procedures; (iii) risk reduction with multi-domain interventions for secondary prevention; and (iv) cognitive enhancement with cognitive and physical training for tertiary prevention. As the proposal makes clear, the prevention of cognitive impairment in PwPD requires interdisciplinary collaboration organized throughout PD care networks.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kalbe</LastName><ForeName>Elke</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies &amp; Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warnecke</LastName><ForeName>Tobias</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Parkinson Networks Germany e.V., Osnabr&#xfc;ck, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Neurorehabilitation, Klinikum Osnabr&#xfc;ck - Academic Teaching Hospital of the University of M&#xfc;nster, Osnabr&#xfc;ck, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Eggers</LastName><ForeName>Carsten</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Parkinson Networks Germany e.V., Osnabr&#xfc;ck, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Knappschaft Kliniken Bottrop GmbH, Bottrop, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ophey</LastName><ForeName>Anja</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5858-7762</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies &amp; Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Folkerts</LastName><ForeName>Ann-Kristin</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2168-140X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Psychology | Neuropsychology and Gender Studies &amp; Center for Neuropsychological Diagnostics and Intervention, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Cologne, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Parkinsons Dis</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101567362</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1877-7171</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D060825" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognitive Dysfunction</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003704" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dementia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText>Many people with Parkinson's disease (PwPD) experience cognitive problems, relating to memory and thinking. This can impair their quality of life. However, there are few strategies in regular medical care to help prevent these issues. This text explains the main facts about cognitive problems in PwPD and suggests ways to prevent them. It describes how &#x201c;cognitive reserve&#x201d; can help protect cognitive skills. Lifestyle factors that are important for cognitive health, like staying mentally, physically, and socially active, and a healthy diet, are discussed. Managing hearing loss, heart disease, and other health issues is also important. Different interventions to support brain health in PwPD are reviewed. These include medication, mental exercises, physical activity, diet changes, and combined approaches. Based on scientific recommendations, a plan is proposed to include prevention strategies in routine care.The key steps in this plan are: Regularly checking cognitive skills, along with possible risk factors.Educating PwPD about ways to lower their risks.Using combined intervention approaches to help slow cognitive loss.Offering cognitive and physical training to support cognitive skills.Preventing cognitive decline in PwPD requires teamwork between different medical experts. These efforts should be organized in special PD care networks to provide the best support.</AbstractText></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parkinson's disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognition</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive reserve</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dementia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of conflicting interestsEK has received grants from the German Federal Ministry of Education, RheinEnergie Stiftung Germany, and STADAPHARM GmbH as well as honoraria from EISAI GmbH, BIAL GmbH, Memodio GmbH, Kohlhammer Verlag, Hogrefe Testzentrale, ProLog Wissen GmbH. EK is one of the authors of the cognitive intervention series &#x201c;NEUROvitalis&#x201d; but receives no corresponding honoraria.TW has received honoraria from BIAL, Abbvie, Desitin, Pftzer, Britannia, Esteve and Licher, consultancies from Stadapharm and Phagenesis, and funding from Abbvie and EVER Pharma.CE received in the last 12 months payments as a consultant for Abbvie Inc., Bial Inc., Gerresheimer AG. CE received honoraria as a speaker from Abbvie Inc., Bial Inc., Bristol-Myers Squibbs Inc., Merck Inc., Synaptikon Inc. CE is in the steering board of Parkinson Netzwerke Deutschland.AO received grants from the Koeln Fortune Program (grant-no. 329/2021, 142/2023, 145/2024, 15/2025), Faculty of Medicine, University of Cologne and the &#x201c;Novartis-Stiftung f&#xfc;r therapeutische Forschung&#x201d;, all outside the submitted work.AKF has received grants from the German Parkinson Society and STADAPHARM GmbH as well as honoraria from ProLog Wissen GmbH, Cologne, Germany; Seminar- und Fortbildungszentrum Rheine, Germany; LOGOMANIA, Fendt &amp; Sax GbR, Munich, Germany; and LOGUAN, Ulm, Germany; dbs e.V., Moers, Germany. AKF is one of the authors of the cognitive intervention series &#x201c;NEUROvitalis&#x201d; but receives no corresponding honoraria.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>10</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>28</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41032653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1877718X251365769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>