<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30931151</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2058-5241</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>4</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>EFORT open reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>EFORT Open Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Comparison of revision rates and radiographic observations of long and short, uncoated and coated humeral stem designs in total shoulder arthroplasty.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>70</StartPage><EndPage>76</EndPage><MedlinePgn>70-76</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1302/2058-5241.4.180046</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>There is no consensus on outcomes of long <i>versus</i> short and uncoated <i>versus</i> coated uncemented stems in total shoulder arthroplasty (TSA).We reviewed the literature to compare revision rates and adverse radiographic observations at &#x2a7e; 2 years of various uncemented humeral stem designs.We performed an electronic PubMed search for studies on uncemented primary TSA that reported one or more of the following observations at &#x2a7e; 2 years for distinct stem designs: stem revision; subsidence; stress shielding; radiolucent lines; and humeral loosening.The search returned 258 records, from which 20 articles (22 cohorts) met the inclusion criteria.The most frequently reported designs were short uncoated stems (7/13 cohorts) at &lt; 3 years and long uncoated stems (8/9 cohorts) at &gt; 3 years.The incidences of revisions and adverse radiographic observations were lower for short coated designs, compared with short and long uncoated designs, but these findings should be confirmed by prospective studies with a longer follow-up. Cite this article: <i>EFORT Open Rev</i> 2019;4:70-76. DOI: 10.1302/2058-5241.4.180046.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goden&#xe8;che</LastName><ForeName>Arnaud</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Ramsay G&#xe9;n&#xe9;rale de Sant&#xe9;, H&#xf4;pital Priv&#xe9; Jean Mermoz, Centre Orthop&#xe9;dique Santy, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garret</LastName><ForeName>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinique du Parc, Lyon, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barth</LastName><ForeName>Johannes</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre Ost&#xe9;oarticulaire des C&#xe8;dres, Grenoble, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Michelet</LastName><ForeName>Aude</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ReSurg SA, Nyon, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Geais</LastName><ForeName>Laurent</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Move-Up SAS, Alixan, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Shoulder Friends Institute</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>EFORT Open Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101695674</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2058-5241</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">humerus</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stem designs</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">total shoulder arthroplasty</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>ICMJE Conflict of interest statement: A. Goden&#xe8;che declares consultancy for Wright-Arthex and Conmed; royalties for Wright, activities relating to the submitted work. J. Barth declares consultancy for Arthrex and SBM, activities relating to the submitted work. A. Michelet declares payment for writing or reviewing from ReSurg, activity relating to the submitted work. L. Geais declares employment at Move-Up, activity relating to the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2019</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30931151</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6404789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1302/2058-5241.4.180046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1302_2058-5241.4.180046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Deshmukh AV, Koris M, Zurakowski D, Thornhill TS. Total shoulder arthroplasty: long-term survivorship, functional outcome, and quality of life. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2005;14:471-479.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16194737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verborgt O, El-Abiad R, Gazielly DF. Long-term results of uncemented humeral components in shoulder arthroplasty. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2007;16(Suppl):S13-S18.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17067822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagels J, Stokdijk M, Rozing PM. Stress shielding and bone resorption in shoulder arthroplasty. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2003;12:35-39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12610484</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Torchia ME, Cofield RH, Settergren CR. Total shoulder arthroplasty with the Neer prosthesis: long-term results. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 1997;6:495-505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9437598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Throckmorton TW, Zarkadas PC, Sperling JW, Cofield RH. Radiographic stability of ingrowth humeral stems in total shoulder arthroplasty. Clin Orthop Relat Res 2010;468:2122-2128.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2895835</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20232183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Werthel JD, Lonjon G, Jo S, et al. Long-term outcomes of cemented versus cementless humeral components in arthroplasty of the shoulder: a propensity score-matched analysis. Bone Joint J 2017;99-B:666-673.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28455477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raiss P, Edwards TB, Deutsch A, et al. Radiographic changes around humeral components in shoulder arthroplasty. J Bone Joint Surg [Am] 2014;96-A:e54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24695931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnetzke M, Coda S, Raiss P, Walch G, Loew M. Radiologic bone adaptations on a cementless short-stem shoulder prosthesis. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2016;25:650-657.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26560021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, Group P. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLoS Med 2009;6:e1000097.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Betts HM, Abu-Rajab R, Nunn T, Brooksbank AJ. Total shoulder replacement in rheumatoid disease: a 16- to 23-year follow-up. J Bone Joint Surg [Br] 2009;91:1197-1200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19721046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Casagrande DJ, Parks DL, Torngren T, et al. Radiographic evaluation of short-stem press-fit total shoulder arthroplasty: short-term follow-up. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2016;25:1163-1169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26897311</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denard PJ, Noyes MP, Walker JB, et al. Proximal stress shielding is decreased with a short stem compared with a traditional-length stem in total shoulder arthroplasty. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2018;27:53-58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28865965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jost PW, Dines JS, Griffith MH, et al. Total shoulder arthroplasty utilizing mini-stem humeral components: technique and short-term results. HSS J 2011;7:213-217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3192896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23024616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litchfield RB, McKee MD, Balyk R, et al. Cemented versus uncemented fixation of humeral components in total shoulder arthroplasty for osteoarthritis of the shoulder: a prospective, randomized, double-blind clinical trial-A JOINTs Canada Project. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2011;20:529-536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21570660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matsen FA, III, Iannotti JP, Rockwood CA., Jr Humeral fixation by press-fitting of a tapered metaphyseal stem: a prospective radiographic study. J Bone Joint Surg [Am] 2003;85:304-308.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12571309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morwood MP, Johnston PS, Garrigues GE. Proximal ingrowth coating decreases risk of loosening following uncemented shoulder arthroplasty using mini-stem humeral components and lesser tuberosity osteotomy. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2017;26:1246-1252.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28159474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romeo AA, Thorsness RJ, Sumner SA, et al. Short-term clinical outcome of an anatomic short-stem humeral component in total shoulder arthroplasty. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2018;27:70-74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28734716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg N, Neumann L, Modi A, Mersich IJ, Wallace AW. Improvements in survival of the uncemented Nottingham Total Shoulder prosthesis: a prospective comparative study. BMC Musculoskelet Disord 2007;8:76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1964758</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17683577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanchez-Sotelo J, Wright TW, O&#x2019;Driscoll SW, Cofield RH, Rowland CM. Radiographic assessment of uncemented humeral components in total shoulder arthroplasty. J Arthroplasty 2001;16:180-187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11222891</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandow MJ, David H, Bentall SJ. Hemiarthroplasty vs total shoulder replacement for rotator cuff intact osteoarthritis: how do they fare after a decade? J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2013;22:877-885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23333174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnetzke M, Coda S, Walch G, Loew M. Clinical and radiological results of a cementless short stem shoulder prosthesis at minimum follow-up of two years. Int Orthop 2015;39:1351-1357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25900366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schnetzke M, Preis A, Coda S, Raiss P, Loew M. Anatomical and reverse shoulder replacement with a convertible, uncemented short-stem shoulder prosthesis: first clinical and radiological results. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg 2017;137:679-684.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28337535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperling JW, Cofield RH, O&#x2019;Driscoll SW, Torchia ME, Rowland CM. Radiographic assessment of ingrowth total shoulder arthroplasty. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2000;9:507-513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11155304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Denard PJ, Noyes MP, Walker JB, et al. Radiographic changes differ between two different short press-fit humeral stem designs in total shoulder arthroplasty. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2018;27:217-223.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28965688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sperling JW, Cofield RH, Rowland CM. Minimum fifteen-year follow-up of Neer hemiarthroplasty and total shoulder arthroplasty in patients aged fifty years or younger. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2004;13:604-613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15570228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panti JP, Tan S, Kuo W, et al. Clinical and radiologic outcomes of the second-generation Trabecular Metal glenoid for total shoulder replacements after 2-6 years follow-up. Arch Orthop Trauma Surg 2016;136:1637-1645.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27566616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Szerlip BW, Morris BJ, Laughlin MS, Kilian CM, Edwards TB. Clinical and radiographic outcomes after total shoulder arthroplasty with an anatomic press-fit short stem. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2018;27:10-16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29032988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmer L, Throckmorton T, Sperling JW. Total shoulder arthroplasty: are the humeral components getting shorter? Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med 2016;9:17-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4762805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26801933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cofield RH. Total shoulder arthroplasty with the Neer prosthesis. J Bone Joint Surg [Am] 1984;66-A:899-906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6736090</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh JA, Sperling JW, Cofield RH. Revision surgery following total shoulder arthroplasty: analysis of 2588 shoulders over three decades (1976 to 2008). J Bone Joint Surg [Br] 2011;93-B:1513-1517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3882033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22058304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Razfar N, Reeves JM, Langohr DG, et al. Comparison of proximal humeral bone stresses between stemless, short stem, and standard stem length: a finite element analysis. J Shoulder Elbow Surg 2016;25:1076-1083.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26810016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>