<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41079976</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>15</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-1683</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>81</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>European urology open science</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Eur Urol Open Sci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Defining the Minimal Important Difference in International Prostate Symptom Score for Men with Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms Using a Patient-centered Anchor Measure.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>44</StartPage><EndPage>49</EndPage><MedlinePgn>44-49</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.euros.2025.09.003</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Few studies have investigated the minimal important difference (MID) for the International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS), which is essential for interpreting clinical outcomes after treatment for lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS). The aim of our study was to determine the IPSS MID using data from a randomized controlled trial (RCT) evaluating an app-based intervention (Kranus Lutera) for LUTS in men.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patients with LUTS diagnosed with benign prostatic hyperplasia, overactive bladder, or both by office-based urologists across Germany were included. After following the Kranus Lutera app for LUT therapy for 12&#xa0;wk, participants completed the IPSS and the Patient Global Impression of Change (PGIC) questionnaire. The MID, defined as the mean change from baseline in IPSS among 82 men who reported "minimally improved" on the PGIC, was calculated in a secondary exploratory analysis.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="KEY FINDINGS AND LIMITATIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The MID calculated for the IPSS was 5.26 points (95% confidence interval [CI] 4.38-6.13). Stratified analysis revealed a higher MID in the subgroup with severe baseline symptoms (8.23; 95% CI 6.58-9.88) than for the subgroup with moderate symptoms (4.00; 95% CI 3.14-4.86). As the data were drawn from a single RCT, the generalizability may be limited, particularly for results for subgroups with small sample sizes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND CLINICAL IMPLICATIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">These findings provide a valuable reference for clinicians interpreting treatment outcomes and offer important insights for future trial design. Further research in larger and more diverse populations is essential to improve generalizability and external validation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PATIENT SUMMARY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We looked at results for the International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS), a questionnaire used to assess lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS) in men, to determine what patients feel is a meaningful improvement in symptoms. We used data from a clinical trial that tested an app to help men in improving their LUTS. Men felt that the minimum level of improvement for a benefit was change of 5.26 points in IPSS. Men with more severe symptoms at the start of treatment required greater improvements, while men with moderate symptoms needed smaller changes. These findings may help doctors in understanding the amount of improvement in symptoms that patients feel is significant, and could guide future LUTS treatments and trials.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wiemer</LastName><ForeName>Laura</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kranus Health GmbH, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lehmacher</LastName><ForeName>Walter</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Medical Statistics and Computational Biology, University of Cologne, Cologne, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sch&#xf6;nburg</LastName><ForeName>Sandra</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology and Kidney Transplantation, Martin Luther University Halle Wittenberg, Halle (Saale), Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>BG Klinikum Bergmannstrost, Halle (Saale), Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gratzke</LastName><ForeName>Christian</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, University of Freiburg, Freiburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Miller</LastName><ForeName>Kurt</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Urology, Charit&#xe9; - Universit&#xe4;tsmedizin Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kranus Health GmbH, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Patrick Papp</LastName><ForeName>C</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kranus Health GmbH, Munich, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Eur Urol Open Sci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101771568</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-1683</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Benign prostatic enlargement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">International Prostate Symptom Score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lower urinary tract symptoms</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Minimal clinically important difference</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Minimal important difference</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized controlled trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Urology</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>31</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41079976</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12509103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.euros.2025.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-1683(25)00304-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Gravas S., Cornu J.N., Gacci M., et al. European Association of Urology; Arnhem, The Netherlands: 2022. EAU guidelines on management of non-neurogenic male lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS) incl. benign prostatic obstruction (BPO)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gacci M., Corona G., Sebastianelli A., et al. Male lower urinary tract symptoms and cardiovascular events: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Urol. 2016;70:788&#x2013;796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27451136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akerla J., Pesonen J.S., Poyhonen A., et al. Lower urinary tract symptoms and mortality among Finnish men: the roles of symptom severity and bother. J Urol. 2022;207:1285&#x2013;1294.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cornu J.N., Gacci M., Hashim H., et al. European Association of Urology; Arnhem, The Netherlands: 2024. EAU guidelines on the management of non-neurogenic male lower urinary tract symptoms (LUTS)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry M.J., Fowler F.J., Jr, O&#x2019;Leary M.P., et al. The American Urological Association Symptom Index for benign prostatic hyperplasia. J Urol. 1992;148:1549&#x2013;1557.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1279218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yao M.W., Green J.S.A. How international is the International Prostate Symptom Score? A literature review of validated translations of the IPSS, the most widely used self-administered patient questionnaire for male lower urinary tract symptoms. Lower Urin Tract Symptoms. 2022;14:92&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34734477</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry M.J., Williford W.O., Chang Y., et al. Benign prostatic hyperplasia specific health status measures in clinical research: how much change in the American Urological Association Symptom Index and the Benign Prostatic Hyperplasia Impact Index is perceptible to patients? J Urol. 1995;154:1770&#x2013;1774.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7563343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanker M.H., Alma H.J., Devji T.S., Roelofs M., Steffens M.G., van der Worp H. Determining the minimal important differences in the International Prostate Symptom Score and Overactive Bladder Questionnaire: results from an observational cohort study in Dutch primary care. BMJ Open. 2019;9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7008409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31874883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Babar M., Abramson M., Labagnara K., et al. Predictors of achieving a minimal clinically important difference in lower urinary tract symptoms 3 months after Rezum therapy. Cent Eur J Urol. 2024;77:262&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11428353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39345329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chapple C.R., Montorsi F., Tammela T.L., et al. Silodosin therapy for lower urinary tract symptoms in men with suspected benign prostatic hyperplasia: results of an international, randomized, double-blind, placebo- and active-controlled clinical trial performed in Europe. Eur Urol. 2011;59:342&#x2013;352.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21109344</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Albarqouni L., Sanders S., Clark J., Tikkinen K.A.O., Glasziou P. Self-management for men with lower urinary tract symptoms: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Fam Med. 2021;19:157&#x2013;167.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7939720</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33685877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gratzke C., Schonburg S., Eger S., et al. A randomized trial of an app-based therapeutic for lower urinary tract symptoms. NEJM Evid. 2025;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40130971</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viktrup L., Hayes R.P., Wang P., Shen W. Construct validation of Patient Global Impression of Severity (PGI-S) and Improvement (PGI-I) questionnaires in the treatment of men with lower urinary tract symptoms secondary to benign prostatic hyperplasia. BMC Urol. 2012;12:30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3503561</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23134716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carrasco-Labra A., Devji T., Qasim A., et al. Minimal important difference estimates for patient-reported outcomes: a systematic survey. J Clin Epidemiol. 2021;133:61&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33321175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D., Hahn E.A., Dineen K. Meaningful change in cancer-specific quality of life scores: differences between improvement and worsening. Qual Life Res. 2002;11:207&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12074259</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guyatt G.H., Norman G.R., Juniper E.F., Griffith L.E. A critical look at transition ratings. J Clin Epidemiol. 2002;55:900&#x2013;908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12393078</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elterman D. Beyond medications - the promise of app-based digital therapeutics for lower urinary tract symptoms. NEJM Evid. 2025;4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40130973</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlichting M., Hennig M., Rudell K., et al. Is IQWiG&#x2019;s 15% threshold universally applicable in assessing the clinical relevance of patient-reported outcomes changes? An ISPOR Special Interest Group Report. Value Health. 2022;25:1463&#x2013;1468.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36049796</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institut f&#xfc;r Qualit&#xe4;t und Wirtschaftlichkeit im Gesundheitswesen. IQWiG general methods version 6.0. Cologne, Germany: IQWiG; 2020. https://www.iqwig.de/methoden/general-methods_version-6-0.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayadevappa R., Cook R., Chhatre S. Minimal important difference to infer changes in health-related quality of life&#x2014;a systematic review. J Clin Epidemiol. 2017;89:188&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28676426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Su F., Allahabadi S., Bongbong D.N., Feeley B.T., Lansdown D.A. Minimal clinically important difference, substantial clinical benefit, and patient acceptable symptom state of outcome measures relating to shoulder pathology and surgery: a systematic review. Curr Rev Musculoskelet Med. 2021;14:27&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7930136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33433840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>