<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37954005</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>14</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-7762</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>33</Volume><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Lancet regional health. Europe</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Reg Health Eur</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Use of smartphone application versus written titration charts for basal insulin titration in adults with type 2 diabetes and suboptimal glycaemic control (My Dose Coach): multicentre, open-label, parallel, randomised controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100702</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100702</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100702</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lanepe.2023.100702</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The majority of people with type 2 diabetes who require insulin therapy use only basal insulin in combination with other anti-diabetic agents. We tested whether using a smartphone application to titrate insulin could improve glycaemic control in people with type 2 diabetes who use basal insulin.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This was a 12-week, multicentre, open-label, parallel, randomised controlled trial conducted in 36 diabetes practices in Germany. Eligible participants had type 2 diabetes, a BMI &#x2265;25.0&#xa0;kg/m<sup>2</sup>, were on basal insulin therapy or were initiating basal insulin therapy, and had suboptimal glycaemic control (HbA1c &gt;7.5%; 58.5&#xa0;mmol/mol). Block randomisation with 1:1 allocation was performed centrally. Participants in the intervention group titrated their basal insulin dose using a smartphone application (My Dose Coach) for 12 weeks. Control group participants titrated their basal insulin dose according to a written titration chart. The primary outcome was the baseline-adjusted change in HbA1c at 12 weeks. The intention-to-treat analysis included all randomised participants.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Between 13 July 2021 and 21 March 2022, 251 study participants were randomly assigned (control group: n&#xa0;=&#xa0;123; intervention group: n&#xa0;=&#xa0;128), and 236 completed the follow-up phase (control group: n&#xa0;=&#xa0;119; intervention group: n&#xa0;=&#xa0;117). Regarding the HbA1c a model-based adjusted between-group difference of&#xa0;-0.31% (95% CI: 0.01%-0.69%; p&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.0388) in favour of the intervention group was observed. There were 30 adverse events reported: 16 in the control group, 14 in the intervention group. Of these, 15 adverse events were serious. No event was considered to be related to the investigational device.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERPRETATION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Study results suggest that utilizing this digital health smartphone application for basal insulin titration may have resulted in a comparatively greater reduction in HbA1c levels among individuals with type 2 diabetes, as compared to basal insulin titration guided by a written titration schedule. No negative effect on safety outcomes was observed.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="FUNDING" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sanofi-Aventis Deutschland GmbH.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hermanns</LastName><ForeName>Norbert</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of the Diabetes Academy Mergentheim (FIDAM), Johann-Hammer-Str. 24, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Centre Bad Mergentheim, Theodor-Klotzbuecher-Str. 12, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, University of Bamberg, Markusplatz 3, Bamberg 96047, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ehrmann</LastName><ForeName>Dominic</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of the Diabetes Academy Mergentheim (FIDAM), Johann-Hammer-Str. 24, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, University of Bamberg, Markusplatz 3, Bamberg 96047, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finke-Groene</LastName><ForeName>Katharina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of the Diabetes Academy Mergentheim (FIDAM), Johann-Hammer-Str. 24, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krichbaum</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of the Diabetes Academy Mergentheim (FIDAM), Johann-Hammer-Str. 24, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roos</LastName><ForeName>Timm</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of the Diabetes Academy Mergentheim (FIDAM), Johann-Hammer-Str. 24, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Haak</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Centre Bad Mergentheim, Theodor-Klotzbuecher-Str. 12, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Freckmann</LastName><ForeName>Guido</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>IfDT - Institut f&#xfc;r Diabetes-Technologie Forschungs- und Entwicklungsgesellschaft mbH, Helmholtzstr. 20, Ulm 89081, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kulzer</LastName><ForeName>Bernhard</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Research Institute of the Diabetes Academy Mergentheim (FIDAM), Johann-Hammer-Str. 24, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Diabetes Centre Bad Mergentheim, Theodor-Klotzbuecher-Str. 12, Bad Mergentheim 97980, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Clinical Psychology and Psychotherapy, University of Bamberg, Markusplatz 3, Bamberg 96047, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Reg Health Eur</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101777707</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-7762</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Basal insulin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digital health tool</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Insulin titration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">My Dose Coach app</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Titration app</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Type 2 diabetes</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>NH reports Advisory Board member fees from Abbott Diabetes Care and Insulet as well as honoraria for lectures from Berlin Chemie AG, Becton Dickenson. Sanofi Germany and Roche Diabetes Care and Dexcom, Germany. DE reports Advisory Board member fees from mySugr, Dexcom Germany and Roche Diabetes Care as honoraria for lectures from Berlin Chemie AG, Dexcom, Germany and Roche Diabetes Care. KFG, MK and TR declare no conflict of interest. GF reports Advisory Board member fees from Abbott Diabetes Care, Sanofi Germany, Dexcom as well as support for meeting attendance and travel from Novo Nordisk. TH reports Advisory Board member fees from Abbott Diabetes Care, Sanofi Germany, Gruenenthal, Lilly Germany, Dexcom Germany and Bayer as well as honoraria for lectures from Sanofi Germany, Abbott Diabetes Care, Lilly Germany and Astra Zenecca. BK reports Advisory Board member fees from Abbott Diabetes Care, Embecta, Roche Diabetes Care, Novo Nordisk, Berlin Chemie AG and Dexcom Germany as well as honoraria for lectures from Sanofi Germany, Novo Nordisk, Abbott Diabetes Care, Roche Diabetes Care, Berlin Chemie AG, Embecta, Dexcom and Feen. In addition he reports support for travel and fees for scientific meetings from Sanofi, Roche and Berlin Chemie as well as unpaid obligations as workshop leader and member of working groups of the German Diabetes Association.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37954005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10636267</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2023.100702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-7762(23)00121-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>IDF DF diabetes atlas 2021. 10th ed. 2021. https://diabetesatlas.org/atlas/tenth-edition/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Basu S., Yudkin J.S., Kehlenbrink S., et al. Estimation of global insulin use for type 2 diabetes, 2018&#x2013;30: a microsimulation analysis. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol. 2019;7(1):25&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30470520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies M.J., Aroda V.R., Collins B.S., et al. Management of hyperglycemia in type 2 diabetes, 2022. A consensus report by the American Diabetes Association (ADA) and the European Association for the study of diabetes (EASD) Diabetes Care. 2022;45(11):2753&#x2013;2786.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10008140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36148880</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Russell-Jones D., Dauchy A., Delgado E., et al. Take control: a randomized trial evaluating the efficacy and safety of self-versus physician-managed titration of insulin glargine 300 U/mL in patients with uncontrolled type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metabol. 2019;21(7):1615&#x2013;1624.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6767413</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30851006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauricio D., Meneghini L., Seufert J., et al. Glycaemic control and hypoglycaemia burden in patients with type 2 diabetes initiating basal insulin in Europe and the USA. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2017;19(8):1155&#x2013;1164.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5573947</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28251792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K., Nikolajsen A., Thorsted B.L., Andersen M., Davies M.J., Paul S.K. Clinical inertia with regard to intensifying therapy in people with type 2 diabetes treated with basal insulin. Diabetes Obes Metabol. 2016;18(4):401&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5067688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26743666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khunti K., Millar-Jones D. Clinical inertia to insulin initiation and intensification in the UK: a focused literature review. Prim Care Diabetes. 2017;11(1):3&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27727005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies M.J., Gagliardino J.J., Gray L.J., Khunti K., Mohan V., Hughes R. Real-world factors affecting adherence to insulin therapy in patients with type 1 or type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review. Diabet Med. 2013;30(5):512&#x2013;524.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23323988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes-Truscott E., Skinner T.C., Pouwer F., Speight J. Negative appraisals of insulin therapy are common among adults with type 2 diabetes using insulin: results from diabetes MILES - Australia cross-sectional survey. Diabet Med. 2015;32(10):1297&#x2013;1303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25683652</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polinski J.M., Smith B.F., Curtis B.H., et al. Barriers to insulin progression among patients with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review. Diabetes Educ. 2013;39(1):53&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23192599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergenstal R.M., Johnson M., Passi R., et al. Automated insulin dosing guidance to optimise insulin management in patients with type 2 diabetes: a multicentre, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2019;393(10176):1138&#x2013;1148.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6715130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30808512</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Franc S., Joubert M., Daoudi A., et al. Efficacy of two telemonitoring systems to improve glycaemic control during basal insulin initiation in patients with type 2 diabetes: the TeleDiab-2 randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Obes Metabol. 2019;21(10):2327&#x2013;2332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6771866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bee Y.M., Batcagan-Abueg A.P.M., Chei C.-L., et al. A&#xa0;smartphone application to deliver a treat-to-target insulin titration algorithm in insulin-naive patients with type 2 diabetes: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Diabetes Care. 2016;39(10):e174&#x2013;e176.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27506223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies M., Bain S., Charpentier G., et al. A&#xa0;randomized controlled, treat-to-target study evaluating the efficacy and safety of insulin glargine 300 U/mL (Gla-300) administered using either device-supported or routine titration in people with type 2 diabetes. J&#xa0;Diabetes Sci Technol. 2019;13(5):881&#x2013;889.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6955447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30646755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajaj H.S., Venn K., Ye C., Aronson R. Randomized trial of long-acting insulin glargine titration web tool (LTHome) versus enhanced usual therapy of glargine titration (INNOVATE Trial) Diabetes Technol Ther. 2016;18(10):610&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27652718</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomsen C.H.N., Hangaard S., Kronborg T., Vestergaard P., Hejlesen O., Jensen M.H. Time for using machine learning for dose guidance in titration of people with type 2 diabetes? A systematic review of basal insulin dose guidance. J&#xa0;Diabetes Sci Technol. 2022 doi: 10.1177/19322968221145964.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19322968221145964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11418255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36562599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kerr D., Edelman S., Vespasiani G., Khunti K. New digital health technologies for insulin initiation and optimization for people with type 2 diabetes. Endocr Pract. 2022;28(8):811&#x2013;821.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35452813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tamez-P&#xe9;rez H.E., Cant&#xfa;-Santos O.M., Gutierrez-Gonz&#xe1;lez D., Gonz&#xe1;lez-Facio R., Romero-Ibarguengoitia M.E. Effect of digital-tool-supported basal insulin titration algorithm in reaching glycemic control in patients with type 2 diabetes in Mexico. J&#xa0;Diabetes Sci Technol. 2022;16(6):1513&#x2013;1520.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9631525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34323110</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermanns N., Ehrmann D., Finke-Grone K., Roos T., Freckmann G., Kulzer B. Evaluation of a digital health tool for titration of basal insulin in people with type 2 diabetes: rationale and design of a randomized controlled trial. J&#xa0;Diabetes Sci Technol. 2023 doi: 10.1177/19322968221148756.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/19322968221148756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11307223</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36602040</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermanns N., Kulzer B., Krichbaum M., Kubiak T., Haak T. How to screen for depression and emotional problems in patients with diabetes: comparison of screening characteristics of depression questionnaires, measurement of diabetes-specific emotional problems and standard clinical assessment. Diabetologia. 2006;49(3):469&#x2013;477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16432706</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmitt A., Gahr A., Hermanns N., Kulzer B., Huber J., Haak T. The diabetes self-management questionnaire (DSMQ): development and evaluation of an instrument to assess diabetes self-care activities associated with glycaemic control. Health QualLife Outcomes. 2013;11(1):138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3751743</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23937988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergis N., Ehrmann D., Hermanns N., Kulzer B., Haak T. L&#xe4;sst sich Empowerment bei Menschen mit Diabetes messen? [Is empowerment measurable in persons with diabetes?]Diabetol Stoffwechs. 2012;7(S 01):9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergis-Jurgan N., Hermanns N., Kulzer B., Ehrmann D., Haak T. Einfluss der Selbstwirksamkeit auf die glykaemische Kontrolle bei Typ-1 und Typ-2-Diabetikern mit einer intensivierten Insulintherapie [Influence of self-efficacy on glycemic control in people with type 1 and type 2 diabetes with an intensified insulin therapy]Diabetol Stoffwechs. 2013;8(Suppl. 1):134.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulzer B., Bauer U., Hermanns N., Bergis K.H. Entwicklung eines Problemfragebogens fuer Diabetiker zur Identifikation von Schwierigkeiten im Umgang mit der Krankheit [Development of&#xa0;a&#xa0;questionnaire for the assessment of diabetes related problems&#xa0;and satisfaction with insulin treatment]Verhaltenstherapie. 1995;5(Suppl. 1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;hler E., M&#xfc;hlan H., Albani C., Schmidt S. Teststatistische pr&#xfc;fung und normierung der deutschen versionen des EUROHIS-QOL lebensqualit&#xe4;t-Index und des WHO-5 wohlbefindens-index. Diagnostica. 2007;53(2):83&#x2013;96.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Terhorst Y., Philippi P., Sander L.B., et al. Validation of the mobile application rating scale (MARS) PLoS One. 2020;15(11)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7605637</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33137123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paddison C.A., Eborall H.C., Sutton S., et al. Are people with negative diabetes screening tests falsely reassured? Parallel group cohort study embedded in the ADDITION (Cambridge) randomised controlled trial. BMJ. 2009;339</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2785870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19948642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hodges J.L., Jr., Lehmann E.L. Springer; 2011. Estimates of location based on rank tests. Selected works of EL Lehmann; pp. 287&#x2013;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>EMA . 2017. EMA. CH E9 (R1) addendum on estimands and sensitivity 5 analysis in clinical trials to the guideline on statistical 6 principles for clinical trials.https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/scientific-guideline/draft-ich-e9-r1-addendum-estimands-sensitivity-analysis-clinical-trials-guideline-statistical_en.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bajaj H.S., Aronson R., Venn K., Ye C., Sharaan M.E. The need associated with diabetes primary care and the impact of referral to a specialist-centered multidisciplinary diabetes program (the NADIR study) Can J Diabetes. 2016;40(2):120&#x2013;125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26612189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moschonis G., Siopis G., Jung J., et al. Effectiveness, reach, uptake, and feasibility of digital health interventions for adults with type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. Lancet Digit Health. 2023;5(3):e125&#x2013;e143.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36828606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>