<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">20025864</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>09</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-564X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>338</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>15</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Developmental biology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Dev Biol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Genetic fate mapping demonstrates contribution of epicardium-derived cells to the annulus fibrosis of the mammalian heart.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>251</StartPage><EndPage>261</EndPage><MedlinePgn>251-61</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ydbio.2009.12.007</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The annulus fibrosis electrically insulates the atria and ventricles, allowing the timed sequential beating of these structures that is necessary for efficient heart function. Abnormal development of the annulus fibrosis leads to persistence of accessory electrical pathways from atria to ventricles, providing the anatomical substrate for re-entrant cardiac arrhythmias such as Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. To better understand the development of the annulus fibrosis and the etiology of these cardiac arrhythmias, we used Cre-LoxP technology to assess the contribution of epicardium derived cells (EPDCs) to the annulus fibrosis. We found that EPDCs migrated into the region of the forming annulus fibrosis, marked by the protein periostin. These EPDCs also stained positive for procollagen I, suggesting that the EPDCs themselves synthesize proteins of the annulus fibrosis. To further test the hypothesis that EPDCs contribute to cells that synthesize the annulus fibrosis, we purified genetically marked EPDCs from the atrioventricular region and measured gene expression by quantitative PCR. These EPDCs were highly enriched for mRNAs encoding periostin, procollagen I, fibronectin I, vimentin, discoidin domain receptor 2, and tenascin C, markers of fibroblasts and components of the annulus fibrosis. In addition, these EPDCs were highly enriched for Snail, Smad1, Slug, and Twist1, markers for epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EMT), and a metalloprotease, Mmp2, that contributes to cellular migration. Our work provides for the first time definitive evidence that epicardium contributes to formation of the mammalian annulus fibrosis through EMT. Abnormalities of this differentiation process may underlie development of some forms of re-entrant atrioventricular tachycardia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright 2009 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Bin</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Children's Hospital Boston and Department of Genetics, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA 02115, USA. bzhoupumc@gmail.com</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>von Gise</LastName><ForeName>Alexander</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ma</LastName><ForeName>Qing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Yong Wu</ForeName><Initials>YW</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pu</LastName><ForeName>William T</ForeName><Initials>WT</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL094683</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>1R01HL094683</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Dev Biol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0372762</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0012-1606</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012333">RNA, Messenger</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001145" MajorTopicYN="N">Arrhythmias, Cardiac</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="Y">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D054849" MajorTopicYN="N">Cardiac Electrophysiology</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002465" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Movement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005355" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrosis</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020869" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Profiling</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006325" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Atria</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006329" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Conduction System</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006352" MajorTopicYN="N">Heart Ventricles</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="N">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009206" MajorTopicYN="N">Myocardium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010496" MajorTopicYN="N">Pericardium</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012333" MajorTopicYN="N">RNA, Messenger</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000032" MajorTopicYN="N">analysis</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2009</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>10</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20025864</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS166329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2815244</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ydbio.2009.12.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0012-1606(09)01396-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>BECKER AE, ANDERSON RH, DURRER D, WELLENS HJ. The anatomical substrates of wolff-parkinson-white syndrome. A clinicopathologic correlation in seven patients. Circulation. 1978;57:870&#x2013;879.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">639209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>BUCKINGHAM M, MEILHAC S, ZAFFRAN S. Building the mammalian heart from two sources of myocardial cells. Nat Rev Genet. 2005;6:826&#x2013;835.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16304598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CAI CL, MARTIN JC, SUN Y, CUI L, WANG L, OUYANG K, YANG L, BU L, LIANG X, ZHANG X, STALLCUP WB, DENTON CP, MCCULLOCH A, CHEN J, EVANS SM. A myocardial lineage derives from Tbx18 epicardial cells. Nature. 2008;454:104&#x2013;108.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5540369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18480752</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>FEIL R, WAGNER J, METZGER D, CHAMBON P. Regulation of Cre recombinase activity by mutated estrogen receptor ligand-binding domains. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 1997;237:752&#x2013;757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9299439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GITTENBERGER-DE GROOT AC, VRANCKEN PEETERS MP, MENTINK MM, GOURDIE RG, POELMANN RE. Epicardium-derived cells contribute a novel population to the myocardial wall and the atrioventricular cushions. Circ Res. 1998;82:1043&#x2013;1052.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9622157</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KERN CB, HOFFMAN S, MORENO R, DAMON BJ, NORRIS RA, KRUG EL, MARKWALD RR, MJAATVEDT CH. Immunolocalization of chick periostin protein in the developing heart. Anat Rec A Discov Mol Cell Evol Biol. 2005;284:415&#x2013;423.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15803479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KOLDITZ DP, WIJFFELS MC, BLOM NA, VAN DER LAARSE A, HAHURIJ ND, LIE-VENEMA H, MARKWALD RR, POELMANN RE, SCHALIJ MJ, GITTENBERGER-DE GROOT AC. Epicardium-derived cells in development of annulus fibrosis and persistence of accessory pathways. Circulation. 2008;117:1508&#x2013;1517.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18332266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KOLDITZ DP, WIJFFELS MC, BLOM NA, VAN DER LAARSE A, MARKWALD RR, SCHALIJ MJ, GITTENBERGER-DE GROOT AC. Persistence of functional atrioventricular accessory pathways in postseptated embryonic avian hearts: implications for morphogenesis and functional maturation of the cardiac conduction system. Circulation. 2007;115:17&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17190860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>KRUZYNSKA-FREJTAG A, MACHNICKI M, ROGERS R, MARKWALD RR, CONWAY SJ. Periostin (an osteoblast-specific factor) is expressed within the embryonic mouse heart during valve formation. Mech Dev. 2001;103:183&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11335131</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LAVINE KJ, YU K, WHITE AC, ZHANG X, SMITH C, PARTANEN J, ORNITZ DM. Endocardial and epicardial derived FGF signals regulate myocardial proliferation and differentiation in vivo. Dev Cell. 2005;8:85&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15621532</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LI WE, WALDO K, LINASK KL, CHEN T, WESSELS A, PARMACEK MS, KIRBY ML, LO CW. An essential role for connexin43 gap junctions in mouse coronary artery development. Development. 2002;129:2031&#x2013;2042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11934868</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>LIE-VENEMA H, ERALP I, MARKWALD RR, VAN DEN AKKER NM, WIJFFELS MC, KOLDITZ DP, VAN DER LAARSE A, SCHALIJ MJ, POELMANN RE, BOGERS AJ, GITTENBERGER-DE GROOT AC. Periostin expression by epicardium-derived cells is involved in the development of the atrioventricular valves and fibrous heart skeleton. Differentiation. 2008;76:809&#x2013;819.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18294225</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MA Q, ZHOU B, PU WT. Reassessment of Isl1 and Nkx2-5 cardiac fate maps using a Gata4-based reporter of Cre activity. Dev Biol. 2008;323:98&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2655699</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18775691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MANI SA, GUO W, LIAO MJ, EATON EN, AYYANAN A, ZHOU AY, BROOKS M, REINHARD F, ZHANG CC, SHIPITSIN M, CAMPBELL LL, POLYAK K, BRISKEN C, YANG J, WEINBERG RA. The epithelial-mesenchymal transition generates cells with properties of stem cells. Cell. 2008;133:704&#x2013;715.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2728032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18485877</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MERKI E, ZAMORA M, RAYA A, KAWAKAMI Y, WANG J, ZHANG X, BURCH J, KUBALAK SW, KALIMAN P, BELMONTE JC, CHIEN KR, RUIZ-LOZANO P. Epicardial retinoid X receptor alpha is required for myocardial growth and coronary artery formation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102:18455&#x2013;18460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1317903</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16352730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MUZUMDAR MD, TASIC B, MIYAMICHI K, LI L, LUO L. A global double-fluorescent Cre reporter mouse. Genesis. 2007;45:593&#x2013;605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17868096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>NORRIS RA, MORENO-RODRIGUEZ RA, SUGI Y, HOFFMAN S, AMOS J, HART MM, POTTS JD, GOODWIN RL, MARKWALD RR. Periostin regulates atrioventricular valve maturation. Dev Biol. 2008;316:200&#x2013;213.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2386672</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18313657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>PEREZ-POMARES JM, PHELPS A, SEDMEROVA M, CARMONA R, GONZALEZ-IRIARTE M, MUNOZ-CHAPULI R, WESSELS A. Experimental studies on the spatiotemporal expression of WT1 and RALDH2 in the embryonic avian heart: a model for the regulation of myocardial and valvuloseptal development by epicardially derived cells (EPDCs) Dev Biol. 2002;247:307&#x2013;326.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12086469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SNIDER P, HINTON RB, MORENO-RODRIGUEZ RA, WANG J, ROGERS R, LINDSLEY A, LI F, INGRAM DA, MENICK D, FIELD L, FIRULLI AB, MOLKENTIN JD, MARKWALD R, CONWAY SJ. Periostin is required for maturation and extracellular matrix stabilization of noncardiomyocyte lineages of the heart. Circ Res. 2008;102:752&#x2013;760.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2754697</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18296617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SORIANO P. Generalized lacZ expression with the ROSA26 Cre reporter strain. Nat Genet. 1999;21:70&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9916792</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>VOOIJS M, JONKERS J, BERNS A. A highly efficient ligand-regulated Cre recombinase mouse line shows that LoxP recombination is position dependent. EMBO Rep. 2001;2:292&#x2013;297.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1083861</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11306549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WILM B, IPENBERG A, HASTIE ND, BURCH JB, BADER DM. The serosal mesothelium is a major source of smooth muscle cells of the gut vasculature. Development. 2005;132:5317&#x2013;5328.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16284122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>WU H, LEE SH, GAO J, LIU X, IRUELA-ARISPE ML. Inactivation of erythropoietin leads to defects in cardiac morphogenesis. Development. 1999;126:3597&#x2013;3605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10409505</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZAMORA M, MANNER J, RUIZ-LOZANO P. Epicardium-derived progenitor cells require beta-catenin for coronary artery formation. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007;104:18109&#x2013;18114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2084304</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17989236</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZHOU B, MA Q, KONG SW, HU Y, CAMPBELL PH, MCGOWAN FX, ACKERMAN KG, WU B, ZHOU B, TEVOSIAN SG, PU WT. Fog2 is critical for cardiac function and maintenance of coronary vasculature in the adult mouse heart. J Clin Invest. 2009;119:1462&#x2013;1476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2689123</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19411759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZHOU B, MA Q, RAJAGOPAL S, WU SM, DOMIAN I, RIVERA-FELICIANO J, JIANG D, VON GISE A, IKEDA S, CHIEN KR, PU WT. Epicardial progenitors contribute to the cardiomyocyte lineage in the developing heart. Nature. 2008a;454:109&#x2013;113.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2574791</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18568026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ZHOU B, VON GISE A, MA Q, RIVERA-FELICIANO J, PU WT. Nkx2-5- and Isl1-expressing cardiac progenitors contribute to proepicardium. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2008b;375:450&#x2013;453.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2610421</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18722343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>