<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41339841</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6874</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>26</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>03</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC women's health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Perceived infertility-related stress, partner attachment, and psychological distress among women undergoing in-vitro fertilization treatment: a latent profile and mediation analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>13</StartPage><MedlinePgn>13</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">13</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12905-025-04172-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">The heterogeneity of infertility-related stress and its psychological impact among women undergoing in vitro fertilization (IVF) treatment remain insufficiently understood. This study aims to identify distinct stress profiles and examine the mediating role of partner attachment in the link between stress profiles and psychological distress.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A total of 312 infertile women undergoing IVF treatment were enrolled in this cross-sectional survey. Perceived infertility-related stress, partner attachment, and psychological distress was assessed using the Copenhagen Multi-Centre Psychosocial Infertility Fertility Problem Stress Scale, Experiences in Close Relationships Scale, and Kessler Psychological Distress Scale. Latent profile analysis was used to identify distinct infertility stress profiles. Mediation analysis was performed to explore the role of partner attachment in the relationship between perceived infertility stress profiles and psychological distress.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Latent profile analysis on three infertility stress dimensions (personal stress, marital stress, and social stress) indicated three profiles: high-stress profile (7%), moderate-stress profile (54%), low-stress profile (39%). Multi-categorical mediation analysis showed that both attachment anxiety and attachment avoidant partially mediated effect in the connection of high-stress profile and psychological distress (B&#x2009;=&#x2009;1.9310, 95%CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.8122, 3.2378; B&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.9635, 95%CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.2682, 1.8954), whereas it fully mediated effect in the moderate-stress profile and psychological distress (B&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.8928, 95%CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.4124, 1.4401; B&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.6230, 95%CI&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.1874, 1.1291).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">This study identified heterogeneity in the infertility-related stress patterns of women undergoing IVF treatment and explored the associations between perceived infertility stress profiles and psychological distress using a person-centered approach. These findings offer preliminary insights suggesting that attachment-oriented interventions may be helpful in supporting this vulnerable population.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Liu</LastName><ForeName>Dan</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, The Third XiangYa Hospital of Central South University, Changsha, Hunan Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hu</LastName><ForeName>Sijie</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, The Third XiangYa Hospital of Central South University, No138, Tongzipo Road, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fu</LastName><ForeName>Bing</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, The Third XiangYa Hospital of Central South University, No138, Tongzipo Road, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410013, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Qinjing</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, The Third XiangYa Hospital of Central South University, Changsha, Hunan Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Ruirui</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, Hunan University of Medicine, Huaihua, Hunan Province, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huang</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nursing, People's Hospital of Xiangxi Tujia and Miao Autonomous Prefecture, The First Affiliated Hospital of Jishou University, Jishou, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shen</LastName><ForeName>Quan</ForeName><Initials>Q</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, The Third XiangYa Hospital of Central South University, No138, Tongzipo Road, Changsha, Hunan Province, 410013, China. shenquan@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>2024JJ6611</GrantID><Agency>Hunan Natural Science Foundation Youth Project</Agency><Country/></Grant><Grant><GrantID>2024JJ6625</GrantID><Agency>Hunan Natural Science Foundation Youth Project</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>03</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Womens Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088690</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6874</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Attachment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">In-virto fertilization treatment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Infertility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Perceived infertility-related stress</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Person-centered</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychological distress</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: This study was conducted in accordance with the principles outlined in the Declaration of Helsinki and was approved by the Third XiangYa Hospital of Central South University (Approval number: EC-LCKY2025010). Written informed consent was obtained from all participants before their inclusion in the study. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>2</Hour><Minute>11</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>45</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41339841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12781556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-025-04172-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12905-025-04172-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 1 in 6 people globally affected by infertility: WHO. Retrieved from: https://www.who.int/news/item/04-04-2023-1-in-6-people-globally-affected-by-infertility. 4 April 2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wei M, Zou J, Wei J, Lai X, Gong X, et al. Infertility trends in China: analyzing temporal changes, public demand, and demographic differences based on Baidu index. BMC Public Health. 2025;25(1):2481.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-025-23655-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12269174</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40676594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Qiao J, Wang Y, Li X, Jiang F, Zhang Y, Ma J, et al. A Lancet Commission on 70 years of women&#x2019;s reproductive, maternal, newborn, child, and adolescent health in China. Lancet. 2021;397(10293):2497&#x2013;536.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)32708-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34043953</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Logan S, Gu R, Li W, Xiao S, Anazodo A. Infertility in China: culture, society and a need for fertility counselling. Asian Pac J Reprod. 2019;8(1):1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2305-0500.250416</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nik Hazlina NH, Norhayati MN, Shaiful Bahari I, Nik Muhammad Arif NA. Worldwide prevalence, risk factors and psychological impact of infertility among women: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMJ Open. 2022;12(3):e057132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-057132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8968640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35354629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greil AL, Slauson-Blevins KS, Lowry MH, McQuillan J. Concerns about treatment for infertility in a probability-based sample of US women. J Reprod Infant Psychol. 2020;38(1):16&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02646838.2019.1587395</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6754327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30892066</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aimagambetova G, Issanov A, Terzic S, Bapayeva G, Ukybassova T, Baikoshkarova S, et al. The effect of psychological distress on IVF outcomes: reality or speculations? PLoS ONE. 2020;15(12):e0242024.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0242024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7735622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33315878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shani C, Yelena S, Reut BK, Adrian S, Sami H. Suicidal risk among infertile women undergoing in-vitro fertilization: incidence and risk factors. Psychiatry Res. 2016;240:53&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2016.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27084991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stellar C, Garcia-Moreno C, Temmerman M, van der Poel S. A systematic review and narrative report of the relationship between infertility, subfertility, and intimate partner violence. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2016;133(1):3&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijgo.2015.08.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26797197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler RC. Stress, social status, and psychological distress. J Health Soc Behav. 1979;20(3):259&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/2136450</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">479536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdoli S, Gholami AH, Masoumi SZ, Najafi-Vosough R, Azimi M, Jenabi E, et al. The association of anxiety and perceived stress with in vitro fertilization outcomes in infertile women: a cross-sectional study. J Hum Reprod Sci. 2025;18(1):16&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jhrs.jhrs_168_24</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12057839</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40342885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobral MP, Costa ME, Schmidt L, Martins MV. COMPI fertility problem stress scales is a brief, valid and reliable tool for assessing stress in patients seeking treatment. Hum Reprod. 2017;32(2):375&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/humrep/dew315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27979919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lykeridou K, Gourounti K, Deltsidou A, Loutradis D, Vaslamatzis G. The impact of infertility diagnosis on psychological status of women undergoing fertility treatment. J Reprod Infant Psyc. 2009;27(3):223&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/02646830802350864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilmaz T, Oskay UY. The evaluation of methods used to cope with infertility stress of infertile couples in Turkey. Int J Caring Sci. 2017;10(3):1595&#x2013;604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X, Wang K, Huo Y, Zhou M. The effect of infertility-related stress on Chinese infertile females&#x2019; mental health: the moderating role of marital adjustment. Psych J. 2019;8(2):232&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pchj.255</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30468007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luo D, Zhouchen YB, Li L, Jiang YL, Liu Y, Redding SR, et al. The stigma and infertility-related stress of Chinese infertile women: a cross-sectional study. Healthcare. 2024;12(11):1053.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare12111053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11171736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38891128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang X, Li J, Xie F, Chen X, Xu W, Hudson NW. The relationship between adult attachment and mental health: a meta-analysis. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2022;123(5):1089&#x2013;137.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pspp0000437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36201836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesta CE, Viktorin A, Olsson H, Johansson V, Sj&#xf6;lander A, Bergh C, et al. Depression, anxiety, and antidepressant treatment in women: association with in vitro fertilization outcome. Fertil Steril. 2016;105(6):1594&#x2013;e6023.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fertnstert.2016.01.036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26920258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diamond G, Diamond GM, Levy S. Attachment-based family therapy: theory, clinical model, outcomes, and process research. J Affect Disord. 2021;294:286&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2021.07.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8489519</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34304083</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson JA, Rholes WS. Adult attachment, stress, and romantic relationships. Curr Opin Psychol. 2017;13:19&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.copsyc.2016.04.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4845754</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27135049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowlby J. Attachment and loss: Vol. 1. Attachment. New York: Basic Books; 1969. /1982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowlby J. Attachment and loss. Vol. 2: Separation: Anxiety and anger. New York: Basic Books; 1973.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowlby J. Attachment and loss: Vol. 3. Sadness and depression. New York: Basic Books; 1980.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moutzouroulia A, Asimakopoulou Z, Tzavara C, Asimakopoulos K, Adonakis G, Kaponis A. The impact of infertility on the mental health of women undergoing in vitro fertilization treatment. Sexual &amp; Reproductive Healthcare. 2025;43:101072.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.srhc.2025.101072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39884254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Remondi C, Casu G, Pozzi C, Greco F, Gremigni P, Brugnera A. A serial mediation model of insecure attachment and psychological distress: the role of dispositional shame and shame-coping styles. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2023;20(4):3193.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph20043193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9966328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36833888</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trucharte A, Valiente C, Espinosa R, Chaves C. The role of insecure attachment and psychological mechanisms in paranoid and depressive symptoms: an exploratory model. Schizophr Res. 2022;243:9&#x2013;16.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.schres.2022.02.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35220038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donarelli Z, Lo Coco G, Gullo S, Marino A, Volpes A, Allegra A. Are attachment dimensions associated with infertility-related stress in couples undergoing their first IVF treatment? A study on the individual and cross-partner effect. Hum Reprod. 2012;27(11):3215&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/humrep/des307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22926837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donarelli Z, Kivlighan DM, Allegra A, Lo Coco G. How do individual attachment patterns of both members of couples affect their perceived infertility stress? An actor&#x2013;partner interdependence analysis. Pers Individ Differ. 2016;92:63&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2015.12.023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61(4):344&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2007.11.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18313558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carson SA, Kallen AN. Diagnosis and management of infertility: a review. JAMA. 2021;326(1):65&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.4788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9302705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34228062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Buchner A, Lang AG. Statistical power analyses using G*Power 3.1: tests for correlation and regression analyses. Behav Res Methods. 2009;41(4):1149&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3758/BRM.41.4.1149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19897823</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kessler R, Mroczek D. Final versions of our Non -specific psychological distress scale. Ann arbor (MI), survey research center of the Institute for social research. University of Michigan. 1994.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Chu J, Wang T, Peng Q, He J, Zheng W, et al. Reliability and validity of 10-item Kessler scale (k10) Chinese version in evaluation of mental health status of Chinese population. Chin J Cli Psyc. 2008;16(06):627&#x2013;9. (In Chinese).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt L, Holstein BE, Boivin J, S&#xe5;ngren H, Tj&#xf8;rnh&#xf8;j-Thomsen T, Blaabjerg J, et al. Patients&#x2019; attitudes to medical and psychosocial aspects of care in fertility clinics: findings from the Copenhagen Multi-centre psychosocial infertility (COMPI) research programme. Hum Reprod. 2003;18(3):628&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/humrep/deg149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12615837</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fraley RC, Waller NG, Brennan KA. An item response theory analysis of self-report measures of adult attachment. J Pers Soc Psychol. 2000;78(2):350&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-3514.78.2.350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10707340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Du K, Dong Y. The dyadic interaction model of relationship quality and the impact of attachment orientation and empathy on infertile couples in China. Nurs Open. 2021;8(5):2664&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.819</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8363387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33630423</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polas MRH. Common method bias in social and behavioral research: Strategic solutions for quantitative research in the doctoral research. J Compr Bus Adm Res. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williams GA, Kibowski F. Latent class analysis and latent profile analysis. In: Jason L, Glenwick D, editors. Handbook of methodological approaches to Community-Based research: Qualitative, Quantitative, and mixed methods. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinha P, Calfee CS, Delucchi KL. Practitioner&#x2019;s guide to latent class analysis: methodological considerations and common pitfalls. Crit Care Med. 2021;49(1):e63&#x2013;79.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0000000000004710</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7746621</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33165028</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dziak JJ, Coffman DL, Lanza ST, Li R, Jermiin LS. Sensitivity and specificity of information criteria. Brief Bioinform. 2020;21(2):553&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bib/bbz016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7299313</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30895308</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tein JY, Coxe S, Cham H. Statistical power to detect the correct number of classes in latent profile analysis. Struct Equ Model. 2013;20(4):640&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10705511.2013.824781</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3904803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24489457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang CC. Evaluating latent class analysis models in qualitative phenotype identification. Comput Stat Data Anal. 2006;50(4):1090&#x2013;104.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes AF, Preacher KJ. Statistical mediation analysis with a multicategorical independent variable. Br J Math Stat Psychol. 2014;67(3):451&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bmsp.12028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24188158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes AF. PROCESS: A versatile computational tool for mediation. Moderation and Conditional Process Analysis. New York: Guilford Press; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>VanderWeele TJ. Mediation analysis: a practitioner&#x2019;s guide. Annu Rev Public Health. 2016;37:17&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032315-021402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26653405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groene EA, Mutabuzi C, Chinunje D, Shango EM, Kulasingam S, Majinge CR. Comparing infertility-related stress in high fertility and low fertility countries. Sexual &amp; Reproductive Healthcare. 2021;29:100653.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.srhc.2021.100653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34450403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Lu E, Thayer Z. The influence of assisted reproductive technologies-related stressors and social support on perceived stress and depression. BMC Womens Health. 2024;24(1):431.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-024-03262-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11282751</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39068405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang L, Zeng T, Wu M, et al. Infertility psychological distress in women undergoing assisted reproductive treatment: a grounded theory study. J Clin Nurs. 2024;33(9):3642&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jocn.17195</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38716811</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swift A, Reis P, Swanson M. Infertility stress, cortisol, coping, and quality of life in U.S. women who undergo infertility treatments. J Obstet Gynecol Neonatal Nurs. 2021;50(3):275&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jogn.2020.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33497688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cesta CE, Johansson ALV, Hreinsson J, et al. A prospective investigation of perceived stress, infertility-related stress, and cortisol levels in women undergoing in vitro fertilization: influence on embryo quality and clinical pregnancy rate. Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2018;97(3):258&#x2013;68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aogs.13280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29250769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins MV, Peterson BD, Costa P, Costa ME, Lund R, Schmidt L. Interactive effects of social support and disclosure on fertility-related stress. J Soc Pers Relat. 2013;30:371&#x2013;88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0265407512456672</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dagan O, Groh AM, Madigan S, Bernard K. A lifespan development theory of insecure attachment and internalizing symptoms: integrating meta-analytic evidence via a testable evolutionary mis/match hypothesis. Brain Sci. 2021;11(9):1226.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/brainsci11091226</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8469853</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34573246</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brenning K, Braet C. The emotion regulation model of attachment: an emotion-specific approach. Pers Relatsh. 2013;20:107&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1475-6811.2012.01399.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chatziioannidis S, Andreou C, Agorastos A, Kaprinis S, Malliaris Y, Garyfallos G, et al. The role of attachment anxiety in the relationship between childhood trauma and schizophrenia-spectrum psychosis. Psychiatry Res. 2019;276:223&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2019.05.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31112856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillath O, Karantzas G, Fraley R. Adult attachment: A concise introduction to theory and research. Londres: Academic Press; 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winterheld HA. Calibrating use of emotion regulation strategies to the relationship context: an attachment perspective. J Pers. 2016;84(3):369&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jopy.12165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25643648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malik S, Wells A, Wittkowski A. Emotion regulation as a mediator in the relationship between attachment and depressive symptomatology: a systematic review. J Affect Disord. 2015;172:428&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2014.10.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25451448</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mikulincer M, Shaver PR. Attachment orientations and emotion regulation. Curr Opin Psychol. 2019;25:6&#x2013;10.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.copsyc.2018.02.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29494853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Umemura T, Lacinov&#xe1; L, Kotr&#x10d;ov&#xe1; K, Fraley RC. Similarities and differences regarding changes in attachment preferences and attachment styles in relation to romantic relationship length: longitudinal and concurrent analyses. Attach Hum Dev. 2018;20(2):135&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14616734.2017.1383488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28959920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis J, George B, Dike J, Breaux R, Brem M. Family-of-origin of violence, insecure attachment, and depression symptoms in emerging adults: A brief report. J Fam Viol. 2025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Di Maio S, Villinger K, Knoll N, Scholz U, Stadler G, Gawrilow C, et al. Compendium of dyadic intervention techniques (DITs) to change health behaviours: A systematic review. Health Psychol Rev. 2024;18(3):538&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17437199.2024.2307534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38437798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLeod S, Berry K, Hodgson C, Wearden A. Attachment and social support in romantic dyads: a systematic review. J Clin Psychol. 2020;76(1):59&#x2013;101.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.22868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31566266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koochaksaraei FY, Simbar M, Khoshnoodifar M, Faramarzi M, Nasiri M. Interventions promoting mental health dimensions in infertile women: a systematic review. BMC Psychol. 2023;11(1):254.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40359-023-01285-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10472670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37653562</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soleimani R, Ansari F, Hamzehgardeshi Z, Elyasi F, Moosazadeh M, Yazdani F, et al. Perceived stress reduction through an infertility coaching program: a randomized controlled clinical trial. Sci Rep. 2023;13(1):14511.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-023-41845-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10477300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37666933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benson LA, Sevier M, Christensen A. The impact of behavioral couple therapy on attachment in distressed couples. J Marital Fam Ther. 2013;39(4):407&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jmft.12020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4581532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25800417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vedelago L, Balzarini RN, Fitzpatrick S, Muise A. Tailoring dyadic coping strategies to attachment style: emotion-focused and problem-focused dyadic coping differentially buffer anxiously and avoidantly attached partners. J Soc Pers Relat. 2022;40(6):1830&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02654075221133575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>