<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">35311685</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2291-9694</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Mar</Month><Day>21</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR medical informatics</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Med Inform</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Prediction of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease Exacerbation Events by Using Patient Self-reported Data in a Digital Health App: Statistical Evaluation and Machine Learning Approach.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e26499</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e26499</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e26499</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/26499</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Self-reporting digital apps provide a way of remotely monitoring and managing patients with chronic conditions in the community. Leveraging the data collected by these apps in prognostic models could provide increased personalization of care and reduce the burden of care for people who live with chronic conditions. This study evaluated the predictive ability of prognostic models for the prediction of acute exacerbation events in people with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease by using data self-reported to a digital health app.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study was to evaluate if data self-reported to a digital health app can be used to predict acute exacerbation events in the near future.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a retrospective study evaluating the use of symptom and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease assessment test data self-reported to a digital health app (myCOPD) in predicting acute exacerbation events. We include data from 2374 patients who made 68,139 self-reports. We evaluated the degree to which the different variables self-reported to the app are predictive of exacerbation events and developed both heuristic and machine learning models to predict whether the patient will report an exacerbation event within 3 days of self-reporting to the app. The model's predictive ability was evaluated based on self-reports from an independent set of patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Users self-reported symptoms, and standard chronic obstructive pulmonary disease assessment tests displayed correlation with future exacerbation events. Both a baseline model (area under the receiver operating characteristic curve [AUROC] 0.655, 95% CI 0.689-0.676) and a machine learning model (AUROC 0.727, 95% CI 0.720-0.735) showed moderate ability in predicting exacerbation events, occurring within 3 days of a given self-report. Although the baseline model obtained a fixed sensitivity and specificity of 0.551 (95% CI 0.508-0.596) and 0.759 (95% CI 0.752-0.767) respectively, the sensitivity and specificity of the machine learning model can be tuned by dichotomizing the continuous predictions it provides with different thresholds.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Data self-reported to health care apps designed to remotely monitor patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease can be used to predict acute exacerbation events with moderate performance. This could increase personalization of care by allowing preemptive action to be taken to mitigate the risk of future exacerbation events.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Francis P Chmiel, Dan K Burns, John Brian Pickering, Alison Blythin, Thomas MA Wilkinson, Michael J Boniface. Originally published in JMIR Medical Informatics (https://medinform.jmir.org), 21.03.2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chmiel</LastName><ForeName>Francis P</ForeName><Initials>FP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0674-8098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Computer Science, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burns</LastName><ForeName>Dan K</ForeName><Initials>DK</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6976-1068</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Computer Science, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pickering</LastName><ForeName>John Brian</ForeName><Initials>JB</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6815-2938</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Computer Science, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blythin</LastName><ForeName>Alison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6080-0120</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>my mHealth Limited, Bournemouth, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Wilkinson</LastName><ForeName>Thomas Ma</ForeName><Initials>TM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1771-3851</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>my mHealth Limited, Bournemouth, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>National Institute for Health Research Applied Research Collaboration Wessex, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y"><LastName>Boniface</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9281-6095</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Electronics and Computer Science, University of Southampton, Southampton, United Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Med Inform</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101645109</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2291-9694</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COPD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chronic disease</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital applications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exacerbation events</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health care applications</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myCOPD</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">remote monitoring</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: TMAW is Chief Science Officer and cofounder of my mHealth, the developer of the myCOPD app. AB is a Senior Research Nurse and Clinical Trial Manager at my mHealth. All other authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35311685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8981014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/26499</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v10i3e26499</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>McLean S, Hoogendoorn M, Hoogenveen RT, Feenstra TL, Wild S, Simpson CR, M&#xf6;lken Maureen Rutten-van, Sheikh A. Projecting the COPD population and costs in England and Scotland: 2011 to 2030. Sci Rep. 2016 Sep 01;6:31893. doi: 10.1038/srep31893. doi: 10.1038/srep31893.srep31893</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep31893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5008118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27583987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lozano R, Naghavi M, Foreman K, Lim S, Shibuya K, Aboyans V, Abraham J, Adair T, Aggarwal R, Ahn SY, Alvarado M, Anderson HR, Anderson LM, Andrews KG, Atkinson C, Baddour LM, Barker-Collo S, Bartels DH, Bell ML, Benjamin EJ, Bennett D, Bhalla K, Bikbov B, Bin Abdulhak Aref, Birbeck G, Blyth F, Bolliger I, Boufous S, Bucello C, Burch M, Burney P, Carapetis J, Chen H, Chou D, Chugh SS, Coffeng LE, Colan SD, Colquhoun S, Colson KE, Condon J, Connor MD, Cooper LT, Corriere M, Cortinovis M, de Vaccaro Karen Courville, Couser W, Cowie BC, Criqui MH, Cross M, Dabhadkar KC, Dahodwala N, De Leo Diego, Degenhardt L, Delossantos A, Denenberg J, Des Jarlais Don C, Dharmaratne SD, Dorsey ER, Driscoll T, Duber H, Ebel B, Erwin PJ, Espindola P, Ezzati M, Feigin V, Flaxman AD, Forouzanfar MH, Fowkes FGR, Franklin R, Fransen M, Freeman MK, Gabriel SE, Gakidou E, Gaspari F, Gillum RF, Gonzalez-Medina D, Halasa YA, Haring D, Harrison JE, Havmoeller R, Hay RJ, Hoen B, Hotez PJ, Hoy D, Jacobsen KH, James SL, Jasrasaria R, Jayaraman S, Johns N, Karthikeyan G, Kassebaum N, Keren A, Khoo J, Knowlton LM, Kobusingye O, Koranteng A, Krishnamurthi R, Lipnick M, Lipshultz SE, Ohno SL, Mabweijano J, MacIntyre MF, Mallinger L, March L, Marks GB, Marks R, Matsumori A, Matzopoulos R, Mayosi BM, McAnulty JH, McDermott MM, McGrath J, Mensah GA, Merriman TR, Michaud C, Miller M, Miller TR, Mock C, Mocumbi AO, Mokdad AA, Moran A, Mulholland K, Nair MN, Naldi L, Narayan KMV, Nasseri K, Norman P, O'Donnell M, Omer SB, Ortblad K, Osborne R, Ozgediz D, Pahari B, Pandian JD, Rivero AP, Padilla RP, Perez-Ruiz F, Perico N, Phillips D, Pierce K, Pope CA, Porrini E, Pourmalek F, Raju M, Ranganathan D, Rehm JT, Rein DB, Remuzzi G, Rivara FP, Roberts T, De Le&#xf3;n Felipe Rodriguez, Rosenfeld LC, Rushton L, Sacco RL, Salomon JA, Sampson U, Sanman E, Schwebel DC, Segui-Gomez M, Shepard DS, Singh D, Singleton J, Sliwa K, Smith E, Steer A, Taylor JA, Thomas B, Tleyjeh IM, Towbin JA, Truelsen T, Undurraga EA, Venketasubramanian N, Vijayakumar L, Vos T, Wagner GR, Wang M, Wang W, Watt K, Weinstock MA, Weintraub R, Wilkinson JD, Woolf AD, Wulf S, Yeh P, Yip P, Zabetian A, Zheng Z, Lopez AD, Murray CJL, AlMazroa MA, Memish ZA. Global and regional mortality from 235 causes of death for 20 age groups in 1990 and 2010: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. Lancet. 2012 Dec 15;380(9859):2095&#x2013;128. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(12)61728-0.S0140-6736(12)61728-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(12)61728-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10790329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245604</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miravitlles M, Vogelmeier C, Roche N, Halpin D, Cardoso J, Chuchalin AG, Kankaanranta H, Sandstr&#xf6;m Thomas, &#x15a;liwi&#x144;ski P, Zatloukal J, Blasi F. A review of national guidelines for management of COPD in Europe. Eur Respir J. 2016 Feb;47(2):625&#x2013;37. doi: 10.1183/13993003.01170-2015. 
 
13993003.01170-2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01170-2015</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4733567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26797035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Roisin R. Toward a consensus definition for COPD exacerbations. Chest. 2000 May;117(5 Suppl 2):398S&#x2013;401S. doi: 10.1378/chest.117.5_suppl_2.398s.S0012-3692(15)32859-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.117.5_suppl_2.398s</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10843984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hoogendoorn M, Feenstra TL, Hoogenveen RT, Al M, M&#xf6;lken Maureen Rutten-van. Association between lung function and exacerbation frequency in patients with COPD. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2010 Dec 09;5:435&#x2013;44. doi: 10.2147/COPD.S13826. doi: 10.2147/COPD.S13826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/COPD.S13826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3008329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21191438</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson GC, Seemungal TAR, Bhowmik A, Wedzicha JA. Relationship between exacerbation frequency and lung function decline in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Thorax. 2002 Oct;57(10):847&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1136/thorax.57.10.847. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thorax.57.10.847</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1746193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12324669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donaldson GC, Wedzicha JA. COPD exacerbations .1: Epidemiology. Thorax. 2006 Feb;61(2):164&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1136/thx.2005.041806. 
 
61/2/164</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2005.041806</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2104564</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16443707</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson TMA, Donaldson GC, Hurst JR, Seemungal TAR, Wedzicha JA. Early Therapy Improves Outcomes of Exacerbations of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2004 Jun 15;169(12):1298&#x2013;1303. doi: 10.1164/rccm.200310-1443oc.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200310-1443oc</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14990395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wedzicha JA, Seemungal TAR. COPD exacerbations: defining their cause and prevention. Lancet. 2007 Sep 01;370(9589):786&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(07)61382-8. 
 
S0140-6736(07)61382-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)61382-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7134993</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17765528</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adibi A, Sin DD, Safari A, Johnson KM, Aaron SD, FitzGerald JM, Sadatsafavi M. The Acute COPD Exacerbation Prediction Tool (ACCEPT): a modelling study. Lancet Respir Med. 2020 Oct;8(10):1013&#x2013;1021. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30397-2.S2213-2600(19)30397-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30397-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32178776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guerra B, Gaveikaite V, Bianchi C, Puhan MA. Prediction models for exacerbations in patients with COPD. Eur Respir Rev. 2017 Jan;26(143):160061. doi: 10.1183/16000617.0061-2016. 
 
26/143/160061</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/16000617.0061-2016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9489020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28096287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobnath DD, Philip N, Kayyali R, Nabhani-Gebara S, Pierscionek B, Vaes AW, Spruit MA, Kaimakamis E. Features of a Mobile Support App for Patients With Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease: Literature Review and Current Applications. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2017 Feb 20;5(2):e17. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.4951. 
 
v5i2e17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.4951</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5339437</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28219878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velardo C, Shah SA, Gibson O, Clifford G, Heneghan C, Rutter H, Farmer A, Tarassenko L, EDGE COPD Team  Digital health system for personalised COPD long-term management. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2017 Feb 20;17(1):19. doi: 10.1186/s12911-017-0414-8. 
 
10.1186/s12911-017-0414-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-017-0414-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5319140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28219430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>North M, Bourne S, Green B, Chauhan AJ, Brown T, Winter J, Jones T, Neville D, Blythin A, Watson A, Johnson M, Culliford D, Elkes J, Cornelius V, Wilkinson TMA. A randomised controlled feasibility trial of E-health application supported care vs usual care after exacerbation of COPD: the RESCUE trial. NPJ Digit Med. 2020;3:145. doi: 10.1038/s41746-020-00347-7. doi: 10.1038/s41746-020-00347-7.347</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-020-00347-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7603326</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33145441</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones PW, Harding G, Berry P, Wiklund I, Chen W, Kline Leidy N. Development and first validation of the COPD Assessment Test. Eur Respir J. 2009 Sep;34(3):648&#x2013;54. doi: 10.1183/09031936.00102509. 
 
34/3/648</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00102509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19720809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dodd JW, Hogg L, Nolan J, Jefford H, Grant A, Lord VM, Falzon C, Garrod R, Lee C, Polkey MI, Jones PW, Man WD, Hopkinson NS. The COPD assessment test (CAT): response to pulmonary rehabilitation. A multicentre, prospective study. Thorax. 2011 May;66(5):425&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1136/thx.2010.156372.thx.2010.156372</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2010.156372</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21398686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta N, Pinto LM, Morogan A, Bourbeau J. The COPD assessment test: a systematic review. Eur Respir J. 2014 Oct;44(4):873&#x2013;84. doi: 10.1183/09031936.00025214. 
 
09031936.00025214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00025214</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24993906</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstra J, Bardenet R, Bengio Y, K&#xe9;gl B. Algorithms for hyper-parameter optimization. In Advances in neural information processing systems -2554. doi/10.5555/2986459.298. 2011;2546:6743. doi: 10.5555/2986459.2986743.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5555/2986459.2986743</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergstra J, Yamins D, Cox D. Making a science of model search: Hyperparameter optimization in hundreds of dimensions for vision architectures. ICML'13: Proceedings of the 30th International Conference on International Conference on Machine Learning; June; Atlanta, GA, USA. 2013. pp. 115&#x2013;123.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Youden WJ. Index for rating diagnostic tests. Cancer. 1950 Jan;3(1):32&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15405679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Varol Y, Ozacar R, Balci G, Usta L, Taymaz Z. Assessing the effectiveness of the COPD Assessment Test (CAT) to evaluate COPD severity and exacerbation rates. COPD. 2014 Apr;11(2):221&#x2013;5. doi: 10.3109/15412555.2013.836169.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/15412555.2013.836169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24111793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halpin DM, Miravitlles M, Metzdorf N, Celli B. Impact and prevention of severe exacerbations of COPD: a review of the evidence. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2017;12:2891&#x2013;2908. doi: 10.2147/COPD.S139470. doi: 10.2147/COPD.S139470.copd-12-2891</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/COPD.S139470</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5638577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29062228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Global strategy for the diagnosis, management and prevention of COPD. Global Initiative for Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease (GOLD) 2020.  [2020-11-25].  
 https://goldcopd.org/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson TMA, Donaldson GC, Johnston SL, Openshaw PJM, Wedzicha JA. Respiratory syncytial virus, airway inflammation, and FEV1 decline in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2006 Apr 15;173(8):871&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1164/rccm.200509-1489OC.200509-1489OC</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.200509-1489OC</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16456141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomasic I, Tomasic N, Trobec R, Krpan M, Kelava T. Continuous remote monitoring of COPD patients-justification and explanation of the requirements and a survey of the available technologies. Med Biol Eng Comput. 2018 Apr;56(4):547&#x2013;569. doi: 10.1007/s11517-018-1798-z. 
 
10.1007/s11517-018-1798-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11517-018-1798-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5857273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29504070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Siafakas N, Vermeire P, Pride N, Paoletti P, Gibson J, Howard P, Yernault J, Decramer M, Higenbottam T, Postma D. Optimal assessment and management of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). The European Respiratory Society Task Force. Eur Respir J. 1995 Aug;8(8):1398&#x2013;420. doi: 10.1183/09031936.95.08081398. 
 
</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.95.08081398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7489808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lundberg SM, Nair B, Vavilala MS, Horibe M, Eisses MJ, Adams T, Liston DE, Low DK, Newman S, Kim J, Lee S. Explainable machine-learning predictions for the prevention of hypoxaemia during surgery. Nat Biomed Eng. 2018 Oct;2(10):749&#x2013;760. doi: 10.1038/s41551-018-0304-0. 
 
10.1038/s41551-018-0304-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41551-018-0304-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6467492</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31001455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walters EH, Walters J, Wills KE, Robinson A, Wood-Baker R. Clinical diaries in COPD: compliance and utility in predicting acute exacerbations. Int J Chron Obstruct Pulmon Dis. 2012;7:427&#x2013;35. doi: 10.2147/COPD.S32222. doi: 10.2147/COPD.S32222.copd-7-427</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/COPD.S32222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3402058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22848156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone AA, Shiffman S. Capturing momentary, self-report data: a proposal for reporting guidelines. Ann Behav Med. 2002;24(3):236&#x2013;43. doi: 10.1207/S15324796ABM2403_09.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/S15324796ABM2403_09</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12173681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bradbury K, Morton K, Band R, van Woezik A, Grist R, McManus RJ, Little P, Yardley L. Using the Person-Based Approach to optimise a digital intervention for the management of hypertension. PLoS One. 2018;13(5):e0196868. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0196868. 
 
PONE-D-17-30284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0196868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5933761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29723262</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>