<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38803869</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>29</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2405-8440</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>10</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>30</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Heliyon</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Heliyon</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Exacerbation predictive modelling using real-world data from the myCOPD app.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e31201</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e31201</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e31201</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31201</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Acute exacerbations of COPD (AECOPD) are episodes of breathlessness, cough and sputum which are associated with the risk of hospitalisation, progressive lung function decline and death. They are often missed or diagnosed late. Accurate timely intervention can improve these poor outcomes. Digital tools can be used to capture symptoms and other clinical data in COPD. This study aims to apply machine learning to the largest available real-world digital dataset to develop AECOPD Prediction tools which could be used to support early intervention and improve clinical outcomes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To create and validate a machine learning predictive model that forecasts exacerbations of COPD 1-8 days in advance. The model is based on routine patient-entered data from myCOPD self-management app.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Adaptations of the AdaBoost algorithm were employed as machine learning approaches. The dataset included 506 patients users between 2017 and 2021. 55,066 app records were available for stable COPD event labels and 1263 records of AECOPD event labels. The data used for training the model included COPD assessment test (CAT) scores, symptom scores, smoking history, and previous exacerbation frequency. All exacerbation records used in the model were confined to the 1-8 days preceding a self-reported exacerbation event.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">TheEasyEnsemble Classifier resulted in a Sensitivity of 67.0&#xa0;% and a Specificity of 65&#xa0;% with a positive predictive value (PPV) of 5.0&#xa0;% and a negative predictive value (NPV) of 98.9&#xa0;%. An AdaBoost model with a cost-sensitive decision tree resulted in a a Sensitivity of 35.0&#xa0;% and a Specificity of 89.0&#xa0;% with a PPV of 7.08&#xa0;% and NPV of 98.3&#xa0;%.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This preliminary analysis demonstrates that machine learning approaches to real-world data from a widely deployed digital therapeutic has the potential to predict AECOPD and can be used to confidently exclude the risk of exacerbations of COPD within the next 8 days.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2024 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glyde</LastName><ForeName>Henry M G</ForeName><Initials>HMG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>EPSRC Centre for Doctoral Training in Digital Health and Care, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Blythin</LastName><ForeName>Alison M</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>My mHealth, Bournemouth, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wilkinson</LastName><ForeName>Tom M A</ForeName><Initials>TMA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>My mHealth and Clinical and Experimental Science, University of Southampton, Southampton, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nabney</LastName><ForeName>Ian T</ForeName><Initials>IT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Engineering Mathematics and Technology, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dodd</LastName><ForeName>James W</ForeName><Initials>JW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Academic Respiratory Unit, Translational Health Sciences, Bristol Medical School, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>14</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Heliyon</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101672560</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2405-8440</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Machine learning</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prediction models</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests. Tom Wilkinson reports a relationship with my mhealth ltd that includes: board membership. Alison Blythin reports a relationship with my mhealth ltd that includes: employment. If there are other authors, they declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>28</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>47</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38803869</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11128912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-8440(24)07232-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Adeloye D., Song P., Zhu Y., Campbell H., Sheikh A., Rudan I., et al. Global, regional, and national prevalence of, and risk factors for, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) in 2019: a systematic review and modelling analysis. Lancet Respir. Med. 2022;10(5):447&#x2013;458.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9050565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35279265</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Viegi G., Maio S., Fasola S., Baldacci S. Global burden of chronic respiratory diseases. J. Aerosol Med. Pulm. Drug Deliv. 2020;33(4):171&#x2013;177.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32423274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li X., Cao X., Guo M., Xie M., Liu X. Trends and risk factors of mortality and disability adjusted life years for chronic respiratory diseases from 1990 to 2017: systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2017. Br. Med. J. 2020:368.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7190065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raherison C., Girodet P. Epidemiology of COPD. Eur. Respir. Rev. 2009;18(114):213&#x2013;221.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20956146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toy E.L., Gallagher K.F., Stanley E.L., Swensen A.R., Duh M.S. The economic impact of exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and exacerbation definition: a review. COPD: journal of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease. 2010;7(3):214&#x2013;228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20486821</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wouters E. Economic analysis of the Confronting COPD survey: an overview of results. Respir. Med. 2003;97:S3&#x2013;S14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12647938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iheanacho I., Zhang S., King D., Rizzo M., Ismaila A.S. Economic burden of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD): a systematic literature review. Int. J. Chronic Obstr. Pulm. Dis. 2020;15:439.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7049777</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32161455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seemungal T.A., Donaldson G.C., Paul E.A., Bestall J.C., Jeffries D.J., Wedzicha J.A. Effect of exacerbation on quality of life in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 1998;157(5):1418&#x2013;1422.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9603117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miravitlles M., Ferrer M., Pont A., Zalacain R., Alvarez-Sala J., Masa F., et al. Effect of exacerbations on quality of life in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a 2 year follow up study. Thorax. 2004;59(5):387&#x2013;395.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1746989</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15115864</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Niewoehner D.E. The impact of severe exacerbations on quality of life and the clinical course of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am. J. Med. 2006;119(10):38&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16996898</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurst J.R., Skolnik N., Hansen G.J., Anzueto A., Donaldson G.C., Dransfield M.T., et al. Understanding the impact of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbations on patient health and quality of life. Eur. J. Intern. Med. 2020;73:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31954592</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqahtani J.S., Aquilina J., Bafadhel M., Bolton C.E., Burgoyne T., Holmes S., et al. Research priorities for exacerbations of COPD. Lancet Respir. Med. 2021;9(8):824&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34000234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkinson T.M., Donaldson G.C., Hurst J.R., Seemungal T.A., Wedzicha J.A. Early therapy improves outcomes of exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. Am. J. Respir. Crit. Care Med. 2004;169(12):1298&#x2013;1303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14990395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dinesen B., Haesum L.K., Soerensen N., Nielsen C., Grann O., Hejlesen O., et al. Using preventive home monitoring to reduce hospital admission rates and reduce costs: a case study of telehealth among chronic obstructive pulmonary disease patients. J. Telemed. Telecare. 2012;18(4):221&#x2013;225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22653618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Calvo G.S., G&#x2032;omez-Su&#x2032;arez C., Soriano J., Zamora E., G&#x2032;onzalez-Gamarra A., Gonz&#x2032;alez-B&#x2032;ejar M., et al. A home telehealth program for patients with severe COPD: the PROMETE study. Respir. Med. 2014;108(3):453&#x2013;462.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24433744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orchard P., Agakova A., Pinnock H., Burton C.D., Sarran C., Agakov F., et al. Improving prediction of risk of hospital admission in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: application of machine learning to telemonitoring data. J. Med. Internet Res. 2018;20(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6231768</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30249589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hastie T., Rosset S., Zhu J., Zou H. Multi-class adaboost. Stat. Interface. 2009;2(3):349&#x2013;360.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breiman L., Friedman J.H., Olshen R.A., Stone C.J. vol. 432. Wadsworth. International Group; Belmont, CA: 1984. pp. 151&#x2013;166. (Classification and Regression Trees).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu X.Y., Wu J., Zhou Z.H. Exploratory undersampling for class-imbalance learning. IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, Part B (Cybernetics) 2008;39(2):539&#x2013;550.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19095540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xie Y., Redmond S.J., Mohktar M.S., Shany T., Basilakis J., Hession M., et al. 2013 35th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC) IEEE; 2013. Prediction of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease exacerbation using physiological time series patterns; pp. 6784&#x2013;6787.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24111301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohktar M.S., Redmond S.J., Antoniades N.C., Rochford P.D., Pretto J.J., Basilakis J., et al. Predicting the risk of exacerbation in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease using home telehealth measurement data. Artif. Intell. Med. 2015;63(1):51&#x2013;59.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25704112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel N., Kinmond K., Jones P., Birks P., Spiteri M.A. Validation of COPDPredict&#x2122;: unique combination of remote monitoring and exacerbation prediction to support preventative management of COPD exacerbations. Int. J. Chronic Obstr. Pulm. Dis. 2021;16:1887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8232856</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34188465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah S.A., Velardo C., Farmer A., Tarassenko L. Exacerbations in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: identification and prediction using a digital health system. J. Med. Internet Res. 2017;19(3)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5360891</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28270380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van der Heijden M., Velikova M., Lucas P.J. Learning Bayesian networks for clinical time series analysis. J. Biomed. Inf. 2014;48:94&#x2013;105.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24361389</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen M.H., Cichosz S.L., Dinesen B., Hejlesen O.K. Moving prediction of exacerbation in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease for patients in telecare. J. Telemed. Telecare. 2012;18(2):99&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22267305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>