<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">33118640</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1540-8159</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>44</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Pacing and clinical electrophysiology : PACE</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Pacing Clin Electrophysiol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The use of intravenous amiodarone in patients with atrial fibrillation and Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>35</StartPage><EndPage>43</EndPage><MedlinePgn>35-43</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/pace.14113</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">It was reported that intravenous amiodarone might induce ventricular fibrillation for acute treatment in patients with atrial fibrillation (AF) and Wolff-Parkinson-White (WPW) syndrome. No study was done to assess its application comprehensively in this population.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">This study was a retrospective analysis and undertaken by reviewing medical records and electronic databases to search for patients admitted with tachycardia resulting from WPW syndrome and AF, who have intravenously administrated amiodarone at the emergency department from January 2008 to June 2018.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Thirty patients were involved in this study, of which 27 were males. The mean age of the patients was 47.8 &#xb1; 17.0 years. The mean systolic blood pressure and diastolic blood pressure were 111.9 &#xb1; 18.3&#xa0;mmHg and 76.1 &#xb1; 14.6&#xa0;mmHg, respectively. The mean heart rate was 171 (150-189) beats per minute. Half of the patients (53.3%) had no comorbidities, and only one had prior syncope. Nearly 17 patients (56.7%) started with a loading dose of 150&#xa0;mg. No ventricular acceleration or VF developed. The incidence of hypotension was 3.3% (1/30). Eighteen patients (60.0%) restored to sinus rhythm by amiodarone with the conversion time of 486.0 (229.0-1278.0) minutes.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Intravenous amiodarone might be an alternative for acute treatment of AF and WPW syndrome in patients characterized by stable hemodynamics, relatively low admission heart rate, few comorbidities, elder age, and no prior syncope. The loading dosage of 150&#xa0;mg appeared to be preferred, and the maintenance period was better to less than 12&#xa0;hours. Monitoring and electrolyte correction were also necessary. It is essential to keep a defibrillator nearby during pharmacologic cardioversion.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2020 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ren</LastName><ForeName>Jiameng</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Intensive Care Center, State Key Laboratory of Cardiovascular Disease, Fuwai Hospital, National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Yanmin</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0742-3853</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Intensive Care Center, State Key Laboratory of Cardiovascular Disease, Fuwai Hospital, National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhu</LastName><ForeName>Jun</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Intensive Care Center, State Key Laboratory of Cardiovascular Disease, Fuwai Hospital, National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Shuang</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Intensive Care Center, State Key Laboratory of Cardiovascular Disease, Fuwai Hospital, National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Juan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Intensive Care Center, State Key Laboratory of Cardiovascular Disease, Fuwai Hospital, National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhang</LastName><ForeName>Han</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Intensive Care Center, State Key Laboratory of Cardiovascular Disease, Fuwai Hospital, National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shao</LastName><ForeName>Xinghui</ForeName><Initials>X</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Emergency and Intensive Care Center, State Key Laboratory of Cardiovascular Disease, Fuwai Hospital, National Center for Cardiovascular Diseases, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences and Peking Union Medical College, Beijing, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>09</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Pacing Clin Electrophysiol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7803944</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0147-8389</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000889">Anti-Arrhythmia Agents</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>N3RQ532IUT</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000638">Amiodarone</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 2021 Mar;44(3):568. doi: 10.1111/pace.14172.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">33481256</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>Pacing Clin Electrophysiol. 2021 Mar;44(3):566-567. doi: 10.1111/pace.14176.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">33491814</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000638" MajorTopicYN="N">Amiodarone</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000889" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Arrhythmia Agents</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000008" MajorTopicYN="N">administration &amp; dosage</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="Y">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001281" MajorTopicYN="N">Atrial Fibrillation</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007262" MajorTopicYN="N">Infusions, Intravenous</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D014927" MajorTopicYN="N">Wolff-Parkinson-White Syndrome</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="Y">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">atrial fibrillation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intravenous amiodarone</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>20</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>29</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33118640</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pace.14113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Blomstrom-Lundqvist C, Scheinman MM, Aliot EM, et&#xa0;al. ACC/AHA/ESC guidelines for the management of patients with supraventricular arrhythmias-executive summary. a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on practice guidelines and the European Society of Cardiology Committee for practice guidelines (writing committee to develop guidelines for the management of patients with supraventricular arrhythmias) developed in collaboration with NASPE-Heart Rhythm Society. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2003;42(8):1493-1531.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Group JCSJW. Guidelines for pharmacotherapy of atrial fibrillation (JCS 2013). Circ J. 2014;78(8):1997-2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Etheridge SP, Escudero CA, Blaufox AD, et&#xa0;al. Life-threatening event risk in children with Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome: a multicenter international study. JACC Clin Electrophysiol. 2018;4(4):433-444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gemma LW, Steinberg LA, Prystowsky EN, Padanilam BJ. Development of rapid preexcited ventricular response to atrial fibrillation in a patient with intermittent preexcitation. J Cardiovasc Electrophysiol. 2013;24(3):347-350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein GJ, Bashore TM, Sellers TD, Pritchett EL, Smith WM, Gallagher JJ. Ventricular fibrillation in the Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. N Engl J Med. 1979;301(20):1080-1085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dreifus LS, Haiat R, Watanabe Y, Arriaga J, Reitman N. Ventricular fibrillation. A possible mechanism of sudden death in patients and Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. Circulation. 1971;43(4):520-527.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowey PR, Marinchak RA, Rials SJ, Filart RA. Intravenous amiodarone. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1997;29(6):1190-1198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kappenberger LJ, Fromer MA, Steinbrunn W, Shenasa M. Efficacy of amiodarone in the Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome with rapid ventricular response via accessory pathway during atrial fibrillation. Am J Cardiol. 1984;54(3):330-335.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schutzenberger W, Leisch F, Gmeiner R. Enhanced accessory pathway conduction following intravenous amiodarone in atrial fibrillation. A case report. Int J Cardiol. 1987;16(1):93-95.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boriani G, Biffi M, Frabetti L, et&#xa0;al. Ventricular fibrillation after intravenous amiodarone in Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome with atrial fibrillation. Am Heart J. 1996;131(6):1214-1216.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tijunelis MA, Herbert M. Intravenous amiodarone is safe in patients with atrial fibrillation and Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome in the emergency department. Can J Emerg Med 2005;7(4):262-265.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyo M, Hosokawa K, Ohshimo S, et&#xa0;al. High serum potassium level is associated with successful electrical cardioversion for new-onset atrial fibrillation in the intensive care unit: a retrospective observational study. Anaesth Intensive Care. 2019;47(1):52-59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheinman BD, Evans T. Acceleration of ventricular rate by fibrillation associated with the Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed). 1982;285(6347):999-1000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugada J, Katritsis DG, Arbelo E, et&#xa0;al. 2019 ESC guidelines for the management of patients with supraventricular tachycardia: The task force for the management of patients with supraventricular tachycardia of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J. 2019;41(5):655-720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellers TD, Campbell RW, Bashore TM, Gallagher JJ. Effects of procainamide and quinidine sulfate in the Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. Circulation. 1977;55(1):15-22.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sulke AN, Holt P, Sowton GE. Acceleration of conduction within an accessory pathway with propafenone. Int J Cardiol. 1990;28(1):105-107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Layman TE. Electrical cardioversion resulting in death from synchronization failure. Am J Cardiol. 1995;75(7):551.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adlam D, Azeem T. Ventricular fibrillation during electrical cardioversion of pre-excited atrial fibrillation. Postgrad Med J. 2003;79(931):297-299.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xavier LC, Memon A. Synchronized cardioversion of unstable supraventricular tachycardia resulting in ventricular fibrillation. Ann Emerg Med. 2004;44(2):178-180.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Connell M, Bernard A. A serious cause of panic attack. Case Rep Emerg Med. 2012;2012:1-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaufmann MR, McKillop MS, Burkart TA, Panna M, Conti JB, Miles WM. Iatrogenic ventricular fibrillation after direct-current cardioversion of preexcited atrial fibrillation caused by inadvertent T-Wave synchronization. Tex Heart Inst J. 2018;45(1):39-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danon A, Militianu A, Schliamser JE. Cardioversion of pre-excited atrial fibrillation leading to ventricular fibrillation- case report and review of literature. Am J Emerg Med. 2019;37(8):1539-1543.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pastor A, Almendral J, Ormaetxe J, et&#xa0;al. Ventricular fibrillation during treatment of atrial fibrillation with intravenous amiodarone in patients with the WPW syndrome [abstract]. Eur Heart J. 1993;14(suppl):294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellens HJ, Durrer D. Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome and atrial fibrillation. Relation between refractory period of accessory pathway and ventricular rate during atrial fibrillation. Am J Cardiol. 1974;34(7):777-782.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rakovec P, Cijan A, Kenda MF, Rode P, Jakopin J, Turk J. Failure of the refractory period of the accessory pathway to predict the ventricular rate during atrial fibrillation in Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. Int J Cardiol. 1982;1(3-4):329-330.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirchhof P, Benussi S, Kotecha D, et&#xa0;al. 2016 ESC guidelines for the management of atrial fibrillation developed in collaboration with EACTS. Europace. 2016;18(11):1609-1678.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nattel S, Talajic M, Quantz M, DeRoode M. Frequency-dependent effects of amiodarone on atrioventricular nodal function and slow-channel action potentials: evidence for calcium channel-blocking activity. Circulation. 1987;76(2):442-449.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montoya PT, Brugada P, Smeets J, et&#xa0;al. Ventricular fibrillation in the Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. Eur Heart J. 1991;12(2):144-150.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timmermans C, Smeets JL, Rodriguez LM, Vrouchos G, van den Dool A, Wellens HJ. Aborted sudden death in the Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. Am J Cardiol. 1995;76(7):492-494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein GJ, Yee R, Sharma AD. Longitudinal electrophysiologic assessment of asymptomatic patients with the Wolff-Parkinson-White electrocardiographic pattern. N Engl J Med. 1989;320(19):1229-1233.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bromberg BI, Lindsay BD, Cain ME, Cox JL. Impact of clinical history and electrophysiologic characterization of accessory pathways on management strategies to reduce sudden death among children with Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. J Am Coll Cardiol. 1996;27(3):690-695.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith WM, Gallagher JJ, Kerr CR, et&#xa0;al. The electrophysiologic basis and management of symptomatic recurrent tachycardia in patients with Ebstein's anomaly of the tricuspid valve. Am J Cardiol. 1982;49(5):1223-1234.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cushing DJ, Cooper WD, Gralinski MR, Lipicky RJ. The hypotensive effect of intravenous amiodarone is sustained throughout the maintenance infusion period. Clin Exp Pharmacol Physiol. 2010;37(3):358-361.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lindquist DE, Rowe AS, Heidel E, Fleming T, Yates JR. Evaluation of the hemodynamic effects of intravenous amiodarone formulations during the maintenance phase infusion. Ann Pharmacother. 2015;49(12):1317-1321.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chow MS. Intravenous amiodarone: pharmacology, pharmacokinetics, and clinical use. Ann Pharmacother. 1996;30(6):637-643.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faniel R, Schoenfeld P. Efficacy of i.v. amiodarone in converting rapid atrial fibrillation and flutter to sinus rhythm in intensive care patients. Eur Heart J. 1983;4(3):180-185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vietti-Ramus G, Veglio F, Marchisio U, Burzio P, Latini R. Efficacy and safety of short intravenous amiodarone in supraventricular tachyarrhythmias. Int J Cardiol. 1992;35(1):77-85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kuga K, Yamaguchi I, Sugishita Y. Effect of intravenous amiodarone on electrophysiologic variables and on the modes of termination of atrioventricular reciprocating tachycardia in Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. Jpn Circ J. 1999;63(3):189-195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wellens HJ, Brugada P, Abdollah H, Dassen WR. A comparison of the electrophysiologic effects of intravenous and oral amiodarone in the same patient. Circulation. 1984;69(1):120-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chait L, Mandel WJ. Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome: alterations in ventricular activation induced by changes in serum potassium. Chest. 1973;64(6):780-781.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sideris AM, Galiatsu E, Filippatos GS, Kappos K, Anthopoulos LP. Effects of magnesium and potassium on Wolff-Parkinson-White syndrome. J Electrocardiol. 1996;29(1):11-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwartz AB. Potassium-related cardiac arrhythmias and their treatment. Angiology. 1978;29(3):194-205.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tazmini K, Fraz MSA, Nymo SH, Stokke MK, Louch WE, Oie E. Potassium infusion increases the likelihood of conversion of recent-onset atrial fibrillation-A single-blinded, randomized clinical trial. Am Heart J. 2020;221:114-124.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brugada J, Katritsis DG, Arbelo E, et&#xa0;al. 2019 ESC guidelines for the management of patients with supraventricular tachycardia: the task force for the management of patients with supraventricular tachycardia of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J. 2020;41(5):655-720.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>