<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40046409</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2214-7829</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>39</Volume><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Internet interventions</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Internet Interv</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Influence of patient satisfaction, system usability, and working alliance on depressive symptom improvement in blended cognitive behavioral therapy (bCBT): Secondary analysis of an open trial data.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100815</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100815</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100815</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.invent.2025.100815</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Blended cognitive behavioral therapy (bCBT), which involves the use of a digital application to support face-to-face psychotherapy, is increasingly offered to patients with depression amid a growing body of research on its efficacy. However, there is still limited understanding of the factors that influence the efficacy of this novel treatment method. To investigate the effects of potential factors such as patient satisfaction with the received treatment, patients' self-rated working alliance with their therapist, and patients' rating of system usability of the digital application, this secondary analysis study focused on a sample of 66 university students who completed an effective 6-week bCBT program that included weekly sessions with a therapist and access to a digital mental health application. We examined whether those three potential factors predict patients' improvement in depressive symptoms in a bCBT treatment. Patient satisfaction and working alliance are known predictors of treatment success in standard psychotherapy, yet their importance in blended treatment is largely unstudied. System usability is a factor that is frequently addressed while describing digital treatment programs, yet its contribution to the success of treatments has been mostly omitted. All the variables analyzed displayed a significant positive correlation with improvement in depressive symptoms. When taken together, all the factors account for 16.6&#xa0;% of the variance in the outcome. However, when three variables were added in the backward multiple linear regression with stepwise elimination, only patient satisfaction emerged as a predictor of the outcome. Although there are significant correlations between working alliance and system usability and the improvement of depression in the bCBT program, their lack of predictive power in comparison to patient satisfaction renders the results inconclusive. Future studies could explore the potential contribution of additional variables to the improvement of depressive symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Atik</LastName><ForeName>Ece</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Translational Psychotherapy, Georg-Elias-Mueller-Institute of Psychology, University of Goettingen.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hornstein</LastName><ForeName>Silvan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, Humboldt-Universit&#xe4;t zu Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reinking</LastName><ForeName>Elisabeth</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Psychology and Neuroscience, University of Maastricht, Netherlands.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sch&#xfc;ckes</LastName><ForeName>Magnus</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute for SME Research and Entrepreneurship, University of Mannheim, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Internet Interv</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101631612</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2214-7829</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Blended cognitive behavioral therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Patient satisfaction</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">System usability</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Working alliance</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>This declaration addresses the manuscript titled &#x201c;Influence of system usability, working alliance and patient satisfaction on depressive symptom improvement in blended cognitive behavioral therapy (bCBT): Secondary analysis of an open trial data&#x201d;. Author EA declares that she is employed by Elona Health, the manufacturer of the elona therapy app used in this study. ER and SH are employed part-time by Elona Health. MS is a shareholder of Elona Health.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>40</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40046409</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11880594</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2025.100815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2214-7829(25)00016-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Andersson G. Internet-Delivered Psychological Treatments. Annu. Rev. Clin. Psychol. 2016;12:157&#x2013;179. doi: 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-021815-093006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-021815-093006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26652054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersson G., Paxling B., Wiwe M., Vernmark K., Felix C.B., Lundborg L., Furmark T., Cuijpers P., Carlbring P. Therapeutic alliance in guided internet-delivered cognitive behaviouraltreatment of depression, generalized anxiety disorder and social anxiety disorder. Behav. Res. Ther. 2012;50(9):544&#x2013;550. doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2012.05.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2012.05.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22728647</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asif S., Mudassar A., Shahzad T.Z., Raouf M., Pervaiz T. Frequency of depression, anxiety and stress among university students. Pakistan Journal of Medical Sciences. 2020;36(5):971&#x2013;976. doi: 10.12669/pjms.36.5.1873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12669/pjms.36.5.1873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7372668</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32704273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Askjer S., Mathiasen K. The working alliance in blended versus face-to-face cognitive therapy for depression: a secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. 2021;25 doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2021.100404.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2021.100404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8350587</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34401364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atik E., Stricker J., Sch&#xfc;ckes M., Pittig A. Efficacy of a brief blended cognitive behavioral therapy program for the treatment of depression and anxiety in university students: uncontrolled intervention study. JMIR Mental Health. 2023;10 doi: 10.2196/44742.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/44742</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10492172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37624631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Attkisson C.C., Zwick R. The client satisfaction questionnaire. Eval. Program Plann. 1982;5(3):233&#x2013;237. doi: 10.1016/0149-7189(82)90074-X.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0149-7189(82)90074-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10259963</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baier A.L., Kline A.C., Feeny N.C. Therapeutic alliance as a mediator of change: a systematic review and evaluation of research. Clin. Psychol. Rev. 2020;82 doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2020.101921.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2020.101921</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33069096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bastien J.M.C. Usability testing: a review of some methodological and technical aspects of the method. Int. J. Med. Inform. 2010;79(4):e18&#x2013;e23. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2008.12.004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2008.12.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19345139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baumeister S.E., Schomerus G., Schmidt C.O., M&#xf6;ckel F., van den Berg N., Hoffmann W., V&#xf6;lzke H., Grabe H.J. Change in depressive symptoms and mental health-related quality of life in Northeast Germany between 1997-2001 and 2008-2012. Int. J. Public Health. 2015;60(1):33&#x2013;39. doi: 10.1007/s00038-014-0632-0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00038-014-0632-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25500698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beck A.T., Steer R.A., Brown G.K. Psychological Corporation; 1996. Manual for the Beck Depression Inventory&#x2013;II.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beiter R., Nash R., McCrady M., Rhoades D., Linscomb M., Clarahan M., Sammut S. The prevalence and correlates of depression, anxiety, and stress in a sample of college students. J. Affect. Disord. 2015;173:90&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2014.10.054.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2014.10.054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25462401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berger T., Krieger T., Sude K., Meyer B., Maercker A. Evaluating an e-mental health program (&#x201c;deprexis&#x201d;) as adjunctive treatment tool in psychotherapy for depression: results of a pragmatic randomized controlled trial. J. Affect. Disord. 2018;227:455&#x2013;462. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2017.11.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29154168</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bergman Nordgren L., Carlbring P., Linna E., Andersson G. Role of the working Alliance on treatment outcome in tailored internet-based cognitive Behavioural therapy for anxiety disorders: randomized controlled pilot trial. JMIR Research Protocols. 2013;2(1) doi: 10.2196/resprot.2292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/resprot.2292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3628159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23612437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berryhill M.B., Culmer N., Williams N., Halli-Tierney A., Betancourt A., Roberts H., King M. Videoconferencing psychotherapy and depression: a systematic review. Telemedicine Journal and e-health: The Official Journal of the American Telemedicine Association. 2019;25(6):435&#x2013;446. doi: 10.1089/tmj.2018.0058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/tmj.2018.0058</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30048211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bielinski L.L., Bur O.T., W&#xe4;lchli G., Suter J.M., Walsh N., Kley M.A., Krieger T., Berger T. Two sides of the same coin? Patient and therapist experiences with a transdiagnostic blended intervention focusing on emotion regulation. Internet Interv. 2022;30 doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2022.100586.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2022.100586</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9663910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36386404</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bordin E.S. The generalizability of the psychoanalytic concept of the working alliance. Psychother.: Theory Res. Pract. 1979;16(3):252&#x2013;260. doi: 10.1037/h0085885.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/h0085885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braun P., Atik E., Guthardt L., Apolin&#xe1;rio-Hagen J., Sch&#xfc;ckes M. Barriers to and facilitators of a blended cognitive behavioral therapy program for depression and anxiety based on experiences of university students: qualitative interview study. JMIR Formative Research. 2023;7 doi: 10.2196/45970.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/45970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10134026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37043272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brooke J. In: Usability Evaluation in Industry. Jordan P.W., Thomas B., Weerdmeester B.A., McClelland A.L., editors. Taylor and Francis; 1996. SUS: A &#x201c;quick and dirty&#x201d; usability scale.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busch M.A., Maske U.E., Ryl L., Schlack R., Hapke U. Pr&#xe4;valenz von depressiver Symptomatik und diagnostizierter Depression bei Erwachsenen in Deutschland: Ergebnisse der Studie zur Gesundheit Erwachsener in Deutschland (DEGS1) [Prevalence of depressive symptoms and diagnosed depression among adults in Germany: results of the German Health Interview and Examination Survey for Adults (DEGS1)] Bundesgesundheitsbl. Gesundheitsforsch. Gesundheitsschutz. 2013;56(5&#x2013;6):733&#x2013;739. doi: 10.1007/s00103-013-1688-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00103-013-1688-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23703492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P., Kleiboer A., Karyotaki E., Riper H. Internet and mobile interventions for depression: opportunities and challenges. Depress. Anxiety. 2017;34(7):596&#x2013;602. doi: 10.1002/da.22641.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22641</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28471479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P., van Straten A., Andersson G. Internet-administered cognitive behavior therapy for health problems: a systematic review. J. Behav. Med. 2008;31(2):169&#x2013;177. doi: 10.1007/s10865-007-9144-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10865-007-9144-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2346512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18165893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dambi J.M., Mavhu W., Beji-Chauke R., Kaiyo-Utete M., Mills R., Shumba R., Muchemwa S., Musesengwa R., Verhey R., Abas M., Hirsch C.R., Chibanda D. The impact of working alliance in managing youth anxiety and depression: a scoping review. Npj Mental Health Research. 2023;2(1):1. doi: 10.1038/s44184-023-00021-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s44184-023-00021-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9885927</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37520938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doukani A., Free C., Michelson D., Araya R., Montero-Marin J., Smith S., Cerga-Pashoja A., Kakuma R. Towards a conceptual framework of the working alliance in a blended low-intensity cognitive behavioural therapy intervention for depression in primary mental health care: a qualitative study. BMJ Open. 2020;10(9) doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-036299.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-036299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7513595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32967872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doukani A., Quartagno M., Sera F., Free C., Kakuma R., Riper H., Kleiboer A., Cerga-Pashoja A., van Schaik A., Botella C., Berger T., Chevreul K., Matynia M., Krieger T., Hazo J.B., Draisma S., Titzler I., Topooco N., Mathiasen K., Vernmark K., Araya R. Comparison of the working Alliance in blended cognitive behavioral therapy and treatment as usual for depression in Europe: secondary data analysis of the E-COMPARED randomized controlled trial. J. Med. Internet Res. 2024;26 doi: 10.2196/47515.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/47515</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11179025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38819882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doyle C., Lennox L., Bell D. A systematic review of evidence on the links between patient experience and clinical safety and effectiveness. BMJ Open. 2013;3(1) doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2012-001570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2012-001570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3549241</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23293244</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubina M.I., O&#x2019;Neill J.L., Feldman S.R. Effect of patient satisfaction on outcomes of care. Expert Rev. Pharmacoecon. Outcomes Res. 2009;9(5):393&#x2013;395. doi: 10.1586/erp.09.45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1586/erp.09.45</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19817520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert D.D., Berking M., Thiart H., Riper H., Laferton J.A.C., Cuijpers P., Sieland B., Lehr D. Restoring depleted resources: efficacy and mechanisms of change of an internet-based unguided recovery training for better sleep and psychological detachment from work. Health Psychol. 2015;34S:1240&#x2013;1251. doi: 10.1037/hea0000277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/hea0000277</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26651465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erbe D., Eichert H.-C., Riper H., Ebert D.D. Blending face-to-face and internet-based interventions for the treatment of mental disorders in adults: systematic review. J. Med. Internet Res. 2017;19(9) doi: 10.2196/jmir.6588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.6588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5622288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28916506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fl&#xfc;ckiger C., Del Re A.C., Wampold B.E., Horvath A.O. The alliance in adult psychotherapy: a meta-analytic synthesis. Psychotherapy. 2018;55(4):316&#x2013;340. doi: 10.1037/pst0000172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pst0000172</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29792475</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forand N.R., Feinberg J.E., Barnett J.G., Strunk D.R. Guided internet CBT versus &#x201c;gold standard&#x201d; depression treatments: an individual patient analysis. J. Clin. Psychol. 2019;75(4):581&#x2013;593. doi: 10.1002/jclp.22733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.22733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30597551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedrich M.J. Depression is the leading cause of disability around the world. JAMA. 2017;317(15):1517. doi: 10.1001/jama.2017.3826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.3826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28418490</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuertes J.N., Boylan L.S., Fontanella J.A. Behavioral indices in medical care outcome: the working Alliance, adherence, and related factors. J. Gen. Intern. Med. 2009;24(1):80&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1007/s11606-008-0841-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11606-008-0841-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2607493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18972089</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gao, M., Kortum, P., &amp; Oswald, F. L. (2020). Multi-language toolkit for the system usability scale. <i>International Journal of Human&#x2013;Computer Interaction</i>, 36(20), 1883&#x2013;1901. doi: 10.1080/10447318.2020.1801173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10447318.2020.1801173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatcher R.L., Gillaspy J.A. Development and validation of a revised short version of the working alliance inventory. Psychother. Res. 2006;16(1):12&#x2013;25. doi: 10.1080/10503300500352500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10503300500352500</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haug T., Nordgreen T., &#xd6;st L.G., Kvale G., Tangen T., Andersson G., Carlbring P., Heiervang E.R., Havik O.E. Stepped care versus face-to-face cognitive behavior therapy for panic disorder and social anxiety disorder: predictors and moderators of outcome. Behav. Res. Ther. 2015;71:76&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2015.06.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2015.06.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26081010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hentati A., Forsell E., Lj&#xf3;tsson B., Kaldo V., Lindefors N., Kraepelien M. The effect of user interface on treatment engagement in a self-guided digital problem-solving intervention: a randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. 2021;26 doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2021.100448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2021.100448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8387893</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34471610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hocking R.R. The analysis and selection of variables in linear regression. Biometrics. 1976;32</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobi F., Wittchen H.-U., Holting C., H&#xf6;fler M., Pfister H., M&#xfc;ller N., Lieb R. Prevalence, co-morbidity and correlates of mental disorders in the general population: results from the German health interview and examination survey (GHS) Psychol. Med. 2004;34(4):597&#x2013;611. doi: 10.1017/S0033291703001399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291703001399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15099415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaspers M.W.M. A comparison of usability methods for testing interactive health technologies: methodological aspects and empirical evidence. Int. J. Med. Inform. 2009;78(5):340&#x2013;353. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2008.10.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2008.10.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19046928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Karyotaki E., Klein A.M., Ciharova M., Bolinski F., Krijnen L., de Koning L., de Wit L., van der Heijde C.M., Ebert D.D., Riper H., Batelaan N., Vonk P., Auerbach R.P., Kessler R.C., Bruffaerts R., Struijs S., Wiers R.W., Cuijpers P. Guided internet-based transdiagnostic individually tailored cognitive behavioral therapy for symptoms of depression and/or anxiety in college students: a randomized controlled trial. Behav. Res. Ther. 2022;150 doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2021.104028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2021.104028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35066365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelley J.M., Kraft-Todd G., Schapira L., Kossowsky J., Riess H. The influence of the patient-clinician relationship on healthcare outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. PLoS One. 2014;9(4) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0094207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0094207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3981763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24718585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kemmeren L.L., van Schaik D.J.F., Riper H., Kleiboer A.M., Bosmans J.E., Smit J.H. Effectiveness of blended depression treatment for adults in specialised mental healthcare: study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. BMC Psychiatry. 2016;16(1):113. doi: 10.1186/s12888-016-0818-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-016-0818-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4839153</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27102812</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein A.A., Slaymaker V.J., Dugosh K.L., McKay J.R. Computerized continuing care support for alcohol and drug dependence: a preliminary analysis of usage and outcomes. J. Subst. Abus. Treat. 2012;42(1):25&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2011.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2011.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6498848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein J.P., Berger T., Schr&#xf6;der J., Sp&#xe4;th C., Meyer B., Caspar F., Lutz W., Arndt A., Greiner W., Gr&#xe4;fe V., Hautzinger M., Fuhr K., Rose M., Nolte S., L&#xf6;we B., Andersson G., Vettorazzi E., Moritz S., Hohagen F. Effects of a psychological internet intervention in the treatment of mild to moderate depressive symptoms: results of the EVIDENT study, a randomized controlled trial. Psychother. Psychosom. 2016;85(4):218&#x2013;228. doi: 10.1159/000445355.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000445355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8117387</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27230863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooistra L.C., Ruwaard J., Wiersma J.E., van Oppen P., van der Vaart R., van Gemert-Pijnen J.E.W.C., Riper H. Development and initial evaluation of blended cognitive behavioural treatment for major depression in routine specialized mental health care. Internet Interv. 2016;4:61&#x2013;71. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2016.01.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2016.01.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135791</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kooistra L.C., Wiersma J.E., Ruwaard J., Neijenhuijs K., Lokkerbol J., van Oppen P., Smit F., Riper H. Cost and effectiveness of blended versus standard cognitive behavioral therapy for outpatients with depression in routine specialized mental health care: pilot randomized controlled trial. J. Med. Internet Res. 2019;21(10) doi: 10.2196/14261.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/14261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6914243</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31663855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kroenke K., Spitzer R.L. The PHQ-9: a new depression diagnostic and severity measure. Psychiatr. Ann. 2002;32(9):509&#x2013;515. doi: 10.3928/0048-5713-20020901-06.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3928/0048-5713-20020901-06</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xfc;hner C., B&#xfc;rger C., Keller F., Hautzinger M. Reliabilit&#xe4;t und Validit&#xe4;t des revidierten Beck-Depressionsinventars (BDI-II): Befunde aus deutschsprachigen Stichproben. Nervenarzt. 2007;78(6):651&#x2013;656. doi: 10.1007/s00115-006-2098-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00115-006-2098-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16832698</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert M.J., Barley D.E. Research summary on the therapeutic relationship and psychotherapy outcome. Psychotherapy: theory, research, practice. Training. 2001;38(4):357&#x2013;361. doi: 10.1037/0033-3204.38.4.357.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-3204.38.4.357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ly K.H., Topooco N., Cederlund H., Wallin A., Bergstr&#xf6;m J., Molander O., Carlbring P., Andersson G. Smartphone-supported versus full Behavioural activation for depression: a randomised controlled trial. PLoS One. 2015;10(5) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0126559.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0126559</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4444307</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26010890</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xe5;nsson K.N., Skagius Ruiz E., Gervind E., Dahlin M., Andersson G. Development and initial evaluation of an internet-based support system for face-to-face cognitive behavior therapy: a proof of concept study. J. Med. Internet Res. 2013;15(12) doi: 10.2196/jmir.3031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3868964</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24326065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maramba I., Chatterjee A., Newman C. Methods of usability testing in the development of eHealth applications: a scoping review. Int. J. Med. Inform. 2019;126:95&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2019.03.018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijmedinf.2019.03.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31029270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mol M., van Schaik A., Dozeman E., Ruwaard J., Vis C., Ebert D.D., Etzelmueller A., Mathiasen K., Moles B., Mora T., Pedersen C.D., Skj&#xf8;th M.M., Pensado L.P., Piera-Jimenez J., Gokcay D., Ince B.&#xdc;., Russi A., Sacco Y., Zanalda E., Smit J.H. Dimensionality of the system usability scale among professionals using internet-based interventions for depression: a confirmatory factor analysis. BMC Psychiatry. 2020;20(1):218. doi: 10.1186/s12888-020-02627-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-020-02627-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7216472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32398111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neter J., Wasserman W., Kutner M.H. Irwin; Chicago: 1996. Applied Linear Statistical Models.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel S., Akhtar A., Malins S., Wright N., Rowley E., Young E., Sampson S., Morriss R. The acceptability and usability of digital health interventions for adults with depression, anxiety, and somatoform disorders: qualitative systematic review and Meta-synthesis. J. Med. Internet Res. 2020;22(7) doi: 10.2196/16228.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/16228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Philippe T.J., Sikder N., Jackson A., Koblanski M.E., Liow E., Pilarinos A., Vasarhelyi K. Digital health interventions for delivery of mental health care: systematic and comprehensive Meta-review. JMIR Mental Health. 2022;9(5) doi: 10.2196/35159.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/35159</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9109782</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35551058</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash B. Patient satisfaction. J Cutan Aesthet Surg. 2010;3(3):151. doi: 10.4103/0974-2077.74491.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0974-2077.74491</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3047732</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21430827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Romijn G., Batelaan N., Koning J., van Balkom A., de Leeuw A., Benning F., Hakkaart van Roijen L., Riper H. Acceptability, effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of blended cognitive-behavioural therapy (bCBT) versus face-to-face CBT (ftfCBT) for anxiety disorders in specialised mental health care: a 15-week randomised controlled trial with 1-year follow-up. PLoS One. 2021;16(11) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0259493.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0259493</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8589191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34767575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental A., Boettcher J., Andersson G., Schmidt B., Carlbring P. Negative effects of internet interventions: a qualitative content analysis of patients&#x2019; experiences with treatments delivered online. Cogn. Behav. Ther. 2015;44(3):223&#x2013;236. doi: 10.1080/16506073.2015.1008033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2015.1008033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25705924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmidt J., Lamprecht F., Wittmann W.W. Zufriedenheit mit der station&#xe4;ren Versorgung. Entwicklung eines Fragebogens und erste Validit&#xe4;tsuntersuchungen [satisfaction with inpatient care: development of a questionnaire and first validity assessments]. PPmP. Psychother. Psychosom. Med. Psychol. 1989;39(7):248&#x2013;255.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2762479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schneider F., Erhart M., Hewer W., Loeffler L.A., Jacobi F. Mortality and medical comorbidity in the severely mentally ill. Deutsches Arzteblatt international. 2019;116(23&#x2013;24):405&#x2013;411. doi: 10.3238/arztebl.2019.0405.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3238/arztebl.2019.0405</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6683445</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31366432</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schuster R., Laireiter A.R., Berger T., Moritz S., Meyer B., Hohagen F., Klein J.P. Immediate and long-term effectiveness of adding an internet intervention for depression to routine outpatient psychotherapy: subgroup analysis of the EVIDENT trial. J. Affect. Disord. 2020;274:643&#x2013;651. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2020.05.122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2020.05.122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663998</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shay L.A., Dumenci L., Siminoff L.A., Flocke S.A., Lafata J.E. Factors associated with patient reports of positive physician relational communication. Patient Educ. Couns. 2012;89(1):96&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1016/j.pec.2012.04.003.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pec.2012.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3431455</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22554386</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Step M.M., Rose J.H., Albert J.M., Cheruvu V.K., Siminoff L.A. Modeling patient-centered communication: oncologist relational communication and patient communication involvement in breast cancer adjuvant therapy decision-making. Patient Educ. Couns. 2009;77(3):369&#x2013;378. doi: 10.1016/j.pec.2009.09.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pec.2009.09.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2787652</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19811883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thase M.E., Wright J.H., Eells T.D., Barrett M.S., Wisniewski S.R., Balasubramani G.K., McCrone P., Brown G.K. Improving the efficiency of psychotherapy for depression: computer-assisted versus standard CBT. Am. J. Psychiatry. 2018;175(3):242&#x2013;250. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2017.17010089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2017.17010089</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5848497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28969439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Titzler I., Saruhanjan K., Berking M., Riper H., Ebert D.D. Barriers and facilitators for the implementation of blended psychotherapy for depression: a qualitative pilot study of therapists&#x2019; perspective. Internet Interv. 2018;12:150&#x2013;164. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2018.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uysal B., Morg&#xfc;l E., Ta&#x15f;tekne F., S&#xf6;nmez D., Tepedelen M.S., G&#xfc;lay S., Eskio&#x11f;lu Ayd&#x131;n I., Evecek H., Gormez V. Videoconferencing-based cognitive behavioral therapy for youth with anxiety and depression during COVID-19 pandemic. Sch. Psychol. Int. 2022;43(4):420&#x2013;439. doi: 10.1177/01430343221097613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/01430343221097613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9096007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38603261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vernmark K., Hesser H., Topooco N., Berger T., Riper H., Luuk L., Backlund L., Carlbring P., Andersson G. Working alliance as a predictor of change in depression during blended cognitive behaviour therapy. Cogn. Behav. Ther. 2019;48(4):285&#x2013;299. doi: 10.1080/16506073.2018.1533577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2018.1533577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30372653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waller R., Gilbody S. Barriers to the uptake of computerized cognitive behavioural therapy: a systematic review of the quantitative and qualitative evidence. Psychol. Med. 2009;39(5):705&#x2013;712. doi: 10.1017/S0033291708004224.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291708004224</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18812006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wentzel J., van der Vaart R., Bohlmeijer E.T., van Gemert-Pijnen J.E. Mixing online and face-to-face therapy: how to benefit from blended Care in Mental Health Care. JMIR mental health. 2016;3(1) doi: 10.2196/mental.4534.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mental.4534</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4764785</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26860537</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilmers F., Munder T., Leonhart R., Herzog T., Plassmann R., Barth J., Linster H.W. Die deutschsprachige version des working Alliance inventory &#x2013; short revised (WAI-SR) &#x2013; Ein schulen&#xfc;bergreifendes, &#xf6;konomisches und empirisch validiertes instrument zur Erfassung der therapeutischen Allianz [the German version of the working Alliance inventory &#x2013; short revised (WAI-SR) &#x2013; a pantheoretic, economic, and empirically validated instrument to assess the therapeutic alliance] Klinische Diagnostik Und Evaluation. 2008;1(3):343&#x2013;358.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wright J.H., Mishkind M., Eells T.D., Chan S.R. Computer-Assisted Cognitive-Behavior Therapy and Mobile Apps for Depression and Anxiety. Curr. Psychiatry Rep. 2019;21(7):62. doi: 10.1007/s11920-019-1031-2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11920-019-1031-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31250242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>