<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">30416995</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2296-2646</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>6</Volume><PubDate><Year>2018</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Frontiers in chemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Front Chem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Wavelet Transform-Based UV Spectroscopy for Pharmaceutical Analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>503</StartPage><MedlinePgn>503</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">503</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fchem.2018.00503</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In research and development laboratories, chemical or pharmaceutical analysis has been carried out by evaluating sample signals obtained from instruments. However, the qualitative and quantitative determination based on raw signals may not be always possible due to sample complexity. In such cases, there is a need for powerful signal processing methodologies that can effectively process raw signals to get correct results. Wavelet transform is one of the most indispensable and popular signal processing methods currently used for noise removal, background correction, differentiation, data smoothing and filtering, data compression and separation of overlapping signals etc. This review article describes the theoretical aspects of wavelet transform (i.e., discrete, continuous and fractional) and its characteristic applications in UV spectroscopic analysis of pharmaceuticals.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Din&#xe7;</LastName><ForeName>Erdal</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Analytical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Ankara University, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yazan</LastName><ForeName>Zehra</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Ankara University Faculty of Science, Ankara, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Switzerland</Country><MedlineTA>Front Chem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101627988</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2296-2646</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">UV spectroscopy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">continuous wavelet transform</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">discrete wavelet transform</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fractional wavelet transform</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmaceutical analysis</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>27</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2018</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30416995</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6212466</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fchem.2018.00503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aballe A., Bethencourt M., Botana F. J., Marcos M. (1999). Using wavelet transform in the analysis of electrochemical noise data. Electrochim. Acta 44, 4805&#x2013;4816. 10.1016/S0013-4686(99)00222-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0013-4686(99)00222-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alsberg B. K., Woodward A. M., Kell D. B. (1997). An introduction to wavelet transform for chemometricians: a time-frequency approach. Chemom. Intell. Lab. Syst. 37, 215&#x2013;239. 10.1016/S0169-7439(97)00029-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-7439(97)00029-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barache D., Antoine J. P., Dereppe J. M. (1997). The continuous wavelet transform, an analysis tool for NMR spectroscopy. J. Magn. Reson. 128, 1&#x2013;11. 10.1006/jmre.1997.1214</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/jmre.1997.1214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barclay V. J., Bonner R. F., Hamilton I. P. (1997). Application of wavelet transforms to experimental spectra: smoothing, denoising, and data set compression. Anal. Chem. 69, 78&#x2013;90. 10.1021/ac960638m</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ac960638m</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berzas Nevado J. J., Guiberteau Cabanillas C., Salinas F. (1992). Spectrophotometric resolution of ternary mixtures of salicylaldehyde, 3-hydroxybenzaldehyde and 4-hydroxybenzaldehyde by the derivative ratio spectrum-zero crossing method. Talanta 39, 547&#x2013;553. 10.1016/0039-9140(92)80179-H</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0039-9140(92)80179-H</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18965415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blu T., Unser M. (2000). The fractional spline wavelet transform: definition and implementation, in Proceedings of the Twenty-Fifth IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP'00) (Istanbul: ), 512&#x2013;515.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blu T., Unser M. (2002). Wavelets, fractals, and radial basis functions. IEEE Trans. Signal Process. 50, 543&#x2013;553. 10.1109/78.984733</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/78.984733</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brereton R. G. (2003). Data Analysis for the Laboratory and Chemical Plant. New York, NY: Wiley; &amp; Sons, Inc., 167.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brereton R. G. (2008). Applied Chemometrics for Scientists. John-Wiley; &amp; sons Ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown S., Blank T. B., Sum S. T., Weyer L. G. (1994). Chemometrics. Anal. Chem. 66, 315R&#x2212;359R. 10.1021/ac00084a014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ac00084a014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8092471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown S., Sum S. T., Despagne F. (1996). Chemometrics. Anal. Chem. 68, 21R&#x2212;62R. 10.1021/a1960005x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/a1960005x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Byrnes J. S., Byrnes J. L., Hargreaves K. A., Berry K. (1994). Wavelet and Their Application. Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cai W. S., Wang L. Y., Pan Z. X., Zuo J., Xu C. Y., Shao X. G. (2001). Application of the wavelet transform method in quantitative analysis of raman spectra. J. Raman Spectrosc. 32, 207&#x2013;209. 10.1002/jrs.688</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jrs.688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc7;elebier M., Altin&#xf6;z S., Din&#xe7; E. (2010). Fractional wavelet transform and chemometric calibrations for the simultaneous determination of amlodipine and valsartan in their complex mixture, in New Trends in Nanotechnology and Fractional Calculus, eds Baleanu D., G&#xfc;ven&#xe7; Z. B., Tenreiro Machado J. A. (Dordrecht; Heidelberg; London; New York, NY: Springer; ), 333&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chalus P., Walter S., Ulmschneider M. (2007). Combined wavelet transform&#x2013;artificial neural network use in tablet active content determination by near-infrared spectroscopy. Anal. Chim. Acta 591, 219&#x2013;224. 10.1016/j.aca.2007.03.076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aca.2007.03.076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17481412</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlotte Grinter H., Threlfall T. L. (1992). UV-VIS Spectroscopy and its Applications. Berlin; Heidelberg; New York, NY: Springer-Verlag.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chau F., Yi-Zeng L., Junbin G., Xue-Guang S., James D.W. (2004). Chemometrics, from Basics to Wavelet Transform 1st Edn. Hoboken, NJ: Wiley-Interscience.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen J., Zhong H. B., Pan Z. X., Zhang M. S. (1996). Application of the wavelet transform in differential pulse voltammetric data processing. Chin. J. Anal. Chem. 24, 1002&#x2013;1006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chui C. K. (1992). An Introduction to Wavelets. New York, NY: Academic Press. 49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chui C. K., Montefusco L., Puccio L. (1994). Wavelets: Theory, Algorithms and Applications. San Diego, CA: Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chun-Lin L. (2010). A Tutorial of the Wavelet Transform. Available online at: http://disp.ee.ntu.edu.tw/tutorial/WaveletTutorial.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cooper J. W. (1978). Chapter: Data handling in fourier transform spectroscopy, in Transform Techniques in Chemistry, ed Griffiths P. R. (New York, NY: Plenum Press; ), 4, 69&#x2013;108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danzer K. (2007). Analytical Chemistry. Theoretical and Metrological Fundamentals. Berlin; New York, NY: Springer.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darwish H. W., Metwally F. H., El.Bayoumi A. (2014). Application of continous wavelet transform for derivative spectrophotometric determination of binary mixture in pharmaceutical dosage form. Dig. J. Nanomater. Biostruct. 9, 7&#x2013;18.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daubechies I. (1992). Ten Lectures on Wavelets, Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics. Philadelphia, PA.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Depczynski U., Jetter K., Molt K., Niemoller A. (1997). The fast wavelet transform on compact intervals as a tool in chemometrics. I. Mathematical background. Chem. Intell. Lab. Syst. 39, 19&#x2013;27. 10.1016/S0169-7439(97)00068-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-7439(97)00068-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devrim B., Din&#xe7; E., Bozkir A. (2014). Fast determination of diphenhydramine hydrochloride in reconstituted table syrups by CWT, PLS and PCR methods. Acta Pol. Pharm. 71, 721&#x2013;729.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25362800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E. (1999). The spectrophotometric multicomponent analysis of a ternary mixture of ascorbic acid, acetylsalicylic acid and paracetamol by the double divisor-ratio spectra derivative and ratio spectra-zero crossing methods. Talanta 48, 1145&#x2013;1157. 10.1016/S0039-9140(98)00337-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0039-9140(98)00337-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18967559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E. (2013). Wavelet transforms and applications in drug analysis, FABAD J. Pharm. Sci. 38, 159&#x2013;165.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Arslan F., Baleanu D. (2009a). Alternative approaches to the spectral quantitative resolution of two-component mixture by wavelet families. J. Chil. Chem. Soc. 54, 28&#x2013;35. 10.4067/S0717-97072009000100007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4067/S0717-97072009000100007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2003a). Multidetermination of thiamine HCl and pyridoxine HCl in their mixture using continuous daubechies and biorthogonal wavelet analysis. Talanta 59, 707&#x2013;717. 10.1016/S0039-9140(02)00611-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0039-9140(02)00611-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18968959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2003b). A zero-crossing technique for the multidetermination of thiamine HCl and pyridoxine HCl in their mixture by using one-dimensional wavelet transform. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 31, 969&#x2013;978. 10.1016/S0731-7085(02)00705-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0731-7085(02)00705-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12684109</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2004a). Multicomponent quantitative resolution of binary mixtures using continuous wavelet transform. J. AOAC Int. 87, 360&#x2013;365.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15164828</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2004b). Application of the wavelet method for the simultaneous quantitative determination of benazepril and hydrochlorothiazide in their mixtures. J. AOAC Int. 87, 834&#x2013;841.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15295876</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2004c). One-dimension continuous wavelet resolution for the simultaneous analysis of binary mixture of benazepril and hydrochlorothiazide in tablets using spectrophotometric absorbance data. Rev. Roum. Chim. 49, 917&#x2013;925.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2006). A new fractional wavelet approach for the simultaneous determination of ampicillin sodium and sulbactam sodium in a binary mixture. Spectrochim. Acta Part A 63, 631&#x2013;638. 10.1016/j.saa.2005.06.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.saa.2005.06.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16024281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2007a). Continuous wavelet transform and chemometric methods for quantitative resolution of a binary mixture of quinapril and hydrochlorothiazide in tablets. J. Braz. Chem. Soc. 18, 962&#x2013;968. 10.1590/S0103-50532007000500013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0103-50532007000500013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2007b). A review on the wavelet transforms applications in analytical chemistry, in Mathematical Methods in Engineering, eds Ta&#x15f; K., Tenreiro Machado J. A., Balanu D. (Dordrecht: Springer; ), 265&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2007c). Continuous wavelet transform applied to the overlapping absorption signals and their ratio signals for the quantitative resolution of mixture of oxfendazole and oxyclozanide in bolus. J. Food Drug Anal. 15, 109&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2008a). Application of haar and mexican hat wavelets to double divisor-ratio Spectra for the multicomponent determination of ascorbic acid, acetylsalicylic acid and paracetamol in effervescent tablets. J. Braz. Chem. Soc. 19, 434&#x2013;444. 10.1590/S0103-50532008000300010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0103-50532008000300010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2008b). Ratio spectra-continuous wavelet transform and ratio spectra-derivative spectrophotometry for the quantitative analysis of effervescent tablets of vitamin C and aspirin. Rev. Chim. (Bucuresti) 59, 499&#x2013;504.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2009a). Continuous wavelet transform applied to the quantitative analysis of a binary mixture. Rev. Chim. (Bucuresti) 60, 216&#x2013;221.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2009b). Spectral continuous wavelet transform for the simultaneous spectrophotometric analysis of a combined pharmaceutical formulation. Rev. Chim. 60, 741&#x2013;744.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2010a). Continuous wavelet transform applied to the simultaneous spectrophotometric determination of valsartan and amlodipine in tablets. Rev. Chim. 61, 290&#x2013;294.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2010b). Fractional wavelet transform for the quantitative spectral resolution of the composite signals of the active compounds in a two-component mixture. Comput. Math. Appl. 59, 1701&#x2013;1708. 10.1016/j.camwa.2009.08.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.camwa.2009.08.012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2012). Fractional-continuous wavelet transforms and ultra-performance liquid chromatography for the multicomponent analysis of a ternary mixture containing thiamine, pyridoxine, and lidocaine in ampules. J. AOAC Int. 95, 903&#x2013;912. 10.5740/jaoacint.11-199</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5740/jaoacint.11-199</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22816281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., Abaul-Enein H. Y. (2004a). Wavelet analysis for the multicomponent determination in a binary mixture of caffeine and propyphenazone in tablets. IL Farmaco 59, 335&#x2013;342. 10.1016/j.farmac.2004.01.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.farmac.2004.01.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15081352</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., Ioele G., De Luca M., Ragno G. (2008). Multivariate analysis of paracetamol, propyphenazone, caffeine and thiamine in quaternary mixtures by PCR, PLS and ANN calibrations applied on wavelet transform data. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 48, 1471&#x2013;1475. 10.1016/j.jpba.2008.09.035</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2008.09.035</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18990522</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., Kanbur M. (2005c). A comparative application of wavelet approaches to the absorption and ratio spectra for the simultaneous determination of diminazene aceturate and phenazone in veterinary granules for injection. Pharmazie 60, 892&#x2013;896.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16398263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., Ta&#x15f; A. (2006b). Wavelet transforms and artificial neural network for the quantitative resolution of ternary mixtures. Rev. Chim. 57, 626&#x2013;631.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., Ta&#x15f; K. (2007a). Continuous wavelet analysis for the ratio signals of the absorption spectra of binary mixtures, in Mathematical Methods Engineering, ed Ta&#x15f; K., Tenreiro Machado J. A., Baleanu D. (Dordrecht: Springer; ), 285&#x2013;293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., Ta&#x15f; K. (2007b). Fractional wavelet analysis for the composite signals of two-component mixture by multivariate spectral calibration. J. Vib. Control 13, 1283&#x2013;1290. 10.1177/1077546307077464</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077546307077464</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., &#xdc;st&#xfc;ndag &#xd6;. (2003). An approach to quantitative two-component analysis of a mixture containing hydrochlorothiazide and spironolactone in tablets by one-dimensional continuous daubechies and biorthogonal wavelet analysis of UV-spectra, Spectros. Lett. 36, 341&#x2013;355. 10.1081/SL-120024583</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1081/SL-120024583</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., &#xdc;st&#xfc;ndag &#xd6;., Abaul-Enein H. Y. (2004c). Continuous wavelet transformation applied to the simultaneous quantitative analysis of two&#x2013;component mixtures. Pharmazie 59, 618&#x2013;623.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15378851</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., B&#xfc;ker E., Baleanu D. (2011a). Fractional and continuous wavelet transforms for the simultaneous spectral analysis of a binary mixture system. Commun. Nonlinear Sci. Numer. Simul. 16, 4602&#x2013;4609. 10.1016/j.cnsns.2011.02.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cnsns.2011.02.018</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Demirkaya F., Baleanu D., Kadioglu Y., Kadioglu E. (2010). New approach for simultaneous spectral analysis of a complex mixture using the fractional wavelet transform. Commun. Nonlinear Sci. Numer. Simul. 15, 812&#x2013;818. 10.1016/j.cnsns.2009.05.021</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cnsns.2009.05.021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Duarte F. B., Tenreiro Machado J. A., Baleanu D. (2015). Application of continuous wavelet transform to the analysis of the modulus of the fractional fourier transform bands for resolving two component mixture. Signal Image Video P. 9, 801&#x2013;807. 10.1007/s11760-013-0503-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11760-013-0503-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Kadioglu Y., Demirkaya F., Baleanu D. (2011b). Continuous wavelet transforms for simultaneous spectral determination of trimethoprim and sulphamethoxazole in tablets. J. Iran. Chem. Soc. 8, 90&#x2013;99. 10.1007/BF03246205</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF03246205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Kanbur M., Baleanu D. (2007c). Comparative spectral analysis of veterinary powder product by continuous wavelet and derivative transforms. Spectrochim. Acta Part A. 68, 225&#x2013;230. 10.1016/j.saa.2006.11.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.saa.2006.11.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17320471</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Ka&#x15f; F., Baleanu D. (2013a). A signal processing tool based on the continuous wavelet for the simultaneous determination of estradiol valerate and cyproterone acetate in their mixtures. Rev. Chim. 64, 124&#x2013;126.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Kaya S., Doganay D., Baleanu D. (2007d). Continuous wavelet and derivative transforms for the simultaneous quantitative analysis and dissolution test of levodopa-benserazide tablets. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 44, 991&#x2013;995. 10.1016/j.jpba.2007.03.027</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2007.03.027</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17512691</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Onur F. (1998). Application of a new spectrophotometric method for the analysis of a ternary mixture containing metamizol, paracetamol and caffeine in tablets. Anal. Chim. Acta 359, 93&#x2013;106. 10.1016/S0003-2670(97)00615-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0003-2670(97)00615-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., &#xd6;zdemir A., Baleanu D. (2005a). An application of derivative and continuous wavelet transforms to the overlapping ratio spectra for the quantitative multiresolution of a ternary mixture of paracetamol, acetylsalicylic acid and caffeine in tablets. Talanta 65, 36&#x2013;47. 10.1016/j.talanta.2004.05.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.talanta.2004.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18969761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., &#xd6;zdemir A., Baleanu D. (2005b). Comparative study of the continuous wavelet transform, derivative and partial least squares methods applied to the overlapping spectra for the simultaneous quantitative resolution of ascorbic acid and acetylsalicylic acid in effervescent tablets. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 37, 569&#x2013;575. 10.1016/j.jpba.2004.11.020</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2004.11.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15740918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., &#xd6;zdemir A., Baleanu D., Ta&#x15f; K. (2006a). Wavelet transform with chemometrics techniques for quantitative multiresolution analysis of a ternary mixture consisting of paracetamol, ascorbic acid and acetylsalicylic acid in effervescent tablets. Rev. Chim. (Bucharest) 57, 505&#x2013;510.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., &#xd6;zdemir N., &#xdc;st&#xfc;ndag &#xd6;., G&#xfc;nseli Tilkan M. (2013b). Continuous wavelet transforms for the simultaneous quantitative analysis and dissolution testing of lamivudine&#x2013;zidovudine tablets. Chem. Pharm. Bull. 61, 1220&#x2013;1227. 10.1248/cpb.c13-00284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1248/cpb.c13-00284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24292784</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Pekta&#x15f; G., Baleanu D. (2009b). Continuous wavelet transform and derivative spectrophotometry for the quantitative spectral resolution of a mixture containing levamizole and triclabendazole in veterinary tablets. Rev. Anal. Chem. 28, 79&#x2013;92. 10.1515/REVAC.2009.28.2.79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/REVAC.2009.28.2.79</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Ragno G., Baleanu D., De Luca M., Ioele G. (2012). Fractional wavelet transform-continuous wavelet transform for the quantification of melatonin and its photodegradation product. Spectrosc. Lett. 45, 337&#x2013;343. 10.1080/00387010.2012.666699</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00387010.2012.666699</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Ragno G., Ioele G., Baleanu D. (2006c). Fractional wavelet analysis for the simultaneous quantitative analysis of lacidipine and its photodegradation product by continuous wavelet transform and multilinear regression calibration. JAOAC Int. 89, 1538&#x2013;1546.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17225599</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Sayge&#xe7;itli E., Ertekin Z. C. (2017b). Simultaneous determination of atenolol and chlorthalidone in tablets by wavelet transform methods. FABAD J. Pharm. Sci. 42, 103&#x2013;109.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., &#xdc;st&#xfc;nda&#x1e7; &#xd6;., Y&#xfc;ksel Tilkan G., T&#xfc;rkmen B., &#xd6;zdemir N. (2017a). Continuous wavelet transform methods for the simultaneous determinations and dissolution profiles of valsartan and hydrochlorothiazide in tablets. Braz. J. Pharm. Sci. 53:e16050 10.1590/s2175-97902017000116050</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/s2175-97902017000116050</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D., Kanbur M. (2004b). Spectrophotometric multicomponent determination of tetramethrin, propoxur and piperonyl butoxide in insecticide formulation by principal component regression and partial least squares techniques with continuous wavelet transform. Can. J. Anal. Sci. Spect. 49, 218&#x2013;225.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dubrovkin J. (2018). Mathematical Processing of Spectral Data in Analytical Chemistry: A Guide to Error Analysis. Newcastle upon Tyne: Cambridge Scholars Publishing.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehrentreich F., Summchen L. (2001). Spike removal and denoising of Raman spectra by wavelet transform methods. Anal. Chem. 73, 4364&#x2013;4373. 10.1021/ac0013756</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ac0013756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11569832</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ernst R. R. (1989). Nuclear magnetic resonance fourier transform spectroscopy. Bull. Magn. Resonance 16, 5&#x2013;29.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1391683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang H., Chen H. Y. (1997). Wavelet analyses of electroanalytical chemistry responses and an adaptive wavelet filter. Anal. Chim. Acta 346, 319-&#x2212;325. 10.1016/S0003-2670(97)90071-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0003-2670(97)90071-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gohel R. V., Parmar S. J., Patel B. A. (2014). Development and validation of double divisor-ratio spectra derivative spectrophotometric method for simultaneous estimation of olmesartan medoxomil, amlodipine besylate and hydrochlorthiazide in tablet dosage form. Int. J. Pharm.Tech. Res. 6, 1518&#x2013;1525.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths P. R. (1977). Recent applications of fourier transform infrared spectrometry in chemical and environmental analysis. Appl. Spectros. 31, 497&#x2013;505. 10.1366/000370277774464084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1366/000370277774464084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths P. R., De Haseth J. A. (1986). Fourier Transform Infrared Spectroscopy. New York, NY: Wiley.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hwang M. S., Choa C., Chunga H., Woo Y. A. (2005). Nondestructive determination of the ambroxol content in tablets by Raman spectroscopy. J. Pharm. Biomed. Anal. 38, 210&#x2013;215. 10.1016/j.jpba.2004.12.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2004.12.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15925210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jun-fang X., Xiao-yu L., Pei-wu L., Qian M. A., Xiao-xia D. (2007). Application of wavelet transform in the prediction of navel orange vitamin C content by near-infrared spectroscopy. Agr. Sci. China 6, 1067&#x2013;1073. 10.1016/S1671-2927(07)60148-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1671-2927(07)60148-5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kambur M., Narin I., Din&#xe7; E., Candir S., Baleanu D. (2011). Fractional wavelet transform for the quantitative spectral resolution of the commercial veterinary preparations. Rev. Chim. (Bucuresti) 62, 618&#x2013;621.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kanbur M., Narin I., &#xd6;zdemir E., Din&#xe7; E. (2010). Fractional wavelet transform for the quantitative spectral analysis of two-component system, New Trends in Nanotechnology and Fractional Calculus, eds Baleanu D., G&#xfc;ven&#xe7; Z. B., Tenreiro Machado J. A. (Dordrecht; Heidelberg; London; New York, NY: Springer; ), 321&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lai Y., Nia N., Kokot S. (2011). Discrimination of Rhizoma Corydalis from two sources by near-infrared spectroscopy supported by the wavelet transform and least-squares support vector machine methods. Vib. Spectrosc. 56, 154&#x2013;160. 10.1016/j.vibspec.2011.01.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.vibspec.2011.01.007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leung A. K. M., Chau F.-T., Gau J.-B. (1998). A review on applications of wavelets transform techniques in chemical analysis, 1989-1997. Chem. Intell. Lab. Sys. 43, 165&#x2013;184. 10.1016/S0169-7439(98)00080-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-7439(98)00080-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levillain P., Fompeydie D. (1986). Spectrophotom&#xe9;trie d&#xe9;riv&#xe9;e: int&#xe9;r&#xea;t, limites et applications. Analusis 14, 1&#x2013;20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li B., Chen X. (2014). Wavelet-based numerical analysis: a review and classification. Finite Elem. Anal. Des., 81, 14&#x2013;31. 10.1016/j.finel.2013.11.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.finel.2013.11.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallat S. (1988). A Wavelet Tour of Signal Processing. New York, NY: Academic Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mark H., Workman J. (2007). Chemometrics in Spectroscopy. London; San Diego, CA; Cambridge, MA, Oxford: Elsevier.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medhat M. E. (2015). A review on applications of the wavelet transform technique in spectral analysis. J. Appl. Computat. Math. 4, 1&#x2013;6. 10.4172/2168-9679.1000224</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2168-9679.1000224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neue G. (1996). Simplification of dynamic NMR spectroscopy by wavelet transform. Solid State Nucl. Magn. Reson. 5, 305&#x2013;314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8925260</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Newland D. E. (1993). An Introduction to Random Vibrations, Spectral and Wavelet Analysis. Longman: University of Cambridge. 295&#x2013;370.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Haver T. C. (1979). Derivative and wavelength modulation spectrometry. Anal. Chem. 51, 91A&#x2212;100A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">466781</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O'Haver T. C., Green G. L. (1976). Numerical error analysis of derivative spectrometry for the quantitative analysis of mixtures. Anal. Chem. 48, 312&#x2013;318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palavajjhala S., Motard R. L., Joseph B. (1994). Wavelet Application in Chemical Engineering. eds Motard R. L., Joseph B. (Norwell, MA: Kluwer Academic Publishers; ), 33&#x2013;83.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pekta&#x15f; G., Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2009). Combined application of continuous wavelet transform-zero crossing technique in the simultaneous spectrophotometric determination of perindopril and indapamid in tablets. Qu&#xed;m. Nova 32, 1416&#x2013;1421.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ragno G., Ioele G., De Luca M., Garofalo A., Grande F., Risoli A. (2006). A critical study on the application of the zero-crossing derivative spectrophotometry to the photodegradation monitoring of lacidipine. J. Pharm. Biom. Anal. 42, 39&#x2013;45. 10.1016/j.jpba.2005.11.025</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpba.2005.11.025</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16406449</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salinas F., Berzas Nevado J. J., Espinoso Mansilla A. E. (1990). A new spectrophotometric method for quantitative multicomponent analysis resolution of mixtures of salicylic and salicyluric acids. Talanta 37, 347&#x2013;351. 10.1016/0039-9140(90)80065-N</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0039-9140(90)80065-N</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18964949</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao X., Cai W., Sun P. (1998a). Determination of the component number in overlapping multicomponent chromatogram using wavelet transform. Chemom. Intell. Lab. Syst. 43, 147&#x2013;155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao X., Cai W., Sun P., Zhang M., Zhao G. (1997). Quantitative Determination of the components in overlapping chromatographic peaks using wavelet transform. Anal. Chem. 69, 1722&#x2013;1725. 10.1021/ac9608679</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ac9608679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21639295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao X., Hou S., Fang N., He Y., Zhao G. (1998b). Quantitative determination of plant hormones by high performance liquid chromatography with wavelet transform. Chin. J. Anal. Chem. 26, 107&#x2013;110.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao X., Hou S., Zhao G. (1998c). Extraction of the component information from overlapping chromatograms by wavelet transform. Chin. J. Anal. Chem. 26, 1428&#x2013;1431.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao X., Zhuang Y. (2004). Determination of chlorogenic acid in plant samples by using near-infrared spectrum with wavelet transform preprocessing. Anal. Sci. 20, 451&#x2013;454. 10.2116/analsci.20.451</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2116/analsci.20.451</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15068286</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shariati-Rad M., Irandoust M., Amini T., Ahmadi F. (2012). Partial least squares and continuous wavelet transformation in simultaneous spectrophotometric determination of amlodipin and atorvastatine. Pharm. Anal. Acta 3:178 10.4172/2153-2435.1000178</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2153-2435.1000178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shokry E., El-Gendy A. E., Kawy M. A., Hegazy M. (2014). Application of double divisor ratio spectra derivative spectrophotometric [DDRS-DS], chemometric and chromatographic methods for stability indicating determination of moexipril hydrochloride and hydrochlorothiazide. Curr. Sci. Int. 3, 352&#x2013;380.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sohrabi M. R., Kamali N., Khakpour M. (2011). Simultaneous spectrophotometric determination of metformin hydrochloride and glibenclamide in binary mixtures using combined discrete and continuous wavelet transforms. Anal. Sci. 27, 1037&#x2013;1041.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21985929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strang G., Nguyen T.(eds.). (1996). Wavelets and Filter Banks. MA: Wellesley-Cambridge Press; 72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ugurlu G., &#xd6;zaltin N., Din&#xe7; E. (2008). Spectrophotometric determination of risedronate sodium in pharmaceutical preparations by derivative and continuous wavelet transforms. Rev. Anal. Chem. 27, 215&#x2013;233. 10.1515/REVAC.2008.27.4.215</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/REVAC.2008.27.4.215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unser M., Blu T. (2000). Fractional splines and wavelets. SIAM Rev. 42, 43&#x2013;67. 10.1137/S0036144598349435</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1137/S0036144598349435</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xdc;st&#xfc;ndag &#xd6;., Din&#xe7; E., Baleanu D. (2008). Applications of Mexican hat wavelet function to binary mixture analysis. Rev. Chim. (Bucuresti) 59, 1387&#x2013;1391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vetterli M., Kova&#x10d;evi&#x107; J. (1995). Wavelets and Subband Coding. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall PTR.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walczak B., Massart D. (1997a). Wavelet packet transform applied to a set of signals: a new approach to the best-basis selection. Chemom. Intell. Lab. Syst. 38, 39&#x2013;50. 10.1016/S0169-7439(97)00050-6</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-7439(97)00050-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walczak B., Massart D. L. (1997b). Noise suppression and signal compression using the wavelet packet transform. Chemom. Intell. Lab. Sys. 36, 81&#x2013;94. 10.1016/S0169-7439(96)00077-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-7439(96)00077-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walczak B., Massart D. L. (1997c). Wavelets-something for analytical chemistry. Trends Analyt. Chem. 16, 451&#x2013;463. 10.1016/S0165-9936(97)00065-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0165-9936(97)00065-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walczak B., Massart D. L. (2000a). Calibration in wavelet domain, in Wavelets in Chemistry, ed Walczak B. (Amsterdam: Elsevier; ), 323&#x2013;347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walczak B., Massart D. L. (2000b). Joint basis and joint best-basis for data sets, in Wavelets in Chemistry, ed Walczak B. (Amsterdam: Elsevier; ), 165&#x2013;171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walczak B., Radomski J. P. (2000). Wavelet bases for IR library compression, searching and reconstruction, in Wavelets in Chemistry, ed Walczak B.(Amsterdam: Elsevier; ), 291&#x2013;308.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang H., Xiao J., Fan Z., Zhang M. (1997). Wavelet transform and its application in chemistry. Chem. Bull. Huaxue Tongbao 6, 20&#x2013;23.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wickerhauser M. V. (1994). Adapted Wavelet Analysis From Theory to Software. New York, NY:A.K. Peters, ltd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan-Fang S. (2013). A review on the applications of wavelet transform in hydrology time series analysis. Atmospheric Res. 122, 8&#x2013;15. 10.1016/j.atmosres.2012.11.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atmosres.2012.11.003</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X. P., Mo J. Y. (1999). The coupled application of the B-spline wavelet and RLT filtration in staircase voltammetry. Chemometr. Intell. Lab. Syst. 45, 157-&#x2212;161. 10.1016/S0169-7439(98)00099-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0169-7439(98)00099-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng X. P., Mo J. Y., Cai &#x2018;P. X. (1998). Simultaneous application of spline wavelet and Riemann-Liouville transform filtration in electroanalytical chemistry. Anal. Commun. 35, 57&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhong H. B., Zheng J. B., Pan Z. X., Zhang M. S., Gao H. (1998). Investigation on application of wavelet transform in recovering useful information from oscillographic signal. Chem. J. Chin. Univ. 19, 547&#x2013;549.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>