<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">36246038</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1752-0894</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>15</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Nature geoscience</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Nat Geosci</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Deep hydration and lithospheric thinning at oceanic transform plate boundaries.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>741</StartPage><EndPage>746</EndPage><MedlinePgn>741-746</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41561-022-01003-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Transform faults accommodate the lateral motions between lithospheric plates, producing large earthquakes. Away from active transform boundaries, former oceanic transform faults also form the fracture zones that cover the ocean floor. However, the deep structure of these faults remains enigmatic. Here we present ultra-long offset seismic data from the Romanche transform fault in the equatorial Atlantic Ocean that indicates the presence of a low-velocity anomaly extending down to ~60 km depth below sea level. We performed 3D thermal modelling that suggests the anomaly is likely to be due to extensive serpentinization down to ~16 km depth, overlying a hydrated, shear mylonite zone down to 32 km depth. The water is considered to be sourced from seawater-derived fluids that infiltrate deep into the fault. Below 32 km is interpreted to be a low-temperature, water-induced melting zone that elevates the lithosphere-asthenosphere boundary, causing significant thinning of the lithosphere at the transform fault. The presence of a thinned lithosphere at transform faults could explain observations of volcanism, thickened crust and intra-transform spreading centres at transform faults. It also suggests that migration and mixing of water-induced melt with the high temperature melt may occur beneath the ridge axis.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Zhikai</ForeName><Initials>Z</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Institut de Physique du Globe de Paris, CNRS, F-75005 Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singh</LastName><ForeName>Satish C</ForeName><Initials>SC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Institut de Physique du Globe de Paris, CNRS, F-75005 Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prigent</LastName><ForeName>C&#xe9;cile</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Institut de Physique du Globe de Paris, CNRS, F-75005 Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gregory</LastName><ForeName>Emma P M</ForeName><Initials>EPM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Institut de Physique du Globe de Paris, CNRS, F-75005 Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Marjanovi&#x107;</LastName><ForeName>Milena</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Universit&#xe9; Paris Cit&#xe9;, Institut de Physique du Globe de Paris, CNRS, F-75005 Paris, France.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>339442</GrantID><Acronym>ERC_</Acronym><Agency>European Research Council</Agency><Country>International</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>25</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Nat Geosci</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101482213</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1752-0894</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>Competing interests The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>24</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>13</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36246038</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">EMS149414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7613702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41561-022-01003-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Wilson JT. A New Class of Faults and their Bearing on Continental Drift. Nature. 1965;207:343&#x2013;347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird P. An updated digital model of plate boundaries. Geochem Geophys Geosyst. 2003;4:1027.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bird P, Kagan YY, Jackson DD. Plate tectonics and earthquake potential of spreading ridges and oceanic transform faults, in Plate Boundary Zones. Vol. 30 American Geophysical Union; Washington, D.C: 2002. (Geodynamics Series).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roland E, Lizarralde D, McGuire JJ, Collins JA. Seismic velocity constraints on the material properties that control earthquake behavior at the Quebrada-Discovery-Gofar transform faults, East Pacific Rise. J Geophys Res. 2012;117:B11102</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gregory EPM, Singh SC, Marjanovi&#x107; M, Wang Z. Serpentinized peridotite versus thick mafic crust at the Romanche oceanic transform fault. Geology. 2021;49:1132&#x2013;1136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GEBCO Compilation Group. GEBCO 2021 Grid. doi: 10.5285/c6612cbe-50b3-0cff-e053-6c86abc09f8f.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5285/c6612cbe-50b3-0cff-e053-6c86abc09f8f</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeMets C, Gordon RG, Argus DF. Geologically current plate motions. Geophys J Int. 2010;181:1&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abercrombie RE, Ekstr&#xf6;m G. Earthquake slip on oceanic transform faults. Nature. 2001;410:74&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11242043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris RJ, Toy VG. Continental transforms: A view from the Alpine Fault. J Struct Geol. 2014;64:3&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>M&#xfc;ller RD, Sdrolias M, Gaina C, Roest WR. Age, spreading rates, and spreading asymmetry of the world&#x2019;s ocean crust. Geochem Geophys Geosyst. 2008;9:Q04006</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bonatti E, et al. Steady-state creation of crust-free lithosphere at cold spots in mid-ocean ridges. Geology. 2001;29:979&#x2013;982.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehouachi F, Singh SC. Water-rich sublithospheric melt channel in the equatorial Atlantic Ocean. Nature Geosci. 2018;11:65&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Melo GWS, et al. Uppermost Mantle Velocity beneath the Mid-Atlantic Ridge and Transform Faults in the Equatorial Atlantic Ocean. Bull Seismol Soc Am. 2021;111:1067&#x2013;1079.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Avendonk HJA, Shillington DJ, Holbrook WS, Hornbach MJ. Inferring crustal structure in the Aleutian island arc from a sparse wide-angle seismic data set. Geochem Geophys Geosyst. 2004;5:Q08008</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grevemeyer I, R&#xfc;pke LH, Morgan JP, Iyer K, Devey CW. Extensional tectonics and two-stage crustal accretion at oceanic transform faults. Nature. 2021;591:402&#x2013;407.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33731945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prigent C, Warren JM, Kohli AH, Teyssier C. Fracture-mediated deep seawater flow and mantle hydration on oceanic transform faults. Earth Planet Sci Lett. 2020;532:115988</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohli AH, Warren JM. Evidence for a Deep Hydrologic Cycle on Oceanic Transform Faults. J Geophys Res. 2020;125:e2019JB017751</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohli A, Wolfson-Schwehr M, Prigent C, Warren JM. Oceanic transform fault seismicity and slip mode influenced by seawater infiltration. Nature Geosci. 2021;14:606&#x2013;611.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKenzie D, Jackson J, Priestley K. Thermal structure of oceanic and continental lithosphere. Earth Planet Sci Lett. 2005;233:337&#x2013;349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guillot S, Schwartz S, Reynard B, Agard P, Prigent C. Tectonic significance of serpentinites. Tectonophysics. 2015;646:1&#x2013;19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hicks SP, et al. Back-propagating supershear rupture in the 2016 Mw 7.1 Romanche transform fault earthquake. Nature Geosci. 2020;13:647&#x2013;653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abers GA, Hacker BR. A MATLAB toolbox and Excel workbook for calculating the densities, seismic wave speeds, and major element composition of minerals and rocks at pressure and temperature. Geochem Geophys Geosyst. 2016;17:616&#x2013;624.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu Z, et al. Semibrittle seismic deformation in high-temperature mantle mylonite shear zone along the Romanche transform fault. Sci Adv. 2021;7:eabf3388.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8034845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33837085</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lizarralde D, Gaherty JB, Collins JA, Hirth G, Kim SD. Spreading-rate dependence of melt extraction at mid-ocean ridges from mantle seismic refraction data. Nature. 2004;432:744&#x2013;747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15592410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor MAJ, Singh SC. Composition and microstructure of magma bodies from effective medium theory. Geophys J Int. 2002;149:15&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katz RF, Spiegelman M, Langmuir CH. A new parameterization of hydrous mantle melting. Geochem Geophys Geosyst. 2003;4:1073.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keller T, Katz RF. The Role of Volatiles in Reactive Melt Transport in the Asthenosphere. J Petrol. 2016;57:1073&#x2013;1108.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang S, Constable S, Rychert CA, Harmon N. A Lithosphere-Asthenosphere Boundary and Partial Melt Estimated Using Marine Magnetotelluric Data at the Central Middle Atlantic Ridge. Geochem Geophys Geosyst. 2020;21:e2020GC009177</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rychert CA, et al. A dynamic lithosphere-asthenosphere boundary near the equatorial Mid-Atlantic Ridge. Earth Planet Sci Lett. 2021;566:116949</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harmon N, et al. Evolution of the Oceanic Lithosphere in the Equatorial Atlantic From Rayleigh Wave Tomography, Evidence for Small-Scale Convection From the PI-LAB Experiment. Geochem Geophys Geosyst. 2020;21:e2020GC009174</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marjanovi&#x107; M, et al. Seismic Crustal Structure and Morpho-tectonic Features Associated with the Chain Fracture Zone and their Role in the Evolution of the Equatorial Atlantic Region. J Geophys Res. 2020;125:e2020JB020275</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33282617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Growe K, et al. Seismic structure of the St. Paul Fracture Zone and Late Cretaceous to Mid Eocene oceanic crust in the equatorial Atlantic Ocean near 18&#xb0;W. J Geophys Res. 2021;126:e2021JB022456</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fox PJ, Gallo DG. A tectonic model for ridge-transform-ridge plate boundaries: Implications for the structure of oceanic lithosphere. Tectonophysics. 1984;104:205&#x2013;242.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>H&#xe9;kinian R, Bideau D, H&#xe9;bert R, Niu Y. Magmatism in the Garrett transform fault (East Pacific Rise near 13&#xb0; 27&#x2019; S) J Geophys Res. 1995;100:10163&#x2013;10185.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maia M, et al. Extreme mantle uplift and exhumation along a transpressive transform fault. Nature Geosci. 2016;9:619&#x2013;623.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roland E, Behn MD, Hirth G. Thermal-mechanical behavior of oceanic transform faults: Implications for the spatial distribution of seismicity. Geochem Geophys Geosyst. 2010;11:Q07001</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Behn MD, Boettcher MS, Hirth G. Thermal structure of oceanic transform faults. Geology. 2007;35:307&#x2013;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Le Voyer M, Cottrell E, Kelley KA, Brounce M, Hauri EH. The effect of primary versus secondary processes on the volatile content of MORB glasses: An example from the equatorial Mid-Atlantic Ridge (5&#xb0;N&#x2013;3&#xb0;S) J Geophys Res. 2015;120:125&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menard HW, Atwater T. Origin of Fracture Zone Topography. Nature. 1969;222:1037&#x2013;1040.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ten Brink US, et al. Seismic imaging of deep low-velocity zone beneath the Dead Sea basin and transform fault: Implications for strain localization and crustal rigidity. Geophys Res Lett. 2006;33:L24314</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuis GS, et al. A Comparison Between the Transpressional Plate Boundaries of South Island, New Zealand, and Southern California, USA: The Alpine and San Andreas Fault Systems, in A Continental Plate Boundary: Tectonics at South Island, New Zealand. Vol. 175 American Geophysical Union; Washington, DC: 2007. (Geophysical Monograph Series).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fichtner A, et al. The deep structure of the North Anatolian Fault Zone. Earth Planet Sci Lett. 2013;373:109&#x2013;117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;cel A, et al. Moho, crustal architecture and deep deformation under the North Marmara Trough, from the SEISMARMARA Leg 1 offshore&#x2013;onshore reflection&#x2013;refraction survey. Tectonophysics. 2009;467:1&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moser TJ. Shortest path calculation of seismic rays. Geophysics. 1991;56:59&#x2013;67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korenaga J, et al. Crustal structure of the southeast Greenland margin from joint refraction and reflection seismic tomography. J Geophys Res. 2000;105:21591&#x2013;21614.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangerth W, Dannberg J, Gassm&#xf6;ller R, Heister T. ASPECT: Advanced Solver for Problems in Earth&#x2019;s ConvecTion. User Manual. 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seyler M, Bonatti E. Regional-scale melt-rock interaction in lherzolitic mantle in the Romanche Fracture Zone (Atlantic Ocean) Earth Planet Sci Lett. 1997;146:273&#x2013;287.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tartarotti P, Susini S, Nimis P, Ottolini L. Melt migration in the upper mantle along the Romanche Fracture Zone (Equatorial Atlantic) Lithos. 2002;63:125&#x2013;149.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mookherjee M, Mainprice D. Unusually large shear wave anisotropy for chlorite in subduction zone settings. Geophys Res Lett. 2014;41:1506&#x2013;1513.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goes S, Govers R, Vacher P. Shallow mantle temperatures under Europe from P and S wave tomography. J Geophys Res. 2000;105:11153&#x2013;11169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark AN, Lesher CE, Jacobsen SD, Wang Y. Anomalous density and elastic properties of basalt at high pressure: Reevaluating of the effect of melt fraction on seismic velocity in the Earth&#x2019;s crust and upper mantle. J Geophys Res. 2016;121:4232&#x2013;4248.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>