<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32791465</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>05</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-2828</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>70</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Jan</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Ultrasonics sonochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ultrason Sonochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Scale-up of vortex based hydrodynamic cavitation devices: A case of degradation of di-chloro aniline in water.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>105295</StartPage><MedlinePgn>105295</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">105295</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ultsonch.2020.105295</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1350-4177(20)30631-3</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hydrodynamic cavitation (HC) is being increasingly used in a wide range of applications. Unlike ultrasonic cavitation, HC is scalable and has been used at large scale industrial applications. However, no information about influence of scale on performance of HC is available in the open literature. In this work, we present for the first time, experimental data on use of HC for degradation of complex organic pollutants in water on four different scales (~200 times scale-up in terms of capacity). Vortex based HC devices offer various advantages like early inception, high cavitational yield and significantly lower propensity to clogging and erosion. We have used vortex based HC devices in this work. 2,4 dichloroaniline (DCA) - an aromatic compound with multiple functional groups was considered as a model pollutant. Degradation of DCA in water was performed using vortex-based HC devices with characteristic throat dimension, d<sub>t</sub> as 3, 6, 12 and 38&#xa0;mm with scale-up of almost 200 time based on the flow rates (1.3 to 247 LPM). Considering the experimental constraints on operating the largest scale HC device, the experimental data is presented here at only one value of pressure drop across HC device (280&#xa0;kPa). A previously used per-pass degradation model was extended to describe the experimental data for the pollutant used in this study and a generalised form is presented. The degradation performance was found to decrease with increase in the scale and then plateaus. Appropriate correlation was developed based on the experimental data. The developed approach and presented results provide a sound basis and a data set for further development of comprehensive multi-scale modelling of HC devices.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2020 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranade</LastName><ForeName>Vivek V</ForeName><Initials>VV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, Northern Ireland, UK; Bernal Institute, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland. Electronic address: V.Ranade@qub.ac.uk.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Prasad Sarvothaman</LastName><ForeName>Varaha</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, Northern Ireland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simpson</LastName><ForeName>Alister</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Aerospace and Mechanical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, Northern Ireland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagarajan</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, Northern Ireland, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Multiphase Reactors, Intensification Group (mRING)</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Ultrason Sonochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9433356</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-4177</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrodynamic cavitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Per-pass degradation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Scale-up</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vortex-based devices</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: One of the authors (VVR) is a Director of Vivira Process Technologies Pvt., Ltd., which commercially offers the vortex-based cavitation devices used in this study. One of the authors (VVR) is a Director of Vivira Process Technologies Pvt., Ltd., which commercially offers the vortex-based cavitation devices used in this study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32791465</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultsonch.2020.105295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1350-4177(20)30631-3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Albanese L., Ciriminna R., Meneguzzo F., Pagliaro M. Gluten reduction in beer by hydrodynamic cavitation assisted brewing of barley malts. LWT-Food Sci. Technol. 2017;82:342&#x2013;353.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alkhuraiji T.S., Alkhuraiji W.S. Detailed study of water radiolysis-based degradation of chloroorganic pollutants in aqueous solutions. J. Hazard. Mater. 2019;368:569&#x2013;577.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30711705</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Badmus K.O., Tijani J.O., Massima E., Petrik L. Treatment of persistent organic pollutants in wastewater using hydrodynamic cavitation in synergy with advanced oxidation process. Environ. Sci. Pollut. Res. 2018;25(8):7299&#x2013;7314.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29349742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biobang, 2019, https://www.biobang.com, last accessed: 9th January 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Braeutigam P., Franke M., Schneider R.J., Lehmann A., Stolle A., Ondruschka B. Degradation of carbamazepine in environmentally relevant concentrations in water by Hydrodynamic-Acoustic-Cavitation (HAC) Water Res. 2012;46(7):2469&#x2013;2477.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22365175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burzio E., Bersani F., Caridi G.C.A., Vesipa R., Ridolfi L., Manes C. Water disinfection by orifice-induced hydrodynamic cavitation. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2019;104740</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31539726</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capocelli M., Musmarra D., Prisciandaro M., Lancia A. Chemical effect of hydrodynamic cavitation: simulation and experimental comparison. AIChE J. 2014;60(7):2566&#x2013;2572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capocelli M., Prisciandaro M., Lancia A., Musmarra D. Hydrodynamic cavitation of p-nitrophenol: a theoretical and experimental insight. Chem. Eng. J. 2014;254:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter J., Badve M., Rajoriya S., George S., Saharan V.K., Pandit A.B. Hydrodynamic cavitation: an emerging technology for the intensification of various chemical and physical processes in a chemical process industry. Rev. Chem. Eng. 2017;33(5):433&#x2013;468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavimax, 2019, http://www.cavimax.co.uk, last accessed: 9th January 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cavitation Technologies, 2019, http://www.ctinanotech.com, last accessed: 9th January 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dular M., Griessler-Bulc T., Gutierrez-Aguirre I., Heath E., Kosjek T., Klemen&#x10d;i&#x10d; A.K., Oder M., Petkov&#x161;ek M., Ra&#x10d;ki N., Ravnikar M., &#x160;arc A. Use of hydrodynamic cavitation in (waste) water treatment. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2016;29:577&#x2013;588.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26515938</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dynaflow, 2019, http://www.dynaflow-inc.com, last accessed: 9th January 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farvardin M., Hosseinzadeh Samani B., Rostami S., Abbaszadeh-Mayvan A., Najafi G., Fayyazi E. Enhancement of biodiesel production from waste cooking oil: ultrasonic-hydrodynamic combined cavitation system. Energy Sources, Part A: Recov. Utiliz. Environ. Effects. 2019:1&#x2013;15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogate P.R., Pandit A.B. Hydrodynamic cavitation reactors: a state of the art review. Rev. Chem. Eng. 2001;17(1):1&#x2013;85.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gore M.M., Saharan V.K., Pinjari D.V., Chavan P.V., Pandit A.B. Degradation of reactive orange 4 dye using hydrodynamic cavitation based hybrid techniques. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2014;21(3):1075&#x2013;1082.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24360991</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holkar C.R., Jadhav A.J., Pinjari D.V., Pandit A.B. Cavitationally driven transformations: A technique of process intensification. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2019;58(15):5797&#x2013;5819.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jain P., Bhandari V.M., Balapure K., Jena J., Ranade V.V., Killedar D.J. Hydrodynamic cavitation using vortex diode: An efficient approach for elimination of pathogenic bacteria from water. J. Environ. Manage. 2019;242:210&#x2013;219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31039530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kahl, T., Schr&#xf6;der, K.W., Lawrence, F.R., Marshall, W.J., H&#xf6;ke, H. and J&#xe4;ckh, R., 2000. Aniline. Ullmann's Encyclopedia of Industrial Chemistry.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni A.A., Ranade V.V., Rajeev R., Koganti S.B. CFD simulation of flow in vortex diodes. AIChE J. 2008;54(5):1139&#x2013;1152.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar M.S., Sonawane S.H., Bhanvase B.A., Bethi B. Treatment of ternary dye wastewater by hydrodynamic cavitation combined with other advanced oxidation processes (AOP&#x2019;s) J. Water Process Eng. 2018;23:250&#x2013;256.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagarajan S., Ranade V.V. Pretreatment of Lignocellulosic Biomass Using Vortex-Based Devices for Cavitation: Influence on Biomethane Potential. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2019;58(35):15975&#x2013;15988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nakashima K., Ebi Y., Shibasaki-Kitakawa N., Soyama H., Yonemoto T. Hydrodynamic cavitation reactor for efficient pretreatment of lignocellulosic biomass. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2016;55(7):1866&#x2013;1871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozonek J. CRC Press; 2012. Application of Hydrodynamic Cavitation In Environmental Engineering.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pandare A., Ranade V.V. Flow in vortex diodes. Chem. Eng. Res. Des. 2015;102:274&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajoriya S., Bargole S., Saharan V.K. Degradation of a cationic dye (Rhodamine 6G) using hydrodynamic cavitation coupled with other oxidative agents: Reaction mechanism and pathway. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2017;34:183&#x2013;194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27773234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranade, V.V., Kulkarni, A.A. and Bhandari, V.M., Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (CSIR), 2017. Apparatus and method for reduction in ammoniacal nitrogen from waste waters. U.S. Patent 9,725,338.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saharan V.K., Pinjari D.V., Gogate P.R., Pandit A.B. Industrial Wastewater Treatment, Recycling and Reuse. Elsevier; 2014. Advanced oxidation technologies for wastewater treatment: an overview; pp. 141&#x2013;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarvothaman V.P., Nagarajan S., Ranade V.V. Treatment of solvent-contaminated water using vortex-based cavitation: influence of operating pressure drop, temperature, aeration, and reactor scale. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2018;57(28):9292&#x2013;9304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarvothaman V.P., Simpson A.T., Ranade V.V. Modelling of vortex based hydrodynamic cavitation reactors. Chem. Eng. J. 2019;377</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson A., Ranade V.V. 110th Anniversary: comparison of cavitation devices based on linear and swirling flows: hydrodynamic characteristics. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2019;58(31):14488&#x2013;14509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson A., Ranade V.V. Flow characteristics of vortex based cavitation devices: Computational investigation on influence of operating parameters and scale. AIChE J. 2019;65(9):16675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suryawanshi N.B., Bhandari V.M., Sorokhaibam L.G., Ranade V.V. Developing techno-economically sustainable methodologies for deep desulfurization using hydrodynamic cavitation. Fuel. 2017;210:482&#x2013;490.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suryawanshi P.G., Bhandari V.M., Sorokhaibam L.G., Ruparelia J.P., Ranade V.V. Solvent degradation studies using hydrodynamic cavitation. Environ. Prog. Sustainable Energy. 2018;37(1):295&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thanekar P., Panda M., Gogate P.R. Degradation of carbamazepine using hydrodynamic cavitation combined with advanced oxidation processes. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2018;40:567&#x2013;576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28946459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Utikar, R.P. (2019), Private communications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vivira Process Technologies Ltd, 2019, http://www.vivira.in, last accessed: 9th January 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Waghmare A., Nagula K., Pandit A., Arya S. Hydrodynamic cavitation for energy efficient and scalable process of microalgae cell disruption. Algal Res. 2019;40</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu Z., Zheng T., Wu L., Lou H., Xie Q., Lu M., Zhang L., Nie Y., Ji J. Novel reactor for exothermic heterogeneous reaction systems: Intensification of mass and heat transfer and application to vegetable oil epoxidation. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2017;56(18):5231&#x2013;5238.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>