<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36001306</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>30</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2168-6238</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>79</Volume><Issue>10</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JAMA psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Percentage of Heavy Drinking Days Following Psilocybin-Assisted Psychotherapy vs Placebo in the Treatment of Adult Patients With Alcohol Use Disorder: A Randomized Clinical Trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>953</StartPage><EndPage>962</EndPage><MedlinePgn>953-962</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.2096</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE">Although classic psychedelic medications have shown promise in the treatment of alcohol use disorder (AUD), the efficacy of psilocybin remains unknown.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate whether 2 administrations of high-dose psilocybin improve the percentage of heavy drinking days in patients with AUD undergoing psychotherapy relative to outcomes observed with active placebo medication and psychotherapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DESIGN, SETTING, AND PARTICIPANTS">In this double-blind randomized clinical trial, participants were offered 12 weeks of manualized psychotherapy and were randomly assigned to receive psilocybin vs diphenhydramine during 2 day-long medication sessions at weeks 4 and 8. Outcomes were assessed over the 32-week double-blind period following the first dose of study medication. The study was conducted at 2 academic centers in the US. Participants were recruited from the community between March 12, 2014, and March 19, 2020. Adults aged 25 to 65 years with a DSM-IV diagnosis of alcohol dependence and at least 4 heavy drinking days during the 30 days prior to screening were included. Exclusion criteria included major psychiatric and drug use disorders, hallucinogen use, medical conditions that contraindicated the study medications, use of exclusionary medications, and current treatment for AUD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS">Study medications were psilocybin, 25 mg/70 kg, vs diphenhydramine, 50 mg (first session), and psilocybin, 25-40 mg/70 kg, vs diphenhydramine, 50-100 mg (second session). Psychotherapy included motivational enhancement therapy and cognitive behavioral therapy.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="MAIN OUTCOMES AND MEASURES">The primary outcome was percentage of heavy drinking days, assessed using a timeline followback interview, contrasted between groups over the 32-week period following the first administration of study medication using multivariate repeated-measures analysis of variance.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">A total of 95 participants (mean [SD] age, 46 [12] years; 42 [44.2%] female) were randomized (49 to psilocybin and 46 to diphenhydramine). One participant (1.1%) was American Indian/Alaska Native, 3 (3.2%) were Asian, 4 (4.2%) were Black, 14 (14.7%) were Hispanic, and 75 (78.9%) were non-Hispanic White. Of the 95 randomized participants, 93 received at least 1 dose of study medication and were included in the primary outcome analysis. Percentage of heavy drinking days during the 32-week double-blind period was 9.7% for the psilocybin group and 23.6% for the diphenhydramine group, a mean difference of 13.9%; (95% CI, 3.0-24.7; F1,86&#x2009;=&#x2009;6.43; P&#x2009;=&#x2009;.01). Mean daily alcohol consumption (number of standard drinks per day) was also lower in the psilocybin group. There were no serious adverse events among participants who received psilocybin.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE">Psilocybin administered in combination with psychotherapy produced robust decreases in percentage of heavy drinking days over and above those produced by active placebo and psychotherapy. These results provide support for further study of psilocybin-assisted treatment for AUD.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION">ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT02061293.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogenschutz</LastName><ForeName>Michael P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ross</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bhatt</LastName><ForeName>Snehal</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, University of New Mexico School of Medicine, Albuquerque.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Baron</LastName><ForeName>Tara</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forcehimes</LastName><ForeName>Alyssa A</ForeName><Initials>AA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>The Change Companies, Carson City, Nevada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laska</LastName><ForeName>Eugene</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population Health, Division of Biostatistics, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mennenga</LastName><ForeName>Sarah E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Donnell</LastName><ForeName>Kelley</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Owens</LastName><ForeName>Lindsey T</ForeName><Initials>LT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Alabama at Birmingham.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Podrebarac</LastName><ForeName>Samantha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rotrosen</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, New York University Langone Center for Psychedelic Medicine, New York University Grossman School of Medicine, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tonigan</LastName><ForeName>J Scott</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of New Mexico Center on Alcohol, Substance Use and Addictions, Albuquerque.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Worth</LastName><ForeName>Lindsay</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, University of New Mexico School of Medicine, Albuquerque.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT02061293</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JAMA Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101589550</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-622X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006213">Hallucinogens</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>2RV7212BP0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D011562">Psilocybin</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>8GTS82S83M</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D004155">Diphenhydramine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><CommentsCorrectionsList><CommentsCorrections RefType="CommentIn"><RefSource>JAMA Psychiatry. 2022 Oct 1;79(10):945-946. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.2029.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36001305</PMID></CommentsCorrections><CommentsCorrections RefType="ErratumIn"><RefSource>JAMA Psychiatry. 2022 Sep 14. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.2982.</RefSource><PMID Version="1">36103174</PMID></CommentsCorrections></CommentsCorrectionsList><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000428" MajorTopicYN="N">Alcohol Drinking</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000437" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alcoholism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004155" MajorTopicYN="N">Diphenhydramine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004311" MajorTopicYN="N">Double-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006213" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hallucinogens</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011562" MajorTopicYN="N">Psilocybin</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011613" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychotherapy</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016896" MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment Outcome</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement><b>Conflict of Interest Disclosures:</b> Dr Bogenschutz reported grants from the Heffter Research Institute, Carey and Claudia Turnbull, Efrem Nulman, MD, Rodrigo Ni&#xf1;o, and Cody Swift during the conduct of the study and the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, the National Institute on Drug Abuse, the Heffter Research Institute, Mind Medicine, Inc, Tilray Canada, the Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies (MAPS), B. More, Inc, the Turnbull Family Foundation, the Fournier Family Foundation, Dr Bronner&#x2019;s Family Foundation, and the Riverstyx Foundation as well as personal fees from the Heffter Research Institute, Ajna Labs LLC, Beckley Psytech Limited, Journey Colab, and Bright Minds Biosciences outside the submitted work; Dr Bogenschutz also reports being listed as inventor in a provisional patent application related to this work, filed by his employer (New York University Grossman School of Medicine), for which Dr Bogenschutz has formally waived all rights and has no prospect of financial gain; moreover, Dr Bogenschutz&#x2019;s employer has licensed the commercial rights to the data from the study described in this manuscript to B.More, Inc, for a nominal sum, and Dr Bogenschutz has no financial stake in this agreement. Dr Ross reported grants from Heffter Research Institute during the conduct of the study and from Usona Institute and Reset Pharmaceutical outside the submitted work; in addition, Dr Ross had a patent for N420838US and for N419987US, both issued by Reset Pharmaceuticals. Dr Forcehimes reported personal fees from New York University Grossman School of Medicine during the conduct of the study. Dr Mennenga reported grants from Ceruvia Lifesciences outside the submitted work. Dr O&#x2019;Donnell reported personal fees from MAPS-Public Benefit Corporation and Polaris Insight Center outside the submitted work. Dr Rotrosen reported having served as a principal investigator or a coinvestigator on studies for which support in the form of donated or discounted medication, smartphone apps, and/or funds has been or is provided by Alkermes, Inc (vivitrol, extended-release injectable naltrexone), Indivior, Inc (formerly Reckitt-Benckiser; suboxone, buprenorphine/naloxone combination), Braeburn Pharmaceuticals, Inc (extended-release injectable buprenorphine), Pear Therapeutics (smartphone apps ReSET and ReSET-O), CHESS Health (Connections smartphone app), and Data Cubed (smartphone apps SOAR and mSAPPORT), directed to either New York University, or to National Institute on Drug Abuse, or to National Institute on Drug Abuse&#x2019;s contractor Emmes, Inc; served in a nonpaid capacity as a member of an Alkermes study steering committee, as a nonpaid scientific advisor to Mind-Medicine, Inc, as principal investigator on RD-i15-00461 (National Institute on Drug Abuse Clinical Trials Network: New York Node), which is an umbrella grant that supports numerous studies, as a member on each of 2 doctoral dissertation committees at the University of Oslo, Norway, and as a nonpaid chair of the data and safety monitoring board for the OPTIMA trial conducted by CRISM, the Canadian addiction treatment clinical trials network; and currently serves as Chair of the data and safety monitoring board for the US Department of Veterans Affairs Cooperative Studies Program 2014. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36001306</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9403854</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.2096</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2795625</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Griffiths RR, Johnson MW, Carducci MA, et al. Psilocybin produces substantial and sustained decreases in depression and anxiety in patients with life-threatening cancer: a randomized double-blind trial. J Psychopharmacol. 2016;30(12):1181-1197. doi: 10.1177/0269881116675513</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881116675513</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5367557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27909165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ross S, Bossis A, Guss J, et al. Rapid and sustained symptom reduction following psilocybin treatment for anxiety and depression in patients with life-threatening cancer: a randomized controlled trial. J Psychopharmacol. 2016;30(12):1165-1180. doi: 10.1177/0269881116675512</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881116675512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5367551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27909164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogenschutz MP, Forcehimes AA, Pommy JA, Wilcox CE, Barbosa PC, Strassman RJ. Psilocybin-assisted treatment for alcohol dependence: a proof-of-concept study. J Psychopharmacol. 2015;29(3):289-299. doi: 10.1177/0269881114565144</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881114565144</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25586396</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson MW, Garcia-Romeu A, Cosimano MP, Griffiths RR. Pilot study of the 5-HT2AR agonist psilocybin in the treatment of tobacco addiction. J Psychopharmacol. 2014;28(11):983-992. doi: 10.1177/0269881114548296</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881114548296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4286320</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25213996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carhart-Harris R, Giribaldi B, Watts R, et al. Trial of psilocybin versus escitalopram for depression. N Engl J Med. 2021;384(15):1402-1411. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2032994</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2032994</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33852780</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis AK, Barrett FS, May DG, et al. Effects of psilocybin-assisted therapy on major depressive disorder: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78(5):481-489. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.3285</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.3285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7643046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33146667</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carhart-Harris RL, Bolstridge M, Rucker J, et al. Psilocybin with psychological support for treatment-resistant depression: an open-label feasibility study. Lancet Psychiatry. 2016;3(7):619-627. doi: 10.1016/S2215-0366(16)30065-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2215-0366(16)30065-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27210031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grob CS, Danforth AL, Chopra GS, et al. Pilot study of psilocybin treatment for anxiety in patients with advanced-stage cancer. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2011;68(1):71-78. doi: 10.1001/archgenpsychiatry.2010.116</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archgenpsychiatry.2010.116</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20819978</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daws RE, Timmermann C, Giribaldi B, et al. Increased global integration in the brain after psilocybin therapy for depression. Nat Med. 2022;28(4):844-851. doi: 10.1038/s41591-022-01744-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-022-01744-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35411074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halberstadt AL. Recent advances in the neuropsychopharmacology of serotonergic hallucinogens. Behav Brain Res. 2015;277:99-120. doi: 10.1016/j.bbr.2014.07.016</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbr.2014.07.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4642895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25036425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols DE. Hallucinogens. Pharmacol Ther. 2004;101(2):131-181. doi: 10.1016/j.pharmthera.2003.11.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2003.11.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14761703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aleksandrova LR, Phillips AG. Neuroplasticity as a convergent mechanism of ketamine and classical psychedelics. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2021;42(11):929-942. doi: 10.1016/j.tips.2021.08.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tips.2021.08.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34565579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doss MK, Pova&#x17e;an M, Rosenberg MD, et al. Psilocybin therapy increases cognitive and neural flexibility in patients with major depressive disorder. Transl Psychiatry. 2021;11(1):574. doi: 10.1038/s41398-021-01706-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-021-01706-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8575795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34750350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carhart-Harris RL, Friston KJ. REBUS and the anarchic brain: toward a unified model of the brain action of psychedelics. Pharmacol Rev. 2019;71(3):316-344. doi: 10.1124/pr.118.017160</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/pr.118.017160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6588209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31221820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Catlow BJ, Song S, Paredes DA, Kirstein CL, Sanchez-Ramos J. Effects of psilocybin on hippocampal neurogenesis and extinction of trace fear conditioning. Exp Brain Res. 2013;228(4):481-491. doi: 10.1007/s00221-013-3579-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00221-013-3579-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23727882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelly JR, Gillan CM, Prenderville J, et al. Psychedelic therapy&#x2019;s transdiagnostic effects: a research domain criteria (RDoC) perspective. Front Psychiatry. 2021;12:800072. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2021.800072</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2021.800072</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8718877</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34975593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roseman L, Demetriou L, Wall MB, Nutt DJ, Carhart-Harris RL. Increased amygdala responses to emotional faces after psilocybin for treatment-resistant depression. Neuropharmacology. 2018;142:263-269. doi: 10.1016/j.neuropharm.2017.12.041</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2017.12.041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29288686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meinhardt MW, Pfarr S, Fouquet G, et al. Psilocybin targets a common molecular mechanism for cognitive impairment and increased craving in alcoholism. Sci Adv. 2021;7(47):eabh2399. doi: 10.1126/sciadv.abh2399</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/sciadv.abh2399</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8598005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34788104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertens LJ, Wall MB, Roseman L, Demetriou L, Nutt DJ, Carhart-Harris RL. Therapeutic mechanisms of psilocybin: Changes in amygdala and prefrontal functional connectivity during emotional processing after psilocybin for treatment-resistant depression. J Psychopharmacol. 2020;34(2):167-180. doi: 10.1177/0269881119895520</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881119895520</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31941394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mertens LJ, Preller KH. Classical psychedelics as therapeutics in psychiatry&#x2014;current clinical evidence and potential therapeutic mechanisms in substance use and mood disorders. Pharmacopsychiatry. 2021;54(4):176-190. doi: 10.1055/a-1341-1907</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1341-1907</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33472250</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barrett FS, Doss MK, Sepeda ND, Pekar JJ, Griffiths RR. Emotions and brain function are altered up to one month after a single high dose of psilocybin. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):2214. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-59282-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-59282-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7010702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32042038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goldberg SB, Shechet B, Nicholas CR, et al. Post-acute psychological effects of classical serotonergic psychedelics: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Psychol Med. 2020;50(16):2655-2666. doi: 10.1017/S003329172000389X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S003329172000389X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7855004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33143790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cameron LP, Benson CJ, Dunlap LE, Olson DE. Effects of N, N-dimethyltryptamine on rat behaviors relevant to anxiety and depression. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2018;9(7):1582-1590. doi: 10.1021/acschemneuro.8b00134</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acschemneuro.8b00134</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7196340</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29664276</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao LX, Liao C, Gregg I, et al. Psilocybin induces rapid and persistent growth of dendritic spines in frontal cortex in vivo. Neuron. 2021;109(16):2535-2544.e4. doi: 10.1016/j.neuron.2021.06.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2021.06.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8376772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34228959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesselgrave N, Troppoli TA, Wulff AB, Cole AB, Thompson SM. Harnessing psilocybin: antidepressant-like behavioral and synaptic actions of psilocybin are independent of 5-HT2R activation in mice. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2021;118(17):e2022489118. doi: 10.1073/pnas.2022489118</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1073/pnas.2022489118</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8092378</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33850049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roseman L, Nutt DJ, Carhart-Harris RL. Quality of acute psychedelic experience predicts therapeutic efficacy of psilocybin for treatment-resistant depression. Front Pharmacol. 2018;8:974. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2017.00974</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2017.00974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5776504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29387009</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis AK, Barrett FS, Griffiths RR. Psychological flexibility mediates the relations between acute psychedelic effects and subjective decreases in depression and anxiety. J Contextual Behav Sci. 2020;15:39-45. doi: 10.1016/j.jcbs.2019.11.004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcbs.2019.11.004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7451132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32864325</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Romeu A, Griffiths RR, Johnson MW. Psilocybin-occasioned mystical experiences in the treatment of tobacco addiction. Curr Drug Abuse Rev. 2014;7(3):157-164. doi: 10.2174/1874473708666150107121331</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1874473708666150107121331</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4342293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25563443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yaden DB, Griffiths RR. The subjective effects of psychedelics are necessary for their enduring therapeutic effects. ACS Pharmacol Transl Sci. 2020;4(2):568-572. doi: 10.1021/acsptsci.0c00194</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acsptsci.0c00194</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8033615</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33861219</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rieser NM, Herdener M, Preller KH. Psychedelic-assisted therapy for substance use disorders and potential mechanisms of action. Curr Top Behav Neurosci. 2021. doi: 10.1007/7854_2021_284</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/7854_2021_284</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34910289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy R, Kettner H, Zeifman R, et al. Therapeutic alliance and rapport modulate responses to psilocybin assisted therapy for depression. Front Pharmacol. 2022;12:788155. doi: 10.3389/fphar.2021.788155</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2021.788155</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9009076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenway KT, Garel N, Jerome L, Feduccia AA. Integrating psychotherapy and psychopharmacology: psychedelic-assisted psychotherapy and other combined treatments. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2020;13(6):655-670. doi: 10.1080/17512433.2020.1772054</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17512433.2020.1772054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32478631</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smart RG, Storm T, Baker EF, Solursh L. A controlled study of lysergide in the treatment of alcoholism. <i>I</i>. the effects on drinking behavior. Q J Stud Alcohol. 1966;27(3):469-482. doi: 10.15288/qjsa.1966.27.469</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15288/qjsa.1966.27.469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5970697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollister LE, Shelton J, Krieger G. A controlled comparison of lysergic acid diethylamide (LSD) and dextroamphetmine in alcoholics. Am J Psychiatry. 1969;125(10):1352-1357. doi: 10.1176/ajp.125.10.1352</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ajp.125.10.1352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4886242</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ludwig A, Levine J, Stark L, Lazar R. A clinical study of LSD treatment in alcoholism. Am J Psychiatry. 1969;126(1):59-69. doi: 10.1176/ajp.126.1.59</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ajp.126.1.59</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5798383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bowen WT, Soskin RA, Chotlos JW. Lysergic acid diethylamide as a variable in the hospital treatment of alcoholism: a follow-up study. J Nerv Ment Dis. 1970;150(2):111-118. doi: 10.1097/00005053-197002000-00003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005053-197002000-00003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4906920</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pahnke WN, Kurland AA, Unger S, Savage C, Grof S. The experimental use of psychedelic (LSD) psychotherapy. JAMA. 1970;212(11):1856-1863. doi: 10.1001/jama.1970.03170240060010</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.1970.03170240060010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5467681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomsovic M, Edwards RV. Lysergide treatment of schizophrenic and nonschizophrenic alcoholics: a controlled evaluation. Q J Stud Alcohol. 1970;31(4):932-949. doi: 10.15288/qjsa.1970.31.932</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15288/qjsa.1970.31.932</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5490826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs TS, Johansen PO. Lysergic acid diethylamide (LSD) for alcoholism: meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Psychopharmacol. 2012;26(7):994-1002. doi: 10.1177/0269881112439253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881112439253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>First MB, Spitzer RL, Gibbon M, Williams JBW. Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-IV Axis I Disorders-Patient Edition. New York: Biometrics Research Department . State Psychiatric Institute; 1997.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bogenschutz MP, Forcehimes AA. Development of a psychotherapeutic model for psilocybin-assisted treatment of alcoholism. J Humanist Psychol. 2016;57:389-414. doi: 10.1177/0022167816673493</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0022167816673493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Griffiths RR, Richards WA, McCann U, Jesse R. Psilocybin can occasion mystical-type experiences having substantial and sustained personal meaning and spiritual significance. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 2006;187(3):268-283. doi: 10.1007/s00213-006-0457-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00213-006-0457-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16826400</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell LC, Sobell MB. Timeline follow-back: A technique for assessing self-reported alcohol consumption. In: Litten RA, Allen JP, eds. Measuring Alcohol Consumption: Psychosocial and Biological Methods. Humana Press; 1992. doi: 10.1007/978-1-4612-0357-5_3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4612-0357-5_3</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell LC, Sobell MB. Timeline Follow Back: A Calendar Method for Assessing Alcohol and Drug Use (User&#x2019;s Guide). Addiction Research Foundation; 1996.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Drug Evaluation and Research . Alcoholism: Developing Drugs for Treatment: Guidance for Industry. US Food and Drug Administration, Center for Drug Evaluation and Research; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell LC, Sobell MB, Leo GI, Cancilla A. Reliability of a timeline method: assessing normal drinkers&#x2019; reports of recent drinking and a comparative evaluation across several populations. Br J Addict. 1988;83(4):393-402. doi: 10.1111/j.1360-0443.1988.tb00485.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1360-0443.1988.tb00485.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3395719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell LC, Brown J, Leo GI, Sobell MB. The reliability of the Alcohol Timeline Followback when administered by telephone and by computer. Drug Alcohol Depend. 1996;42(1):49-54. doi: 10.1016/0376-8716(96)01263-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0376-8716(96)01263-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8889403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Falk DE, O&#x2019;Malley SS, Witkiewitz K, et al. ; Alcohol Clinical Trials Initiative (ACTIVE) Workgroup . Evaluation of drinking risk levels as outcomes in alcohol pharmacotherapy trials: a secondary analysis of 3 randomized clinical trials. JAMA Psychiatry. 2019;76(4):374-381. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2018.3079</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2018.3079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6450273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30865232</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . International Guide for Monitoring Alcohol Consumption and Related Harm. World Health Organization; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller WR, Tonigan JS, Longabaugh R. The Drinker Inventory of Consequences (DrInC): An Instrument for Assessing Adverse Consequences of Alcohol Abuse: Test Manual. Vol. 4. US Government Printing Office; ; 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gamble C, Krishan A, Stocken D, et al. Guidelines for the content of statistical analysis plans in clinical trials. JAMA. 2017;318(23):2337-2343. doi: 10.1001/jama.2017.18556</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.18556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29260229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S, Groothuis-Oudshoorn K. MICE: Multivariate Imputation by Chained Equations in R. J Stat Softw. 2011;45(3):1-67. doi: 10.18637/jss.v045.i03</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18637/jss.v045.i03</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens J. Applied multivariate statistics for the social sciences. Lawrence Erlbaum Associates; 2002.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>