<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36449315</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2168-6238</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>80</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Jan</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JAMA psychiatry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JAMA Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Clinical Trial Design Challenges and Opportunities for Emerging Treatments for Opioid Use Disorder: A Review.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>84</StartPage><EndPage>92</EndPage><MedlinePgn>84-92</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.4020</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="IMPORTANCE">Novel treatments for opioid use disorder (OUD) are needed to address both the ongoing opioid epidemic and long-standing barriers to existing OUD treatments that target the endogenous &#x3bc;-opioid receptor (MOR) system. The goal of this review is to highlight unique clinical trial design considerations for the study of emerging treatments for OUD that address targets beyond the MOR system. In November 2019, the Analgesic, Anesthetic, and Addiction Clinical Trial Translations, Innovations, Opportunities, and Networks (ACTTION) public-private partnership with the US Food and Drug Administration sponsored a meeting to discuss the current evidence regarding potential treatments for OUD, including cannabinoids, psychedelics, sedative-hypnotics, and immunotherapeutics, such as vaccines.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBSERVATIONS">Consensus recommendations are presented regarding the most critical elements of trial design for the evaluation of novel OUD treatments, such as: (1) stage of treatment that will be targeted (eg, seeking treatment, early abstinence/detoxification, long-term recovery); (2) role of treatment (adjunctive with or independent of existing OUD treatments); (3) primary outcomes informed by patient preferences that assess opioid use (including changes in patterns of use), treatment retention, and/or global functioning and quality of life; and (4) adverse events, including the potential for opioid-related relapse or overdose, especially if the patient is not simultaneously taking maintenance MOR agonist or antagonist medications.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND RELEVANCE">Applying the recommendations provided here as well as considering input from people with lived experience in the design phase will accelerate the development, translation, and uptake of effective and safe therapeutics for individuals struggling with OUD.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kiluk</LastName><ForeName>Brian D</ForeName><Initials>BD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Yale School of Medicine, New Haven, Connecticut.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kleykamp</LastName><ForeName>Bethea A</ForeName><Initials>BA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Rochester School of Medicine and Dentistry, Rochester, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Comer</LastName><ForeName>Sandra D</ForeName><Initials>SD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division on Substance Use Disorders, New York State Psychiatric Institute, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Columbia University Irving Medical Center, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Griffiths</LastName><ForeName>Roland R</ForeName><Initials>RR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huhn</LastName><ForeName>Andrew S</ForeName><Initials>AS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Matthew W</ForeName><Initials>MW</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kampman</LastName><ForeName>Kyle M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pravetoni</LastName><ForeName>Marco</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, University of Washington School of Medicine, Harborview Medical Center, Seattle.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Preston</LastName><ForeName>Kenzie L</ForeName><Initials>KL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology and Therapeutics Research Branch, National Institute on Drug Abuse, National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Vandrey</LastName><ForeName>Ryan</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bergeria</LastName><ForeName>Cecilia L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bogenschutz</LastName><ForeName>Michael P</ForeName><Initials>MP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, NYU Grossman School of Medicine, New York University, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brown</LastName><ForeName>Randall T</ForeName><Initials>RT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine and Community Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison School of Medicine and Public Health, Madison.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dunn</LastName><ForeName>Kelly E</ForeName><Initials>KE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dworkin</LastName><ForeName>Robert H</ForeName><Initials>RH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Rochester School of Medicine and Dentistry, Rochester, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finan</LastName><ForeName>Patrick H</ForeName><Initials>PH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hendricks</LastName><ForeName>Peter S</ForeName><Initials>PS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Behavior, School of Public Health, University of Alabama at Birmingham.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Houtsmuller</LastName><ForeName>Elisabeth J</ForeName><Initials>EJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute, Washington, DC.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kosten</LastName><ForeName>Thomas R</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Michael E. DeBakey VA Medical Center, Houston, Texas.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Dustin C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Levin</LastName><ForeName>Frances R</ForeName><Initials>FR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division on Substance Use Disorders, New York State Psychiatric Institute, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia University, New York, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McRae-Clark</LastName><ForeName>Aimee</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raison</LastName><ForeName>Charles L</ForeName><Initials>CL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Human Development and Family Studies, School of Human Ecology, University of Wisconsin-Madison.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rasmussen</LastName><ForeName>Kurt</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Delix Therapeutics, Bedford, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Turk</LastName><ForeName>Dennis C</ForeName><Initials>DC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Washington School of Medicine, Seattle.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiss</LastName><ForeName>Roger D</ForeName><Initials>RD</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Alcohol, Drugs, and Addiction, McLean Hospital, Belmont, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strain</LastName><ForeName>Eric C</ForeName><Initials>EC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UH3 DA047711</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UH3 DA048386</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 DA051639</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K02 AA027300</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UG3 DA047711</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 FD005936</GrantID><Acronym>FD</Acronym><Agency>FDA HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UG3 DA048386</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013487">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JAMA Psychiatry</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101589550</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-622X</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000701">Analgesics, Opioid</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>40D3SCR4GZ</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D002047">Buprenorphine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000701" MajorTopicYN="N">Analgesics, Opioid</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058850" MajorTopicYN="N">Opiate Substitution Treatment</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002986" MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009293" MajorTopicYN="Y">Opioid-Related Disorders</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002047" MajorTopicYN="Y">Buprenorphine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>Dr Kiluk has received grants from the National Institute on Drug Abuse and National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism and personal fees from the Analgesic, Anesthetic, and Addiction Clinical Trial Translations, Innovations, Opportunities, and Networks (ACTTION) during the conduct of the study as well as personal fees from CBT4CBT and Sparian Biosciences outside the submitted work. Dr Kleykamp has received personal fees from ACTTION during the conduct of the study; personal fees from American Society of Addiction Medicine, Pinney Associates, Symplr, ECRI, STATinMED, and Palladian Associates; and honoraria from Filter Magazine and Next Avenue outside the submitted work. Dr Comer has received grants from Alkermes, Lyndra Therapeutics, IntraCellular Therapies, GoMedical, BioXcel, and Janssen as well as consulting fees from Mallinckrodt, Alkermes, Clinilabs, Opiant, Nektar, and Otsuka outside the submitted work. Dr Griffiths has received grants from the Steven and Alexandra Cohen Foundation and from Tim Ferris, Matt Mullenweg, Blake Mycoskie, and Craig Nerenberg during the conduct of the study as well as personal fees from the Heffter Research Institute outside the submitted work. Dr Johnson has received grants from the National Institutes of Health, the Heffter Research Institute, and Mydecine Innovations Group; personal fees from AJNA Labs, AWAKN Life Sciences, Beckley Psychedelic, Entheogen Biomedical, Mind Medicine, Field Trip Psychedelics, Silo Pharma, and Otsuka Pharmaceutical Development and Commercialization; and nonfinancial support from Mydecine Innovations Group outside the submitted work. Dr Kampman has received grants from US World Meds and Alkermes outside the submitted work. Dr Pravetoni has received grants from the National Institutes of Health during the conduct of the study and has a patent pending for disclosing technology related to vaccines and monoclonal antibodies and other treatment strategies for substance use disorders and overdose. Dr Vandrey has received personal fees from Canopy Health Innovations, MyMD Pharmaceuticals, Mira1a Pharmaceuticals, WebMD, Radicle Science, and Syqe Medical during the conduct of the study. Dr Bergeria has received grants from the National Institute on Drug Abuse and ACTTION during the conduct of the study as well as grants from Canopy Growth Corporation outside the submitted work. Dr Bogenschutz has received research funding from the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, National Institute on Drug Abuse, Heffter Research Institute, Mind Medicine, Tilray Canada, Multidisciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies (MAPS), B.More, Turnbull Family Foundation, Fournier Family Foundation, Dr Bronner&#x2019;s Family Foundation, and Riverstyx Foundation and from Rodrigo Nino, a philanthropic donor, as well as personal fees from the Heffter Research Institute, Ajna Labs, Beckley Psytech, Journey Colab, and Bright Minds Biosciences outside the submitted work. Dr Brown has received grants from the National Institutes of Health, Health Services and Resources Administration, Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, Usona Institute, Multi-Disciplinary Association for Psychedelic Studies, Etheridge Foundation, and Heffter Research Institute outside the submitted work. Dr Dunn has received grants from the National Institutes of Health as well as personal fees from Mind Medicine, Canopy Corporation, and Canopy-Beckley outside the submitted work. Dr Dworkin has received grants from US Food and Drug Administration and National Institutes of Health during the conduct of the study; personal fees from Abide, Acadia, Adynxx, Analgesic Solutions, Aptinyx, Aquinox, Asahi Kasei, Astellas, Beckley, Biogen, Biohaven, Biosplice, Boston Scientific, Braeburn, Cardialen, Celgene, Centrexion, Chiesi, Chromocell, Clexio, Collegium, Concert, Confo, Decibel, Editas, Eli Lilly, Endo, Eupraxia, Exicure, Glenmark, Gloriana, Grace, Hope, Lotus, Mainstay, Merck, Mind Medicine, Neumentum, Neurana, NeuroBo, Novaremed, Novartis, Oxford Cannabinoid Technologies, OliPass, Pfizer, Q-State, Reckitt Benckiser, Regenacy, Sangamo, Sanifit, Scilex, Semnur, SIMR Biotech, Sinfonia, SK Biopharmaceuticals, Sollis, SPRIM, Teva, Theranexus, Toray, Vertex, Vizuri, and WCG and holds equity in Ethismos, Regenacy, and Mind Medicine outside the submitted work. Dr Finan has received personal fees from Ninnion Therapeutics outside the submitted work. Dr Hendricks has received grants from the Heffter Research Institute and National Institutes of Health as well as personal fees from Bright Minds Biosciences, Eleusis Health Solutions, Reset Pharmaceuticals, and Silo Pharma outside the submitted work. Dr Kosten has received grants from the US Department of Defense, National Institutes of Health, Toomim Family Foundation, and John O&#x2019;Quinn Foundation as well as personal fees from Alkermes, Amygdala Neurosciences, Aptinyx, Arbor Pharma, Astellas, BioXcel, Boehringer Ingelheim, Braeburn, Data Analytics, Diamond, Embera, Epiodyne, Indivior, Intra-Cellular Therapies, Mallinckrodt, Medscape, Nektar, Nirsum, Novartis, Opiant, Otsuka, Pfizer, Phenex, Promentis, Relmada, Sage, United Neuroscience, US World Meds, and Zynerba. Dr Levin has received grants from US World Meds Medication, Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, and National Institute on Drug Abuse; personal fees from Major League Baseball; and nonfinancial support from Indivior outside the submitted work; and served on the scientific advisory boards of Alkermes, Indivior, Novartis, Teva, and US World Meds. Dr Raison has received personal fees from Usona Institute, Novartis, Alfasigma, Emory Healthcare, and Otsuka during the conduct of the study. Dr Rasmussen was Director of the Division of Therapeutics and Medical Consequences of the National Institute on Drug Abuse from 2018 to 2021. Dr Turk has received personal fees from GlaxoSmithKline/Novartis and nonfinancial support from Pfizer outside the submitted work and is Editor-in-Chief of the <i>Clinical Journal of Pain</i> and Associate Director of ACTTION. Dr Weiss has received personal fees from Alkermes, Cerevel Therapeutics, Takeda Pharmaceuticals, and Astellas Pharma outside the submitted work. Dr Strain has received personal fees from Caron, Cerevel, Elsevier, Fast Track Drugs and Biologics, Otsuka, Pear Therapeutics, and UpToDate as well as nonfinancial support from Masimo/Innovative Health Solutions outside the submitted work. No other disclosures were reported.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>11</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36449315</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1907289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10297827</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2022.4020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">2799201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Volkow ND, Woodcock J, Compton WM, et al. Medication development in opioid addiction: meaningful clinical end points. Sci Transl Med. 2018; 10(434):eaan2595. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.aan2595</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scitranslmed.aan2595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29593105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degenhardt L, Charlson F, Mathers B, et al. The global epidemiology and burden of opioid dependence: results from the Global Burden of Disease 2010 study. Addiction. 2014;109(8):1320&#x2013;1333. doi: 10.1111/add.12551</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.12551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24661272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hser Y-I, Mooney LJ, Saxon AJ, et al. High mortality among patients with opioid use disorder in a large healthcare system. J Addict Med. 2017;11 (4):315&#x2013;319. doi: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000312</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0000000000000312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5930020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28426439</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkow ND, Blanco C. Medications for opioid use disorders: clinical and pharmacological considerations. J Clin Invest. 2020;130(1):10&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1172/JCI134708</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1172/JCI134708</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6934219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31763992</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine; Health and Medicine Division; Board on Health Sciences Policy; Committee on Medication-Assisted Treatment for Opioid Use Disorder; Mancher M, Leshner AI, eds. Medications for Opioid Use Disorder Save Lives. National Academies Press; 2019.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30896911</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morgan JR, Schackman BR, Leff JA, Linas BP, Walley AY. Injectable naltrexone, oral naltrexone, and buprenorphine utilization and discontinuation among individuals treated for opioid use disorder in a United States commercially insured population. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2018;85:90&#x2013;96. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2017.07.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2017.07.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5750108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28733097</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JD, Nunes EV Jr, Novo P, et al. Comparative effectiveness of extended-release naltrexone versus buprenorphine-naloxone for opioid relapse prevention (X:BOT): a multicentre, open-label, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2018;391 (10118):309&#x2013;318. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32812-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(17)32812-X</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5806119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29150198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor AM, Cousins G, Durand L, Barry J, Boland F. Retention of patients in opioid substitution treatment: a systematic review. PLoS One. 2020;15(5):e0232086. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0232086</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0232086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7224511</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32407321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Volkow ND, Frieden TR, Hyde PS, Cha SS. Medication-assisted therapies&#x2013;tackling the opioid-overdose epidemic. N Engl J Med. 2014;370 (22):2063&#x2013;2066. doi: 10.1056/NEJMp1402780</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMp1402780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24758595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuehrlein BS, Ross DA. Opioid use disorder: a desperate need for novel treatments. Biol Psychiatry. 2017;81(7):e43&#x2013;e45. doi: 10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.01.014</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.01.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5712904</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28283055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen K, White DA, Acri JB. NIDA&#x2019;s medication development priorities in response to the opioid crisis: ten most wanted. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2019;44(4):657&#x2013;659. doi: 10.1038/s41386-018-0292-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-018-0292-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6372702</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30538289</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blanco C, Volkow ND. Management of opioid use disorder in the USA: present status and future directions. Lancet. 2019;393(10182):1760&#x2013;1772. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)33078-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)33078-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30878228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Strain EC, Kampman KM, Weiss RD. Moving beyond medications that act at the &#x3bc; receptor in the treatment of opioid use disorder. JAMA Psychiatry. 2021;78(7):701&#x2013;702. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.0259</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2021.0259</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33851964</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Analgesic, Anesthetic, and Addiction Clinical Trial Translations, Innovations, Opportunities, and Networks. Consortium for Addiction Research on Efficacy and Safety (CARES). Accessed
June 10, 2022. https://www.acttion.org/cares</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Food US and Administration Drug. Patient-focused drug development: collecting comprehensive and representative input. Accessed
July 27, 2021. https://www.fda.gov/regulatory-information/search-fda-guidance-documents/patient-focused-drug-development-collecting-comprehensive-and-representative-input</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dennis BB, Sanger N, Bawor M, et al. A call for consensus in defining efficacy in clinical trials for opioid addiction: combined results from a systematic review and qualitative study in patients receiving pharmacological assisted therapy for opioid use disorder. Trials. 2020;21(1):30. doi: 10.1186/s13063-019-3995-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-019-3995-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6945391</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31907000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cook NS, Cave J, Holtorf A-P. Patient preference studies during early drug development: aligning stakeholders to ensure development plans meet patient needs. Front Med (Lausanne). 2019;6:82. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2019.00082</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2019.00082</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6491461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31069227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallerstein N, Duran B. Community-based participatory research contributions to intervention research: the intersection of science and practice to improve health equity. Am J Public Health. 2010; 100(suppl 1):S40&#x2013;S46. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2009.184036</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2009.184036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2837458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20147663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheridan S, Schrandt S, Forsythe L, Hilliard TS, Paez KA; Advisory Panel on Patient Engagement (2013 Inaugural Panel). The PCORI Engagement Rubric: promising practices for partnering in research. Ann Fam Med. 2017;15(2):165&#x2013;170. doi: 10.1370/afm.2042</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1370/afm.2042</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5348236</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28289118</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humphreys K, Saitz R. Should physicians recommend replacing opioids with cannabis? JAMA. 2019;321(7):639&#x2013;640. doi: 10.1001/jama.2019.0077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2019.0077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30707218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurd YL. Cannabidiol: swinging the marijuana pendulum from &#x2018;weed&#x2019; to medication to treat the opioid epidemic. Trends Neurosci. 2017;40(3):124&#x2013;127. doi: 10.1016/j.tins.2016.12.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tins.2016.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28162799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hurd YL, Yoon M, Manini AF, et al. Early phase in the development of cannabidiol as a treatment for addiction: opioid relapse takes initial center stage. Neurotherapeutics. 2015;12(4):807&#x2013;815. doi: 10.1007/s13311-015-0373-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-015-0373-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4604178</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26269227</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lucas P Rationale for cannabis-based interventions in the opioid overdose crisis. Harm Reduct J. 2017;14(1):58. doi: 10.1186/s12954-017-0183-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12954-017-0183-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5563007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28821296</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bisaga A, Sullivan MA, Glass A, et al. The effects of dronabinol during detoxification and the initiation of treatment with extended release naltrexone. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2015;154:38&#x2013;45. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2015.05.013</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2015.05.013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4536087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26187456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jicha CJ, Lofwall MR, Nuzzo PA, Babalonis S, Elayi SC, Walsh SL. Safety of oral dronabinol during opioid withdrawal in humans. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2015;157:179&#x2013;183. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2015.09.031</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2015.09.031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4663169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26483357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lofwall MR, Babalonis S, Nuzzo PA, Elayi SC, Walsh SL. Opioid withdrawal suppression efficacy of oral dronabinol in opioid dependent humans. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2016;164:143&#x2013;150. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2016.05.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2016.05.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4910823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27234658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiese B, Wilson-Poe AR. Emerging evidence for cannabis&#x2019; role in opioid use disorder. Cannabis Cannabinoid Res. 2018;3(1):179&#x2013;189. doi: 10.1089/can.2018.0022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/can.2018.0022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6135562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30221197</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nichols DE, Johnson MW, Nichols CD. Psychedelics as medicines: an emerging new paradigm. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2017;101(2):209&#x2013;219. doi: 10.1002/cpt.557</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpt.557</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28019026</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Romeu A, Kersgaard B, Addy PH. Clinical applications of hallucinogens: a review. Exp Clin Psychopharmacol. 2016;24(4):229&#x2013;268. doi: 10.1037/pha0000084</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pha0000084</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5001686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27454674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krebs TS, Johansen P&#xd8;. Lysergic acid diethylamide (LSD) for alcoholism: meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Psychopharmacol. 2012;26(7):994&#x2013;1002. doi: 10.1177/0269881112439253</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881112439253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22406913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia-Romeu A, Davis AK, Erowid E, Erowid F, Griffiths RR, Johnson MW. Persisting reductions in cannabis, opioid, and stimulant misuse after naturalistic psychedelic use: an online survey. Front Psychiatry. 2020;10:955&#x2013;955. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00955</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2019.00955</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6987443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32038317</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pisano VD, Putnam NP, Kramer HM, Franciotti KJ, Halpern JH, Holden SC. The association of psychedelic use and opioid use disorders among illicit users in the United States. J Psychopharmacol. 2017;31(5):606&#x2013;613. doi: 10.1177/0269881117691453</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881117691453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belouin SJ, Henningfield JE. Psychedelics: where we are now, why we got here, what we must do. Neuropharmacology. 2018;142:7&#x2013;19. doi: 10.1016/j.neuropharm.2018.02.018</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2018.02.018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29476779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Argento E, Tupper KW, Socias ME. The tripping point: the potential role of psychedelic-assisted therapy in the response to the opioid crisis. Int J Drug Policy. 2019;66:80&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1016/j.drugpo.2018.11.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugpo.2018.11.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30743091</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheatle MD, Webster LR. Opioid therapy and sleep disorders: risks and mitigation strategies. Pain Med. 2015;16(suppl 1):S22&#x2013;S26. doi: 10.1111/pme.12910</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pme.12910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4608386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26461072</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huhn AS, Harris J, Cleveland HH, et al. Ecological momentary assessment of affect and craving in patients in treatment for prescription opioid dependence. Brain Res Bull. 2016;123:94&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1016/j.brainresbull.2016.01.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresbull.2016.01.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4919812</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26876756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lydon-Staley DM, Cleveland HH, Huhn AS, et al. Daily sleep quality affects drug craving, partially through indirect associations with positive affect, in patients in treatment for nonmedical use of prescription drugs. Addict Behav. 2017;65:275&#x2013;282. doi: 10.1016/j.addbeh.2016.08.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2016.08.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5140682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27544697</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fathi HR, Yoonessi A, Khatibi A, Rezaeitalab F, Rezaei-Ardani A. Crosstalk between sleep disturbance and opioid use disorder: a narrative review. Addict Health. 2020;12(2):140&#x2013;158. doi: 10.22122/ahj.v12i2.249</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.22122/ahj.v12i2.249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7395935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32782736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freeman LK, Gottfredson NC. Using ecological momentary assessment to assess the temporal relationship between sleep quality and cravings in individuals recovering from substance use disorders. Addict Behav. 2018;83:95&#x2013;101. doi: 10.1016/j.addbeh.2017.11.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2017.11.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7080296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29137841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolsen MR, Harvey AG. Life-time history of insomnia and hypersomnia symptoms as correlates of alcohol, cocaine and heroin use and relapse among adults seeking substance use treatment in the United States from 1991 to 1994. Addiction. 2017;112(6):1104&#x2013;1111. doi: 10.1111/add.13772</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.13772</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5407928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28127809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James MH, Fragale JE, Aurora RN, Cooperman NA, Langleben DD, Aston-Jones G. Repurposing the dual orexin receptor antagonist suvorexant for the treatment of opioid use disorder: why sleep on this any longer? Neuropsychopharmacology. 2020;45 (5):717&#x2013;719. doi: 10.1038/s41386-020-0619-x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-020-0619-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7265392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31986520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pravetoni M, Comer SD. Development of vaccines to treat opioid use disorders and reduce incidence of overdose. Neuropharmacology. 2019; 158:107662. doi: 10.1016/j.neuropharm.2019.06.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2019.06.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6919211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31173759</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baehr C, Pravetoni M. Vaccines to treat opioid use disorders and to reduce opioid overdoses. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2019;44(1):217&#x2013;218. doi: 10.1038/s41386-018-0197-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-018-0197-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6235930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30405185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bremer PT, Kimishima A, Schlosburg JE, Zhou B, Collins KC, Janda KD. Combatting synthetic designer opioids: a conjugate vaccine ablates lethal doses of fentanyl class drugs. Angew Chem Int Ed Engl. 2016;55(11):3772&#x2013;3775. doi: 10.1002/anie.201511654</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.201511654</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4860013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26879590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ohia-Nwoko O, Kosten TA, Haile CN. Animal models and the development of vaccines to treat substance use disorders. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2016; 126:263&#x2013;291. doi: 10.1016/bs.irn.2016.02.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.irn.2016.02.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27055616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tenney RD, Blake S, Bremer PT, et al. Vaccine blunts fentanyl potency in male rhesus monkeys. Neuropharmacology. 2019;158:107730. doi: 10.1016/j.neuropharm.2019.107730</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2019.107730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6745253</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31369740</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Townsend EA, Blake S, Faunce KE, et al. Conjugate vaccine produces long-lasting attenuation of fentanyl vs. food choice and blocks expression of opioid withdrawal-induced increases in fentanyl choice in rats. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2019;44(10):1681&#x2013;1689. doi: 10.1038/s41386-019-0385-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41386-019-0385-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6784909</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31043682</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Banks ML, Olson ME, Janda KD. Immunopharmacotherapies for treating opioid use disorder. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2018;39(11):908&#x2013;911. doi: 10.1016/j.tips.2018.08.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tips.2018.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6472257</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30343725</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raleigh MD, King SJ, Baruffaldi F, et al. Pharmacological mechanisms underlying the efficacy of antibodies generated by a vaccine to treat oxycodone use disorder. Neuropharmacology. 2021;195:108653. doi: 10.1016/j.neuropharm.2021.108653</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2021.108653</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8410661</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34126123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baehr C, Kelcher AH, Khaimraj A, et al. Monoclonal antibodies counteract opioid-induced behavioral and toxic effects in mice and rats. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2020;375(3):469&#x2013;477. doi: 10.1124/jpet.120.000124</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1124/jpet.120.000124</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7718726</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32980813</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Savage C, McCabe OL. Residential psychedelic (LSD) therapy for the narcotic addict. a controlled study. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1973;28(6):808&#x2013;814. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.1973.01750360040005</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.1973.01750360040005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4575166</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein MD, Kurth ME, Sharkey KM, Anderson BJ, Corso RP, Millman RP. Trazodone for sleep disturbance during methadone maintenance: a double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2012;120(1&#x2013;3):65&#x2013;73. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2011.06.026</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2011.06.026</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3214692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21798674</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akbarzadeh A, Norouzian D, Farhangi A, et al. Immunotherapy of 347 volunteer outpatient morphine addicts by human therapeutic morphine vaccine in Kermanshah Province of Iran. J Pharmacol Toxicol. 2009;4:30&#x2013;35. doi: 10.3923/jpt.2009.30.35</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3923/jpt.2009.30.35</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinical Trials of Multivalent Opioid Vaccine Components. ClinicalTrials.gov identifier: NCT04458545. Updated July 5, 2022.
Accessed
August 20, 2022. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04458545</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ekhtiari H, Tavakoli H, Addolorato G, et al. Transcranial electrical and magnetic stimulation (tES and TMS) for addiction medicine: a consensus paper on the present state of the science and the road ahead. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2019;104:118&#x2013;140. doi: 10.1016/j.neubiorev.2019.06.007</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neubiorev.2019.06.007</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7293143</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31271802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford I, Norrie J. Pragmatic trials. N Engl J Med. 2016;375(5):454&#x2013;463. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra1510059</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra1510059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27518663</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pallmann P, Bedding AW, Choodari-Oskooei B, et al. Adaptive designs in clinical trials: why use them, and how to run and report them. BMC Med. 2018;16(1):29. doi: 10.1186/s12916-018-1017-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-018-1017-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5830330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29490655</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dugosh K, Abraham A, Seymour B, McLoyd K, Chalk M, Festinger D. A systematic review on the use of psychosocial interventions in conjunction with medications for the treatment of opioid addiction. J Addict Med. 2016;10(2):93&#x2013;103. doi: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000193</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0000000000000193</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4795974</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26808307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mauri L, D&#x2019;Agostino RB Sr. Challenges in the design and interpretation of noninferiority trials. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(14):1357&#x2013;1367. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra1510063</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra1510063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28976859</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uscher-Pines L, Huskamp HA, Mehrotra A. Treating patients with opioid use disorder in their homes: an emerging treatment model. JAMA. 2020;324(1):39&#x2013;40. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.3940</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2020.3940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459292</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ho C, Arg&#xe1;ez C. Telehealth-Delivered Opioid Agonist Therapy for the Treatment of Adults With Opioid Use Disorder: Review of Clinical Effectiveness, Cost-effectiveness, and Guidelines. Canadian Agency for Drugs and Technologies in Health; 2018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30817107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dahne J, Tomko RL, McClure EA, Obeid JS, Carpenter MJ. Remote methods for conducting tobacco-focused clinical trials. Nicotine Tob Res. 2020;22(12):2134&#x2013;2140. doi: 10.1093/ntr/ntaa105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ntr/ntaa105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454765</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32531046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley D, Delargy I. A national model of remote care for assessing and providing opioid agonist treatment during the COVID-19 pandemic: a report. Harm Reduct J. 2020;17(1):49. doi: 10.1186/s12954-020-00394-z</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12954-020-00394-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7366558</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32680520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell MM, Mendelson J, Gryczynski J, Carswell SB, Schwartz RP. A novel telehealth platform for alcohol use disorder treatment: preliminary evidence of reductions in drinking. Am J Drug Alcohol Abuse. 2020;46(3):297&#x2013;303. doi: 10.1080/00952990.2019.1658197</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00952990.2019.1658197</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31596648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Korthuis PT, McCarty D, Weimer M, et al. Primary care&#x2013;based models for the treatment of opioid use disorder: a scoping review. Ann Intern Med. 2017;166(4):268&#x2013;278. doi: 10.7326/M16-2149</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M16-2149</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5504692</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27919103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donroe JH, Bhatraju EP, Tsui JI, Edelman EJ. Identification and management of opioid use disorder in primary care: an update. Curr Psychiatry Rep. 2020;22(5):23. doi: 10.1007/s11920-020-01149-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11920-020-01149-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32285215</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hendricks PS, Copes H, Family N, Williams LT, Luke D, Raz S. Perceptions of safety, subjective effects, and beliefs about the clinical utility of lysergic acid diethylamide in healthy participants within a novel intervention paradigm: qualitative results from a proof-of-concept study. J Psychopharmacol. 2022;36(3):337&#x2013;347. doi: 10.1177/02698811211055855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02698811211055855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35253517</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Family N, Hendricks PS, Williams LT, et al. Safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics, and subjective effects of 50, 75, and 100 &#x3bc;g LSD in healthy participants within a novel intervention paradigm: a proof-of-concept study. J Psychopharmacol. 2022;36(3):321&#x2013;336. doi: 10.1177/02698811211069103</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02698811211069103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35253516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Priester MA, Browne T, Iachini A, Clone S, DeHart D, Seay KD. Treatment access barriers and disparities among individuals with co-occurring mental health and substance use disorders: an integrative literature review. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2016;61:47&#x2013;59. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2015.09.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2015.09.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4695242</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26531892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olfson M, Zhang VS, Schoenbaum M, King M. Trends in buprenorphine treatment in the United States, 2009&#x2013;2018. JAMA. 2020;323(3):276&#x2013;277. doi: 10.1001/jama.2019.18913</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2019.18913</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6990679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31961408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon AJ, Drexler K, Hawkins EJ, et al. Stepped Care for Opioid Use Disorder Train the Trainer (SCOUTT) initiative: expanding access to medication treatment for opioid use disorder within Veterans Health Administration facilities. Subst Abus. 2020;41(3):275&#x2013;282. doi: 10.1080/08897077.2020.1787299</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08897077.2020.1787299</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7849630</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32697170</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Short VL, Hand DJ, MacAfee L, Abatemarco DJ, Terplan M. Trends and disparities in receipt of pharmacotherapy among pregnant women in publically funded treatment programs for opioid use disorder in the United States. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2018;89:67&#x2013;74. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2018.04.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2018.04.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29706175</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eghaneyan BH, Sanchez K, Haeny AM, et al. Hispanic participants in the National Institute on Drug Abuse&#x2019;s Clinical Trials Network: a scoping review of two decades of research. Addict Behav Rep. 2020;12:100287. doi: 10.1016/j.abrep.2020.100287</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.abrep.2020.100287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7330873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32637563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinedo M A current re-examination of racial/ethnic disparities in the use of substance abuse treatment: do disparities persist? Drug Alcohol Depend. 2019;202:162&#x2013;167. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2019.05.017</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2019.05.017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10676029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31352305</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abraham AJ, Andrews CM, Yingling ME, Shannon J. Geographic disparities in availability of opioid use disorder treatment for Medicaid enrollees. Health Serv Res. 2018;53(1):389&#x2013;404. doi: 10.1111/1475-6773.12686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1475-6773.12686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5785305</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28345210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stahler GJ, Mennis J. Treatment outcome disparities for opioid users: are there racial and ethnic differences in treatment completion across large US metropolitan areas? Drug Alcohol Depend. 2018;190:170&#x2013;178. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2018.06.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2018.06.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30041092</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Biondi BE, Zheng X, Frank CA, Petrakis I, Springer SA. A literature review examining primary outcomes of medication treatment studies for opioid use disorder: what outcome should be used to measure opioid treatment success? Am J Addict. 2020;29(4):249&#x2013;267. doi: 10.1111/ajad.13051</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajad.13051</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7377168</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32346932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>US Food and Drug Administration. Opioid use disorder: endpoints for demonstrating effectiveness of drugs for treatment guidance for industry. Accessed
July
27, 2021. https://www.fda.gov/regulatory-information/search-fda-guidance-documents/opioid-use-disorder-endpointsdemonstrating-effectiveness-drugs-treatment-guidance-industry</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiluk BD, Fitzmaurice GM, Strain EC, Weiss RD. What defines a clinically meaningful outcome in the treatment of substance use disorders: reductions in direct consequences of drug use or improvement in overall functioning? Addiction. 2019;114(1):9&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1111/add.14289</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.14289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29900624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fitzmaurice GM, Lipsitz SR, Weiss RD. Within-treatment frequency of use versus abstinence as a predictor of longitudinal post-treatment follow-up assessments of drug use. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2020;208:107857. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2020.107857</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2020.107857</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039756</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31968301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Timko C, Schultz NR, Cucciare MA, Vittorio L, Garrison-Diehn C. Retention in medication-assisted treatment for opiate dependence: a systematic review. J Addict Dis. 2016;35(1):22&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1080/10550887.2016.1100960</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10550887.2016.1100960</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6542472</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26467975</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsden J, Tai B, Ali R, Hu L, Rush AJ, Volkow N. Measurement-based care using DSM-5 for opioid use disorder: can we make opioid medication treatment more effective? Addiction. 2019;114(8):1346&#x2013;1353. doi: 10.1111/add.14546</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.14546</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6766896</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614096</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiluk BD, Frankforter TL, Cusumano M, Nich C, Carroll KM. Change in DSM-5 alcohol use disorder criteria count and severity level as a treatment outcome indicator: results from a randomized trial. Alcohol Clin Exp Res. 2018. doi: 10.1111/acer.13807</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acer.13807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6281805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29870051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cousins G, Teljeur C, Motterlini N, McCowan C, Dimitrov BD, Fahey T. Risk of drug-related mortality during periods of transition in methadone maintenance treatment: a cohort study. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2011;41(3):252&#x2013;260. doi: 10.1016/j.jsat.2011.05.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2011.05.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21696913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sordo L, Barrio G, Bravo MJ, et al. Mortality risk during and after opioid substitution treatment: systematic review and meta-analysis of cohort studies. BMJ. 2017;357:j1550. doi: 10.1136/bmj.j1550</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.j1550</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5421454</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28446428</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dunn KE, Barrett FS, Yepez-Laubach C, et al. Brief Opioid Overdose Knowledge (BOOK): a questionnaire to assess overdose knowledge in individuals who use illicit or prescribed opioids. J Addict Med. 2016;10(5):314&#x2013;323. doi: 10.1097/ADM.0000000000000235</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0000000000000235</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5042823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27504923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McLarnon ME, Monaghan TL, Stewart SH, Barrett SP. Drug misuse and diversion in adults prescribed anxiolytics and sedatives. Pharmacotherapy. 2011;31(3):262&#x2013;272. doi: 10.1592/phco.31.3.262</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1592/phco.31.3.262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21361736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasin DS, Sarvet AL, Cerd&#xe1; M, et al. US adult illicit cannabis use, cannabis use disorder, and medical marijuana laws: 1991&#x2013;1992 to 2012&#x2013;2013. JAMA Psychiatry. 2017;74(6):579&#x2013;588. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0724</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.0724</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5539836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28445557</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sellers EM, Leiderman DB. Psychedelic drugs as therapeutics: no illusions about the challenges. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2018;103(4):561&#x2013;564. doi: 10.1002/cpt.776</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cpt.776</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28836272</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell JM, Bogenschutz M, Lilienstein A, et al. MDMA-assisted therapy for severe PTSD: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 study. Nat Med. 2021;27(6):1025&#x2013;1033. doi: 10.1038/s41591-021-01336-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-021-01336-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8205851</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33972795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comer SD, Pravetoni M, Coop A, Baumann MH, Cunningham CW. Potential unintended consequences of class-wide drug scheduling based on chemical structure: a cautionary tale for fentanyl-related compounds. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2021;221:108530. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2021.108530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2021.108530</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Palamar JJ, Ciccarone D, Rutherford C, Keyes KM, Carr TH, Cottler LB. Trends in seizures of powders and pills containing illicit fentanyl in the United States, 2018 through 2021. Drug Alcohol Depend. 2022;234:109398. doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2022.109398</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2022.109398</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9027012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35370014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunetti P, Pirani F, Carlier J, Giorgetti R, Busard&#xf2; FP, Lo Faro AFA. A 2017&#x2013;2019 update on acute intoxications and fatalities from illicit fentanyl and analogs. J Anal Toxicol. 2021;45(6):537&#x2013;554. doi: 10.1093/jat/bkaa115</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jat/bkaa115</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>