<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37091101</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2633-4895</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>3</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Implementation research and practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Implement Res Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Approaches for implementing digital interventions for alcohol use disorders in primary care: A qualitative, user-centered design study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>26334895221135264</StartPage><MedlinePgn>26334895221135264</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26334895221135264</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/26334895221135264</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Digital interventions, such as smartphone apps, can be effective in treating alcohol use disorders (AUD). However, efforts to integrate digital interventions into primary care have been challenging. To inform successful implementation, we sought to understand how patients and clinicians preferred to use apps in routine primary care.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study combined user-centered design and qualitative research methods, interviewing 18 primary care patients with AUD and nine primary care clinicians on topics such as prior experiences with digital tools, and design preferences regarding approaches for offering apps for AUD in primary care. Interviews were recorded and transcribed for template analysis whereby a priori codes were based on interview topics and refined through iterative coding. New codes and cross-cutting themes emerged from the data.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Patient participants with AUD indicated they would be more likely to engage in treatment if primary care team members were involved in their use of apps. They also preferred to see clinicians "invested" and recommended that clinicians ask about app use and progress during follow-up appointments or check-ins. Clinician participants valued the opportunity to offer apps to their patients but noted that workflows would need to be tailored to individual patient needs. Time pressures, implementation complexity, and lack of appropriate staffing were cited as barriers. Clinicians proposed concrete solutions (e.g., education, tools, and staffing models) that could improve their ability to use apps within the constraints of primary care and suggested that some patients could potentially use apps without clinician support.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A user-centered approach to engaging patients in digital alcohol interventions in primary care may require personalized support for both initiation and follow-up. Meeting patients' needs likely require increased staffing and efficient workflows in primary care. Health systems should consider offering multiple pathways for enrolling patients in apps to accommodate individual preferences and contextual barriers.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="PLAIN LANGUAGE SUMMARY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Healthcare systems have begun using app-based treatments to help patients manage their health conditions, including alcohol use disorders. Some apps have been tested in research studies and appear to be effective. However, it is difficult for healthcare teams to offer apps to patients. Clinicians must engage in new activities that they have not done before, such as "teaching" patients to use apps and checking in on their use of the apps. Identifying how to use apps in routine healthcare is critical to their successful implementation. This study interviewed 27 people, including healthcare providers and patients in primary care, to uncover the most optimal ways to offer apps to patients with alcohol use disorders. The interviews combined the use of qualitative research methods and user-centered design. Results suggest that to use to address alcohol use disorders, primary care teams should be prepared to offer personalized support to patients. Both patient and clinician interviewees said that the steps required to use apps must be intuitive and simple. Patients could gain more benefits if clinicians introduced the apps and guided patients to use them, as opposed to making apps available for patients to download and use on their own. However, the exact approach to offering apps would depend on a given patient's preferences and the extent that staffing was available in the clinic to support patients. Health systems should be prepared to offer and support patients in their use of apps, which should accommodate patient preferences and the constraints of the clinic.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glass</LastName><ForeName>Joseph E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2923-3698</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tiffany</LastName><ForeName>Brooks</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matson</LastName><ForeName>Theresa E</ForeName><Initials>TE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lim</LastName><ForeName>Catherine</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gundersen</LastName><ForeName>Gabrielle</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5530-5184</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kimbel</LastName><ForeName>Kilian</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartzler</LastName><ForeName>Andrea L</ForeName><Initials>AL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Informatics and Medical Education, School of Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Curran</LastName><ForeName>Geoffrey M</ForeName><Initials>GM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Departments of Pharmacy Practice and Psychiatry, University of Arkansas for Medical Sciences, Little Rock, AR, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Central Arkansas Veterans Healthcare System, Little Rock, AR, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">19961</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McWethy</LastName><ForeName>Angela Garza</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Mental Health &amp; Wellness Services, Renton, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caldeiro</LastName><ForeName>Ryan M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Mental Health &amp; Wellness Services, Renton, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bradley</LastName><ForeName>Katharine A</ForeName><Initials>KA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Implement Res Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101774031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2633-4895</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">alcohol use disorders</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital interventions</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implementation science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primary care</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author(s) declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: Several authors (JEG, RMC, KAB) are investigators on a trial funded by the National Institute on Drug Abuse (R01DA047954; PI: Glass), which evaluates the implementation of reSET and reSET-O, which are digital therapeutics for substance use disorder marketed by Pear Therapeutics, Inc. Pear Therapeutics Inc provided digital therapeutic prescriptions at no cost to Kaiser Permanente Washington during a quality improvement pilot study that preceded the implementation trial. JEG is a coinvestigator on a Small Business Innovation Award funded awarded to Pear Therapeutics, Inc by the National Institute on Drug Abuse, which evaluates potential improvements to reSET-O (R44DA042652). This study is informing our research on the implementation of digital therapeutics, but Pear Therapeutics, Inc was not involved in this study and does not provide funding to the authors</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>24</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>51</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37091101</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9924279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/26334895221135264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_26334895221135264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Auerbach A. D. (2019). Evaluating digital health tools-prospective, experimental, and real world. JAMA Internal Medicine, 179(6), 840&#x2013;841. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.7229</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.7229</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30801610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry C. L., Epstein A. J., Fiellin D. A., Fraenkel L., Busch S. H. (2016). Estimating demand for primary care-based treatment for substance and alcohol use disorders. Addiction, 111(8), 1376&#x2013;1384. 10.1111/add.13364</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.13364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4940268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26899802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bernard H. R., Ryan G. W. (2002). Research methods in anthropology: Qualitative and quantitative methods. AltaMira Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beyer H., Holtzblatt K. (1998). Contextual design. Morgan Kaufman.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel W. K., Marsch L. A., Buchhalter A. R., Badger G. J. (2008). Computerized behavior therapy for opioid-dependent outpatients: A randomized controlled trial. Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology, 16(2), 132&#x2013;143. 10.1037/1064-1297.16.2.132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1064-1297.16.2.132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18489017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodenheimer T., Willard-Grace R., Ghorob A. (2014). Expanding the roles of medical assistants: Who does what in primary care? JAMA Internal Medicine, 174(7), 1025&#x2013;1026. 10.1001/jamainternmed.2014.1319</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamainternmed.2014.1319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24820220</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell A. N., Nunes E. V., Matthews A. G., Stitzer M., Miele G. M., Polsky D., Turrigiano E., Walters S., McClure E. A., Kyle T. L., Wahle A., Van Veldhuisen P., Goldman B., Babcock D., Stabile P. Q., Winhusen T., Ghitza U. E. (2014). Internet-delivered treatment for substance abuse: A multisite randomized controlled trial. American Journal of Psychiatry, 171(6), 683&#x2013;690. 10.1176/appi.ajp.2014.13081055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2014.13081055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4079279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24700332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carayon P. (2009). The balance theory and the work system model &#x2026; twenty years later. International Journal of Human&#x2013;Computer Interaction, 25(5), 313&#x2013;327. 10.1080/10447310902864928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10447310902864928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and
Prevention. (2015a). Alcohol and public
health: Data, trends, and maps. Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention. Retrieved June 12, 2021,
from http://www.cdc.gov/alcohol/quickstats/binge_drinking.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Center for Disease Control and
Prevention. (2015b). Fact sheets&#x2014;Binge
drinking. Center for Disease Control and
Prevention. Retrieved June 12, 2021, from
http://www.cdc.gov/alcohol/quickstats/binge_drinking.htm</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chernof B. A., Sherman S. E., Lanto A. B., Lee M. L., Yano E. M., Rubenstein L. V. (1999). Health habit counseling amidst competing demands: Effects of patient health habits and visit characteristics. Medical Care, 37(8), 738&#x2013;747. 10.1097/00005650-199908000-00004</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005650-199908000-00004</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10448717</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen D. R., Landes R. D., Jackson L., Marsch L. A., Mancino M. J., Chopra M. P., Bickel W. K. (2014). Adding an internet-delivered treatment to an efficacious treatment package for opioid dependence. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 82(6), 964&#x2013;972. 10.1037/a0037496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0037496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4244262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25090043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. W. (2013). Qualitative inquiry &amp; research design: Choosing among five approaches (3rd ed.). Sage.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crowley R. A., Kirschner N., Health &amp; Public Policy Committee of the American College of Physicians. (2015). The integration of care for mental health, substance abuse, and other behavioral health conditions into primary care: Executive summary of an American college of physicians position paper. Annals of Internal Medicine, 163(4), 298&#x2013;299. 10.7326/M15-0510</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/M15-0510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26121401</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degenhardt L., Hall W. (2012). Extent of illicit drug use and dependence, and their contribution to the global burden of disease. The Lancet, 379(9810), 55&#x2013;70. 10.1016/S0140-6736(11)61138-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)61138-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22225671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopp A. R., Parisi K. E., Munson S. A., Lyon A. R. (2019). A glossary of user-centered design strategies for implementation experts. Translational Behavioral Medicine, 9(6), 1057&#x2013;1064. 10.1093/tbm/iby119</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tbm/iby119</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30535343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dopp A. R., Parisi K. E., Munson S. A., Lyon A. R. (2020). Aligning implementation and user-centered design strategies to enhance the impact of health services: Results from a concept mapping study. Implementation Science Communications, 1, 17. 10.1186/s43058-020-00020-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s43058-020-00020-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7427975</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32885179</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley P., Steinberg D., Levine E., Askew S., Batch B. C., Puleo E. M., Svetkey L. P., Bosworth H. B., DeVries A., Miranda H., Bennett G. G. (2016). Track: A randomized controlled trial of a digital health obesity treatment intervention for medically vulnerable primary care patients. Contemporary Clinical Trials, 48, 12&#x2013;20. 10.1016/j.cct.2016.03.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2016.03.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4885789</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26995281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghitza U. E., Tai B. (2014). Challenges and opportunities for integrating preventive substance-use-care services in primary care through the affordable care act. Journal of Health Care for the Poor and Underserved, 25(1 Suppl), 36&#x2013;45. 10.1353/hpu.2014.0067</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1353/hpu.2014.0067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3984935</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24583486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass J. E., Bobb J. F., Lee A. K., Richards J. E., Lapham G. T., Ludman E., Achtmeyer C., Caldeiro R. M., Parrish R., Williams E. C., Lozano P., Bradley K. A. (2018). Study protocol: A cluster-randomized trial implementing sustained patient-centered alcohol-related care (SPARC trial). Implementation Science, 13(1), 108. 10.1186/s13012-018-0795-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-018-0795-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6080376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30081930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass J. E., Matson T. E., Lim C., Hartzler A. L., Kimbel K., Lee A. K., Beatty T., Parrish R., Caldeiro R. M., Garza McWethy A., Curran G. M., Bradley K. A. (2021). Approaches for implementing app-based digital treatments for drug use disorders into primary care: A qualitative, user-centered design study of patient perspectives. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 23(7), e25866. 10.2196/25866</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/25866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8293157</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34255666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass J. E., McKay J. R., Gustafson D. H., Kornfield R., Rathouz P. J., McTavish F. M., Atwood A. K., Isham A., Quanbeck A., Shah D. (2017). Treatment seeking as a mechanism of change in a randomized controlled trial of a mobile health intervention to support recovery from alcohol use disorders. Journal of Substance Abuse Treatment, 77, 57&#x2013;66. 10.1016/j.jsat.2017.03.011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2017.03.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5880274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28476273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass J. E., Perron B. E., Ilgen M. A., Chermack S. T., Ratliff S., Zivin K. (2010). Prevalence and correlates of specialty substance use disorder treatment for department of veterans affairs healthcare system patients with high alcohol consumption. Drug and Alcohol Dependence, 112(1&#x2013;2), 150&#x2013;155. 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2010.06.003</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2010.06.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2967645</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20656425</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham A. K., Greene C. J., Kwasny M. J., Kaiser S. M., Lieponis P., Powell T., Mohr D. C. (2020). Coached mobile app platform for the treatment of depression and anxiety among primary care patients: A randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry, 77(9), 906&#x2013;914. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.1011</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2020.1011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7240649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32432695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham A. K., Greene C. J., Powell T., Lieponis P., Lunsford A., Peralta C. D., Orr L. C., Kaiser S. M., Alam N., Berhane H., Kalan O., Mohr D. C. (2020). Lessons learned from service design of a trial of a digital mental health service: Informing implementation in primary care clinics. Translational Behavioral Medicine, 10(3), 598&#x2013;605. 10.1093/tbm/ibz140</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tbm/ibz140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7413191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32766862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham A. K., Lattie E. G., Powell B. J., Lyon A. R., Smith J. D., Schueller S. M., Stadnick N. A., Brown C. H., Mohr D. C. (2020). Implementation strategies for digital mental health interventions in health care settings. American Psychologist, 75(8), 1080&#x2013;1092. 10.1037/amp0000686</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/amp0000686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7709140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graneheim U. H., Lundman B. (2004). Qualitative content analysis in nursing research: Concepts, procedures and measures to achieve trustworthiness. Nurse Education Today, 24(2), 105&#x2013;112. 10.1016/j.nedt.2003.10.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nedt.2003.10.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant B. F., Goldstein R. B., Saha T. D., Chou S. P., Jung J., Zhang H., Pickering R. P., Ruan W. J., Smith S. M., Huang B., Hasin D. S. (2015). Epidemiology of DSM-5 alcohol use disorder: Results from the national epidemiologic survey on alcohol and related conditions III. JAMA Psychiatry, 72(8), 757&#x2013;766. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.0584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.0584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5240584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26039070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustafson D. H., McTavish F. M., Chih M.-Y., Atwood A. K., Johnson R. A., Boyle M. G., Levy M. S., Driscoll H., Chisholm S. M., Dillenburg L., Isham A., Shah D. (2014). A smartphone application to support recovery from alcoholism: A randomized clinical trial. JAMA Psychiatry, 71(5), 566&#x2013;572. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2013.4642</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2013.4642</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4016167</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24671165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hermes E. D., Lyon A. R., Schueller S. M., Glass J. E. (2019). Measuring the implementation of behavioral intervention technologies: Recharacterization of established outcomes. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 21(1), e11752. 10.2196/11752</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/11752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6367669</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30681966</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine. (2006). Improving the quality of health care for mental and substance-use conditions. National Academy Press.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20669433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>International Organization for
Standardization. (2019). <i>Ergonomics
of human&#x2013;system interaction&#x2014;Part 210: Human-centred design for
interactive systems. I.-. 2019</i>. (2nd ed).
Switzerland.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jaen C. R., Stange K. C., Nutting P. A. (1994). Competing demands of primary care: A model for the delivery of clinical preventive services. The Journal of Family Practice, 38(2), 166&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8308509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kaner E. F., Beyer F. R., Garnett C., Crane D., Brown J., Muirhead C., Redmore J., O&#x2019;Donnell A., Newham J. J., de Vocht F., Hickman M., Brown H., Maniatopoulos G., Michie S. (2017). Personalised digital interventions for reducing hazardous and harmful alcohol consumption in community-dwelling populations. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, 9, CD011479. 10.1002/14651858.CD011479.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011479.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6483779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28944453</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiluk B. D., Devore K. A., Buck M. B., Nich C., Frankforter T. L., LaPaglia D. M., Yates B. T., Gordon M. A., Carroll K. M. (2016). Randomized trial of computerized cognitive behavioral therapy for alcohol use disorders: Efficacy as a virtual stand-alone and treatment add-on compared with standard outpatient treatment. Alcoholism: Clinical and Experimental Research, 40(9), 1991&#x2013;2000. 10.1111/acer.13162</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acer.13162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5008977</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27488212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kiluk B. D., Ray L. A., Walthers J., Bernstein M., Tonigan J. S., Magill M. (2019). Technology-delivered cognitive-behavioral interventions for alcohol use: A meta-analysis. Alcoholism: Clinical and Experimental Research, 43(11), 2285&#x2013;2295. 10.1111/acer.14189</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/acer.14189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6824956</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31566787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>King N. (2004). Using templates in the thematic analysis of text. In Cassell C., Symon G. (Eds.), Essential guide to qualitative methods in organizational research (pp. 256&#x2013;270). London: SAGE Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knowles S. E., Lovell K., Bower P., Gilbody S., Littlewood E., Lester H. (2015). Patient experience of computerised therapy for depression in primary care. BMJ Open, 5(11), e008581. 10.1136/bmjopen-2015-008581</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2015-008581</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4679833</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26621513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lapham G. T., Hawkins E. J., Chavez L. J., Achtmeyer C. E., Williams E. C., Thomas R. M., Ludman E. J., Kypri K., Hunt S. C., Bradley K. A. (2012). Feedback from recently returned veterans on an anonymous web-based brief alcohol intervention. Addiction Science &amp; Clinical Practice, 7(1), 17. 10.1186/1940-0640-7-17</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1940-0640-7-17</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3507636</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23186354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lattie E. G., Nicholas J., Knapp A. A., Skerl J. J., Kaiser S. M., Mohr D. C. (2020). Opportunities for and tensions surrounding the use of technology-enabled mental health services in community mental health care. Administration and Policy in Mental Health and Mental Health Services Research, 47(1), 138&#x2013;149. 10.1007/s10488-019-00979-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10488-019-00979-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6946841</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31535235</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacQueen K. M., McLellan E., Kay K., Milstein B. (1998). Codebook development for team-based qualitative analysis. Field Methods, 10(2), 31&#x2013;36. 10.1177/1525822X980100020301</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1525822X980100020301</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mares M. L., Gustafson D. H., Glass J. E., Quanbeck A., McDowell H., McTavish F., Atwood A. K., Marsch L. A., Thomas C., Shah D., Brown R., Isham A., Nealon M. J., Ward V. (2016). Implementing an mHealth system for substance use disorders in primary care: A mixed methods study of clinicians&#x2019; initial expectations and first year experiences. BMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making, 16(1), 126. 10.1186/s12911-016-0365-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-016-0365-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5043521</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27687632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsch L. A., Guarino H., Acosta M., Aponte-Melendez Y., Cleland C., Grabinski M., Brady R., Edwards J. (2014). Web-based behavioral treatment for substance use disorders as a partial replacement of standard methadone maintenance treatment. Journal of Substance Abuse Treatment, 46(1), 43&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.jsat.2013.08.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2013.08.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3839618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24060350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller C. J., Barnett M. L., Baumann A. A., Gutner C. A., Wiltsey-Stirman S. (2021). The FRAME-IS: A framework for documenting modifications to implementation strategies in healthcare. Implementation Science, 16(1), 36. 10.1186/s13012-021-01105-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-021-01105-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8024675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr D. C., Cuijpers P., Lehman K. (2011). Supportive accountability: A model for providing human support to enhance adherence to eHealth interventions. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 13(1), e30. 10.2196/jmir.1602</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.1602</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3221353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21393123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohr D. C., Lyon A. R., Lattie E. G., Reddy M., Schueller S. M. (2017). Accelerating digital mental health research from early design and creation to successful implementation and sustainment. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 19(5), e153. 10.2196/jmir.7725</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.7725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5443926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28490417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokdad A. H., Marks J. S., Stroup D. F., Gerberding J. L. (2004). Actual causes of death in the United States, 2000. JAMA, 291(10), 1238&#x2013;1245. 10.1001/jama.291.10.1238</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.291.10.1238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15010446</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mordecai D., Histon T., Neuwirth E., Heisler W. S., Kraft A., Bang Y., Franchino K., Taillac C., Nixon J. P. (2021). How Kaiser Permanente created a mental health and wellness digital ecosystem. NEJM Catalyst, 2(1), 1&#x2013;21. 10.1056/CAT.20.0295</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/CAT.20.0295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mu&#xf1;oz R. F. (2017). The efficiency model of support and the creation of digital apothecaries. Clinical Psychology: Science and Practice, 24(1), 46&#x2013;49. 10.1111/cpsp.12174</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cpsp.12174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Council for Mental
Wellbeing. (2018). <i>Implementing care
for alcohol &amp; other drug use in medical settings: An extension of
SBIRT</i>. Retrieved June 12, 2021 from https://www.thenationalcouncil.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/021518_NCBH_ASPTReport-FINAL.pdf?daf=375ateTbd56</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute on Alcohol Abuse
and Alcoholism. (2007). Helping patients who
drink too much: A clinician&#x2019;s guide (updated 2005 edition).
National Institutes of Health, U.S. Department of Health and
Human Services. Retrieved June 12, 2021, from
https://pubs.niaaa.nih.gov/publications/practitioner/cliniciansguide2005/guide.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Connor S., Hanlon P., O&#x2019;Donnell C. A., Garcia S., Glanville J., Mair F. S. (2016). Understanding factors affecting patient and public engagement and recruitment to digital health interventions: A systematic review of qualitative studies. BMC Medical Informatics and Decision Making, 16(1), 120. 10.1186/s12911-016-0359-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12911-016-0359-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5024516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27630020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Padgett D. (2008). Qualitative methods in social work research (2nd ed.). Sage Publications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Perry C. K., Damschroder L. J., Hemler J. R., Woodson T. T., Ono S. S., Cohen D. J. (2019). Specifying and comparing implementation strategies across seven large implementation interventions: A practical application of theory. Implementation Science, 14(1), 32. 10.1186/s13012-019-0876-4</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-019-0876-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6429753</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30898133</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell B. J., McMillen J. C., Proctor E. K., Carpenter C. R., Griffey R. T., Bunger A. C., Glass J. E., York J. L. (2012). A compilation of strategies for implementing clinical innovations in health and mental health. Medical Care Research and Review, 69(2), 123&#x2013;157. 10.1177/1077558711430690</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077558711430690</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3524416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22203646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Powell B. J., Waltz T. J., Chinman M. J., Damschroder L. J., Smith J. L., Matthieu M. M., Proctor E. K., Kirchner J. E. (2015). A refined compilation of implementation strategies: Results from the Expert Recommendations for Implementing Change (ERIC) project. Implementation Science, 10, 21. 10.1186/s13012-015-0209-1</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-015-0209-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4328074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25889199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quanbeck A., Gustafson D. H., Marsch L. A., Chih M. Y., Kornfield R., McTavish F., Johnson R., Brown R. T., Mares M. L., Shah D. V. (2018). Implementing a mobile health system to integrate the treatment of addiction into primary care: A hybrid implementation-effectiveness study. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 20(1), e37. 10.2196/jmir.8928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.8928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5811649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29382624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quanbeck A. R., Gustafson D. H., Marsch L. A., McTavish F., Brown R. T., Mares M.-L., Johnson R., Glass J. E., Atwood A. K., McDowell H. (2014). Integrating addiction treatment into primary care using mobile health technology: Protocol for an implementation research study. Implementation Science, 9(1), 65. 10.1186/1748-5908-9-65</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-9-65</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4072605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24884976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramsey A. T., Satterfield J. M., Gerke D. R., Proctor E. K. (2019). Technology-based alcohol interventions in primary care: Systematic review. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 21(4), e10859. 10.2196/10859</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/10859</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6475823</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30958270</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Villa E., Rauseo-Ricupero N., Camacho E., Wisniewski H., Keshavan M., Torous J. (2020). The digital clinic: Implementing technology and augmenting care for mental health. General Hospital Psychiatry, 66, 59&#x2013;66. 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2020.06.009</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2020.06.009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7324929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32688094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rost K., Nutting P., Smith J., Coyne J. C., Cooper-Patrick L., Rubenstein L. (2000). The role of competing demands in the treatment provided primary care patients with major depression. Archives of Family Medicine, 9(2), 150&#x2013;154. 10.1001/archfami.9.2.150</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archfami.9.2.150</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10693732</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saitz R., Larson M. J., Labelle C., Richardson J., Samet J. H. (2008). The case for chronic disease management for addiction. Journal of Addiction Medicine, 2(2), 55&#x2013;65. 10.1097/ADM.0b013e318166af74</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ADM.0b013e318166af74</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2756688</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19809579</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saunders B., Sim J., Kingstone T., Baker S., Waterfield J., Bartlam B., Burroughs H., Jinks C. (2018). Saturation in qualitative research: Exploring its conceptualization and operationalization. Quality &amp; Quantity, 52(4), 1893&#x2013;1907. 10.1007/s11135-017-0574-8</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11135-017-0574-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5993836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29937585</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schottenfeld L., Petersen D., Peikes D., Ricciardi R., Burak H., McNellis R., Genevro J. (2016). Creating patient-centered team-based primary care. Rockville: Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan D. V., Lecrubier Y., Harnett Sheehan K., Janavs J., Weiller E., Keskiner A., Schinka J., Knapp E., Sheehan M. F., Dunbar G. C. (1997). The validity of the Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview (MINI) according to the SCID-P and its reliability. European Psychiatry, 12(5), 232&#x2013;241. 10.1016/S0924-9338(97)83297-X</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0924-9338(97)83297-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehan D. V., Lecrubier Y., Sheehan K. H., Amorim P., Janavs J., Weiller E., Hergueta T., Baker R., Dunbar G. C. (1998). The Mini-International Neuropsychiatric Interview (M.I.N.I.): The development and validation of a structured diagnostic psychiatric interview for DSM-IV and ICD-10. Journal of Clinical Psychiatry, 59(Suppl 20), 22&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9881538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sobell L. C., Agrawal S., Sobell M. B., Leo G. I., Young L. J., Cunningham J. A., Simco E. R. (2003). Comparison of a quick drinking screen with the timeline followback for individuals with alcohol problems. Journal of Studies on Alcohol, 64(6), 858&#x2013;861. 10.15288/jsa.2003.64.858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15288/jsa.2003.64.858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14743950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SocioCultural Research Consultants. (2018).
<i>Dedoose</i> (Version 8.0.35) [Computer software].
https://www.dedoose.com/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thies K., Anderson D., Cramer B. (2017). Lack of adoption of a mobile app to support patient self-management of diabetes and hypertension in a federally qualified health center: Interview analysis of staff and patients in a failed randomized trial. JMIR Human Factors, 4(4), e24. 10.2196/humanfactors.7709</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/humanfactors.7709</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5645643</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28974481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Truong K. N., Hayes G. R., Abowd G. D. (2006). Storyboarding: An empirical determination of best practices and effective guidelines. In Proceedings of the 6th Conference on Designing Interactive Systems. DIS '06. University Park, PA, USA, June 26&#x2013;28, 2006, ACM, New York, NY. 10.1145/1142405.1142410</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1145/1142405.1142410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>