<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39676816</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>04</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2633-4895</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>5</Volume><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Season>Jan-Dec</Season></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Implementation research and practice</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Implement Res Pract</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Formative evaluation of the implementation of digital therapeutics for opioids and other substance use disorders in primary care (DIGITS trial).</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>26334895241301670</StartPage><MedlinePgn>26334895241301670</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">26334895241301670</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/26334895241301670</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Substance use disorders (SUDs) result in individual and societal burden. However, most individuals with SUD receive no treatment. Implementing SUD interventions in primary care could address this population's treatment needs. In the USA, reSET<sup>&#xae;</sup> and reSET-O<sup>&#xae;</sup> were the first prescription digital therapeutics (PDTs) for SUDs and opioid use disorder (OUD), respectively. The Digital Treatments for Substance Use Disorder (DIGITS) study tested the effectiveness of practice facilitation and health coaching strategies to support reSET and reSET-O implementation into primary care. A formative evaluation was conducted to monitor implementation, inform adaptations, and learn what promotes PDT sustainment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The Dynamic Sustainability Framework and the Framework for Reporting Adaptations and Modifications to Evidence-based Implementation Strategies guided the evaluation. Using rapid qualitative methods, we collected and analyzed observational fieldnotes, key informant interviews, and document sources (e.g., meeting minutes) for synthesis and dissemination to clinical partners and the study team via formative reports. We analyzed the reports to generate evaluation results.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Twenty-four primary care clinics participated. Evaluation data included 98 observational fieldnotes, 16 interviews, and 253 document sources. We produced nine formative reports. The study encountered barriers and facilitators in each DSF domain (ecological system, practice setting, and intervention). In the ecological system, the PDT vendor enabled the study, but the COVID-19 pandemic, laws, regulations, and contracting delayed implementation. In the practice setting, staff shortages and low clinic capacity were implementation challenges, while electronic health record capabilities were both barriers and facilitators. At the intervention level, non-routine workflows, clinician burden, and low patient engagement were barriers despite clinicians' efforts.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Digital therapeutics are promising SUD and OUD treatments, but integration into primary care requires conducive laws and regulations, organizational capacity, and patient and clinician engagement. Formative evaluation identified important lessons for future PDT implementation.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Palazzo</LastName><ForeName>Lorella</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4736-5990</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dorsey</LastName><ForeName>Caitlin N</ForeName><Initials>CN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mogk</LastName><ForeName>Jess</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Beatty</LastName><ForeName>Tara</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>King</LastName><ForeName>Deborah</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Stefanik-Guizlo</LastName><ForeName>Kelsey</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Key</LastName><ForeName>Dustin</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Matson</LastName><ForeName>Tessa E</ForeName><Initials>TE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shea</LastName><ForeName>Mary</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Caldeiro</LastName><ForeName>Ryan M</ForeName><Initials>RM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Mental Health &amp; Wellness Services, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McWethy</LastName><ForeName>Angela Garza</ForeName><Initials>AG</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente National Mental Health &amp; Wellness, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wong</LastName><ForeName>Edwin S</ForeName><Initials>ES</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Systems and Population Health, School of Public Health, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Idu</LastName><ForeName>Abisola E</ForeName><Initials>AE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Glass</LastName><ForeName>Joseph E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2923-3698</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation><Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">343041</Identifier></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Systems and Population Health, School of Public Health, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K01 AA023859</GrantID><Acronym>AA</Acronym><Agency>NIAAA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R01 DA047954</GrantID><Acronym>DA</Acronym><Agency>NIDA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Implement Res Pract</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101774031</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2633-4895</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng"><AbstractText><b><i>Evaluation of the integration of digital treatments for opioid and other substance use disorders in primary care</i></b> . Most people with substance use disorders (SUDs) receive no treatment. In the USA, two smartphone app-based digital treatments for SUD and opioid use disorders (OUDs) became available by prescription. The Digital Treatments for Substance Use Disorder (DIGITS) study, a randomized implementation trial, tested how best to integrate these digital treatments for SUD and OUD into primary care. Throughout the study, we conducted a formative evaluation to observe progress, recommend implementation improvements, and understand how digital treatments could be offered to patients after the study ended. For this evaluation, we collected qualitative data through observing study meetings and interviewing primary care leaders, clinicians, and clinical and study staff. The data were regularly summarized and reported to our clinical partners and the study team. We used two implementation frameworks to interpret the data: the Dynamic Sustainability Framework and the Framework for Reporting Adaptations and Modifications to Evidence-based Implementation Strategies. The evaluation revealed factors that helped and hindered implementation. Obstacles from outside the health care system included the COVID-19 pandemic, laws, regulations, and delays in setting up contractual agreements, whereas a partnership with the digital treatment vendor proved helpful. Clinics had difficulties with clinician burden, staff shortages, lack of time and available appointments, and performing new and unfamiliar tasks. The electronic health record system both supported and impended implementation. Last, few patients accepted the offered digital treatment, or used it persistently. Formative evaluation results suggest that digital treatments for SUD and OUD in primary care are promising, however their successful use requires supportive laws and regulations, health system resources, and increased patient and clinician engagement.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; The Author(s) 2024.</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">formative evaluation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">implementation science</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mHealth</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">primary care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative research</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">substance use disorder</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>reSET&#xae; and reSET-O&#xae; are digital therapeutics for substance use disorder marketed by Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc. that are discussed in this manuscript. During the three-month quality improvement pilot study discussed in this manuscript, Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc. provided digital therapeutic prescriptions at no cost to Kaiser Permanente Washington. Pear Therapeutics (US), Inc. has not provided funding to the authors.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>26</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>17</Hour><Minute>25</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>15</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39676816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11639013</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/26334895241301670</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_26334895241301670</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aarons G. A., Ehrhart M. G., Farahnak L. R., Sklar M. (2014). Aligning leadership across systems and organizations to develop a strategic climate for evidence-based practice implementation. Annual Review of Public Health, 35(1), 255&#x2013;274. 10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032013-182447</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032013-182447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4348088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24641560</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ATLAS.ti 9. (2023). 
https://atlasti.com/
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Austin A. E., Shiue K. Y., Naumann R. B., Figgatt M. C., Gest C., Shanahan M. E. (2021). Associations of housing stress with later substance use outcomes: A systematic review. Addictive Behaviors, 123, 107076. 10.1016/j.addbeh.2021.107076</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.addbeh.2021.107076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34385075</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abernethy A., Adams L., Barrett M., Bechtel C., Brennan P., Butte A., Faulkner J., Fontaine E., Friedhoff S., Halamka J., Howell M., Johnson K., Lee P., Long P., McGraw D., Miller R., Perlin J., Rucker D., Sandy L., &#x2026; Valdes K. (2022). The Promise of Digital Health: Then, Now, and the Future. NAM Perspectives. Discussion Paper, National Academy of Medicine, Washington, DC. 10.31478/202206e.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.31478/202206e</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9499383</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36177208</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barry C. L., Epstein A. J., Fiellin D. A., Fraenkel L., Busch S. H. (2016). Estimating demand for primary care-based treatment for substance and alcohol use disorders. Addiction, 111(8), 1376&#x2013;1384. 10.1111/add.13364</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.13364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4940268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26899802</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bickel W. K., Marsch L. A., Buchhalter A. R., Badger G. J. (2008). Computerized behavior therapy for opioid-dependent outpatients: A randomized controlled trial. Experimental and Clinical Psychopharmacology, 16(2), 132&#x2013;143. 10.1037/1064-1297.16.2.132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1064-1297.16.2.132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746734</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18489017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Binder C. (1996). Behavioral fluency: Evolution of a new paradigm. The Behavior Analyst / Maba, 19(2), 163&#x2013;197. 10.1007/bf03393163</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/bf03393163</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2733609</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22478257</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birt L., Scott S., Cavers D., Campbell C., Walter F. (2016). Member checking: A tool to enhance trustworthiness or merely a nod to validation? Qualitative Health Research: An International, Interdisciplinary Journal, 26(13), 1802&#x2013;1811. 10.1177/1049732316654870</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732316654870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27340178</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Campbell A. N., Nunes E. V., Matthews A. G., Stitzer M., Miele G. M., Polsky D., Turrigiano E., Walters S., McClure E. A., Kyle T. L., Wahle A., Van Veldhuisen P., Goldman B., Babcock D., Stabile P. Q., Winhusen T., Ghitza U. E. (2014). Internet-delivered treatment for substance abuse: A multisite randomized controlled trial. American Journal of Psychiatry, 171(6), 683&#x2013;690. 10.1176/appi.ajp.2014.13081055</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2014.13081055</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4079279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24700332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chambers D. A., Glasgow R. E., Stange K. C. (2013). The dynamic sustainability framework: Addressing the paradox of sustainment amid ongoing change. Implementation Science, 8, 117. 10.1186/1748-5908-8-117</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-8-117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3852739</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24088228</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Christensen D. R., Landes R. D., Jackson L., Marsch L. A., Mancino M. J., Chopra M. P., Bickel W. K. (2014). Adding an internet-delivered treatment to an efficacious treatment package for opioid dependence. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology, 82(6), 964&#x2013;972. 10.1037/a0037496</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0037496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4244262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25090043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clinton-McHarg T., Yoong S. L., Tzelepis F., Regan T., Fielding A., Skelton E., Kingsland M., Ooi J. Y., Wolfenden L. (2016). Psychometric properties of implementation measures for public health and community settings and mapping of constructs against the consolidated framework for implementation research: A systematic review. Implementation Science, 11(1), 148. 10.1186/s13012-016-0512-5</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-016-0512-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5100177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27821146</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CMS. (2023).Quality measures &amp; you: Clinicians. 
https://www.cms.gov/Medicare/Quality-Initiatives-Patient-Assessment-Instruments/MMS/QMY-Clinicians
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Degenhardt L., Hall W. (2012). Extent of illicit drug use and dependence, and their contribution to the global burden of disease. Lancet, 379(9810), 55&#x2013;70. 10.1016/s0140-6736(11)61138-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(11)61138-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22225671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elwy A. R., Wasan A. D., Gillman A. G., Johnston K. L., Dodds N., McFarland C., Greco C. M. (2020). Using formative evaluation methods to improve clinical implementation efforts: Description and an example. Psychiatry Research, 283, 112532. 10.1016/j.psychres.2019.112532</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2019.112532</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31477261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fernandez M. E., Walker T. J., Weiner B. J., Calo W. A., Liang S., Risendal B., Friedman D. B., Tu S. P., Williams R. S., Jacobs S., Herrmann A. K., Kegler M. C. (2018). Developing measures to assess constructs from the inner setting domain of the consolidated framework for implementation research. Implementation Science, 13(1), 52. 10.1186/s13012-018-0736-7</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-018-0736-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5870186</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29587804</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Frost M. C., Coughlin L. N., Zhang L., Lin L. (2024). Comparison of treatment receipt and hospitalization among patients with stimulant use disorder and/or opioid use disorder in the veterans health administration. Journal of Addiction Medicine, 18(5), 561&#x2013;566. 10.1097/adm.0000000000001329</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/adm.0000000000001329</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11446671</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38832683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glass J. E., Dorsey C. N., Beatty T., Bobb J. F., Wong E. S., Palazzo L., King D., Mogk J., Stefanik-Guizlo K., Idu A., Key D., Fortney J. C., Thomas R., McWethy A. G., Caldeiro R. M., Bradley K. A. (2023). Study protocol for a factorial-randomized controlled trial evaluating the implementation, costs, effectiveness, and sustainment of digital therapeutics for substance use disorder in primary care (DIGITS trial). Implementation Science, 18(1), 3. 10.1186/s13012-022-01258-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-022-01258-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9893639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36726127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant B. F., Goldstein R. B., Saha T. D., Chou S. P., Jung J., Zhang H., Pickering R. P., Ruan W. J., Smith S. M., Huang B., Hasin D. S. (2015). Epidemiology of DSM-5 alcohol use disorder: Results from the national epidemiologic survey on alcohol and related conditions III. JAMA Psychiatry, 72(8), 757&#x2013;766. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.0584</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.0584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5240584</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26039070</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grant B. F., Saha T. D., Ruan W. J., Goldstein R. B., Chou S. P., Jung J., Zhang H., Smith S. M., Pickering R. P., Huang B., Hasin D. S. (2016). Epidemiology of DSM-5 drug use disorder: Results from the national epidemiologic survey on alcohol and related conditions&#x2013;III. JAMA Psychiatry, 73(1), 39&#x2013;47. 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.2132</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2015.2132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5062605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26580136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guba E., Lincoln Y. (1994). Chapter 6: Competing Paradigms in Qualitative Research. Sage, pp. 163&#x2013;194. (Handbook of qualitative research)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hagedorn H. J., Stetler C. B., Bangerter A., Noorbaloochi S., Stitzer M. L., Kivlahan D. (2014). An implementation-focused process evaluation of an incentive intervention effectiveness trial in substance use disorders clinics at two veterans health administration medical centers. Addiction Science &amp; Clinical Practice, 9(1), 12. 10.1186/1940-0640-9-12</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1940-0640-9-12</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4106217</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25008457</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hsieh H. F., Shannon S. E. (2005). Three approaches to qualitative content analysis. Qualitative Health Research, 15(9), 1277&#x2013;1288. 10.1177/1049732305276687</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1049732305276687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16204405</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horton T., Illingworth J., Warburton W., Foundation H. (2018). The spread challenge: How to support the successful uptake of innovations and improvements in health care. Health Foundation. 
https://books.google.com/books?id=TLeEzgEACAAJ
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones C. M., McCance-Katz E. F. (2019). Co-occurring substance use and mental disorders among adults with opioid use disorder. Drug Alcohol Depend, 197, 78&#x2013;82. 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2018.12.030</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2018.12.030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30784952</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones C. M., Han B., Baldwin G. T., Einstein E. B., Compton W. M. (2023). Use of medication for opioid use disorder among adults with past-year opioid use disorder in the US, 2021. JAMA Network Open, 6(8), e2327488&#x2013;e2327488. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.27488</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.27488</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10407686</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37548979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lussier J. P., Heil S. H., Mongeon J. A., Badger G. J., Higgins S. T. (2006). A meta-analysis of voucher-based reinforcement therapy for substance use disorders. Addiction, 101(2), 192&#x2013;203. 10.1111/j.1360-0443.2006.01311.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1360-0443.2006.01311.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16445548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lussier Jennifer Plebani, Heil Sarah H, Mongeon Joan A., Badger Gary J, Higgins Stephen T. (2006). A meta&#x2010;analysis of voucher&#x2010;based reinforcement therapy for substance use disorders. Addiction, 101(2), 192&#x2013;203. 10.1111/add.2006.101.issue-2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/add.2006.101.issue-2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16445548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magill M., Ray L. A. (2009). Cognitive-behavioral treatment with adult alcohol and illicit drug users: A meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Journal of Studies on Alcohol and Drugs, 70(4), 516&#x2013;527. 10.15288/jsad.2009.70.516</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15288/jsad.2009.70.516</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2696292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19515291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maricich Y. A., Bickel W. K., Marsch L. A., Gatchalian K., Botbyl J., Luderer H. F. (2021). Safety and efficacy of a prescription digital therapeutic as an adjunct to buprenorphine for treatment of opioid use disorder. Current Medical Research and Opinion, 37(2), 167&#x2013;173. 10.1080/03007995.2020.1846022</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03007995.2020.1846022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8666102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33140994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maricich Y. A., Nunes E. V., Campbell A. N. C., Botbyl J. D., Luderer H. F. (2022). Safety and efficacy of a digital therapeutic for substance use disorder: Secondary analysis of data from a NIDA clinical trials network study. Substance Abuse, 43(1), 937&#x2013;942. 10.1080/08897077.2022.2060425</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08897077.2022.2060425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35420979</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marsch L. A., Guarino H., Acosta M., Aponte-Melendez Y., Cleland C., Grabinski M., Brady R., Edwards J. (2014). Web-based behavioral treatment for substance use disorders as a partial replacement of standard methadone maintenance treatment. Journal of Substance Abuse Treatment, 46(1), 43&#x2013;51. 10.1016/j.jsat.2013.08.012</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jsat.2013.08.012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3839618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24060350</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller-Rosales C., Morden N. E., Brunette M. F., Busch S. H., Torous J. B., Meara E. R. (2023). Provision of digital health technologies for opioid use disorder treatment by US health care organizations. JAMA Network Open, 6(7), e2323741&#x2013;e2323741. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.23741</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2023.23741</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10352858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37459098</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller C. J., Barnett M. L., Baumann A. A., Gutner C. A., Wiltsey-Stirman S. (2021). The FRAME-IS: A framework for documenting modifications to implementation strategies in healthcare. Implementation Science, 16(1), 36. 10.1186/s13012-021-01105-3</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-021-01105-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8024675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827716</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogk J., Idu A., Bobb J., Key D., Wong E., Palazzo L., Stefanik-Guizlo K., King D., Beatty T., Dorsey C., Caldeiro R., Garza McWethy A., Glass J. (2024). Prescription digital therapeutics for substance use disorder in primary care: A mixed methods evaluation of a pilot implementation study. JMIR Formative Research, 8, e59088. 10.2196/59088</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/59088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11406110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39222348</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mogk J. M., Matson T. E., Caldeiro R. M., Garza Mcwethy A. M., Beatty T., Sevey B. C., Hsu C. W., Glass J. E. (2023). Implementation and workflow strategies for integrating digital therapeutics for alcohol use disorders into primary care: A qualitative study. Addiction Science &amp; Clinical Practice, 18(1), 27. 10.1186/s13722-023-00387-w</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13722-023-00387-w</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10169300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37158931</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien B. C., Harris I. B., Beckman T. J., Reed D. A., Cook D. A. (2014). Standards for reporting qualitative research: A synthesis of recommendations. Academic Medicine, 89(9), 1245&#x2013;1251. 10.1097/acm.0000000000000388</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/acm.0000000000000388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24979285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parchman M. L., Palazzo L. G., Mogk J. M., Webbon J. C., Demosthenes L., Vossenkemper E., Hoke G., Moskovitz J., Dunlap L., Diaz del Carpio R. (2022). What strategies are used by clinician champions to reduce low-value care? SAGE Open Medicine, 10, 20503121211069855. 10.1177/20503121211069855</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/20503121211069855</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9133862</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35646351</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proctor E. K., Powell B. J., McMillen J. C. (2013). Implementation strategies: Recommendations for specifying and reporting. Implementation Science, 8, 139. 10.1186/1748-5908-8-139</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1748-5908-8-139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3882890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24289295</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quanbeck A., Gustafson D. H., Marsch L. A., Chih M.-Y., Kornfield R., McTavish F., Johnson R., Brown R. T., Mares M.-L., Shah D. V. (2018). Implementing a mobile health system to integrate the treatment of addiction into primary care: A hybrid implementation-effectiveness study. Journal of Medical Internet Research, 20(1), e37. 10.2196/jmir.8928</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.8928</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5811649</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29382624</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritchie M. J., Parker L. E., Edlund C. N., Kirchner J. E. (2017). Using implementation facilitation to foster clinical practice quality and adherence to evidence in challenged settings: A qualitative study. BMC Health Services Research, 17(1), 294. 10.1186/s12913-017-2217-0</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12913-017-2217-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5397744</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28424052</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose J., Schlichter B. R. (2013). Decoupling, re-engaging: Managing trust relationships in implementation projects. Information Systems Journal, 23(1), 5&#x2013;33. 10.1111/j.1365-2575.2011.00392.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2575.2011.00392.x</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubinsky A. D., Ellerbe L. S., Gupta S., Phelps T. E., Bowe T., Burden J. L., Harris A. H. S. (2018). Outpatient continuing care after residential substance use disorder treatment in the US veterans health administration: Facilitators and challenges. Substance Abuse, 39(3), 322&#x2013;330. 10.1080/08897077.2017.1391923</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08897077.2017.1391923</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29043947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SAMHSA. (2023). SAMHSA Announces National Survey on Drug Use and Health (NSDUH) Results Detailing Mental Illness and Substance Use Levels in 2021. 
https://www.samhsa.gov/newsroom/press-announcements/20230104/samhsa-announces-nsduh-results-detailing-mental-illness-substance-use-levels-2021
</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Slattery P., Saeri A. K., Bragge P. (2020). Research co-design in health: A rapid overview of reviews. Health Research Policy and Systems / Biomed Central, 18(1), 17. 10.1186/s12961-020-0528-9</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12961-020-0528-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7014755</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32046728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stetler C. B., Legro M. W., Wallace C. M., Bowman C., Guihan M., Hagedorn H., Kimmel B., Sharp N. D., Smith J. L. (2006). The role of formative evaluation in implementation research and the QUERI experience. Journal of General Internal Medicine, 21(Suppl 2), S1&#x2013;S8. 10.1111/j.1525-1497.2006.00355.x</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1525-1497.2006.00355.x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2557128</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16637954</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tumulty P. A. (1970). What is a clinician and what does he do? New England Journal of Medicine, 283(1), 20&#x2013;24. https://doi.org/ 10.1056/NEJM197007022830105</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM197007022830105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5419315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson A., Chapman R., Shafai G., Maricich Y. A. (2023). FDA regulations and prescription digital therapeutics: Evolving with the technologies they regulate. Frontiers in Digital Health, 5, 1086219. 10.3389/fdgth.2023.1086219</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2023.1086219</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10150093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37139487</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wiltsey Stirman S., Baumann A. A., Miller C. J. (2019). The FRAME: An expanded framework for reporting adaptations and modifications to evidence-based interventions. Implementation Science, 14(1), 58. 10.1186/s13012-019-0898-y</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-019-0898-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6554895</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31171014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woltmann E. M., Whitley R. (2007). The role of staffing stability in the implementation of integrated dual disorders treatment: An exploratory study. Journal of Mental Health, 16(6), 757&#x2013;769. 10.1080/09638230701496402</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09638230701496402</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu L. T., Zhu H., Mannelli P., Swartz M. S. (2017). Prevalence and correlates of treatment utilization among adults with cannabis use disorder in the United States. Drug and Alcohol Dependence, 177, 153&#x2013;162, doi: 10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2017.03.037</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2017.03.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5538354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28599214</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>