<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">40351480</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>17</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Cureus</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The Composite Digital Therapeutic Index (cDTI): A Multidimensional Framework and Proof-of-Concept Application to FDA-Authorized Treatments.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e83886</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e83886</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e83886</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.83886</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Introduction Prescription digital therapeutics (PDTs) are an emerging class of regulated software-based interventions with increasing FDA authorizations. However, there is no standardized framework to evaluate and benchmark their overall therapeutic value. We aimed to develop and validate a Composite Digital Therapeutic Index (cDTI) framework. This proof-of-concept application integrates efficacy, engagement, quality of evidence, and safety profile from registrational trials to compare PDTs using publicly available regulatory summaries, registries, and study readouts. Methods We developed a scoring framework incorporating four domains (efficacy, engagement, evidence quality, and safety), each quantified and combined into a composite index. Efficacy was calculated using standardized mean difference (SMD; Hedges' g) adjusted for statistical significance. Engagement was based on the mean proportion of patients achieving&#xa0;therapeutic module completion. Evidence quality was graded using an adapted American Academy of Neurology Class of Evidence framework. Safety was assessed based on treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs) using a hierarchical penalty system. In a proof-of-concept application of the framework, we applied cDTI to two FDA-cleared first- and second-generation PDTs, reSET-O for opioid use disorder (Pear Therapeutics, Boston, MA, USA) and CT-132 for episodic migraine (Click Therapeutics, New York, NY, USA), respectively. Results CT-132 achieved a cDTI score of 0.296, substantially (1287%) higher than reSET-O, which scored 0.023. CT-132's superior performance was driven by a statistically significant efficacy outcome (adjusted SMD 0.33), high engagement (89.7%), Class I evidence quality with sham and double-blind, and no treatment-related adverse events. In contrast, reSET-O showed a non-significant primary outcome (adjusted SMD 0.0895), moderate engagement (63.0%), Class III evidence quality without patient blind and usual-care control, and missing systematic safety reporting requiring a conservative penalty. Discussion The cDTI successfully differentiated the overall therapeutic profiles of two PDTs across multiple clinical and usability domains. This multidimensional approach highlights how digital therapeutics with similar regulatory status can differ meaningfully in trial quality, efficacy, engagement, and safety. The cDTI offers a transparent, reproducible method for comparing PDTs and may aid stakeholders including providers, payers, regulators, and patients in decision-making about digital therapeutic adoption and coverage. Conclusion The cDTI provides a reproducible framework to evaluate PDTs based on clinical, usability, and safety parameters. Future work aims to expand the framework across all FDA-cleared PDTs and explore incorporation of real-world effectiveness, equity, and cost-effectiveness domains.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2025, Lakhan et al.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lakhan</LastName><ForeName>Shaheen E</ForeName><Initials>SE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Office, Click Therapeutics, Inc., New York, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Western University of Health Sciences, Pomona, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, A.T. Still University School of Osteopathic Medicine in Arizona, Mesa, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Morehouse School of Medicine, Atlanta, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Bioscience, Global Neuroscience Initiative Foundation, Miami, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>11</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">composite score</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">efficacy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">engagement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">health technology assessment</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescription digital therapeutics</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">safety</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Human subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve human participants or tissue. Animal subjects: All authors have confirmed that this study did not involve animal subjects or tissue. Conflicts of interest: In compliance with the ICMJE uniform disclosure form, all authors declare the following: Payment/services info: All authors have declared that no financial support was received from any organization for the submitted work. Financial relationships: Shaheen E Lakhan declare(s) employment and stock/stock options from Click Therapeutics. Other relationships: All authors have declared that there are no other relationships or activities that could appear to have influenced the submitted work.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>56</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40351480</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12066087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.83886</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>510(k) Premarket Notification. Device Classification Name: Computerized Behavioral Therapy Device For Insomnia. Device Name: reSET-O.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpmn/pmn.cfm?ID=K173681 https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpmn/pmn.cfm?ID=K173681</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>When software becomes medicine: ignoring it may soon be malpractice. Lakhan SE. Cureus. 2025;17:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12015761</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40271230</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>510(k) Premarket Notification. Device Classification Name: Computerized Behavioral Therapy Device For Depressive Disorders. Device Name: Rejoyn.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpmn/pmn.cfm?ID=K231209 https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpmn/pmn.cfm?ID=K231209</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>510(k) Premarket Notification. Device Classification Name: Computerized Behavioral Therapy Device For Insomnia. Device Name: Somryst.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpmn/pmn.cfm?ID=K191716 https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpmn/pmn.cfm?ID=K191716</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FDA. Device Classification Under Section 513(f)(2)(De Novo). Device Name: CT-132.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2025. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpmn/denovo.cfm?id=DEN240064 https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/cdrh/cfdocs/cfpmn/denovo.cfm?id=DEN240064</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The impact of digital therapeutics on current health technology assessment frameworks. Yan K, Balijepalli C, Druyts E. Front Digit Health. 2021;3:667016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8521991</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34713140</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. Guyatt GH, Oxman AD, Vist GE, Kunz R, Falck-Ytter Y, Alonso-Coello P, Sch&#xfc;nemann HJ. BMJ. 2008;336:924&#x2013;926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2335261</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18436948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Value Assessment Framework.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2025. https://icer.org/our-approach/methods-process/value-assessment-framework/ https://icer.org/our-approach/methods-process/value-assessment-framework/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Comparison of health technology assessments for digital therapeutics in Germany, the United Kingdom and France. Arc&#xe0; E, Heldt D, Smith M. Digit Health. 2025;11:20552076241308704.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11752730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39845519</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>510(k) Summary. reSET-O.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2018. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/cdrh_docs/pdf17/K173681.pdf https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/cdrh_docs/pdf17/K173681.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Study of Two Digital Therapeutics for the Prevention of Episodic Migraine (ReMMi-D)  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2025. https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05853900 https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT05853900</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy of Computer Delivered Community Reinforcement Approach (CRA) (Bup II) (CAT)  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2022. https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT00929253 https://clinicaltrials.gov/study/NCT00929253</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Efficacy and safety of a first-in-class investigational prescription digital therapeutic for episodic migraine (CT-132): phase 3 double-blind, randomized, controlled trial (P4-12.006) [ Apr; 2025 ];Snipes C, Kuka A, Petrova M, et al. Neurology. 2025 104</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adding an Internet-delivered treatment to an efficacious treatment package for opioid dependence. Christensen DR, Landes RD, Jackson L, Marsch LA, Mancino MJ, Chopra MP, Bickel WK. J Consult Clin Psychol. 2014;82:964&#x2013;972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4244262</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25090043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Safety and efficacy of a prescription digital therapeutic as an adjunct to buprenorphine for treatment of opioid use disorder. Maricich YA, Bickel WK, Marsch LA, Gatchalian K, Botbyl J, Luderer HF. Curr Med Res Opin. 2021;37:167&#x2013;173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8666102</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33140994</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digital Health Technologies for Opioid Use Disorder: Final Evidence Report.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2020. https://icer.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ICER_DHTs_for_OUD_Final_Report_052722.pdf https://icer.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/ICER_DHTs_for_OUD_Final_Report_052722.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The effectiveness and value of digital health technologies as an adjunct to medication-assisted therapy for opioid use disorder. Tice JA, Whittington MD, Campbell JD, Pearson SD. J Manag Care Spec Pharm. 2021;27:528&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10390940</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33769860</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Digital Therapies Poised for Breakthrough in Migraine Treatment.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2023. https://www.drugtopics.com/view/digital-therapies-poised-for-breakthrough-in-migraine-treatment https://www.drugtopics.com/view/digital-therapies-poised-for-breakthrough-in-migraine-treatment</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borenstein M, Hedges LV, Higgins JP, Rothstein HR. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2009. Introduction to meta&#x2010;analysis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conceptualising engagement with digital behaviour change interventions: a systematic review using principles from critical interpretive synthesis. Perski O, Blandford A, West R, Michie S. Transl Behav Med. 2017;7:254&#x2013;267.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5526809</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27966189</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Measuring engagement in eHealth and mHealth behavior change interventions: viewpoint of methodologies. Short CE, DeSmet A, Woods C, et al. J Med Internet Res. 2018;20:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6269627</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30446482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Persuasive system design does matter: a systematic review of adherence to web-based interventions. Kelders SM, Kok RN, Ossebaard HC, Van Gemert-Pijnen JE. J Med Internet Res. 2012;14:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3510730</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23151820</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>2017 Edition Clinical Practice Guideline Process Manual.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2017. https://www.aan.com/siteassets/home-page/policy-and-guidelines/guidelines/about-guidelines/17guidelineprocman_pg.pdf https://www.aan.com/siteassets/home-page/policy-and-guidelines/guidelines/about-guidelines/17guidelineprocman_pg.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobile app rating scale: a new tool for assessing the quality of health mobile apps. Stoyanov SR, Hides L, Kavanagh DJ, Zelenko O, Tjondronegoro D, Mani M. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2015;3:0.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4376132</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25760773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Verification, analytical validation, and clinical validation (V3): the foundation of determining fit-for-purpose for Biometric Monitoring Technologies (BioMeTs) Goldsack JC, Coravos A, Bakker JP, et al. NPJ Digit Med. 2020;3:55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7156507</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32337371</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DTx Evaluation Toolkit.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2025. https://dtxalliance.org/understanding-dtx/dtx-evaluation-toolkit/ https://dtxalliance.org/understanding-dtx/dtx-evaluation-toolkit/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>ICER-PHTI Assessment Framework for Digital Health Technologies.  [
Apr;
2025 
]. 2023. https://icer.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/ICER-PHTI-Assessment-Framework-for-Digital-Health-Technologies.pdf https://icer.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/ICER-PHTI-Assessment-Framework-for-Digital-Health-Technologies.pdf</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>