<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37140392</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>10</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1930-739X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>31</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>May</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Obesity (Silver Spring, Md.)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Obesity (Silver Spring)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A randomized-controlled trial to evaluate the app-based multimodal weight loss program zanadio for patients with obesity.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1300</StartPage><EndPage>1310</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1300-1310</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/oby.23744</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to evaluate&#xa0;the effectiveness of the app-based, multimodal weight loss program zanadio.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A randomized-controlled trial was conducted from January 2021 to March 2022. A total of 150 adults with obesity were randomized into an intervention group and used zanadio for 1&#x2009;year or into a wait list control group. The primary end point, weight change, and the secondary end points, quality of life, well-being, and waist to height ratio, were assessed every 3&#x2009;months for up to 1&#x2009;year via telephone interviews and online questionnaires.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">After 12 months, participants of the intervention group lost, on average, -7.75% (95% CI: -9.66% to -5.84%) of their initial weight, achieving a clinically relevant and statistically stronger weight reduction than the control group (mean&#xa0;=&#xa0;0.00% [95% CI: -1.98% to 1.99%]). All secondary end points improved significantly in the intervention group, with significantly greater improvements in well-being and waist to height ratio than in the control group.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">This study showed that adults with obesity who have used zanadio achieved a significant and clinically relevant weight loss within 12 months and improved further obesity-related health variables compared with a control group. Because of its effectiveness and flexible applicability, the app-based multimodal treatment zanadio might alleviate the present care gap for patients with obesity in Germany.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. Obesity published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of The Obesity Society.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Roth</LastName><ForeName>Lena</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4254-1561</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and Logopedics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Max Planck Institute for Human Cognitive and Brain Sciences, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>aidhere GmbH, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ordnung</LastName><ForeName>Madeleine</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Faculty, University of Leipzig, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Forkmann</LastName><ForeName>Katarina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>aidhere GmbH, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehl</LastName><ForeName>Nora</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>aidhere GmbH, Hamburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horstmann</LastName><ForeName>Annette</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychology and Logopedics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, Finland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Max Planck Institute for Human Cognitive and Brain Sciences, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Medical Faculty, University of Leipzig, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Obesity (Silver Spring)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101264860</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1930-7381</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D061217" MajorTopicYN="Y">Weight Reduction Programs</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011788" MajorTopicYN="N">Quality of Life</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063731" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mobile Applications</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009765" MajorTopicYN="N">Obesity</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015431" MajorTopicYN="N">Weight Loss</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>21</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>17</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>41</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>5</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37140392</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/oby.23744</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHO European Regional Obesity Report 2022. WHO; 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clark JM, Brancati FL. The challenge of obesity&#x2010;related chronic diseases. J Gen Intern Med. 2000;15(11):828&#x2010;829.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luppino FS, de Wit LM, Bouvy PF, et al. Overweight, obesity, and depression: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of longitudinal studies. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2010;67(3):220&#x2010;229.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Must A, McKeown NM. The disease burden associated with overweight and obesity. In: Feingold KR, Anawalt B, Blackman MR, et al., eds. Endotext. MDText.com, Inc.; 2000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kushner RF, Foster GD. Obesity and quality of life. Nutrition. 2000;16(10):947&#x2010;952.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swencionis C, Wylie&#x2010;Rosett J, Lent MR, et al. Weight change, psychological well&#x2010;being, and vitality in adults participating in a cognitive&#x2013;behavioral weight loss program. Health Psychol. 2013;32(4):439&#x2010;446.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor VH, Forhan M, Vigod SN, McIntyre RS, Morrison KM. The impact of obesity on quality of life. Best Pract Res Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2013;27(2):139&#x2010;146.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>German Obesity Society (DAG) e. V., German Diabetes Society (DDG), German Society for Nutrition (DGE) e. V., German Society for Nutritional Medicine (DGEM). Interdisciplinary Quality Guideline S3 for &#x201c;Prevention and Therapy&#x201d; of Obesity &#x2010; Long Version. German Medical Association (B&#xc4;K); National Association of Statutory Health Insurance Physicians (KBV); Association of Scientific Medical Societies (AWMF); 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magkos F, Fraterrigo G, Yoshino J, et al. Effects of moderate and subsequent progressive weight loss on metabolic function and adipose tissue biology in humans with obesity. Cell Metab. 2016;23(4):591&#x2010;601.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudolph A, Hellbardt M, Baldofski S, de Zwaan M, Hilbert A. Evaluation of the one&#x2010;year multimodal weight loss program DOC WEIGHT&#xae; 1.0 for obesity class II and III [in German]. Psychother Psychosom Med Psychol. 2016;66(8):316&#x2010;323.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yumuk V, Fr&#xfc;hbeck G, Oppert JM, Woodward E, Toplak H. An EASO position statement on multidisciplinary obesity management in adults. Obes Facts. 2014;7(2):96&#x2010;101.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johns DJ, Hartmann&#x2010;Boyce J, Jebb SA, Aveyard P, Behavioural Weight Management Review Group. Diet or exercise interventions vs combined behavioral weight management programs: a systematic review and meta&#x2010;analysis of direct comparisons. J Acad Nutr Diet. 2014;114(10):1557&#x2010;1568.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schippers M, Adam PCG, Smolenski DJ, Wong HTH, de Wit JBF. A meta&#x2010;analysis of overall effects of weight loss interventions delivered via mobile phones and effect size differences according to delivery mode, personal contact, and intervention intensity and duration: mobile phone obesity interventions meta&#x2010;analysis. Obes Rev. 2017;18(4):450&#x2010;459.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arem H, Irwin M. A review of web&#x2010;based weight loss interventions in adults. Obes Rev. 2011;12(5):e236&#x2010;e243.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forkmann K, Roth L, Mehl N. Introducing zanadio&#x2014;A digitalized, multimodal program to treat obesity. Nutrients. 2022;14(15):3172. doi:10.3390/nu14153172</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashwell M, Hsieh SD. Six reasons why the waist&#x2010;to&#x2010;height ratio is a rapid and effective global indicator for health risks of obesity and how its use could simplify the international public health message on obesity. Int J Food Sci Nutr. 2005;56(5):303&#x2010;307.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moosaie F, Fatemi Abhari SM, Deravi N, et al. Waist&#x2010;to&#x2010;height ratio is a more accurate tool for predicting hypertension than waist&#x2010;to&#x2010;hip circumference and BMI in patients with type 2 diabetes: a prospective study. Front Public Health. 2021;9:726288. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2021.726288</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swainson MG, Batterham AM, Tsakirides C, Rutherford ZH, Hind K. Prediction of whole&#x2010;body fat percentage and visceral adipose tissue mass from five anthropometric variables. PloS One. 2017;12(5):e0177175. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0177175</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xe4;hler E, Zenger M, Kemper CJ. Psychologische und sozialwissenschaftliche Kurzskalen. Standardisierte Erhebungsinstrumente f&#xfc;r Wissenschaft und Praxis. Psychological and social science short scales. Standardized survey instruments for science and practice. Medizinisch Wissenschaftliche Verlagsgesellschaft; 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Topp CW, &#xd8;stergaard SD, S&#xf8;ndergaard S, Bech P. The WHO&#x2010;5 Well&#x2010;Being Index: a systematic review of the literature. Psychother Psychosom. 2015;84(3):167&#x2010;176.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skevington SM, Lotfy M, O'Connell KA; WHOQOL Group. The World Health Organization's WHOQOL&#x2010;BREF quality of life assessment: psychometric properties and results of the international field trial. A report from the WHOQOL group. Qual Life Res. 2004;13(2):299&#x2010;310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. WHOQOL User Manual (Revision 1). WHO; 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The WHOQOL Group. Development of the World Health Organization WHOQOL&#x2010;BREF quality of life assessment. Psychol Med. 1998;28(3):551&#x2010;558.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faul F, Erdfelder E, Lang AG, Buchner A. G*Power 3: A flexible statistical power analysis program for the social, behavioral, and biomedical sciences. Behav Res Methods. 2007;39(2):175&#x2010;191.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jebb SA, Ahern AL, Olson AD, et al. Primary care referral to a commercial provider for weight loss treatment versus standard care: a randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2011;378(9801):1485&#x2010;1492.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sepah SC, Jiang L, Ellis RJ, McDermott K, Peters AL. Engagement and outcomes in a digital Diabetes Prevention Program: 3&#x2010;year update. BMJ Open Diabetes Res Care. 2017;5(1):e000422. doi:10.1136/bmjdrc&#x2010;2017&#x2010;000422</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter JR, Roger JH, Kenward MG. Analysis of longitudinal trials with protocol deviation: a framework for relevant, accessible assumptions, and inference via multiple imputation. J Biopharm Stat. 2013;23(6):1352&#x2010;1371.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Graham JW, Olchowski AE, Gilreath TD. How many imputations are really needed? some practical clarifications of multiple imputation theory. Prev Sci. 2007;8(3):206&#x2010;213.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Buuren S. Flexible Imputation of Missing Data. 2nd ed. Chapman and Hall/CRC; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White IR, Royston P, Wood AM. Multiple imputation using chained equations: issues and guidance for practice. Stat Med. 2011;30(4):377&#x2010;399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grund S, L&#xfc;dtke O, Robitzsch A. Pooling ANOVA results from multiply imputed datasets: a simulation study. Methodology. 2016;12(3):75&#x2010;88.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamini Y, Hochberg Y. Controlling the false discovery rate: a practical and powerful approach to multiple testing. J R Stat Soc Series B Stat Methodol. 1995;57(1):289&#x2010;300.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fr&#xfc;hbeck G, Busetto L, Dicker D, et al. The ABCD of obesity: an EASO position statement on a diagnostic term with clinical and scientific implications. Obes Facts. 2019;12(2):131&#x2010;136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>K&#xf6;nig D, H&#xf6;rmann J, Predel HG, Berg A. A 12&#x2010;month lifestyle intervention program improves body composition and reduces the prevalence of prediabetes in obese patients. Obes Facts. 2018;11(5):393&#x2010;399.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lagerstr&#xf8;m D, Berg A, Haas U, et al. Das M.O.B.I.L.I.S.&#x2010;Schulungsprogramm&#x2014;Bewegungstherapie und Lebensstilintervention bei Adipositas und Diabetes. The M.O.B.I.L.I.S. Training Program Exercise Therapy and Lifestyle Intervention for Adiposity and Diabetes. Diabetes Aktuell. 2013;11(1):10&#x2010;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Han M, Rhee SY. Effect of adherence to smartphone app use on the long&#x2010;term effectiveness of weight loss in developing and OECD countries: retrospective cohort study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2021;9(7):e13496. doi:10.2196/13496</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Luley C, Blaik A, G&#xf6;tz A, et al. Weight loss by telemonitoring of nutrition and physical activity in patients with metabolic syndrome for 1 year. J Am Coll Nutr. 2014;33(5):363&#x2010;374.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown A, Flint SW, Kalea AZ, O'Kane M, Williams S, Batterham RL. Negative impact of the first COVID&#x2010;19 lockdown upon health&#x2010;related behaviours and psychological wellbeing in people living with severe and complex obesity in the UK. EClinicalMedicine. 2021;34:100796. doi:10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100796</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai SA, Lv N, Xiao L, Ma J. Gender differences in weight&#x2010;related attitudes and behaviors among overweight and obese adults in the United States. Am J Mens Health. 2016;10(5):389&#x2010;398.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilkins D, Payne S, Granville G, Branney P. The gender and access to health services study: final report. Project Report. Department of Health; 2008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>GKV&#x2010;Spitzenverband. Bericht des GKV&#x2010;Spitzenverbandes &#xfc;ber die Inanspruchnahme und Entwicklung der Versorgung mit Digitalen Gesundheitsanwendungen. Report of the National Association of Statutory Health Insurance Funds on the Utilization and Development of the Provision of Digital Health Applications. Published 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson C, Avenell A, Boachie C, et al. Should weight loss and maintenance programmes be designed differently for men? a systematic review of long&#x2010;term randomised controlled trials presenting data for men and women: the ROMEO project. Obes Res Clin Pract. 2016;10(1):70&#x2010;84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reidpath DD, Cheah JCH, Lam FC, Yasin S, Soyiri I, Allotey P. Validity of self&#x2010;measured waist and hip circumferences: results from a community study in Malaysia. Nutr J. 2013;12(1):135. doi:10.1186/1475&#x2010;2891&#x2010;12&#x2010;135</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>