<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">32673270</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2020</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1929-0748</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>9</Volume><Issue>7</Issue><PubDate><Year>2020</Year><Month>Jul</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JMIR research protocols</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JMIR Res Protoc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A Remotely Delivered, Peer-Led Physical Activity Intervention for Younger Breast Cancer Survivors (Pink Body Spirit): Protocol for a Feasibility Study and Mixed Methods Process Evaluation.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e18420</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e18420</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e18420</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2196/18420</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Younger breast cancer survivors consistently report a greater impact of their cancer experience on quality of life compared with older survivors, including higher rates of body image disturbances, sexual dysfunction, and fatigue. One potential strategy to improve quality of life is through physical activity, but this has been understudied in younger breast cancer survivors, who often decrease their activity during and after cancer treatment.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aim of this study is to explore the feasibility and acceptability of a technology-based, remotely delivered, peer-led physical activity intervention for younger breast cancer survivors. We will also assess the preliminary impact of the intervention on changes in physical activity and multiple aspects of quality of life.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study is a community-academic partnership between University of California, San Diego and Haus of Volta, a nonprofit organization that promotes positive self-image in younger breast cancer survivors. This ongoing pilot study aims to recruit 30 younger breast cancer survivors across the United States (&lt;55 years old, &gt;6 months post primary cancer treatment, self-report &lt;60 min of moderate-to-vigorous-intensity physical activity [MVPA]) into a 3-month peer-delivered, fully remote exercise program. Participants will complete 6 biweekly video chat sessions with a trained peer mentor, a fellow younger breast cancer survivor. Participants will receive a Fitbit Charge 3; weekly feedback on Fitbit data from their peer mentor; and access to a private, in-app Fitbit Community to provide and receive support from other participants and all peer mentors. At baseline, 3 months, and 6 months, participants will complete quality of life questionnaires, and MVPA will be measured using the ActiGraph accelerometer. Feasibility and acceptability will be explored through a mixed methods approach (ie, quantitative questionnaires and qualitative interviews). Intervention delivery and adaptations by peer mentors will be tracked through peer mentor self-evaluations and reflections, review of video-recorded mentoring sessions, and monthly templated reflections by the research team.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Recruitment began in September 2019. As of February 2020, the physical activity intervention is ongoing. Final measures are expected to occur in summer 2020.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study explores the potential for physical activity to improve sexual function, body image, and fatigue, key quality of life issues in younger breast cancer survivors. Using peer mentors extends our reach into the young survivor community. The detailed process evaluation of intervention delivery and adaptations by mentors could inform a future hybrid-effectiveness implementation trial. Finally, remote delivery with commercially available technology could promote broader dissemination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrials.gov NCT04064892; https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04064892.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="INTERNATIONAL REGISTERED REPORT IDENTIFIER (IRRID)" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">DERR1-10.2196/18420.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;Lauren S Weiner, Stori Nagel, H Irene Su, Samantha Hurst, Sheri J Hartman. Originally published in JMIR Research Protocols (http://www.researchprotocols.org), 08.07.2020.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weiner</LastName><ForeName>Lauren S</ForeName><Initials>LS</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1380-1774</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine &amp; Public Health, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Moores Cancer Center, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagel</LastName><ForeName>Stori</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0868-6559</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Haus of Volta, Murrieta, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>H Irene</ForeName><Initials>HI</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6671-5151</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Moores Cancer Center, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Sciences, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hurst</LastName><ForeName>Samantha</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9843-2845</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine &amp; Public Health, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hartman</LastName><ForeName>Sheri J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3719-0624</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine &amp; Public Health, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Moores Cancer Center, University of California, San Diego, La Jolla, CA, United States.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT04064892</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Canada</Country><MedlineTA>JMIR Res Protoc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101599504</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1929-0748</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast cancer</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cancer survivors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fitness trackers</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mobile phone</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peer mentors</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pilot study</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality of life</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflicts of Interest: None declared.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>3</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>8</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32673270</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/18420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">v9i7e18420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Miller K, Nogueira L, Mariotto A, Rowland JH, Yabroff KR, Alfano CM, Jemal A, Kramer JL, Siegel RL. Cancer treatment and survivorship statistics, 2019. CA Cancer J Clin. 2019 Sep;69(5):363&#x2013;85. doi: 10.3322/caac.21565. doi: 10.3322/caac.21565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31184787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ademuyiwa F, Cyr A, Ivanovich J, Thomas M. Managing breast cancer in younger women: challenges and solutions. Breast Cancer (Dove Med Press) 2016;8:1&#x2013;12. doi: 10.2147/BCTT.S68848. doi: 10.2147/BCTT.S68848.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/BCTT.S68848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4694614</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26730210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Murphy BL, Day CN, Hoskin TL, Habermann EB, Boughey JC. Adolescents and young adults with breast cancer have more aggressive disease and treatment than patients in their forties. Ann Surg Oncol. 2019 Nov;26(12):3920&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1245/s10434-019-07653-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-019-07653-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31376035</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Leeuwen M, Husson O, Alberti P, Arraras JI, Chinot OL, Costantini A, Darlington A, Dirven L, Eichler M, Hammerlid EB, Holzner B, Johnson CD, Kontogianni M, Kj&#xe6;r TK, Morag O, Nolte S, Nordin A, Pace A, Pinto M, Polz K, Ramage J, Reijneveld JC, Serpentini S, Tomaszewski KA, Vassiliou V, Verdonck-de Leeuw IM, Vistad I, Young TE, Aaronson NK, van de Poll-Franse LV, EORTC QLG  Understanding the quality of life (QOL) issues in survivors of cancer: towards the development of an EORTC QOL cancer survivorship questionnaire. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2018 Jun 4;16(1):114. doi: 10.1186/s12955-018-0920-0.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12955-018-0920-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5987570</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29866185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pinto A. Sexuality and breast cancer: prime time for young patients. J Thorac Dis. 2013 Jun;5(Suppl 1):S81&#x2013;6. doi: 10.3978/j.issn.2072-1439.2013.05.23. doi: 10.3978/j.issn.2072-1439.2013.05.23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3978/j.issn.2072-1439.2013.05.23</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3695536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23819031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ventura EE, Ganz PA, Bower JE, Abascal L, Petersen L, Stanton AL, Crespi CM. Barriers to physical activity and healthy eating in young breast cancer survivors: modifiable risk factors and associations with body mass index. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2013 Nov;142(2):423&#x2013;33. doi: 10.1007/s10549-013-2749-x.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-013-2749-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4318837</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24177756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin C, Simpson N, Morrow K, Pinto B. Intervention format and delivery preferences among young adult cancer survivors. Int J Behav Med. 2013 Jun;20(2):304&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1007/s12529-012-9227-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12529-012-9227-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22328444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin C. Barriers to increasing physical activity among young adult cancer survivors. J Adolesc Young Adult Oncol. 2017 Jun;6(2):372&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1089/jayao.2016.0056.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jayao.2016.0056</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27893307</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ottenbacher AJ, Day RS, Taylor WC, Sharma SV, Sloane R, Snyder DC, Kraus WE, Demark-Wahnefried W. Exercise among breast and prostate cancer survivors--what are their barriers? J Cancer Surviv. 2011 Dec;5(4):413&#x2013;9. doi: 10.1007/s11764-011-0184-8.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-011-0184-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3223316</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21598023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parsons HM, Harlan LC, Lynch CF, Hamilton AS, Wu X, Kato I, Schwartz SM, Smith AW, Keel G, Keegan TH. Impact of cancer on work and education among adolescent and young adult cancer survivors. J Clin Oncol. 2012 Jul 1;30(19):2393&#x2013;400. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2011.39.6333.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2011.39.6333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3675694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22614977</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone DS, Ganz PA, Pavlish C, Robbins WA. Young adult cancer survivors and work: a systematic review. J Cancer Surviv. 2017 Dec;11(6):765&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1007/s11764-017-0614-3.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-017-0614-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5671547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28478587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vetsch J, Wakefield CE, McGill BC, Cohn RJ, Ellis SJ, Stefanic N, Sawyer SM, Zebrack B, Sansom-Daly UM. Educational and vocational goal disruption in adolescent and young adult cancer survivors. Psychooncology. 2018 Feb;27(2):532&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1002/pon.4525.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4525</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28778113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Avis NE, Crawford S, Manuel J. Quality of life among younger women with breast cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2005 May 20;23(15):3322&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2005.05.130.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2005.05.130</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15908646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruddy KJ, Greaney ML, Sprunck-Harrild K, Meyer ME, Emmons KM, Partridge AH. Young women with breast cancer: a focus group study of unmet needs. J Adolesc Young Adult Oncol. 2013 Dec 1;2(4):153&#x2013;60. doi: 10.1089/jayao.2013.0014.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jayao.2013.0014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3869463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24380034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hungr C, Sanchez-Varela V, Bober SL. Self-image and sexuality issues among young women with breast cancer: practical recommendations. Rev Invest Clin. 2017;69(2):114&#x2013;22. doi: 10.24875/ric.17002200.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24875/ric.17002200</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28453509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leinert E, Singer S, Janni W, Harbeck N, Weissenbacher T, Rack B, Augustin D, Wischnik A, Kiechle M, Ettl J, Fink V, Schwentner L, Eichler M. The impact of age on quality of life in breast cancer patients receiving adjuvant chemotherapy: a comparative analysis from the prospective multicenter randomized Adebar trial. Clin Breast Cancer. 2017 Apr;17(2):100&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.clbc.2016.10.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clbc.2016.10.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27884722</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosenberg SM, Tamimi RM, Gelber S, Ruddy KJ, Kereakoglow S, Borges VF, Come SE, Schapira L, Winer EP, Partridge AH. Body image in recently diagnosed young women with early breast cancer. Psychooncology. 2013 Aug;22(8):1849&#x2013;55. doi: 10.1002/pon.3221.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.3221</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3594059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23132765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheppard VB, Hicks J, Makambi K, Hurtado-de-Mendoza A, Demark-Wahnefried W, Adams-Campbell L. The feasibility and acceptability of a diet and exercise trial in overweight and obese black breast cancer survivors: the stepping STONE study. Contemp Clin Trials. 2016 Jan;46:106&#x2013;13. doi: 10.1016/j.cct.2015.12.005.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2015.12.005</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5091075</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26655430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rock CL, Flatt SW, Byers TE, Colditz GA, Demark-Wahnefried W, Ganz PA, Wolin KY, Elias A, Krontiras H, Liu J, Naughton M, Pakiz B, Parker BA, Sedjo RL, Wyatt H. Results of the exercise and nutrition to enhance recovery and good health for you (ENERGY) trial: a behavioral weight loss intervention in overweight or obese breast cancer survivors. J Clin Oncol. 2015 Oct 1;33(28):3169&#x2013;76. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2015.61.1095.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2015.61.1095</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4582146</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26282657</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen X, Lu W, Zheng W, Gu K, Matthews CE, Chen Z, Zheng Y, Shu XO. Exercise after diagnosis of breast cancer in association with survival. Cancer Prev Res (Phila) 2011 Sep;4(9):1409&#x2013;18. doi: 10.1158/1940-6207.CAPR-10-0355.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1940-6207.CAPR-10-0355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3169008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21795422</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schmid D, Leitzmann M. Association between physical activity and mortality among breast cancer and colorectal cancer survivors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Ann Oncol. 2014 Jul;25(7):1293&#x2013;311. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdu012.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdu012</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24644304</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra S, Scherer R, Geigle P, Berlanstein DR, Topaloglu O, Gotay CC, Snyder C. Exercise interventions on health-related quality of life for cancer survivors. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2012 Aug 15;(8):CD007566. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD007566.pub2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD007566.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7387117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22895961</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferrer RA, Huedo-Medina TB, Johnson BT, Ryan S, Pescatello LS. Exercise interventions for cancer survivors: a meta-analysis of quality of life outcomes. Ann Behav Med. 2011 Feb;41(1):32&#x2013;47. doi: 10.1007/s12160-010-9225-1.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12160-010-9225-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3712334</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20931309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Speck RM, Gross CR, Hormes JM, Ahmed RL, Lytle LA, Hwang W, Schmitz KH. Changes in the body image and relationship scale following a one-year strength training trial for breast cancer survivors with or at risk for lymphedema. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2010 Jun;121(2):421&#x2013;30. doi: 10.1007/s10549-009-0550-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-009-0550-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19771507</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howard-Anderson J, Ganz PA, Bower JE, Stanton AL. Quality of life, fertility concerns, and behavioral health outcomes in younger breast cancer survivors: a systematic review. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2012 Mar 7;104(5):386&#x2013;405. doi: 10.1093/jnci/djr541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/djr541</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22271773</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Cancer Institute. Bethesda MD. Cancer Trends Progress Report. 2020. Mar,  [2020-06-08].   https://progressreport.cancer.gov/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin C, Dunsiger S, Ness KK, Marcus BH. Internet-based physical activity intervention targeting young adult cancer survivors. J Adolesc Young Adult Oncol. 2011 Dec;1(4):188&#x2013;94. doi: 10.1089/jayao.2011.0040.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jayao.2011.0040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623566</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23610737</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Valle CG, Tate DF, Mayer DK, Allicock M, Cai J. A randomized trial of a Facebook-based physical activity intervention for young adult cancer survivors. J Cancer Surviv. 2013 Sep;7(3):355&#x2013;68. doi: 10.1007/s11764-013-0279-5.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-013-0279-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3737370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23532799</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rabin C, Pinto B, Fava J. Randomized trial of a physical activity and meditation intervention for young adult cancer survivors. J Adolesc Young Adult Oncol. 2016 Mar;5(1):41&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1089/jayao.2015.0033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jayao.2015.0033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26812450</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bluethmann SM, Vernon SW, Gabriel KP, Murphy CC, Bartholomew LK. Taking the next step: a systematic review and meta-analysis of physical activity and behavior change interventions in recent post-treatment breast cancer survivors. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2015 Jan;149(2):331&#x2013;42. doi: 10.1007/s10549-014-3255-5.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10549-014-3255-5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4310805</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25555831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Ashford S, Sniehotta FF, Dombrowski SU, Bishop A, French DP. A refined taxonomy of behaviour change techniques to help people change their physical activity and healthy eating behaviours: the CALO-RE taxonomy. Psychol Health. 2011 Nov;26(11):1479&#x2013;98. doi: 10.1080/08870446.2010.540664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08870446.2010.540664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21678185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bluethmann SM, Bartholomew LK, Murphy CC, Vernon SW. Use of theory in behavior change interventions. Health Educ Behav. 2017 Apr;44(2):245&#x2013;53. doi: 10.1177/1090198116647712.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1090198116647712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5503486</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27226430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan AN, Lachman ME. Behavior change with fitness technology in sedentary adults: a review of the evidence for increasing physical activity. Front Public Health. 2016;4:289. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2016.00289. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2016.00289.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2016.00289</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5225122</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28123997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mercer K, Li M, Giangregorio L, Burns C, Grindrod K. Behavior change techniques present in wearable activity trackers: a critical analysis. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2016 Apr 27;4(2):e40. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.4461.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.4461</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4917727</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27122452</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lyons EJ, Lewis ZH, Mayrsohn BG, Rowland JL. Behavior change techniques implemented in electronic lifestyle activity monitors: a systematic content analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2014 Aug 15;16(8):e192. doi: 10.2196/jmir.3469.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/jmir.3469</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4147713</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25131661</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Abraham C, Whittington C, McAteer J, Gupta S. Effective techniques in healthy eating and physical activity interventions: a meta-regression. Health Psychol. 2009 Nov;28(6):690&#x2013;701. doi: 10.1037/a0016136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0016136</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19916637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Samdal GB, Eide GE, Barth T, Williams G, Meland E. Effective behaviour change techniques for physical activity and healthy eating in overweight and obese adults; systematic review and meta-regression analyses. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2017 Mar 28;14(1):42. doi: 10.1186/s12966-017-0494-y.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12966-017-0494-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5370453</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28351367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Richardson M, Johnston M, Abraham C, Francis J, Hardeman W, Eccles MP, Cane J, Wood CE. The behavior change technique taxonomy (v1) of 93 hierarchically clustered techniques: building an international consensus for the reporting of behavior change interventions. Ann Behav Med. 2013 Aug;46(1):81&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1007/s12160-013-9486-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12160-013-9486-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23512568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman SJ, Nelson SH, Cadmus-Bertram LA, Patterson RE, Parker BA, Pierce JP. Technology- and phone-based weight loss intervention: pilot RCT in women at elevated breast cancer risk. Am J Prev Med. 2016 Nov;51(5):714&#x2013;21. doi: 10.1016/j.amepre.2016.06.024.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amepre.2016.06.024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5502803</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27593420</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman SJ, Nelson SH, Myers E, Natarajan L, Sears DD, Palmer BW, Weiner LS, Parker BA, Patterson RE. Randomized controlled trial of increasing physical activity on objectively measured and self-reported cognitive functioning among breast cancer survivors: the memory &amp; motion study. Cancer. 2018 Jan 1;124(1):192&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1002/cncr.30987. doi: 10.1002/cncr.30987.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.30987</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5735009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28926676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman SJ, Nelson SH, Weiner LS. Patterns of FitBit use and activity levels throughout a physical activity intervention: exploratory analysis from a randomized controlled trial. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2018 Feb 5;6(2):e29. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.8503.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.8503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5818675</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29402761</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd G, Hoffman S, Welch W, Blanch-Hartigan D, Gavin KL, Cottrell A, Cadmus-Bertram L, Spring B, Penedo F, Courneya KS, Phillips SM. Breast cancer survivors' preferences for social support features in technology-supported physical activity interventions: findings from a mixed methods evaluation. Transl Behav Med. 2020 May 20;10(2):423&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1093/tbm/iby112.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tbm/iby112</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7237539</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30445595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Robertson MC, Tsai E, Lyons EJ, Srinivasan S, Swartz MC, Baum ML, Basen-Engquist KM. Mobile health physical activity intervention preferences in cancer survivors: a qualitative study. JMIR Mhealth Uhealth. 2017 Jan 24;5(1):e3. doi: 10.2196/mhealth.6970.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/mhealth.6970</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5296620</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28119278</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abrol E, Groszmann M, Pitman A, Hough R, Taylor RM, Aref-Adib G. Exploring the digital technology preferences of teenagers and young adults (TYA) with cancer and survivors: a cross-sectional service evaluation questionnaire. J Cancer Surviv. 2017 Dec;11(6):670&#x2013;82. doi: 10.1007/s11764-017-0618-z.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11764-017-0618-z</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5671543</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28634734</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israel BA, Schulz AJ, Parker EA, Becker AB. Review of community-based research: assessing partnership approaches to improve public health. Annu Rev Public Health. 1998;19:173&#x2013;202. doi: 10.1146/annurev.publhealth.19.1.173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.publhealth.19.1.173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9611617</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Israel BA, Coombe CM, Cheezum RR, Schulz AJ, McGranaghan RJ, Lichtenstein R, Reyes AG, Clement J, Burris A. Community-based participatory research: a capacity-building approach for policy advocacy aimed at eliminating health disparities. Am J Public Health. 2010 Nov;100(11):2094&#x2013;102. doi: 10.2105/AJPH.2009.170506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2105/AJPH.2009.170506</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2951933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20864728</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hartman SJ, Natarajan L, Palmer BW, Parker B, Patterson RE, Sears DD. Impact of increasing physical activity on cognitive functioning in breast cancer survivors: rationale and study design of memory &amp; motion. Contemp Clin Trials. 2015 Nov;45(Pt B):371&#x2013;6. doi: 10.1016/j.cct.2015.09.021.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2015.09.021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4674350</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26427563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu YP, Yi J, McClellan J, Kim J, Tian T, Grahmann B, Kirchhoff AC, Holton A, Wright J. Barriers and facilitators of healthy diet and exercise among adolescent and young adult cancer survivors: implications for behavioral interventions. J Adolesc Young Adult Oncol. 2015 Dec;4(4):184&#x2013;91. doi: 10.1089/jayao.2015.0028.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jayao.2015.0028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4684662</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26697268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gorman JR, Roberts SC, Dominick SA, Malcarne VL, Dietz AC, Su HI. A diversified recruitment approach incorporating social media leads to research participation among young adult-aged female cancer survivors. J Adolesc Young Adult Oncol. 2014 Jun 1;3(2):59&#x2013;65. doi: 10.1089/jayao.2013.0031.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jayao.2013.0031</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4048966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24940529</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thomas S, Reading J, Shephard RJ. Revision of the physical activity readiness questionnaire (PAR-Q) Can J Sport Sci. 1992 Dec;17(4):338&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1330274</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolin KY, Schwartz AL, Matthews CE, Courneya KS, Schmitz KH. Implementing the exercise guidelines for cancer survivors. J Support Oncol. 2012;10(5):171&#x2013;7. doi: 10.1016/j.suponc.2012.02.001.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.suponc.2012.02.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3543866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22579268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martins RK, McNeil DW. Review of motivational interviewing in promoting health behaviors. Clin Psychol Rev. 2009 Jun;29(4):283&#x2013;93. doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2009.02.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2009.02.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19328605</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Motivational Interviewing Step by Step. Pychotherapy.net Academy.  [2020-06-08].   https://academy.psychotherapy.net/store/jhDjd9Xc.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carver CS, Scheier MF. Control theory: a useful conceptual framework for personality&#x2013;social, clinical, and health psychology. Psychol Bull. 1982;92(1):111&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1037/0033-2909.92.1.111.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.92.1.111</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7134324</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. Social Foundations of Thought and Action: A Social Cognitive Theory. Englewood Cliffs, NJ: Prentice Hall; 1986.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rock CL, Doyle C, Demark-Wahnefried W, Meyerhardt J, Courneya KS, Schwartz AL, Bandera EV, Hamilton KK, Grant B, McCullough M, Byers T, Gansler T. Nutrition and physical activity guidelines for cancer survivors. CA Cancer J Clin. 2012;62(4):243&#x2013;74. doi: 10.3322/caac.21142. doi: 10.3322/caac.21142.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3322/caac.21142</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22539238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Diabetes Prevention Program (DPP) Research Group  The diabetes prevention program (DPP): description of lifestyle intervention. Diabetes Care. 2002 Dec;25(12):2165&#x2013;71. doi: 10.2337/diacare.25.12.2165.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/diacare.25.12.2165</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1282458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Look AHEAD Research Group. Wadden TA, West DS, Delahanty L, Jakicic J, Rejeski J, Williamson D, Berkowitz RI, Kelley DE, Tomchee C, Hill JO, Kumanyika S. The look AHEAD study: a description of the lifestyle intervention and the evidence supporting it. Obesity (Silver Spring) 2006 May;14(5):737&#x2013;52. doi: 10.1038/oby.2006.84. doi: 10.1038/oby.2006.84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2006.84</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2613279</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16855180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J. In: Designing and Conducting Mixed Methods Research. Third Edition. Plano W, Clark VL, editors. Thousand Oaks, CA: SAGE Publications; 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weiner BJ, Lewis CC, Stanick C, Powell BJ, Dorsey CN, Clary AS, Boynton MH, Halko H. Psychometric assessment of three newly developed implementation outcome measures. Implement Sci. 2017 Aug 29;12(1):108. doi: 10.1186/s13012-017-0635-3.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13012-017-0635-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5576104</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28851459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedson PS, Melanson E, Sirard J. Calibration of the computer science and applications inc accelerometer. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 1998 May;30(5):777&#x2013;81. doi: 10.1097/00005768-199805000-00021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005768-199805000-00021</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9588623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nelson SH, Weiner LS, Natarajan L, Parker BA, Patterson RE, Hartman SJ. Continuous, objective measurement of physical activity during chemotherapy for breast cancer: the activity in treatment pilot study. Transl Behav Med. 2019 May 29;:-. doi: 10.1093/tbm/ibz079. epub ahead of print.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/tbm/ibz079</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543083</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31141593</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hopwood P, Fletcher I, Lee A, Al Ghazal S. A body image scale for use with cancer patients. Eur J Cancer. 2001 Jan;37(2):189&#x2013;97. doi: 10.1016/s0959-8049(00)00353-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0959-8049(00)00353-1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11166145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lewis-Smith H, Diedrichs PC, Rumsey N, Harcourt D. Efficacy of psychosocial and physical activity-based interventions to improve body image among women treated for breast cancer: a systematic review. Psychooncology. 2018 Dec;27(12):2687&#x2013;99. doi: 10.1002/pon.4870.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/pon.4870</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30161285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosen R, Brown C, Heiman J, Leiblum S, Meston C, Shabsigh R, Ferguson D, D'Agostino R. The female sexual function index (FSFI): a multidimensional self-report instrument for the assessment of female sexual function. J Sex Marital Ther. 2000;26(2):191&#x2013;208. doi: 10.1080/009262300278597.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/009262300278597</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10782451</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartula I, Sherman KA. The female sexual functioning index (FSFI): evaluation of acceptability, reliability, and validity in women with breast cancer. Support Care Cancer. 2015 Sep;23(9):2633&#x2013;41. doi: 10.1007/s00520-015-2623-y.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00520-015-2623-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25669965</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Halis F, Yildirim P, Kocaaslan R, Cecen K, Gokce A. Pilates for better sex: changes in sexual functioning in healthy Turkish women after pilates exercise. J Sex Marital Ther. 2016 May 18;42(4):302&#x2013;8. doi: 10.1080/0092623X.2015.1033576.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0092623X.2015.1033576</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25826474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorenz TA, Meston CM. Exercise improves sexual function in women taking antidepressants: results from a randomized crossover trial. Depress Anxiety. 2014 Mar;31(3):188&#x2013;95. doi: 10.1002/da.22208.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4039497</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24754044</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cella D, Lai J, Jensen SE, Christodoulou C, Junghaenel DU, Reeve BB, Stone AA. PROMIS fatigue item bank had clinical validity across diverse chronic conditions. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016 May;73:128&#x2013;34. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2015.08.037.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2015.08.037</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4902759</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26939927</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jensen RE, Moinpour CM, Potosky AL, Lobo T, Hahn EA, Hays RD, Cella D, Smith AW, Wu X, Keegan TH, Paddock LE, Stroup AM, Eton DT. Responsiveness of 8 patient-reported outcomes measurement information system (PROMIS) measures in a large, community-based cancer study cohort. Cancer. 2017 Jan 1;123(2):327&#x2013;35. doi: 10.1002/cncr.30354. doi: 10.1002/cncr.30354.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.30354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5222745</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27696377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rogers LQ, Vicari S, Trammell R, Hopkins-Price P, Fogleman A, Spenner A, Rao K, Courneya KS, Hoelzer KS, Robbs R, Verhulst S. Biobehavioral factors mediate exercise effects on fatigue in breast cancer survivors. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2014 Jun;46(6):1077&#x2013;88. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000210.  </Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/MSS.0000000000000210</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4435796</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24212124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beebe J. Rapid Assessment Process: An Introduction. Lanham, MD: AltaMira Press; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton A. Qualitative Methods in Rapid Turn-Around Health Services Research. VA's Health Services Research and Development Service. 2013.  [2020-06-08].   https://www.hsrd.research.va.gov/for_researchers/cyber_seminars/archives/video_archive.cfm?SessionID=780.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mobile Fact Sheet. Pew Research Center. 2019.  [2019-06-12].   https://www.pewinternet.org/fact-sheet/mobile/</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>