<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">41950941</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-1058</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Psychotherapie, Psychosomatik, medizinische Psychologie</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Psychother Psychosom Med Psychol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Improving quality of life in cancer patients with an app-based intervention (Mika-App): secondary results from a randomized controlled waitlist-trial in Germany.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-2826-5988</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Psychological distress in cancer patients can be reduced through digital support tools, such as the Mika-App. Yet, the effect on various dimensions of quality of life (QoL) remains unclear. In a secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial (RCT), we aimed to investigate the effect of the Mika-App on physical and mental QoL, and to explore potential moderators such as age, sex, and digital health literacy (DHL).Patients diagnosed with cancer within the past five years were recruited for this nationwide RCT in Germany. Participants were randomly assigned to either the intervention group (IG, access to the Mika-App), or the wait-list control group (CG, usual care). Online questionnaires were administered at baseline, 2, 6 and 12 weeks. Physical and mental QoL was assessed with the Short-Form Health Survey (SF-8). Linear mixed-effects models were used to test for changes in QoL over time between groups and to examine moderating effects. Analyses were conducted intention-to-treat (ITT) and per-protocol (PP).A total of 218 patients (IG=99, CG=119) were included, with a mean age of 56 years, 61% being female. Patients in the IG demonstrated significant improvements in mental QoL over time compared to the CG (ITT: F(3, 623.46)=3.58, p=0.014; PP: F(3, 360.38)=5.54, p=0.001), with small-to-medium effect sizes between groups at the 6- and 12-week follow-ups (Cohens' d=0.26-0.69). There was no change in physical QoL in both groups (ITT: p=0.90; PP: p=0.88). Age, sex, and DHL did not moderate the interventions' effect on QoL (all p&gt;0.05).While physical QoL remained unchanged, mental QoL significantly improved. This reflects the app's content features, mainly targeting self-management skills and psychological distress. The app appears to be equally beneficial across all age groups, for men and women. Since DHL was particularly high in our sample, possibly due to the predominantly online recruitment strategy, results on DHL need to be interpreted with caution. Further research is needed on the role of DHL in the efficacy of digital support tools in the context of routine clinical care.Digital support tools have the potential to improve QoL in patients with cancer. Integrating these tools into clinical care practice might provide valuable support for patients in need by addressing their specific symptoms.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). This is an open access article published by Thieme under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, permitting unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction so long as the original work is properly cited. (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Springer</LastName><ForeName>Franziska</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1586-4050</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Psychology and Medical Sociology, Leipzig University, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brock</LastName><ForeName>Hannah</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Psychology and Medical Sociology, Leipzig University, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kreilinger</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Psychology and Medical Sociology, Leipzig University, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Finke</LastName><ForeName>Gandolf</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fosanis GmbH, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Raue</LastName><ForeName>Jan Simon</ForeName><Initials>JS</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Fosanis GmbH, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mehnert-Theuerkauf</LastName><ForeName>Anja</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Psychology and Medical Sociology, Leipzig University, Leipzig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><VernacularTitle>Verbesserung der Lebensqualit&#xe4;t von Krebspatient:innen durch eine App-basierte Intervention (Mika-App): Sekund&#xe4;re Ergebnisse einer randomisierten kontrollierten Wartelistenstudie in Deutschland.</VernacularTitle><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Germany</Country><MedlineTA>Psychother Psychosom Med Psychol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8002823</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0937-2032</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger"><AbstractText>Die psychische Belastung von Krebspatient*innen kann durch digitale Unterst&#xfc;tzungsangebote wie die Mika-App verbessert werden. Unklar bleibt der Effekt auf verschiedenen Dimensionen der Lebensqualit&#xe4;t. Ziel dieser Sekund&#xe4;ranalyse einer randomisierten kontrollierten Studie (RCT) war es, den Effekt der Mika-App auf k&#xf6;rperliche und psychische Lebensqualit&#xe4;t zu untersuchen und m&#xf6;gliche Moderatoren wie Alter, Geschlecht und digitale Gesundheitskompetenz (DHL) zu identifizieren.F&#xfc;r diese deutschlandweite RCT wurden Patient*innen rekrutiert, bei denen innerhalb der letzten f&#xfc;nf Jahre Krebs diagnostiziert wurde. Teilnehmende wurden randomisiert der Interventionsgruppe (IG, Zugang zur Mika-App) oder der Wartelisten-Kontrollgruppe (CG, Standardversorgung) zugewiesen. Online-Frageb&#xf6;gen wurden zur Baseline sowie nach 2, 6 und 12 Wochen ausgef&#xfc;llt. Die Lebensqualit&#xe4;t wurde mit dem Short-Form Health Survey (SF-8) erfasst. Lineare gemischte Modelle pr&#xfc;ften Gruppenunterschiede in der Ver&#xe4;nderungen der Lebensqualit&#xe4;t &#xfc;ber die Zeit, als auch m&#xf6;gliche Moderationseffekte. Die Analysen erfolgten Intention-to-Treat (ITT) und Per-Protocol (PP).Insgesamt wurden 218 Patient*innen (IG=99, CG=119) eingeschlossen, mit einem Durchschnittsalter von 56 Jahren, 61% waren weiblich. Die IG zeigte im Vergleich zur CG eine signifikante Verbesserung der psychischen Lebensqualit&#xe4;t &#xfc;ber die Zeit (ITT: F(3, 623,46)=3.58, p=0,014; PP: F(3, 360,38)=5,54, p=0,001), mit kleinen bis mittleren Effektgr&#xf6;&#xdf;en zwischen den Gruppen zum 6- und 12-w&#xf6;chigen Follow-Up (Cohens&#x2018; d=0,26&#x2013;0,69). Die k&#xf6;rperliche Lebensqualit&#xe4;t unterschied sich nicht (ITT: p=0,90; PP: p=0,88). Es zeigten sich keine Moderationseffekte von Alter, Geschlecht und DHL (p&gt;0,05).W&#xe4;hrend die k&#xf6;rperliche Lebensqualit&#xe4;t unver&#xe4;ndert blieb, verbesserte sich die psychische Lebensqualit&#xe4;t signifikant. Dies spiegelt die App-Inhalte wieder, die v.&#x2009;a. auf Selbstmanagement und psychischen Belastungssymptome abzielen. Die Wirksamkeit zeigt sich in allen Altersgruppen, bei M&#xe4;nnern und Frauen. Die hohe DHL in unserer Stichprobe, m&#xf6;glicherweise durch die vorwiegend onlinebasierten Rekrutierung, erfordert eine Interpretation mit Vorsicht. Der Einfluss der DHL auf die Wirksamkeit digitaler Angebote muss im Rahmen klinischer Routineversorgung weiter untersucht werden.Digitale Unterst&#xfc;tzungsangebote haben das Potential die Lebensqualit&#xe4;t der Betroffenen zu verbessern. Die Integration in die klinische Versorgung bietet eine wertvolle M&#xf6;glichkeit, Betroffene mit spezifischen Symptomen gezielt zu unterst&#xfc;tzen.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). This is an open access article published by Thieme under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, permitting unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction so long as the original work is properly cited. (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</CopyrightInformation></OtherAbstract><CoiStatement>JSR and GF are managing directors, board members of Fosanis GmbH, and own shares of Fosanis GmbH. All other authors have no conflicts of interest</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>53</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41950941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-2826-5988</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>