<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Curated"><PMID Version="1">25436933</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2015</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>06</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1471-2458</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>14 Suppl 3</Volume><Issue>Suppl 3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2014</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC public health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Public Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Fitness level and body composition indices: cross-sectional study among Malaysian adolescent.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>S5</StartPage><MedlinePgn>S5</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/1471-2458-14-S3-S5</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The importance of fitness level on the well-being of children and adolescent has long been recognised. The aim of this study was to investigate the fitness level of school-going Malaysian adolescent, and its association with body composition indices.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">1071 healthy secondary school students participated in the fitness assessment for the Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team (MyHEART) study. Body composition indices such as body mass index for age, waist circumference and waist height ratio were measured. Fitness level was assessed with Modified Harvard Step Test. Physical Fitness Score was calculated using total time of step test exercise and resting heart rates. Fitness levels were divided into 3 categories - unacceptable, marginally acceptable, and acceptable. Partial correlation analysis was used to determine the association between fitness score and body composition, by controlling age, gender, locality, ethnicity, smoking status and sexual maturation. Multiple regression analysis was conducted to determine which body composition was the strongest predictor for fitness.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">43.3% of the participants were categorised into the unacceptable fitness group, 47.1% were considered marginally acceptable, and 9.6% were acceptable. There was a significant moderate inverse association (p &lt; 0.001) between body composition with fitness score (r = -0.360, -0.413 and -0.403 for body mass index for age, waist circumference and waist height ratio, respectively). Waist circumference was the strongest and significant predictor for fitness (&#xdf; = -0.318, p = 0.002).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Only 9.6% of the students were fit. There was also an inverse association between body composition and fitness score among apparently healthy adolescents, with waist circumference indicated as the strongest predictor. The low fitness level among the Malaysian adolescent should necessitate the value of healthy lifestyle starting at a young age.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hanifah</LastName><ForeName>Redzal Abu</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Majid</LastName><ForeName>Hazreen Abdul</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jalaludin</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Yazid</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Al-Sadat</LastName><ForeName>Nabilla</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Murray</LastName><ForeName>Liam J</ForeName><Initials>LJ</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cantwell</LastName><ForeName>Marie</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>Tin Tin</ForeName><Initials>TT</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nahar</LastName><ForeName>Azmi Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Public Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>100968562</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1471-2458</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001823" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Composition</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015992" MajorTopicYN="Y">Body Mass Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008296" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Malaysia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010809" MajorTopicYN="N">Physical Fitness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055105" MajorTopicYN="Y">Waist Circumference</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D065927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Waist-Height Ratio</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2014</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2015</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2014</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25436933</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4251133</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-14-S3-S5</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">1471-2458-14-S3-S5</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Caspersen CJ, Powell KE, Christenson GM. Physical activity, exercise, and physical fitness: definitions and distinctions for health-related research. Public Health Rep. 1985;100(2):126&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1424733</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3920711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pescatello L, American College of Sports Medicine. ACSM's guidelines for exercise testing and prescription. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer/Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins Health; 2014.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clarke H. Phycial Fitness Research Digest Series 1 Number 1. Washington, DC: President's Council on Physical Fitness and Sports; 1971.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laukkanen JA, Rauramaa R, Salonen JT, Kurl S. The predictive value of cardiorespiratory fitness combined with coronary risk evaluation and the risk of cardiovascular and all-cause death. J Intern Med. 2007;262(2):263&#x2013;272.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17645594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Laukkanen JA, Rauramaa R, Kurl S. Exercise workload, coronary risk evaluation and the risk of cardiovascular and all-cause death in middle-aged men. Eur J Cardiovasc Prev Rehabil. 2008;15(3):285&#x2013;292.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18525382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aijaz B, Babuin L, Squires RW, Kopecky SL, Johnson BD, Thomas RJ, Allison TG. Long-term mortality with multiple treadmill exercise test abnormalities: comparison between patients with and without cardiovascular disease. Am Heart J. 2008;156(4):783&#x2013;789.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18926161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Velasquez-Mieyer P, Perez-Faustinelli S, Cowan PA. Identifying Children at Risk for Obesity, Type 2 Diabetes, and Cardiovascular Disease. Diabetes Spectr. 2005;18(4):213&#x2013;220.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman DS, Khan LK, Dietz WH, Srinivasan SR, Berenson GS. Relationship of childhood obesity to coronary heart disease risk factors in adulthood: the Bogalusa Heart Study. Pediatrics. 2001;108(3):712&#x2013;718.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11533341</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agirbasli M, Agaoglu NB, Ergonul O, Yagmur I, Aydogar H, Oneri T, Ozturk O. Comparison of anthropometric indices in predicting metabolic syndrome components in children. Metab Syndr Relat Disord. 2011;9(6):453&#x2013;459.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21830913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim C, Kim B, Joo N, Park Y, Lim H, Ju Y, Yang S, Park S, Cho B, Park K. Determination of the BMI threshold that predicts cardiovascular risk and insulin resistance in late childhood. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2010;88(3):307&#x2013;313.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20223547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JM, Davis MM, Woolford SJ, Gurney JG. Waist circumference percentile thresholds for identifying adolescents with insulin resistance in clinical practice. Pediatr Diabetes. 2009;10(5):336&#x2013;342.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19175894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng L, Luo N, Mi J. Impacts of types and degree of obesity on non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and related dyslipidemia in Chinese school-age children? Biomed Environ Sci. 2011;24(1):22&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21440836</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson ST, Kuk JL, Mackenzie KA, Huang TT, Rosychuk RJ, Ball GD. Metabolic risk varies according to waist circumference measurement site in overweight boys and girls. J Pediatr. 2010;156(2):247&#x2013;252 e241.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19863969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goulding A, Taylor RW, Grant AM, Parnell WR, Wilson NC, Williams SM. Waist-to-height ratios in relation to BMI z-scores in three ethnic groups from a representative sample of New Zealand children aged 5-14 years. Int J Obes. 2010;34(7):1188&#x2013;1190.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20065976</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mokha JS, Srinivasan SR, Dasmahapatra P, Fernandez C, Chen W, Xu J, Berenson GS. Utility of waist-to-height ratio in assessing the status of central obesity and related cardiometabolic risk profile among normal weight and overweight/obese children: the Bogalusa Heart Study. BMC Pediatr. 2010;10:73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2964659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20937123</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwandt P, Bertsch T, Haas GM. Anthropometric screening for silent cardiovascular risk factors in adolescents: The PEP Family Heart Study. Atherosclerosis. 2010;211(2):667&#x2013;671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20417933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee SJ, Arslanian SA. Cardiorespiratory fitness and abdominal adiposity in youth. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2007;61(4):561&#x2013;565.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17021595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brunet M, Chaput JP, Tremblay A. The association between low physical fitness and high body mass index or waist circumference is increasing with age in children: the 'Quebec en Forme' Project. Int J Obes. 2007;31(4):637&#x2013;643.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17006443</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega FB, Tresaco B, Ruiz JR, Moreno LA, Martin-Matillas M, Mesa JL, Warnberg J, Bueno M, Tercedor P, Gutierrez A. et al. Cardiorespiratory fitness and sedentary activities are associated with adiposity in adolescents. Obesity. 2007;15(6):1589&#x2013;1599.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17557997</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hussey J, Bell C, Bennett K, O'Dwyer J, Gormley J. Relationship between the intensity of physical activity, inactivity, cardiorespiratory fitness and body composition in 7-10-year-old Dublin children. Br J Sports Med. 2007;41(5):311&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2659066</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17395610</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dan SP, Mohd Nasir MT, Zalilah MS. Sex and ethnic differentials in physical activity levels of adolescents in kuantan. Malays J Nutr. 2007;13(2):109&#x2013;120.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22691749</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashim HA, Golok F, Ali R. Profiles of exercise motivation, physical activity, exercise habit, and academic performance in Malaysian adolescents: A cluster analysis. Int J Collab Res Internal Med Public Health. 2011;3(6):416&#x2013;428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abu Hanifah R, Mohamed MNA, Jaafar Z, Abdul Mohsein NA-S, MY J. The Correlates of Body Composition with Heart Rate Recovery after Step Test: An Exploratory Study of Malaysian Adolescents. PloS one. 2013;8(12):e82893.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3857804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24349388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanner JM, Whitehouse RH. Clinical longitudinal standards for height, weight, height velocity, weight velocity, and stages of puberty. Arch Dis Child. 1976;51(3):170&#x2013;179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1545912</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">952550</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevino RP, Marshall RM, Hale DE, Rodriguez R, Baker G, Gomez J. Diabetes risk factors in low-income Mexican-American children. Diabetes care. 1999;22(2):202&#x2013;207.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10333934</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Trevino RP, Fogt DL, Wyatt TJ, Leal-Vasquez L, Sosa E, Woods C. Diabetes risk, low fitness, and energy insufficiency levels among children from poor families. J Am Diet Assoc. 2008;108(11):1846&#x2013;1853.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18954574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez-Suarez CB, Lee-Pineda K, Zamora MTG, Sibug EO, Velasco ZF, Grimmer-Somers K. Cardiovascular Fitness and Caloric Intake in Filipino Obese Children: An Observational Study. Asian Journal of Clinical Nutrition 2012. 2012;4(3):88&#x2013;97.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LJ, Fox KR, Haase A, Wang JM. Obesity, fitness and health in Taiwanese children and adolescents. Eur J Clin Nutr. 2006;60(12):1367&#x2013;1375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16775581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mak KK, Ho SY, Lo WS, Thomas GN, McManus AM, Day JR, Lam TH. Health-related physical fitness and weight status in Hong Kong adolescents. BMC public health. 2010;10:88.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2836297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20178615</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ostojic SM, Stojanovic MD, Stojanovic V, Maric J, Njaradi N. Correlation between fitness and fatness in 6-14-year old Serbian school children. J Health Popul Nutr. 2011;29(1):53&#x2013;60.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3075053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21528790</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ortega FB, Ruiz JR, Hurtig-Wennlof A, Vicente-Rodriguez G, Rizzo NS, Castillo MJ, Sjostrom M. Cardiovascular fitness modifies the associations between physical activity and abdominal adiposity in children and adolescents: the European Youth Heart Study. Br J Sports Med. 2010;44(4):256&#x2013;262.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18463298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burns R, Hannon JC, Brusseau TA, Shultz B, Eisenman P. Indices of abdominal adiposity and cardiorespiratory fitness test performance in middle-school students. J Obes. 2013;2013:912460.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3603281</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23533727</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willig AL, Hunter GR, Casazza K, Heimburger DC, Beasley TM, Fernandez JR. Body fat and racial genetic admixture are associated with aerobic fitness levels in a multiethnic pediatric population. Obesity. 2011;19(11):2222&#x2013;2227.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3182292</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21546928</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turley KR. Cardiovascular responses to exercise in children. Sports Med. 1997;24(4):241&#x2013;257.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9339493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rowland T, Goff D, Martel L, Ferrone L. Influence of cardiac functional capacity on gender differences in maximal oxygen uptake in children. Chest. 2000;117(3):629&#x2013;635.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10712984</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tomkinson GR, Annandales M, Ferrar K. Global Changes in Cardiovascular Endurance of Children and Youth Since 1964: Systematic Analysis of 25 Million Fitness Test Results from 28 Countries [abstract] Circulation. 2013;128:A13498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz JR, Rizzo NS, Ortega FB, Loit HM, Veidebaum T, Sjostrom M. Markers of insulin resistance are associated with fatness and fitness in school-aged children: the European Youth Heart Study. Diabetologia. 2007;50(7):1401&#x2013;1408.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17492430</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jimenez-Pavon D, Castillo MJ, Moreno LA, Kafatos A, Manios Y, Kondaki K, Beghin L, Zaccaria M, de Henauw S, Widhalm K. et al. Fitness and fatness are independently associated with markers of insulin resistance in European adolescents; the HELENA study. Int J Pediatr Obes. 2011;6(3-4):253&#x2013;260.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21623681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eisenmann JC, Welk GJ, Ihmels M, Dollman J. Fatness, fitness, and cardiovascular disease risk factors in children and adolescents. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2007;39(8):1251&#x2013;1256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17762357</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berkey CS, Rockett HR, Field AE, Gillman MW, Frazier AL, Camargo CA, Colditz GA. Activity, dietary intake, and weight changes in a longitudinal study of preadolescent and adolescent boys and girls. Pediatrics. 2000;105(4):E56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10742377</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilks DC, Rank M, Christle J, Langhof H, Siegrist M, Halle M. An inpatient lifestyle-change programme improves heart rate recovery in overweight and obese children and adolescents (LOGIC Trial) Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23109407</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara I, Vicente-Rodriguez G, Perez-Gomez J, Jimenez-Ramirez J, Serrano-Sanchez JA, Dorado C, Calbet JA. Influence of extracurricular sport activities on body composition and physical fitness in boys: a 3-year longitudinal study. Int J Obes. 2006;30(7):1062&#x2013;1071.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16801944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hruby A, Chomitz VR, Arsenault LN, Must A, Economos CD, McGowan RJ, Sacheck JM. Predicting maintenance or achievement of healthy weight in children: the impact of changes in physical fitness. Obesity. 2012;20(8):1710&#x2013;1717.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4465563</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22307068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DuBose KD, Eisenmann JC, Donnelly JE. Aerobic fitness attenuates the metabolic syndrome score in normal-weight, at-risk-for-overweight, and overweight children. Pediatrics. 2007;120(5):e1262&#x2013;1268.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17974719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sacheck JM, Kuder JF, Economos CD. Physical fitness, adiposity, and metabolic risk factors in young college students. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010;42(6):1039&#x2013;1044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19997014</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMurray RG, Harrell JS, Bangdiwala SI, Bradley CB, Deng S, Levine A. A school-based intervention can reduce body fat and blood pressure in young adolescents. J Adolesc Health. 2002;31(2):125&#x2013;132.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12127382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Danforth JS, Allen KD, Fitterling JM, Danforth JA, Farrar D, Brown M, Drabman RS. Exercise as a treatment for hypertension in low-socioeconomic-status black children. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1990;58(2):237&#x2013;239.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2335640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McKay HA, MacLean L, Petit M, MacKelvie-O'Brien K, Janssen P, Beck T, Khan KM. "Bounce at the Bell": a novel program of short bouts of exercise improves proximal femur bone mass in early pubertal children. Br J Sports Med. 2005;39(8):521&#x2013;526.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1725273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16046335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacKelvie KJ, Khan KM, Petit MA, Janssen PA, McKay HA. A school-based exercise intervention elicits substantial bone health benefits: a 2-year randomized controlled trial in girls. Pediatrics. 2003;112(6 Pt 1):e447.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14654643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly JE, Lambourne K. Classroom-based physical activity, cognition, and academic achievement. Prev Med. 2011;52(Suppl 1):S36&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21281666</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dwyer T, Sallis JF, Blizzard L, Lazarus R. Relationship of academic performance to physical activity and fitness in children. Pediatr Exerc Sci. 2001;13(3):225&#x2013;237.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winsley RJ, Armstrong N, Middlebrooke AR, Ramos-Ibanez N, Williams CA. Aerobic fitness and visceral adipose tissue in children. Acta Paediatr. 2006;95(11):1435&#x2013;1438.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17062473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haas GM, Liepold E, Schwandt P. Percentile curves for fat patterning in German adolescents. World J Pediatr. 2011;7(1):16&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21191772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brambilla P, Bedogni G, Moreno LA, Goran MI, Gutin B, Fox KR, Peters DM, Barbeau P, De Simone M, Pietrobelli A. Crossvalidation of anthropometry against magnetic resonance imaging for the assessment of visceral and subcutaneous adipose tissue in children. Int J Obes. 2006;30(1):23&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16344845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Seppala-Lindroos A, Vehkavaara S, Hakkinen AM, Goto T, Westerbacka J, Sovijarvi A, Halavaara J, Yki-Jarvinen H. Fat accumulation in the liver is associated with defects in insulin suppression of glucose production and serum free fatty acids independent of obesity in normal men. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2002;87(7):3023&#x2013;3028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12107194</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klein S, Allison DB, Heymsfield SB, Kelley DE, Leibel RL, Nonas C, Kahn R. Waist Circumference and Cardiometabolic Risk: a Consensus Statement from Shaping America's Health: Association for Weight Management and Obesity Prevention; NAASO, the Obesity Society; the American Society for Nutrition; and the American Diabetes Association. Obesity. 2007;15(5):1061&#x2013;1067.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17495180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara I, Moreno LA, Leiva MT, Gutin B, Casajus JA. Adiposity, physical activity, and physical fitness among children from Aragon, Spain. Obesity. 2007;15(8):1918&#x2013;1924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17712107</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ara I, Vicente-Rodriguez G, Jimenez-Ramirez J, Dorado C, Serrano-Sanchez JA, Calbet JA. Regular participation in sports is associated with enhanced physical fitness and lower fat mass in prepubertal boys. Int J Obes Relat Metab Disord. 2004;28(12):1585&#x2013;1593.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15303104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rengasamy S. A physical fitness intervention program within a physical education class on selected health-related fitness among secondary school students. Procedia Soc Behav Sci. 2012;55(2012):1104&#x2013;1112.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>