<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">28191544</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>12</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2474-3690</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2016</Year></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of hypertension and management</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Hypertens Manag</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>MyHEART: A Non Randomized Feasibility Study of a Young Adult Hypertension Intervention.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">016</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In the United States, young adults (18-39 year-olds) have the lowest hypertension control rates (35%) compared to middle-aged (58%) and older (54%) adults. Ambulatory care for hypertension management often focuses on medication with little time for self-management and behavioral counseling. This study was designed to evaluate the feasibility of MyHEART, a telephone-based health coach self-management intervention for young adults. The goals were to determine the intervention's ability to: 1) recruit young adults with uncontrolled hypertension, 2) maintain ongoing communication between the coach and participants, 3) increase participants' engagement in self-management, 4) document coach-patient communication in the electronic health record, and 5) assess patient acceptability.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Eligible participants were identified through the electronic health record. Inclusion criteria included 18-39 year-olds, with ICD-9 hypertension diagnoses and uncontrolled hypertension (&#x2265; 140/90 mmHg), receiving regular primary care at a large multispecialty group practice. The intervention consisted of 6 telephone self-management sessions by a health coach targeting lifestyle modifications. Patients completed an open-ended acceptability survey.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Study uptake was 47% (9 enrolled/19 eligible). Mean (SD) age was 35.8 (2.6) years, 78% male, and 33% Black. Over 85% of enrolled young adults maintained communication with their health coach. At baseline, 11% reported checking their blood pressure outside of clinic; 44% reported blood pressure monitoring after the study. All coach-patient encounters were successfully documented in the electronic health record for primary care provider review. Open-ended responses from all surveys indicated that participants had a positive experience with the MyHEART intervention.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study demonstrated that MyHEART was feasible and acceptable to young adults with uncontrolled hypertension. Health coaches can effectively maintain ongoing communication with young adults, document communication in the electronic health record, and increase engagement with home blood pressure monitoring. The results of this study will inform a multi-center young adult randomized controlled trial of MyHEART.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Heather M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA; Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>LaMantia</LastName><ForeName>Jamie N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA; Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Warner</LastName><ForeName>Ryan C</ForeName><Initials>RC</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Counselor Education and Counseling Psychology, Marquette University, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pandhi</LastName><ForeName>Nancy</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA; Department of Family Medicine and Community Health, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bartels</LastName><ForeName>Christie M</ForeName><Initials>CM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA; Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Maureen A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA; Department of Surgery, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA; Department of Family Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA; Department of Population Health Sciences, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lauver</LastName><ForeName>Diane R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Wisconsin-Madison School of Nursing, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR000427</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K08 AG029527</GrantID><Acronym>AG</Acronym><Agency>NIA NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 RR025011</GrantID><Acronym>RR</Acronym><Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL112907</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>K23 AR062381</GrantID><Acronym>AR</Acronym><Agency>NIAMS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2016</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>J Hypertens Manag</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101697509</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2474-3690</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Feasibility</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health coach</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary care</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-determination theory</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Young adult</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2017</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28191544</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS835211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5300088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.23937/2474-3690/1510016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>  http://www.cdc.gov/bloodpressure/facts.htm.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nguyen QC, Tabor JW, Entzel PP, Lau Y, Suchindran C, et al. Discordance in national estimates of hypertension among young adults. Epidemiology. 2011;22:532&#x2013;541.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3109249</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21610501</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell AB, Cole JW, McArdle PF, Cheng YC, Ryan KA, et al. Obesity increases risk of ischemic stroke in young adults. Stroke. 2015;46:1690&#x2013;1692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4458137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25944320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozaffarian D, Benjamin EJ, Go AS, Arnett DK, Blaha MJ, et al. Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics-2016 Update: A Report From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2016;134:e38&#x2013;e360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26673558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chobanian AV, Bakris GL, Black HR, Cushman WC, Green LA, et al. The Seventh Report of the Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure: the JNC 7 report. JAMA. 2003;289:2560&#x2013;2572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12748199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ES, Ajani UA, Croft JB, Critchley JA, Labarthe DR, et al. Explaining the decrease in U.S. deaths from coronary disease, 1980&#x2013;2000. N Engl J Med. 2007;356:2388&#x2013;2398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17554120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth HB, Powers BJ, Olsen MK, McCant F, Grubber J, et al. Home blood pressure management and improved blood pressure control: results from a randomized controlled trial. Arch Intern Med. 2011;171:1173&#x2013;1180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson GL, Oddone EZ, Olsen MK, Powers BJ, Grubber JM, et al. Racial differences in the effect of a telephone-delivered hypertension disease management program. J Gen Intern Med. 2012;27:1682&#x2013;1689.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3509293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22865016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolius D, Bodenheimer T, Bennett H, Wong J, Ngo V, et al. Health coaching to improve hypertension treatment in a low-income, minority population. Ann Fam Med. 2012;10:199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3354968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22585883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Thorpe CT, Bartels CM, Schumacher JR, Palta M, et al. Antihypertensive medication initiation among young adults with regular primary care use. J Gen Intern Med. 2014;29:723&#x2013;731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4000352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24493322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>  http://www.ahrq.gov/research/findings/final-reports/ptmgmt/ptmgmt.pdf.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Abraham C, Whittington C, McAteer J, Gupta S. Effective techniques in healthy eating and physical activity interventions: a meta-regression. Health Psychol. 2009;28:690&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19916637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh JM, Sundaram V, McDonald K, Owens DK, Goldstein MK. Implementing effective hypertension quality improvement strategies: barriers and potential solutions. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2008;10:311&#x2013;316.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8110041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18401229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deci EL, Ryan RM. Intrinsic Motivation and Self-Determination in Human Behavior. New York, NY: Plenum Press; 1985.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine (US) Committee on Public Health Priorities to Reduce and Control Hypertension. A Population-Based Policy and Systems Change Approach to Prevent and Control Hypertension. Washington, DC: National Academies Press (US); 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25032370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Go AS, Bauman MA, Coleman King SM, Fonarow GC, Lawrence W, et al. An effective approach to high blood pressure control: a science advisory from the American Heart Association, the American College of Cardiology, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2014;63:1230&#x2013;1238.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24246165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Thorpe CT, Bartels CM, Schumacher JR, Palta M, et al. Undiagnosed hypertension among young adults with regular primary care use. J Hypertens. 2014;32:65&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3868024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehy AM, Flood GE, Tuan WJ, Liou JI, Coursin DB. Analysis of guidelines for screening diabetes mellitus in an ambulatory population. Mayo Clin Proc. 2010;85:27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20042558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thorpe CT, Flood GE, Kraft SA, Everett CM, Smith MA. Effect of patient selection method on provider group performance estimates. Med Care. 2011;49:780&#x2013;785.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3137682</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21617570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markland D, Ryan RM, Tobin VJ, Rollnick S. Motivational interviewing and self-determination theory. J Soc Clin Psychol. 2005;24:811&#x2013;831.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller WR, Rose GS. Toward a theory of motivational interviewing. Am Psychol. 2009;64:527&#x2013;537.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2759607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19739882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellg AJ, Borrelli B, Resnick B, Hecht J, Minicucci DS, et al. Enhancing treatment fidelity in health behavior change studies: best practices and recommendations from the NIH Behavior Change Consortium. Health Psychol. 2004;23:443&#x2013;451.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15367063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madson MB, Loignon AC, Lane C. Training in motivational interviewing: a systematic review. J Subst Abuse Treat. 2009;36:101&#x2013;109.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18657936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasgow RE, Funnell MM, Bonomi AE, Davis C, Beckham V, et al. Self-management aspects of the improving chronic illness care breakthrough series: implementation with diabetes and heart failure teams. Ann Behav Med. 2002;24:80&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12054323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutnick D, Reims K, Davis C, Gainforth H, Jay M, et al. Brief action planning to facilitate behavior change and support patient self-management. J Clin Outcomes Manag. 2014;21:17&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth HB, Olsen MK, Neary A, Orr M, Grubber J, et al. Take Control of Your Blood Pressure (TCYB) study: a multifactorial tailored behavioral and educational intervention for achieving blood pressure control. Patient Educ Couns. 2008;70:338&#x2013;347.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2276731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18164894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poobalan AS, Pitchforth E, Imamura M, Tucker JS, Philip K, et al. Characteristics of effective interventions in improving young people&#x2019;s sexual health: a review of reviews. Sex Educ. 2009;9:319&#x2013;336.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber MA, Schiffrin EL, White WB, Mann S, Lindholm LH, et al. Clinical practice guidelines for the management of hypertension in the community: a statement by the American Society of Hypertension and the International Society of Hypertension. J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 2014;16:14&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24341872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>  http://www.dtic.mil/cgi-bin/GetTRDoc?AD=ADA006655.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antal H, Hossain MJ, Hassink S, Henry S, Fuzzell L, et al. Audio-video recording of health care encounters for pediatric chronic conditions: observational reactivity and its correlates. J Pediatr Psychol. 2015;40:144&#x2013;153.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6366659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24974174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson-Kozlow M, Hovell MF, Rovniak LS, Sirikulvadhana L, Wahlgren DR, et al. Fidelity issues in secondhand smoking interventions for children. Nicotine Tob Res. 2008;10:1677&#x2013;1690.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3533496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19023822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forster DA, Savage TL, McLachlan HL, Gold L, Farrell T, et al. Individualised, flexible postnatal care: a feasibility study for a randomised controlled trial. BMC Health Serv Res. 2014;14:569.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4279591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25421495</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pope C, Ziebland S, Mays N. Analysing Qualitative Data. In: Pope C, Mays N, editors. Qualitative Research in Health Care. 3rd. Malden, MA: Blackwell Publishing/BMJ Books; 2006. pp. 63&#x2013;81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Abraham C. Interventions to change health behaviours: evidence-based or evidence inspired? Psychol Health. 2004;19:29&#x2013;49.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Prestwich A. Are interventions theory-based? Development of a theory coding scheme. Health Psychol. 2010;29:1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20063930</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha-Goldberg Mdel P, Corsino L, Batch B, Voils CI, Thorpe CT, et al. Hypertension Improvement Project (HIP) Latino: results of a pilot study of lifestyle intervention for lowering blood pressure in Latino adults. Ethn Health. 2010;15:269&#x2013;282.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2888677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20379894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogrinc G, Davies L, Goodman D, Batalden P, Davidoff F, et al. SQUIRE 2.0 Standards for QUality Improvement Reporting Excellence: revised publication guidelines from a detailed consensus process. BMJ Qual Saf. 2015</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5256233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26369893</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>