<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">29171201</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">1738-5520</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>48</Volume><Issue>2</Issue><PubDate><Year>2018</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Korean circulation journal</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Korean Circ J</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Carotid Artery Stenting.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>97</StartPage><EndPage>113</EndPage><MedlinePgn>97-113</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4070/kcj.2017.0208</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Carotid artery stenosis is relatively common and is a significant cause of ischemic stroke, but carotid revascularization can reduce the risk of ischemic stroke in patients with significant symptomatic stenosis. Carotid endarterectomy has been and remains the gold standard treatment to reduce the risk of carotid artery stenosis. Carotid artery stenting (CAS) (or carotid artery stent implantation) is another method of carotid revascularization, which has developed rapidly over the last 30 years. To date, the frequency of use of CAS is increasing, and clinical outcomes are improving with technical advancements. However, the value of CAS remains unclear in patients with significant carotid artery stenosis. This review article discusses the basic concepts and procedural techniques involved in CAS.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2018. The Korean Society of Cardiology.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Park</LastName><ForeName>Jae Hyeong</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7035-286X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology in Internal Medicine, Chungnam National University School of Medicine, Chungnam National University Hospital, Daejeon, Korea.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lee</LastName><ForeName>Jae Hwan</ForeName><Initials>JH</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6561-7760</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology in Internal Medicine, Chungnam National University School of Medicine, Chungnam National University Hospital, Daejeon, Korea. myheart@cnu.ac.kr.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Korea (South)</Country><MedlineTA>Korean Circ J</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101247141</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1738-5520</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carotid artery stenting</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carotid stenosis</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Percutaneous coronary intervention</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors have no financial conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2017</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2017</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2018</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29171201</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5861011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4070/kcj.2017.0208</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">48.e6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Benjamin EJ, Blaha MJ, Chiuve SE, et al. Heart disease and stroke statistics-2017 update: a report from the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2017;135:e146&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5408160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28122885</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Statistics Korea. Vital statistics 2014 [Internet] Daejeon: Statistics Korea; 2014.  [cited 2015 Sep 23].  Available from:  http://kostat.go.kr.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tendera M, Aboyans V, Bartelink ML, et al. ESC guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of peripheral artery diseases: document covering atherosclerotic disease of extracranial carotid and vertebral, mesenteric, renal, upper and lower extremity arteries: the Task Force on the Diagnosis and Treatment of Peripheral Artery Diseases of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) Eur Heart J. 2011;32:2851&#x2013;2906.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21873417</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Rango P, Parlani G, Verzini F, et al. Long-term prevention of stroke: a modern comparison of current carotid stenting and carotid endarterectomy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;57:664&#x2013;671.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21292127</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>GBD 2013 Mortality and Causes of Death Collaborators. Global, regional, and national age-sex specific all-cause and cause-specific mortality for 240 causes of death, 1990&#x2013;2013: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2013. Lancet. 2015;385:117&#x2013;171.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4340604</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25530442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krishnamurthi RV, Feigin VL, Forouzanfar MH, et al. Global and regional burden of first-ever ischaemic and haemorrhagic stroke during 1990&#x2013;2010: findings from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2010. Lancet Glob Health. 2013;1:e259&#x2013;e281.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4181351</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25104492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kwon YD, Chang H, Choi YJ, Yoon SS. Nationwide trends in stroke hospitalization over the past decade. J Korean Med Assoc. 2012;55:1014&#x2013;1025.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>White H, Boden-Albala B, Wang C, et al. Ischemic stroke subtype incidence among whites, blacks, and Hispanics: the Northern Manhattan Study. Circulation. 2005;111:1327&#x2013;1331.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15769776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wardlaw JM, Chappell FM, Stevenson M, et al. Accurate, practical and cost-effective assessment of carotid stenosis in the UK. Health Technol Assess. 2006;10:iii&#x2013;iiv. ix&#x2013;x, 1&#x2013;182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16904049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett HJ, Gunton RW, Eliasziw M, et al. Causes and severity of ischemic stroke in patients with internal carotid artery stenosis. JAMA. 2000;283:1429&#x2013;1436.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10732932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inzitari D, Eliasziw M, Gates P, et al. The causes and risk of stroke in patients with asymptomatic internal-carotid-artery stenosis. North American Symptomatic Carotid Endarterectomy Trial Collaborators. N Engl J Med. 2000;342:1693&#x2013;1700.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10841871</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bartlett ES, Walters TD, Symons SP, Fox AJ. Quantification of carotid stenosis on CT angiography. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol. 2006;27:13&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7976065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16418349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gupta A, Gialdini G, Lerario MP, et al. Magnetic resonance angiography detection of abnormal carotid artery plaque in patients with cryptogenic stroke. J Am Heart Assoc. 2015;4:e002012.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4599540</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26077590</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Authors/Task Force Members. ESC guidelines on the diagnosis and treatment of peripheral arterial diseases, in collaboration with the European Society for Vascular Surgery (ESVS) Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2017:2017. [Epub ahead of print]</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eastcott HH, Pickering GW, Rob CG. Reconstruction of internal carotid artery in a patient with intermittent attacks of hemiplegia. Lancet. 1954;267:994&#x2013;996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13213095</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>MRC European Carotid Surgery Trial: interim results for symptomatic patients with severe (70&#x2013;99%) or with mild (0&#x2013;29%) carotid stenosis. European Carotid Surgery Trialists&#x2019; Collaborative Group. Lancet. 1991;337:1235&#x2013;1243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1674060</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chiarella F, Santoro E, Domenicucci S, Maggioni A, Vecchio C. Predischarge two-dimensional echocardiographic evaluation of left ventricular thrombosis after acute myocardial infarction in the GISSI-3 study. Am J Cardiol. 1998;81:822&#x2013;827.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9555769</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barnett HJ, Taylor DW, Eliasziw M, et al. Benefit of carotid endarterectomy in patients with symptomatic moderate or severe stenosis. North American Symptomatic Carotid Endarterectomy Trial Collaborators. N Engl J Med. 1998;339:1415&#x2013;1425.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9811916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Endarterectomy for asymptomatic carotid artery stenosis. Executive Committee for the Asymptomatic Carotid Atherosclerosis Study. JAMA. 1995;273:1421&#x2013;1428.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7723155</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohammed N, Anand SS. Prevention of disabling and fatal strokes by successful carotid endarterectomy in patients without recent neurological symptoms: randomized controlled trial. MRC asymptomatic carotid surgery trial (ACST) collaborative group. Lancet 2004; 363: 1491&#x2013;502. Vasc Med. 2005;10:77&#x2013;78.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15921006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothwell PM, Eliasziw M, Gutnikov SA, Warlow CP, Barnett HJ Carotid Endarterectomy Trialists Collaboration. Endarterectomy for symptomatic carotid stenosis in relation to clinical subgroups and timing of surgery. Lancet. 2004;363:915&#x2013;924.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15043958</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein HH, Reiff T, Ringleb P, et al. SPACE-2: a missed opportunity to compare carotid endarterectomy, carotid stenting, and best medical treatment in patients with asymptomatic carotid stenoses. Eur J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2016;51:761&#x2013;765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27085660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothwell PM, Eliasziw M, Gutnikov SA, et al. Analysis of pooled data from the randomised controlled trials of endarterectomy for symptomatic carotid stenosis. Lancet. 2003;361:107&#x2013;116.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12531577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yadav JS, Wholey MH, Kuntz RE, et al. Protected carotid-artery stenting versus endarterectomy in high-risk patients. N Engl J Med. 2004;351:1493&#x2013;1501.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15470212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mas JL, Trinquart L, Leys D, et al. Endarterectomy Versus Angioplasty in Patients with Symptomatic Severe Carotid Stenosis (EVA-3S) trial: results up to 4 years from a randomised, multicentre trial. Lancet Neurol. 2008;7:885&#x2013;892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18774745</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckstein HH, Ringleb P, Allenberg JR, et al. Results of the Stent-Protected Angioplasty versus Carotid Endarterectomy (SPACE) study to treat symptomatic stenoses at 2 years: a multinational, prospective, randomised trial. Lancet Neurol. 2008;7:893&#x2013;902.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18774746</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Komotar RJ, Starke RM, Connolly ES. Carotid endarterectomy vs endovascular stenting: recent results from ICSS and CREST. Neurosurgery. 2010;66:N12&#x2013;N13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20495408</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>George JC, White CJ. Carotid artery stenting lessons from CREST (Carotid Revascularization Endarterectomy Versus Stenting Trial) JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2010;3:988&#x2013;990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20850102</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brott TG, Howard G, Roubin GS, et al. Long-term results of stenting versus endarterectomy for carotid-artery stenosis. N Engl J Med. 2016;374:1021&#x2013;1031.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4874663</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26890472</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahn KT, Lee JH, Kim DH, et al. Technical feasibility and early clinical outcomes associated with distal filter device use for all carotid stenting procedures. Korean Circ J. 2008;38:659&#x2013;665.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nerla R, Castriota F, Micari A, et al. Carotid artery stenting with a new-generation double-mesh stent in three high-volume Italian centres: clinical results of a multidisciplinary approach. EuroIntervention. 2016;12:e677&#x2013;e683.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27497367</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazzaccaro D, Occhiuto MT, Righini P, Malacrida G, Nano G. Initial experience with the inspire MD C-Guard stent in the treatment of carotid artery disease. J Cardiovasc Surg (Torino) 2016;57:474&#x2013;478.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27094426</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garg N, Karagiorgos N, Pisimisis GT, et al. Cerebral protection devices reduce periprocedural strokes during carotid angioplasty and stenting: a systematic review of the current literature. J Endovasc Ther. 2009;16:412&#x2013;427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19702342</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zahn R, Ischinger T, Hochadel M, et al. Carotid artery stenting in octogenarians: results from the ALKK Carotid Artery Stent (CAS) Registry. Eur Heart J. 2007;28:370&#x2013;375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17158826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montorsi P, Caputi L, Galli S, et al. Microembolization during carotid artery stenting in patients with high-risk, lipid-rich plaque. A randomized trial of proximal versus distal cerebral protection. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2011;58:1656&#x2013;1663.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21982309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bijuklic K, Wandler A, Hazizi F, Schofer J. The PROFI study (prevention of cerebral embolization by proximal balloon occlusion compared to filter protection during carotid artery stenting): a prospective randomized trial. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2012;59:1383&#x2013;1389.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22284330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bersin RM, Stabile E, Ansel GM, et al. A meta-analysis of proximal occlusion device outcomes in carotid artery stenting. Catheter Cardiovasc Interv. 2012;80:1072&#x2013;1078.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22454248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu ZJ, Fu WG, Guo ZY, Shen LG, Shi ZY, Li JH. Updated systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized clinical trials comparing carotid artery stenting and carotid endarterectomy in the treatment of carotid stenosis. Ann Vasc Surg. 2012;26:576&#x2013;590.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22410144</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KH, Lee CH, Son YJ, Yang HJ, Chung YS, Lee SH. Post-carotid endarterectomy cerebral hyperperfusion syndrome: is it preventable by strict blood pressure control? J Korean Neurosurg Soc. 2013;54:159&#x2013;163.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3836920</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24278642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogasawara K, Sakai N, Kuroiwa T, et al. Intracranial hemorrhage associated with cerebral hyperperfusion syndrome following carotid endarterectomy and carotid artery stenting: retrospective review of 4494 patients. J Neurosurg. 2007;107:1130&#x2013;1136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18077950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meschia JF, Voeks JH, Leimgruber PP, et al. Management of vascular risk factors in the Carotid Revascularization Endarterectomy Versus Stenting Trial (CREST) J Am Heart Assoc. 2014;3:e001180.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4338705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25428209</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CAPRIE Steering Committee. A randomised, blinded, trial of clopidogrel versus aspirin in patients at risk of ischaemic events (CAPRIE). CAPRIE Steering Committee. Lancet. 1996;348:1329&#x2013;1339.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8918275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amarenco P, Albers GW, Denison H, et al. Efficacy and safety of ticagrelor versus aspirin in acute stroke or transient ischaemic attack of atherosclerotic origin: a subgroup analysis of SOCRATES, a randomised, double-blind, controlled trial. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16:301&#x2013;310.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28238711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markus HS, Droste DW, Kaps M, et al. Dual antiplatelet therapy with clopidogrel and aspirin in symptomatic carotid stenosis evaluated using doppler embolic signal detection: the Clopidogrel and Aspirin for Reduction of Emboli in Symptomatic Carotid Stenosis (CARESS) trial. Circulation. 2005;111:2233&#x2013;2240.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15851601</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>SPS3 Investigators. Effects of clopidogrel added to aspirin in patients with recent lacunar stroke. N Engl J Med. 2012;367:817&#x2013;825.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4067036</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22931315</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kernan WN, Ovbiagele B, Black HR, et al. Guidelines for the prevention of stroke in patients with stroke and transient ischemic attack: a guideline for healthcare professionals from the American Heart Association/American Stroke Association. Stroke. 2014;45:2160&#x2013;2236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24788967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone NJ, Robinson JG, Lichtenstein AH, et al. 2013 ACC/AHA guideline on the treatment of blood cholesterol to reduce atherosclerotic cardiovascular risk in adults: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2014;63:2889&#x2013;2934.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24239923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Piepoli MF, Hoes AW, Agewall S, et al. 2016 European guidelines on cardiovascular disease prevention in clinical practice: the Sixth Joint Task Force of the European Society of Cardiology and Other Societies on Cardiovascular Disease Prevention in Clinical Practice (constituted by representatives of 10 societies and by invited experts) developed with the special contribution of the European Association for Cardiovascular Prevention &amp; Rehabilitation (EACPR) Eur Heart J. 2016;37:2315&#x2013;2381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4986030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27222591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J, Park JB, Kim KI, et al. 2013 Korean Society of Hypertension guidelines for the management of hypertension: part III-hypertension in special situations. Clin Hypertens. 2015;21:3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4750807</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26893917</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J, Park JB, Kim KI, et al. 2013 Korean Society of Hypertension guidelines for the management of hypertension. Part II-treatments of hypertension. Clin Hypertens. 2015;21:2.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4745141</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26893916</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shin J, Park JB, Kim KI, et al. 2013 Korean Society of Hypertension guidelines for the management of hypertension: part I-epidemiology and diagnosis of hypertension. Clin Hypertens. 2015;21:1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4745140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26893915</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancia G, Fagard R, Narkiewicz K, et al. 2013 ESH/ESC guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension: the Task Force for the Management of Arterial Hypertension of the European Society of Hypertension (ESH) and of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) Eur Heart J. 2013;34:2159&#x2013;2219.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23771844</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>