<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">30677485</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>26</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>20</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1559-2030</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>78</Volume><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Mar</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Contemporary clinical trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Contemp Clin Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Rationale and study design of the MyHEART study: A young adult hypertension self-management randomized controlled trial.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>88</StartPage><EndPage>100</EndPage><MedlinePgn>88-100</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cct.2019.01.010</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1551-7144(18)30675-X</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Young adults (18-39 year-olds) with hypertension have a higher lifetime risk for cardiovascular disease. However, less than 50% of young adults achieve hypertension control in the United States. Hypertension self-management programs are recommended to improve control, but have been targeted to middle-aged and older populations. Young adults need hypertension self-management programs (i.e., home blood pressure monitoring and lifestyle modifications) tailored to their unique needs to lower blood pressure and reduce the risks and medication burden they may face over a lifetime. To address the unmet need in hypertensive care for young adults, we developed MyHEART (My Hypertension Education And Reaching Target), a multi-component, theoretically-based intervention designed to achieve self-management among young adults with uncontrolled hypertension. MyHEART is a patient-centered program, based upon the Self-Determination Theory, that uses evidence-based health behavior approaches to lower blood pressure. Therefore, the objective of this study is to evaluate MyHEART's impact on changes in systolic and diastolic blood pressure compared to usual care after 6 and 12 months in 310 geographically and racially/ethnically diverse young adults with uncontrolled hypertension. Secondary outcomes include MyHEART's impact on behavioral outcomes at 6 and 12 months, compared to usual clinical care (increased physical activity, decreased sodium intake) and to examine whether MyHEART's effects on self-management behavior are mediated through variables of perceived competence, autonomy, motivation, and activation (mediation outcomes). MyHEART is one of the first multicenter, randomized controlled hypertension trials tailored to young adults with primary care. The design and methodology will maximize the generalizability of this study. TRIAL REGISTRATION: ClinicalTrials.gov Identifier: NCT03158051.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2019 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnson</LastName><ForeName>Heather M</ForeName><Initials>HM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 1685 Highland Avenue, 5158 Medical Foundation Centennial Building, Madison, WI 53705-2281, USA; Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 800 University Bay Drive, Suite 210, Madison, WI 53705, USA. Electronic address: hm2@medicine.wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sullivan-Vedder</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Aurora Health Care Department of Family Medicine, Family Care Center, 1020 N 12(th) Street, Milwaukee, WI 53233, USA. Electronic address: Lisa.Vedder@aurora.org.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kim</LastName><ForeName>KyungMann</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics and Medical Informatics, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, K6/420 Clinical Sciences Center, 600 Highland Avenue, Madison, WI 53792-4675, USA. Electronic address: kyungmann.kim@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McBride</LastName><ForeName>Patrick E</ForeName><Initials>PE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 1685 Highland Avenue, 5158 Medical Foundation Centennial Building, Madison, WI 53705-2281, USA. Electronic address: pem@medicine.wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Maureen A</ForeName><Initials>MA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 1685 Highland Avenue, 5158 Medical Foundation Centennial Building, Madison, WI 53705-2281, USA; Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 800 University Bay Drive, Suite 210, Madison, WI 53705, USA; Department of Population Health Sciences, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 610 Walnut Street, 707 WARF Building, Madison, WI 53726, USA; Department of Family Medicine and Community Health, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 1100 Delaplaine Court, Madison, WI 53715-1896, USA. Electronic address: maureensmith@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>LaMantia</LastName><ForeName>Jamie N</ForeName><Initials>JN</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 1685 Highland Avenue, 5158 Medical Foundation Centennial Building, Madison, WI 53705-2281, USA; Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 800 University Bay Drive, Suite 210, Madison, WI 53705, USA. Electronic address: jnlamantia@medicine.wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fink</LastName><ForeName>Jennifer T</ForeName><Initials>JT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Health Informatics and Administration, University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee College of Health Sciences, NWQ Building B, Suite #6455, 2025 E. Newport Avenue, Milwaukee, WI 53211-2906, USA. Electronic address: jtfink@uwm.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Knutson Sinaise</LastName><ForeName>Megan R</ForeName><Initials>MR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 1685 Highland Avenue, 5158 Medical Foundation Centennial Building, Madison, WI 53705-2281, USA; Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 800 University Bay Drive, Suite 210, Madison, WI 53705, USA. Electronic address: mknutson2@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zeller</LastName><ForeName>Laura M</ForeName><Initials>LM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 1685 Highland Avenue, 5158 Medical Foundation Centennial Building, Madison, WI 53705-2281, USA; Health Innovation Program, University of Wisconsin School of Medicine and Public Health, 800 University Bay Drive, Suite 210, Madison, WI 53705, USA. Electronic address: lmzeller@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lauver</LastName><ForeName>Diane R</ForeName><Initials>DR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Nursing, University of Wisconsin, Signe Skott Cooper Hall, 701 Highland Avenue, Madison, WI 53705, USA. Electronic address: drlauver@wisc.edu.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><DataBankList CompleteYN="Y"><DataBank><DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName><AccessionNumberList><AccessionNumber>NCT03158051</AccessionNumber></AccessionNumberList></DataBank></DataBankList><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 HL132148</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>UL1 TR002373</GrantID><Acronym>TR</Acronym><Agency>NCATS NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>21</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Contemp Clin Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101242342</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1551-7144</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D012982">Sodium, Dietary</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001794" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D018660" MajorTopicYN="N">Blood Pressure Monitoring, Ambulatory</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="N">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015438" MajorTopicYN="Y">Health Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006973" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hypertension</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008019" MajorTopicYN="N">Life Style</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010353" MajorTopicYN="Y">Patient Education as Topic</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D040242" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Reduction Behavior</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073278" MajorTopicYN="Y">Self-Management</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000193" MajorTopicYN="N">education</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016037" MajorTopicYN="N">Single-Blind Method</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012959" MajorTopicYN="N">Socioeconomic Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012982" MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium, Dietary</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015337" MajorTopicYN="N">Multicenter Studies as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health behavior change</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health coaching</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypertension</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized controlled trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-management</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Young adults</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>None of the other authors declare any relevant conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2018</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>15</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>16</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30677485</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1008613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6387836</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cct.2019.01.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1551-7144(18)30675-X</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Go AS, Bauman MA, Coleman King SM, Fonarow GC, Lawrence W, Williams KA, Sanchez E, An effective approach to high blood pressure control: a science advisory from the American Heart Association, the American College of Cardiology, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, J Am Coll Cardiol 63(12) (2014) 1230&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24246165</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Healthy People 2020: Heart Disease and Stroke - Increase the proportion of adults with hypertension whose blood pressure is under control, 2017. 
http://www.healthypeople.gov/node/4555/data_details. (Accessed June 27 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gooding HC, McGinty S, Richmond TK, Gillman MW, Field AE, Hypertension awareness and control among young adults in the national longitudinal study of adolescent health, J Gen Intern Med 29(8) (2014) 1098&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4099443</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24577758</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whelton PK, Carey RM, Aronow WS, Casey DE Jr., Collins KJ, Dennison Himmelfarb C, DePalma SM, Gidding S, Jamerson KA, Jones DW, MacLaughlin EJ, Muntner P, Ovbiagele B, Smith SC Jr., Spencer CC, Stafford RS, Taler SJ, Thomas RJ, Williams KA Sr., Williamson JD, Wright JT Jr., 2017 ACC/AHA/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/AGS/APhA/ASH/ASPC/NMA/PCNA Guideline for the Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Management of High Blood Pressure in Adults: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines, J Am Coll Cardiol 71(19) (2018) e127&#x2013;e248.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29146535</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, High Blood Pressure Facts, 2018. 
https://www.cdc.gov/bloodpressure/facts.htm. (Accessed June 27 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin EJ, Virani SS, Callaway CW, Chamberlain AM, Chang AR, Cheng S, Chiuve SE, Cushman M, Delling FN, Deo R, de Ferranti SD, Ferguson JF, Fornage M, Gillespie C, Isasi CR, Jimenez MC, Jordan LC, Judd SE, Lackland D, Lichtman JH, Lisabeth L, Liu S, Longenecker CT, Lutsey PL, Mackey JS, Matchar DB, Matsushita K, Mussolino ME, Nasir K, O&#x2019;Flaherty M, Palaniappan LP, Pandey A, Pandey DK, Reeves MJ, Ritchey MD, Rodriguez CJ, Roth GA, Rosamond WD, Sampson UKA, Satou GM, Shah SH, Spartano NL, Tirschwell DL, Tsao CW, Voeks JH, Willey JZ, Wilkins JT, Wu JH, Alger HM, Wong SS, Muntner P, E. American Heart Association Council on, C. Prevention Statistics, S. Stroke Statistics, Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics-2018 Update: A Report From the American Heart Association, Circulation 137(12) (2018) e67&#x2013;e492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29386200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grubbs V, Lin F, Vittinghoff E, Shlipak MG, Peralta CA, Bansal N, Jacobs DR, Siscovick DS, Lewis CE, Bibbins-Domingo K, Body mass index and early kidney function decline in young adults: a longitudinal analysis of the CARDIA (Coronary Artery Risk Development in Young Adults) study, Am J Kidney Dis 63(4) (2014) 590&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3969447</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24295611</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mitchell AB, Cole JW, McArdle PF, Cheng YC, Ryan KA, Sparks MJ, Mitchell BD, Kittner SJ, Obesity increases risk of ischemic stroke in young adults, Stroke 46(6) (2015) 1690&#x2013;1692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4458137</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25944320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chobanian AV, Bakris GL, Black HR, Cushman WC, Green LA, Izzo JL Jr., Jones DW, Materson BJ, Oparil S, Wright JT Jr., Roccella EJ, The Seventh Report of the Joint National Committee on Prevention, Detection, Evaluation, and Treatment of High Blood Pressure: the JNC 7 report, JAMA 289(19) (2003) 2560&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12748199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ford ES, Ajani UA, Croft JB, Critchley JA, Labarthe DR, Kottke TE, Giles WH, Capewell S, Explaining the decrease in U.S. deaths from coronary disease, 1980&#x2013;2000, N Engl J Med 356(23) (2007) 2388&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17554120</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lloyd-Jones DM, Hong Y, Labarthe D, Mozaffarian D, Appel LJ, Van Horn L, Greenlund K, Daniels S, Nichol G, Tomaselli GF, Arnett DK, Fonarow GC, Ho PM, Lauer MS, Masoudi FA, Robertson RM, Roger V, Schwamm LH, Sorlie P, Yancy CW, Rosamond WD, Defining and setting national goals for cardiovascular health promotion and disease reduction: the American Heart Association&#x2019;s strategic Impact Goal through 2020 and beyond, Circulation 121(4) (2010) 586&#x2013;613.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20089546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paramore LC, Halpern MT, Lapuerta P, Hurley JS, Frost FJ, Fairchild DG, Bates D, Impact of poorly controlled hypertension on healthcare resource utilization and cost, Am J Manag Care 7(4) (2001) 389&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11310193</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yano Y, Stamler J, Garside DB, Daviglus ML, Franklin SS, Carnethon MR, Liu K, Greenland P, Lloyd-Jones DM, Isolated Systolic Hypertension in Young and Middle-Aged Adults and 31-Year Risk for Cardiovascular Mortality: The Chicago Heart Association Detection Project in Industry Study, J Am Coll Cardiol 65(4) (2015) 327&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4948287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25634830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holland N, Segraves D, Nnadi VO, Belletti DA, Wogen J, Arcona S, Identifying barriers to hypertension care: implications for quality improvement initiatives, Dis Manag 11(2) (2008) 71&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18426375</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>James PA, Oparil S, Carter BL, Cushman WC, Dennison-Himmelfarb C, Handler J, Lackland DT, LeFevre ML, MacKenzie TD, Ogedegbe O, Smith SC Jr., Svetkey LP, Taler SJ, Townsend RR, Wright JT Jr., Narva AS, Ortiz E, 2014 evidence-based guideline for the management of high blood pressure in adults: report from the panel members appointed to the Eighth Joint National Committee (JNC 8), JAMA 311(5) (2014) 507&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24352797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, Urizar GG Jr., Alehegn T, Stafford RS, Diet and physical activity counseling during ambulatory care visits in the United States, Prev Med 39(4) (2004) 815&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15351551</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weber MA, Schiffrin EL, White WB, Mann S, Lindholm LH, Kenerson JG, Flack JM, Carter BL, Materson BJ, Ram CV, Cohen DL, Cadet JC, Jean-Charles RR, Taler S, Kountz D, Townsend RR, Chalmers J, Ramirez AJ, Bakris GL, Wang J, Schutte AE, Bisognano JD, Touyz RM, Sica D, Harrap SB, Clinical practice guidelines for the management of hypertension in the community: a statement by the American Society of Hypertension and the International Society of Hypertension, J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 16(1) (2014) 14&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8031779</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24341872</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artinian NT, Flack JM, Nordstrom CK, Hockman EM, Washington OG, Jen KL, Fathy M, Effects of nurse-managed telemonitoring on blood pressure at 12-month follow-up among urban African Americans, Nurs Res 56(5) (2007) 312&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17846552</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth HB, Olsen MK, Grubber JM, Neary AM, Orr MM, Powers BJ, Adams MB, Svetkey LP, Reed SD, Li Y, Dolor RJ, Oddone EZ, Two self-management interventions to improve hypertension control: a randomized trial, Ann Intern Med 151(10) (2009) 687&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2892337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19920269</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth HB, Olsen MK, Grubber JM, Powers BJ, Oddone EZ, Racial differences in two self-management hypertension interventions, Am J Med 124(5) (2011) 468 e1&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3086723</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21531237</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth HB, Olsen MK, Neary A, Orr M, Grubber J, Svetkey L, Adams M, Oddone EZ, Take Control of Your Blood Pressure (TCYB) study: a multifactorial tailored behavioral and educational intervention for achieving blood pressure control, Patient Educ Couns 70(3) (2008) 338&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2276731</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18164894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth HB, Powers BJ, Olsen MK, McCant F, Grubber J, Smith V, Gentry PW, Rose C, Van Houtven C, Wang V, Goldstein MK, Oddone EZ, Home blood pressure management and improved blood pressure control: results from a randomized controlled trial, Arch Intern Med 171(13) (2011) 1173&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedberg JP, Rodriguez MA, Watsula ME, Lin I, Wylie-Rosett J, Allegrante JP, Lipsitz SR, Natarajan S, Effectiveness of a tailored behavioral intervention to improve hypertension control: primary outcomes of a randomized controlled trial, Hypertension 65(2) (2015) 440&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25403606</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Green BB, Cook AJ, Ralston JD, Fishman PA, Catz SL, Carlson J, Carrell D, Tyll L, Larson EB, Thompson RS, Effectiveness of home blood pressure monitoring, Web communication, and pharmacist care on hypertension control: a randomized controlled trial, JAMA 299(24) (2008) 2857&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2715866</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18577730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jackson GL, Oddone EZ, Olsen MK, Powers BJ, Grubber JM, McCant F, Bosworth HB, Racial differences in the effect of a telephone-delivered hypertension disease management program, J Gen Intern Med 27(12) (2012) 1682&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3509293</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22865016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim KB, Han HR, Huh B, Nguyen T, Lee H, Kim MT, The effect of a community-based self-help multimodal behavioral intervention in Korean American seniors with high blood pressure, Am J Hypertens 27(9) (2014) 1199&#x2013;208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4184355</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24671049</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolius D, Bodenheimer T, Bennett H, Wong J, Ngo V, Padilla G, Thom DH, Health coaching to improve hypertension treatment in a low-income, minority population, Ann Fam Med 10(3) (2012) 199&#x2013;205.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3354968</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22585883</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehos BM, Saseen JJ, MacLaughlin EJ, Effect of pharmacist intervention and initiation of home blood pressure monitoring in patients with uncontrolled hypertension, Pharmacotherapy 20(11) (2000) 1384&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11079287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ralston JD, Cook AJ, Anderson ML, Catz SL, Fishman PA, Carlson J, Johnson R, Green BB, Home blood pressure monitoring, secure electronic messaging and medication intensification for improving hypertension control: a mediation analysis, Appl Clin Inform 5(1) (2014) 232&#x2013;48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3974258</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24734136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudd P, Miller NH, Kaufman J, Kraemer HC, Bandura A, Greenwald G, Debusk RF, Nurse management for hypertension. A systems approach, Am J Hypertens 17(10) (2004) 921&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15485755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Appel LJ, Champagne CM, Harsha DW, Cooper LS, Obarzanek E, Elmer PJ, Stevens VJ, Vollmer WM, Lin PH, Svetkey LP, Stedman SW, Young DR, Effects of comprehensive lifestyle modification on blood pressure control: main results of the PREMIER clinical trial, JAMA 289(16) (2003) 2083&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12709466</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boulware LE, Daumit GL, Frick KD, Minkovitz CS, Lawrence RS, Powe NR, An evidence-based review of patient-centered behavioral interventions for hypertension, Am J Prev Med 21(3) (2001) 221&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11567845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glynn LG, Murphy AW, Smith SM, Schroeder K, Fahey T, Interventions used to improve control of blood pressure in patients with hypertension, Cochrane Database Syst Rev (3) (2010) CD005182.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20238338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ogedegbe G, Tobin JN, Fernandez S, Gerin W, Diaz-Gloster M, Cassells A, Khalida C, Pickering T, Schoenthaler A, Ravenell J, Counseling African Americans to Control Hypertension (CAATCH) trial: a multi-level intervention to improve blood pressure control in hypertensive blacks, Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes 2(3) (2009) 249&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800792</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20031845</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Senesael E, Borgermans L, Van De Vijver E, Devroey D, Effectiveness of a quality improvement intervention targeting cardiovascular risk factors: are patients responsive to information and encouragement by mail or post?, Vasc Health Risk Manag 9 (2013) 13&#x2013;20.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3576014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23426275</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson AJ, Singh K, Myint UK, Grant RW, Jethwani K, Murachver E, Harris K, Lee TH, Kvedar JC, Evaluating a web-based self-management program for employees with hypertension and prehypertension: a randomized clinical trial, Am Heart J 164(4) (2012) 625&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23067923</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Magid DJ, Ho PM, Olson KL, Brand DW, Welch LK, Snow KE, Lambert-Kerzner AC, Plomondon ME, Havranek EP, A multimodal blood pressure control intervention in 3 healthcare systems, Am J Manag Care 17(4) (2011) e96&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21774100</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Thorpe CT, Bartels CM, Schumacher JR, Palta M, Pandhi N, Sheehy AM, Smith MA, Antihypertensive medication initiation among young adults with regular primary care use, J Gen Intern Med 29(5) (2014) 723&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4000352</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24493322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Allen NB, Siddique J, Wilkins JT, Shay C, Lewis CE, Goff DC, Jacobs DR Jr., Liu K, Lloyd-Jones D, Blood pressure trajectories in early adulthood and subclinical atherosclerosis in middle age, JAMA 311(5) (2014) 490&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4122296</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24496536</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Michie S, Abraham C, Whittington C, McAteer J, Gupta S, Effective techniques in healthy eating and physical activity interventions: a meta-regression, Health Psychol 28(6) (2009) 690&#x2013;701.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19916637</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sher T, Braun L, Domas A, Bellg A, Baucom DH, Houle TT, The partners for life program: a couples approach to cardiac risk reduction, Fam Process 53(1) (2014) 131&#x2013;49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3959575</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24495204</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voils CI, Gierisch JM, Yancy WS Jr., Sandelowski M, Smith R, Bolton J, Strauss JL, Differentiating behavior initiation and maintenance: theoretical framework and proof of concept, Health Educ Behav 41(3) (2014) 325&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24347145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Thorpe CT, Bartels CM, Schumacher JR, Palta M, Pandhi N, Sheehy AM, Smith MA, Undiagnosed hypertension among young adults with regular primary care use, J Hypertens 32(1) (2014) 65&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3868024</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24126711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Warner RC, LaMantia JN, Bowers BJ, &#x201c;I have to live like I&#x2019;m old.&#x201d; Young adults&#x2019; perspectives on managing hypertension: a multi-center qualitative study, BMC Fam Pract 17(1) (2016) 31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4788815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26969619</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien K, Venn BJ, Perry T, Green TJ, Aitken W, Bradshaw A, Thomson R, Reasons for wanting to lose weight: different strokes for different folks, Eat Behav 8(1) (2007) 132&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17174861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Underbakke G, McBride PE, Office systems for heart disease prevention, Prim Care 32(4) (2005) 883&#x2013;900.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16326218</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wolpert HA, Anderson BJ, Young adults with diabetes: need for a new treatment paradigm, Diabetes Care 24(9) (2001) 1513&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11522689</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, LaMantia JN, Warner RC, Pandhi N, Bartels CM, Smith MA, Lauver DR, MyHEART: A Non Randomized Feasibility Study of a Young Adult Hypertension Intervention, J Hypertens Manag 2(2) (2016) 016.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5300088</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28191544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Warner RC, Bartels CM, LaMantia JN, &#x201c;They&#x2019;re younger... it&#x2019;s harder.&#x201d; Primary providers&#x2019; perspectives on hypertension management in young adults: a multicenter qualitative study, BMC Res Notes 10(1) (2017) 9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5217565</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28057065</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deci EL, Ryan RM, Self-determination theory: a macrotherapy of human motivation, development, and health, Can Psychol 49(3) (2008) 182&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kupst MJ, Butt Z, Stoney CM, Griffith JW, Salsman JM, Folkman S, Cella D, Assessment of stress and self-efficacy for the NIH Toolbox for Neurological and Behavioral Function, Anxiety Stress Coping (2015) 1&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4515370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25577948</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molton IR, Jensen MP, Nielson W, Cardenas D, Ehde DM, A preliminary evaluation of the motivational model of pain self-management in persons with spinal cord injury-related pain, J Pain 9(7) (2008) 606&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493418</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18359668</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bodenheimer T, Lorig K, Holman H, Grumbach K, Patient self-management of chronic disease in primary care, JAMA 288(19) (2002) 2469&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12435261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll JK, Fiscella K, Epstein RM, Sanders MR, Williams GC, A 5A&#x2019;s communication intervention to promote physical activity in underserved populations, BMC Health Serv Res 12 (2012) 374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3506481</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23110376</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Markland D, Ryan RM, Tobin VJ, Rollnick S, Motivational interviewing and self-determination theory, J Soc Clin Psychol 24(6) (2005) 811&#x2013;31.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li K, Iannotti RJ, Haynie DL, Perlus JG, Simons-Morton BG, Motivation and planning as mediators of the relation between social support and physical activity among U.S. adolescents: a nationally representative study, Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act 11(1) (2014) 42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3994425</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24656181</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lorig KR, Sobel DS, Ritter PL, Laurent D, Hobbs M, Effect of a self-management program on patients with chronic disease, Eff Clin Pract 4(6) (2001) 256&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11769298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan RM, Frederick CM, Lepes D, Rubio N, Sheldon KM, Intrinsic motivation and exercise adherence, Int J Sport Psychol 28 (1997) 335&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva MN, Markland D, Minderico CS, Vieira PN, Castro MM, Coutinho SR, Santos TC, Matos MG, Sardinha LB, Teixeira PJ, A randomized controlled trial to evaluate self-determination theory for exercise adherence and weight control: rationale and intervention description, BMC Public Health 8 (2008) 234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2483280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18613959</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wisconsin Collaborative for Healthcare Quality, WCHQ website
http://www.wchq.org/. (Accessed May 23 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hatahet MA, Bowhan J, Clough EA, Wisconsin Collaborative for Healthcare Quality (WCHQ): lessons learned, WMJ 103(3) (2004) 45&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15217113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehy A, Pandhi N, Coursin DB, Flood GE, Kraft SA, Johnson HM, Smith MA, Minority status and diabetes screening in an ambulatory population, Diabetes Care 34(6) (2011) 1289&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3114363</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21562321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sheehy AM, Flood GE, Tuan WJ, Liou JI, Coursin DB, Smith MA, Analysis of guidelines for screening diabetes mellitus in an ambulatory population, Mayo Clin Proc 85(1) (2010) 27&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2800288</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20042558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nesbitt SD, Amerena JV, Grant E, Jamerson KA, Lu H, Weder A, Julius S, Home blood pressure as a predictor of future blood pressure stability in borderline hypertension. The Tecumseh Study, Am J Hypertens 10(11) (1997) 1270&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9397247</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fielding RA, Rejeski WJ, Blair S, Church T, Espeland MA, Gill TM, Guralnik JM, Hsu FC, Katula J, King AC, Kritchevsky SB, McDermott MM, Miller ME, Nayfield S, Newman AB, Williamson JD, Bonds D, Romashkan S, Hadley E, Pahor M, LIFE Research Group, The Lifestyle Interventions and Independence for Elders Study: design and methods, J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci 66(11) (2011) 1226&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3193523</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21825283</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering TG, Hall JE, Appel LJ, Falkner BE, Graves J, Hill MN, Jones DW, Kurtz T, Sheps SG, Roccella EJ, Recommendations for blood pressure measurement in humans and experimental animals: part 1: blood pressure measurement in humans: a statement for professionals from the Subcommittee of Professional and Public Education of the American Heart Association Council on High Blood Pressure Research, Circulation 111(5) (2005) 697&#x2013;716.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699287</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unger E, Diez-Roux AV, Lloyd-Jones DM, Mujahid MS, Nettleton JA, Bertoni A, Badon SE, Ning H, Allen NB, Association of neighborhood characteristics with cardiovascular health in the multi-ethnic study of atherosclerosis, Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes 7(4) (2014) 524&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4172357</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25006187</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal R, Bunaye Z, Bekele DM, Prognostic significance of between-arm blood pressure differences, Hypertension 51(3) (2008) 657&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18212263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spacelabs Healthcare, OnTrak, the NEW Evolution of ABPM from Spacelabs Healthcare, 2013. 
https://www.spacelabshealthcare.com/diagnostic-cardiology/abp-monitoring/ontrak#.W894h2hKjct. (Accessed September 27 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering TG, 24 Hour Ambulatory Blood Pressure Monitoring: Is it Necessary to Establish a Diagnosis Before Instituting Treatment of Hypertension?, J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 1(1) (1999) 33&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11416591</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Preventive Services Task Force, Final Recommendation Statement: High Blood Pressure in Adults: Screening, 2015. 
http://www.uspreventiveservicestaskforce.org/Page/Document/RecommendationStatementFinal/high-blood-pressure-in-adults-screening. (Accessed March 23 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pickering TG, Shimbo D, Haas D, Ambulatory blood-pressure monitoring, N Engl J Med 354(22) (2006) 2368&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16738273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harris PA, Taylor R, Thielke R, Payne J, Gonzalez N, Conde JG, Research electronic data capture (REDCap)--a metadata-driven methodology and workflow process for providing translational research informatics support, J Biomed Inform 42(2) (2009) 377&#x2013;81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2700030</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18929686</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center, Project REDCap, 2018. 
https://projectredcap.org/. (Accessed June 27 2018).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Friedberg JP, Lipsitz SR, Natarajan S, Challenges and recommendations for blinding in behavioral interventions illustrated using a case study of a behavioral intervention to lower blood pressure, Patient Educ Couns 78(1) (2010) 5&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19525084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elmer PJ, Obarzanek E, Vollmer WM, Simons-Morton D, Stevens VJ, Young DR, Lin PH, Champagne C, Harsha DW, Svetkey LP, Ard J, Brantley PJ, Proschan MA, Erlinger TP, Appel LJ, Effects of comprehensive lifestyle modification on diet, weight, physical fitness, and blood pressure control: 18-month results of a randomized trial, Ann Intern Med 144(7) (2006) 485&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16585662</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis KL, Kerby TJ, Asche SE, Bergdall AR, Maciosek MV, O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Sperl-Hillen JM, Design and rationale for Home Blood Pressure Telemonitoring and Case Management to Control Hypertension (HyperLink): a cluster randomized trial, Contemp Clin Trials 33(4) (2012) 794&#x2013;803.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3361626</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22498720</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Department of Health and Human Services, Interventions to Improve Hypertension Control Rates in African Americans, 2003. 
http://grants.nih.gov/grants/guide/rfa-files/RFA-HL-04-007.html. (Accessed March 23 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maciejewski ML, Bosworth HB, Olsen MK, Smith VA, Edelman D, Powers BJ, Kaufman MA, Oddone EZ, Jackson GL, Do the benefits of participation in a hypertension self-management trial persist after patients resume usual care?, Circ Cardiovasc Qual Outcomes 7(2) (2014) 269&#x2013;75.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24619321</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh JM, Sundaram V, McDonald K, Owens DK, Goldstein MK, Implementing effective hypertension quality improvement strategies: barriers and potential solutions, J Clin Hypertens (Greenwich) 10(4) (2008) 311&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8110041</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18401229</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute of Medicine (US) Committee on Public Health Priorities to Reduce and Control Hypertension, A Population-Based Policy and Systems Change Approach to Prevent and Control Hypertension, National Academies Press (US), Washington, D.C., 2010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25032370</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Diabetes Prevention Program (DPP): description of lifestyle intervention, Diabetes Care 25(12) (2002) 2165&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1282458</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12453955</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bokhour BG, Cohn ES, Cortes DE, Solomon JL, Fix GM, Elwy AR, Mueller N, Katz LA, Haidet P, Green AR, Borzecki AM, Kressin NR, The role of patients&#x2019; explanatory models and daily-lived experience in hypertension self-management, J Gen Intern Med 27(12) (2012) 1626&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3509311</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22821569</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willard-Grace R, DeVore D, Chen EH, Hessler D, Bodenheimer T, Thom DH, The effectiveness of medical assistant health coaching for low-income patients with uncontrolled diabetes, hypertension, and hyperlipidemia: protocol for a randomized controlled trial and baseline characteristics of the study population, BMC Fam Pract 14 (2013) 27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3616979</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23433349</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth HB, Olsen MK, Gentry P, Orr M, Dudley T, McCant F, Oddone EZ, Nurse administered telephone intervention for blood pressure control: a patient-tailored multifactorial intervention, Patient Educ Couns 57(1) (2005) 5&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15797147</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovejoy TI, Heckman TG, Suhr JA, Anderson T, Heckman BD, France CR, Telephone-administered motivational interviewing reduces risky sexual behavior in HIV-positive late middle-age and older adults: a pilot randomized controlled trial, AIDS Behav 15(8) (2011) 1623&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21809048</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madlensky L, Natarajan L, Flatt SW, Faerber S, Newman VA, Pierce JP, Timing of dietary change in response to a telephone counseling intervention: evidence from the WHEL study, Health Psychol 27(5) (2008) 539&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2562694</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18823180</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller SM, Hui SK, Wen KY, Scarpato J, Zhu F, Buzaglo J, Hernandez EE, Tailored telephone counseling to improve adherence to follow-up regimens after an abnormal pap smear among minority, underserved women, Patient Educ Couns 93(3) (2013) 488&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3852173</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24007767</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller WR, Rose GS, Toward a theory of motivational interviewing, Am Psychol 64(6) (2009) 527&#x2013;37.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2759607</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19739882</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lehr AL, Driver SL, Stone NJ, The ABCDs of lifestyle counseling, JAMA Cardiol 1(5) (2016) 505&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27439176</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glasgow RE, Funnell MM, Bonomi AE, Davis C, Beckham V, Wagner EH, Self-management aspects of the improving chronic illness care breakthrough series: implementation with diabetes and heart failure teams, Ann Behav Med 24(2) (2002) 80&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12054323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whitlock EP, Orleans CT, Pender N, Allan J, Evaluating primary care behavioral counseling interventions: an evidence-based approach, Am J Prev Med 22(4) (2002) 267&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11988383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gutnick D, Reims K, Davis C, Gainforth H, Jay M, Cole S, Brief action planning to facilitate behavior change and support patient self-management, J Clin Outcomes Manag 21(1) (2014) 17&#x2013;29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ritholz MD, Beverly EA, Brooks KM, Abrahamson MJ, Weinger K, Barriers and facilitators to self-care communication during medical appointments in the United States for adults with type 2 diabetes, Chronic Illn 10(4) (2014) 303&#x2013;13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4157962</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24567195</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwarzer R, Self-regulatory Processes in the Adoption and Maintenance of Health Behaviors, J Health Psychol 4(2) (1999) 115&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22021474</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Poobalan AS, Pitchforth E, Imamura M, Tucker JS, Philip K, Spratt J, Mandava L, van Teijlingen E, Characteristics of effective interventions in improving young people&#x2019;s sexual health: a review of reviews, Sex Educ 9(3) (2009) 319&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaede P, Vedel P, Larsen N, Jensen GV, Parving HH, Pedersen O, Multifactorial intervention and cardiovascular disease in patients with type 2 diabetes, N Engl J Med 348(5) (2003) 383&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12556541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davidson KW, Bigger JT, Burg MM, Carney RM, Chaplin WF, Czajkowski S, Dornelas E, Duer-Hefele J, Frasure-Smith N, Freedland KE, Haas DC, Jaffe AS, Ladapo JA, Lesperance F, Medina V, Newman JD, Osorio GA, Parsons F, Schwartz JE, Shaffer JA, Shapiro PA, Sheps DS, Vaccarino V, Whang W, Ye S, Centralized, stepped, patient preference-based treatment for patients with post-acute coronary syndrome depression: CODIACS vanguard randomized controlled trial, JAMA Intern Med 173(11) (2013) 997&#x2013;1004.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3681929</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23471421</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Paasche-Orlow MK, Riekert KA, Bilderback A, Chanmugam A, Hill P, Rand CS, Brancati FL, Krishnan JA, Tailored education may reduce health literacy disparities in asthma self-management, Am J Respir Crit Care Med 172(8) (2005) 980&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718412</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16081544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kincaid JP, Fishburne RP, Rogers RL, Chissom BS, Derivation of New Readability Formulas (Automated Readability Index, Fog Count and Flesch Reading Ease Formula) for Navy Enlisted Personnel, in: C.o.N.T. Training (Ed.) Naval Air Station Memphis, Naval Air Station Memphis, Millington, TN, 1975.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Castro M, Zimmermann NA, Crocker S, Bradley J, Leven C, Schechtman KB, Asthma intervention program prevents readmissions in high healthcare users, Am J Respir Crit Care Med 168(9) (2003) 1095&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12807696</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mozaffarian D, Benjamin EJ, Go AS, Arnett DK, Blaha MJ, Cushman M, Das SR, de Ferranti S, Despres JP, Fullerton HJ, Howard VJ, Huffman MD, Isasi CR, Jimenez MC, Judd SE, Kissela BM, Lichtman JH, Lisabeth LD, Liu S, Mackey RH, Magid DJ, McGuire DK, Mohler ER 3rd, Moy CS, Muntner P, Mussolino ME, Nasir K, Neumar RW, Nichol G, Palaniappan L, Pandey DK, Reeves MJ, Rodriguez CJ, Rosamond W, Sorlie PD, Stein J, Towfighi A, Turan TN, Virani SS, Woo D, Yeh RW, Turner MB, Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics-2016 Update: A Report From the American Heart Association, Circulation 133(4) (2016) e38&#x2013;e360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26673558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Flack JM, Sica DA, Bakris G, Brown AL, Ferdinand KC, Grimm RH Jr., Hall WD, Jones WE, Kountz DS, Lea JP, Nasser S, Nesbitt SD, Saunders E, Scisney-Matlock M, Jamerson KA, Management of high blood pressure in Blacks: an update of the International Society on Hypertension in Blacks consensus statement, Hypertension 56(5) (2010) 780&#x2013;800.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20921433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Harder VS, Ayer LA, Rose GL, Naylor MR, Helzer JE, Alcohol, moods and male-female differences: daily interactive voice response over 6 months, Alcohol Alcohol 49(1) (2014) 60&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3865813</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23847021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wheeler L, Buckley R, Gerald LB, Merkle S, A.M.T., Working with schools to improve pediatric asthma management, Pediatr Asthma Allergy Immunol 22(4) (2010) 197&#x2013;208.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isasi CR, Parrinello CM, Jung MM, Carnethon MR, Birnbaum-Weitzman O, Espinoza RA, Penedo FJ, Perreira KM, Schneiderman N, Sotres-Alvarez D, Van Horn L, Gallo LC, Psychosocial stress is associated with obesity and diet quality in Hispanic/Latino adults, Ann Epidemiol 25(2) (2015) 84&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4306634</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25487969</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Heart Association, Alcohol and Heart Health: AHA Recommendation, 2015. 
http://www.heart.org/HEARTORG/GettingHealthy/NutritionCenter/HealthyEating/Alcohol-and-Heart-Health_UCM_305173_Article.jsp. (Accessed June 29 2016).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leong SL, Gingrich D, Lewis PR, Mauger DT, George JH, Enhancing doctor-patient communication using email: a pilot study, J Am Board Fam Pract 18(3) (2005) 180&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15879565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walsh JM, McDonald KM, Shojania KG, Sundaram V, Nayak S, Lewis R, Owens DK, Goldstein MK, Quality improvement strategies for hypertension management: a systematic review, Med Care 44(7) (2006) 646&#x2013;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16799359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Curley MA, Patient-nurse synergy: optimizing patients&#x2019; outcomes, Am J Crit Care 7(1) (1998) 64&#x2013;72.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9429685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Coleman A, Freeman P, Steel S, Shennan A, Validation of the Omron 705IT (HEM-759-E) oscillometric blood pressure monitoring device according to the British Hypertension Society protocol, Blood Press Monit 11(1) (2006) 27&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16410738</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Brien E, Waeber B, Parati G, Staessen J, Myers MG, Blood pressure measuring devices: recommendations of the European Society of Hypertension, BMJ 322(7285) (2001) 531&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1119736</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11230071</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Takahashi H, Yoshika M, Yokoi T, Validation of two automatic devices for the self-measurement of blood pressure according to the ANSI/AAMI/ISO81060&#x2013;2:2009 guidelines: the Omron BP765 (HEM-7311-ZSA) and the Omron BP760N (HEM-7320-Z), Vasc Health Risk Manag 11 (2015) 49&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4295899</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25657587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anthony CA, Polgreen LA, Chounramany J, Foster ED, Goerdt CJ, Miller ML, Suneja M, Segre AM, Carter BL, Polgreen PM, Outpatient blood pressure monitoring using bi-directional text messaging, J Am Soc Hypertens 9(5) (2015) 375&#x2013;381.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25771023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Victor RG, Ravenell JE, Freeman A, Leonard D, Bhat DG, Shafiq M, Knowles P, Storm JS, Adhikari E, Bibbins-Domingo K, Coxson PG, Pletcher MJ, Hannan P, Haley RW, Effectiveness of a barber-based intervention for improving hypertension control in black men: the BARBER-1 study: a cluster randomized trial, Arch Intern Med 171(4) (2011) 342&#x2013;50.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3365537</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20975012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blonstein AC, Yank V, Stafford RS, Wilson SR, Rosas LG, Ma J, Translating an evidence-based lifestyle intervention program into primary care: lessons learned, Health Promot Pract 14(4) (2013) 491&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4011386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23539264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bellg AJ, Borrelli B, Resnick B, Hecht J, Minicucci DS, Ory M, Ogedegbe G, Orwig D, Ernst D, Czajkowski S, Enhancing treatment fidelity in health behavior change studies: best practices and recommendations from the NIH Behavior Change Consortium, Health Psychol 23(5) (2004) 443&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15367063</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carroll JK, Fiscella K, Epstein RM, Sanders MR, Winters PC, Moorhead SA, van Osch L, Williams GC, Physical activity counseling intervention at a federally qualified health center: improves autonomy-supportiveness, but not patients&#x2019; perceived competence, Patient Educ Couns 92(3) (2013) 432&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3862290</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23932756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Spillane V, Byrne MC, Byrne M, Leathem CS, O&#x2019;Malley M, Cupples ME, Monitoring treatment fidelity in a randomized controlled trial of a complex intervention, J Adv Nurs 60(3) (2007) 343&#x2013;52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17908130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Willard-Grace R, Chen EH, Hessler D, DeVore D, Prado C, Bodenheimer T, Thom DH, Health coaching by medical assistants to improve control of diabetes, hypertension, and hyperlipidemia in low-income patients: a randomized controlled trial, Ann Fam Med 13(2) (2015) 130&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4369595</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25755034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Antal H, Hossain MJ, Hassink S, Henry S, Fuzzell L, Taylor A, Wysocki T, Audio-video recording of health care encounters for pediatric chronic conditions: observational reactivity and its correlates, J Pediatr Psychol 40(1) (2015) 144&#x2013;53.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6366659</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24974174</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson-Kozlow M, Hovell MF, Rovniak LS, Sirikulvadhana L, Wahlgren DR, Zakarian JM, Fidelity issues in secondhand smoking interventions for children, Nicotine Tob Res 10(12) (2008) 1677&#x2013;90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3533496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19023822</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lambert JD, Greaves CJ, Farrand P, Cross R, Haase AM, Taylor AH, Assessment of fidelity in individual level behaviour change interventions promoting physical activity among adults: a systematic review, BMC Public Health 17(1) (2017) 765.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5625828</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28969669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lane C, Huws-Thomas M, Hood K, Rollnick S, Edwards K, Robling M, Measuring adaptations of motivational interviewing: the development and validation of the behavior change counseling index (BECCI), Patient Educ Couns 56(2) (2005) 166&#x2013;73.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15653245</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Madson MB, Loignon AC, Lane C, Training in motivational interviewing: a systematic review, J Subst Abuse Treat 36(1) (2009) 101&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18657936</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rasmussen HN, Wrosch C, Scheier MF, Carver CS, Self-regulation processes and health: the importance of optimism and goal adjustment, J Pers 74(6) (2006) 1721&#x2013;47.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17083664</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baker AL, Turner A, Kelly PJ, Spring B, Callister R, Collins CE, Woodcock KL, Kay-Lambkin FJ, Devir H, Lewin TJ, &#x2018;Better Health Choices&#x2019; by telephone: a feasibility trial of improving diet and physical activity in people diagnosed with psychotic disorders, Psychiatry Res 220(1&#x2013;2) (2014) 63&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25078563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dane AV, Schneider BH, Program integrity in primary and early secondary prevention: are implementation effects out of control?, Clin Psychol Rev 18(1) (1998) 23&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9455622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Santacroce SJ, Maccarelli LM, Grey M, Intervention fidelity, Nurs Res 53(1) (2004) 63&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14726779</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lauver DR, Gross J, Ruff C, Wells TJ, Patient-centered interventions: implications for incontinence, Nurs Res 53(6 Suppl) (2004) S30&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15586145</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Margolis KL, Asche SE, Bergdall AR, Dehmer SP, Groen SE, Kadrmas HM, Kerby TJ, Klotzle KJ, Maciosek MV, Michels RD, O&#x2019;Connor PJ, Pritchard RA, Sekenski JL, Sperl-Hillen JM, Trower NK, Effect of home blood pressure telemonitoring and pharmacist management on blood pressure control: a cluster randomized clinical trial, JAMA 310(1) (2013) 46&#x2013;56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4311883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23821088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Svetkey LP, Harsha DW, Vollmer WM, Stevens VJ, Obarzanek E, Elmer PJ, Lin PH, Champagne C, Simons-Morton DG, Aickin M, Proschan MA, Appel LJ, Premier: a clinical trial of comprehensive lifestyle modification for blood pressure control: rationale, design and baseline characteristics, Ann Epidemiol 13(6) (2003) 462&#x2013;71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12875806</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baral-Grant S, Haque MS, Nouwen A, Greenfield SM, McManus RJ, Self-Monitoring of Blood Pressure in Hypertension: A UK Primary Care Survey, Int J Hypertens 2012 (2012) 582068.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3195273</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22013510</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing RR, Lang W, Wadden TA, Safford M, Knowler WC, Bertoni AG, Hill JO, Brancati FL, Peters A, Wagenknecht L, Benefits of modest weight loss in improving cardiovascular risk factors in overweight and obese individuals with type 2 diabetes, Diabetes Care 34(7) (2011) 1481&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3120182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21593294</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Insignia Health, Insignia Health Patient Activation Measure&#xae;, 2015. 
http://insignia-health.herokuapp.com/products/pam-survey. (Accessed March 23 2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wing RR, Tate DF, Espeland MA, Lewis CE, LaRose JG, Gorin AA, Bahnson J, Perdue LH, Hatley KE, Ferguson E, Garcia KR, Lang W, Innovative Self-Regulation Strategies to Reduce Weight Gain in Young Adults: The Study of Novel Approaches to Weight Gain Prevention (SNAP) Randomized Clinical Trial, JAMA Intern Med 176(6) (2016) 755&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5461816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27136493</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nidich SI, Rainforth MV, Haaga DA, Hagelin J, Salerno JW, Travis F, Tanner M, Gaylord-King C, Grosswald S, Schneider RH, A randomized controlled trial on effects of the Transcendental Meditation program on blood pressure, psychological distress, and coping in young adults, Am J Hypertens 22(12) (2009) 1326&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3128829</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19798037</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panel on Handling Missing Data in Clinical Trials, Committee on National Statistics, Division of Behavioral and Social Sciences and Education, National Research Council, The Prevention and Treatment of Missing Data in Clinical Trials, The National Academies Press, Washington, D.C., 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rubin DB, Multiple Imputation for Nonresponse in Surveys, John Wiley &amp; Sons, New York, NY, 1987.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dmitrienko A, D&#x2019;Agostino R Sr., Traditional multiplicity adjustment methods in clinical trials, Stat Med 32(29) (2013) 5172&#x2013;218.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24114861</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anand IS, Rector TS, Kuskowski M, Thomas S, Holwerda NJ, Cohn JN, Effect of baseline and changes in systolic blood pressure over time on the effectiveness of valsartan in the Valsartan Heart Failure Trial, Circ Heart Fail 1(1) (2008) 34&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19808268</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Johnson HM, Olson AG, LaMantia JN, Kind AJ, Pandhi N, Mendonca EA, Craven M, Smith MA, Documented lifestyle education among young adults with incident hypertension, J Gen Intern Med 30(5) (2014) 556&#x2013;64.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4395591</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25373831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wallace ML, Magnan EM, Thorpe CT, Schumacher JR, Smith MA, Johnson HM, Diagnosis and treatment of incident hypertension among patients with diabetes: a U.S. multi-disciplinary group practice observational study, J Gen Intern Med 30(6) (2015) 768&#x2013;76.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4441679</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25650264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lawson EF, Hersh AO, Applebaum MA, Yelin EH, Okumura MJ, von Scheven E, Self-management skills in adolescents with chronic rheumatic disease: A cross-sectional survey, Pediatr Rheumatol Online J 9(1) (2011) 35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3254592</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22145642</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jerant AF, von Friederichs-Fitzwater MM, Moore M, Patients&#x2019; perceived barriers to active self-management of chronic conditions, Patient Educ Couns 57(3) (2005) 300&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15893212</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lynch EB, Liebman R, Ventrelle J, Avery EF, Richardson D, A self-management intervention for African Americans with comorbid diabetes and hypertension: a pilot randomized controlled trial, Prev Chronic Dis 11 (2014) E90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4040140</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24874782</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jelalian E, Boergers J, Alday CS, Frank R, Survey of physician attitudes and practices related to pediatric obesity, Clin Pediatr (Phila) 42(3) (2003) 235&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12739922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Parra-Medina D, Wilcox S, Wilson DK, Addy CL, Felton G, Poston MB, Heart Healthy and Ethnically Relevant (HHER) Lifestyle trial for improving diet and physical activity in underserved African American women, Contemp Clin Trials 31(1) (2010) 92&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2818166</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19781665</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis SD, Brody AS, Emond MJ, Brumback LC, Rosenfeld M, Endpoints for clinical trials in young children with cystic fibrosis, Proc Am Thorac Soc 4(4) (2007) 418&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2647606</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17652509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beckstead JW, Yang CY, Lengacher CA, Assessing cross-cultural validity of scales: a methodological review and illustrative example, Int J Nurs Stud 45(1) (2008) 110&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17081547</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaffo AL, Roseman JM, Jacobs DR Jr., Lewis CE, Shikany JM, Mikuls TR, Jolly PE, Saag KG, Serum urate and its relationship with alcoholic beverage intake in men and women: findings from the Coronary Artery Risk Development in Young Adults (CARDIA) cohort, Ann Rheum Dis 69(11) (2010) 1965&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5404888</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20525839</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tsai SA, Lv N, Xiao L, Ma J, Gender Differences in Weight-Related Attitudes and Behaviors Among Overweight and Obese Adults in the United States, Am J Mens Health E-pub ahead of print (2015).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25595019</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burke GL, Bertoni AG, Shea S, Tracy R, Watson KE, Blumenthal RS, Chung H, Carnethon MR, The impact of obesity on cardiovascular disease risk factors and subclinical vascular disease: the Multi-Ethnic Study of Atherosclerosis, Arch Intern Med 168(9) (2008) 928&#x2013;35.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2931579</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18474756</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matthews KA, Kelsey SF, Meilahn EN, Kuller LH, Wing RR, Educational attainment and behavioral and biologic risk factors for coronary heart disease in middle-aged women, Am J Epidemiol 129(6) (1989) 1132&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2729252</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vriz O, Nesbitt S, Krause L, Majahalme S, Lu H, Julius S, Smoking is associated with higher cardiovascular risk in young women than in men: the Tecumseh Blood Pressure Study, J Hypertens 15(2) (1997) 127&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9469787</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Donnell DE, Hernandez P, Kaplan A, Aaron S, Bourbeau J, Marciniuk D, Balter M, Ford G, Gervais A, Lacasse Y, Maltais F, Road J, Rocker G, Sin D, Sinuff T, Voduc N, Canadian Thoracic Society recommendations for management of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease - 2008 update - highlights for primary care, Can Respir J 15 Suppl A (2008) 1A&#x2013;8A.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2802325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18292855</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeSalvo KB, Jones TM, Peabody J, McDonald J, Fihn S, Fan V, He J, Muntner P, Health care expenditure prediction with a single item, self-rated health measure, Med Care 47(4) (2009) 440&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19238099</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeSalvo KB, Fan VS, McDonell MB, Fihn SD, Predicting mortality and healthcare utilization with a single question, Health Serv Res 40(4) (2005) 1234&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1361190</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16033502</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McDowell I, Measuring Health: A Guide to Rating Scales and Questionnaires, 3rd ed, Oxford University Press, New York, NY, 2006.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass PF 3rd, Wilson JF, Griffith CH, A shortened instrument for literacy screening, J Gen Intern Med 18(12) (2003) 1036&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1494969</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14687263</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bass SB, Wolak C, Rovito GM, Gordon TF, Ward L, Use of REALM-R vs. S-TOFHLA in an urban African American clinic population to assess health literacy: Practical implications, American Public Health Association 138th Annual Meeting &amp; Expo: Social Justice, Denver, CO, 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borzecki AM, Wong AT, Hickey EC, Ash AS, Berlowitz DR, Identifying hypertension-related comorbidities from administrative data: what&#x2019;s the optimal approach?, Am J Med Qual 19(5) (2004) 201&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15532912</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marciniak MD, Lage MJ, Dunayevich E, Russell JM, Bowman L, Landbloom RP, Levine LR, The cost of treating anxiety: the medical and demographic correlates that impact total medical costs, Depress Anxiety 21(4) (2005) 178&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16075454</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sadock E, Auerbach SM, Rybarczyk B, Aggarwal A, Evaluation of integrated psychological services in a university-based primary care clinic, J Clin Psychol Med Settings 21(1) (2014) 19&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24165929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahern DK, Gorkin L, Anderson JL, Tierney C, Hallstrom A, Ewart C, Capone RJ, Schron E, Kornfeld D, Herd JA, et al. , Biobehavioral variables and mortality or cardiac arrest in the Cardiac Arrhythmia Pilot Study (CAPS), Am J Cardiol 66(1) (1990) 59&#x2013;62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2193497</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elixhauser A, Steiner C, Harris DR, Coffey RM, Comorbidity measures for use with administrative data, Med Care 36(1) (1998) 8&#x2013;27.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9431328</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebert PL, Geiss LS, Tierney EF, Engelgau MM, Yawn BP, McBean AM, Identifying persons with diabetes using Medicare claims data, Am J Med Qual 14(6) (1999) 270&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10624032</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foley RN, Murray AM, Li S, Herzog CA, McBean AM, Eggers PW, Collins AJ, Chronic kidney disease and the risk for cardiovascular disease, renal replacement, and death in the United States Medicare population, 1998 to 1999, J Am Soc Nephrol 16(2) (2005) 489&#x2013;495.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15590763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sherbourne CD, Stewart AL, The MOS social support survey, Soc Sci Med 32(6) (1991) 705&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2035047</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starfield B, Weiner J, Mumford L, Steinwachs D, Ambulatory care groups: a categorization of diagnoses for research and management, Health Serv Res 26(1) (1991) 53&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1069810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1901841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morisky DE, Green LW, Levine DM, Concurrent and predictive validity of a self-reported measure of medication adherence, Med Care 24(1) (1986) 67&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3945130</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kripalani S, Henderson LE, Chiu EY, Robertson R, Kolm P, Jacobson TA, Predictors of medication self-management skill in a low-literacy population, J Gen Intern Med 21(8) (2006) 852&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1831567</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16881946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeWalt DA, Pignone MP, Reading is fundamental: the relationship between literacy and health, Arch Intern Med 165(17) (2005) 1943&#x2013;4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16186462</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelbourne CD, Social Functioning: Social Activity Limitations Measure, in: Stewart AL, Ware JE Jr. (Eds.), Measuring Functioning and Well-Being: The Medical Outcomes Study Approach, Duke University Press, Durham, NC, 1992, pp. 173&#x2013;181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shelbourne CD, Stewart AL, Wells KB, Role Functioning Measures, in: Stewart AL, Ware JE Jr. (Eds.), Measuring Functioning and Well-Being: The Medical Outcomes Study Approach, Duke University Press, Durham, NC, 1992, pp. 205&#x2013;219.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bosworth HB, Powers B, Grubber JM, Thorpe CT, Olsen MK, Orr M, Oddone EZ, Racial differences in blood pressure control: potential explanatory factors, J Gen Intern Med 23(5) (2008) 692&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2324164</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18288540</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson FE, Dixit-Joshi S, Potischman N, Dodd KW, Kirkpatrick SI, Kushi LH, Alexander GL, Coleman LA, Zimmerman TP, Sundaram ME, Clancy HA, Groesbeck M, Douglass D, George SM, Schap TE, Subar AF, Comparison of Interviewer-Administered and Automated Self-Administered 24-Hour Dietary Recalls in 3 Diverse Integrated Health Systems, Am J Epidemiol 181(12) (2015) 970&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4462333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25964261</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair SN, Haskell WL, Ho P, Paffenbarger RS Jr., Vranizan KM, Farquhar JW, Wood PD, Assessment of habitual physical activity by a seven-day recall in a community survey and controlled experiments, Am J Epidemiol 122(5) (1985) 794&#x2013;804.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3876763</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sallis JF, Haskell WL, Wood PD, Fortmann SP, Rogers T, Blair SN, Paffenbarger RS Jr., Physical activity assessment methodology in the Five-City Project, Am J Epidemiol 121(1) (1985) 91&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3964995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sidney S, Jacobs DR Jr., Haskell WL, Armstrong MA, Dimicco A, Oberman A, Savage PJ, Slattery ML, Sternfeld B, Van Horn L, Comparison of two methods of assessing physical activity in the Coronary Artery Risk Development in Young Adults (CARDIA) Study, Am J Epidemiol 133(12) (1991) 1231&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2063831</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Young DR, Haskell WL, Taylor CB, Fortmann SP, Effect of community health education on physical activity knowledge, attitudes, and behavior. The Stanford Five-City Project, Am J Epidemiol 144(3) (1996) 264&#x2013;74.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8686695</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Blair SN, Applegate WB, Dunn AL, Ettinger WH, Haskell WL, King AC, Morgan TM, Shih JA, Simons-Morton DG, Activity Counseling Trial (ACT): rationale, design, and methods. Activity Counseling Trial Research Group, Med Sci Sports Exerc 30(7) (1998) 1097&#x2013;106.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9662679</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dolor RJ, Yancy WS Jr., Owen WF, Matchar DB, Samsa GP, Pollak KI, Lin PH, Ard JD, Prempeh M, McGuire HL, Batch BC, Fan W, Svetkey LP, Hypertension Improvement Project (HIP): study protocol and implementation challenges, Trials 10 (2009) 13.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2654882</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19245692</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mengden T, Hernandez Medina RM, Beltran B, Alvarez E, Kraft K, Vetter H, Reliability of reporting self-measured blood pressure values by hypertensive patients, Am J Hypertens 11(12) (1998) 1413&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9880121</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunther AL, Liese AD, Bell RA, Dabelea D, Lawrence JM, Rodriguez BL, Standiford DA, Mayer-Davis EJ, Association between the dietary approaches to hypertension diet and hypertension in youth with diabetes mellitus, Hypertension 53(1) (2009) 6&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7732209</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19029488</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mellen PB, Gao SK, Vitolins MZ, Goff DC Jr., Deteriorating dietary habits among adults with hypertension: DASH dietary accordance, NHANES 1988&#x2013;1994 and 1999&#x2013;2004, Arch Intern Med 168(3) (2008) 308&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18268173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adams MA, Norman GJ, Hovell MF, Sallis JF, Patrick K, Reconceptualizing decisional balance in an adolescent sun protection intervention: mediating effects and theoretical interpretations, Health Psychol 28(2) (2009) 217&#x2013;25.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657937</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19290714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan RM, Patrick H, Deci EL, Williams GC, Facilitating health behaviour change and its maintenance: Interventions based on Self-Determination Theory, Eur Health Psychologist 10 (2008) 2&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levesque CS, Williams GC, Elliot D, Pickering MA, Bodenhamer B, Finley PJ, Validating the theoretical structure of the Treatment Self-Regulation Questionnaire (TSRQ) across three different health behaviors, Health Educ Res 22(5) (2007) 691&#x2013;702.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17138613</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbard JH, Stockard J, Mahoney ER, Tusler M, Development of the Patient Activation Measure (PAM): conceptualizing and measuring activation in patients and consumers, Health Serv Res 39(4 Pt 1) (2004) 1005&#x2013;26.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1361049</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15230939</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbard JH, Mahoney ER, Stockard J, Tusler M, Development and testing of a short form of the patient activation measure, Health Serv Res 40(6 Pt 1) (2005) 1918&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1361231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16336556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mosen DM, Schmittdiel J, Hibbard J, Sobel D, Remmers C, Bellows J, Is patient activation associated with outcomes of care for adults with chronic conditions?, J Ambul Care Manage 30(1) (2007) 21&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17170635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hibbard JH, Tusler M, Assessing activation stage and employing a &#x201c;next steps&#x201d; approach to supporting patient self-management, J Ambul Care Manage 30(1) (2007) 2&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17170632</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Becker ER, Roblin DW, Translating primary care practice climate into patient activation: the role of patient trust in physician, Med Care 46(8) (2008) 795&#x2013;805.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18665059</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zill JM, Dwinger S, Kriston L, Rohenkohl A, Harter M, Dirmaier J, Psychometric evaluation of the German version of the Patient Activation Measure (PAM13), BMC Public Health 13 (2013) 1027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4228438</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24172020</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wilson DK, Evans AE, Williams J, Mixon G, Sirard JR, Pate R, A preliminary test of a student-centered intervention on increasing physical activity in underserved adolescents, Ann Behav Med 30(2) (2005) 119&#x2013;24.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2830074</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16173908</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bauer DJ, Preacher KJ, Gil KM, Conceptualizing and testing random indirect effects and moderated mediation in multilevel models: new procedures and recommendations, Psychol Methods 11(2) (2006) 142&#x2013;63.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16784335</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kenny DA, Korchmaros JD, Bolger N, Lower level mediation in multilevel models, Psychol Methods 8(2) (2003) 115&#x2013;28.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12924810</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krull JL, MacKinnon DP, Multilevel mediation modeling in group-based intervention studies, Eval Rev 23(4) (1999) 418&#x2013;44.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10558394</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Krull JL, MacKinnon DP, Multilevel Modeling of Individual and Group Level Mediated Effects, Multivariate Behav Res 36(2) (2001) 249&#x2013;77.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26822111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Preacher KJ, Zyphur MJ, Zhang Z, A general multilevel SEM framework for assessing multilevel mediation, Psychol Methods 15(3) (2010) 209&#x2013;33.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20822249</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pituch KA, Stapleton LM, Kang JY, A Comparison of Single Sample and Bootstrap Methods to Assess Mediation in Cluster Randomized Trials, Multivariate Behav Res 41(3) (2006) 367&#x2013;400.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26750340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Warsi A, Wang PS, LaValley MP, Avorn J, Solomon DH, Self-management education programs in chronic disease: a systematic review and methodological critique of the literature, Arch Intern Med 164(15) (2004) 1641&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15302634</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccleston C, Fisher E, Law E, Bartlett J, Palermo TM, Psychological interventions for parents of children and adolescents with chronic illness, Cochrane Database Syst Rev 4 (2015) CD009660.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4838404</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25874881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cantrell J, Hair EC, Smith A, Bennett M, Rath JM, Thomas RK, Fahimi M, Dennis JM, Vallone D, Recruiting and retaining youth and young adults: challenges and opportunities in survey research for tobacco control, Tob Control 27(2) (2018) 147&#x2013;154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28432211</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rocha-Goldberg Mdel P, Corsino L, Batch B, Voils CI, Thorpe CT, Bosworth HB, Svetkey LP, Hypertension Improvement Project (HIP) Latino: results of a pilot study of lifestyle intervention for lowering blood pressure in Latino adults, Ethn Health 15(3) (2010) 269&#x2013;82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2888677</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20379894</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pedersen ER, Naranjo D, Marshall GN, Recruitment and retention of young adult veteran drinkers using Facebook, PLoS One 12(3) (2017) e0172972.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5332067</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28249027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norris SL, Engelgau MM, Narayan KM, Effectiveness of self-management training in type 2 diabetes: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials, Diabetes Care 24(3) (2001) 561&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11289485</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buscemi J, Blumstein L, Kong A, Stolley MR, Schiffer L, Odoms-Young A, Bittner C, Fitzgibbon ML, Retaining traditionally hard to reach participants: Lessons learned from three childhood obesity studies, Contemp Clin Trials 42 (2015) 98&#x2013;104.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4450125</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25847577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corser W, Sikorskii A, Olomu A, Stommel M, Proden C, Holmes-Rovner M, &#x201c;Concordance between comorbidity data from patient self-report interviews and medical record documentation&#x201d;, BMC Health Serv Res 8 (2008) 85.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2346463</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18416841</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taber DR, Stevens J, Murray DM, Elder JP, Webber LS, Jobe JB, Lytle LA, The effect of a physical activity intervention on bias in self-reported activity, Ann Epidemiol 19(5) (2009) 316&#x2013;22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2746093</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19230711</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma J, King AC, Wilson SR, Xiao L, Stafford RS, Evaluation of lifestyle interventions to treat elevated cardiometabolic risk in primary care (E-LITE): a randomized controlled trial, BMC Fam Pract 10 (2009) 71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2779786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19909549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>