<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34528009</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>03</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2666-6065</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>15</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Lancet regional health. Western Pacific</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Reg Health West Pac</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The longitudinal relationship between nutritional status and anaemia among Malaysian adolescents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>100228</StartPage><MedlinePgn>100228</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100228</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.lanwpc.2021.100228</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The triple burden of malnutrition characterised by stunting and wasting, overweight/obesity, and anaemia experienced by Malaysians causes severe and long-lasting damage during the period of development and rapid growth, particularly in adolescence. This study aimed to demonstrate the trend of anaemia prevalence and to determine its longitudinal association with nutritional status and lifestyle among Malaysian adolescents.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study involved secondary data analysis from the Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team (MyHeART) study. A closed cohort secondary data analysis was performed from the dynamic cohort of 528 adolescents (male&#xa0;=&#xa0;151; female&#xa0;=&#xa0;377) aged 13 years attending secondary school who were followed up at 15 and 17 years. Anaemia status was determined by haemoglobin level &lt; 12g/dL based on FBC, and iron deficiency anaemia (IDA) was determined when the Mentzer Index &lt; 13. A generalised estimating equation (GEE) was constructed to investigate the longitudinal relationship between nutritional status and lifestyle on anaemia status over five years.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The trend of anaemia prevalence increased significantly across the age group (7&#x2022;9%; 95% CI: 2&#x2022;3-11&#x2022;1, 13&#x2022;9%; 95% CI: 10&#x2022;8-15&#x2022;7 and 15&#x2022;8%; 95% CI: 3&#x2022;8-23&#x2022;1) at 13, 15 and 17 years, respectively, especially among females. The trend of anaemia prevalence among females, also increased significantly across the age group (11.1%;95% CI:6.7-17.8, 15.7%;95% CI:11.4-21.3, 23.1%;95% CI:16.8-31.0). A similar trend was noted for the prevalence of IDA among those who were anaemic (66&#x2022;5%; 95% CI: 40&#x2022;4-85&#x2022;3, 72&#x2022;2%;95% CI: 54&#x2022;8-85&#x2022;4, 76&#x2022;3%; 95% CI: 59&#x2022;2-87&#x2022;7). A longitudinal analysis using GEE revealed that adolescents who did not meet the Recommended Nutrient Intake (RNI) for total iron intake per day were significantly associated with anaemia (RR=1&#x2022;517;95% CI: 1&#x2022;012-2&#x2022;275; p=0&#x2022;044) and IDA (RR=1&#x2022;776;95% CI: 1&#x2022;225-2&#x2022;57; p= 0&#x2022;002).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The overall trend of anaemia among adolescents is in increasing trend and anaemia is prevalent among female adolescents in this study. It is crucial to understand that the current fortification strategy may need to be revisited, and robust intervention programmes are necessary and should be sex specific.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Krishnan</LastName><ForeName>Vanitha</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Population Health, Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zaki</LastName><ForeName>Rafdzah Ahmad</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Epidemiology and Evidence-Based Practice, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nahar</LastName><ForeName>Azmi Mohamed</ForeName><Initials>AM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, University Malaya Medical Centre, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jalaludin</LastName><ForeName>Muhammad Yazid</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Majid</LastName><ForeName>Hazreen Abdul</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Population Health, Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Nutrition, Faculty of Public Health, Universitas Airlangga.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2021</Year><Month>07</Month><Day>30</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Lancet Reg Health West Pac</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101774968</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2666-6065</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anaemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mentzer Index</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescent</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">haemoglobin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">iron deficiency anaemia</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutritional status</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2021</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2021</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>12</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2021</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34528009</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8342941</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanwpc.2021.100228</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2666-6065(21)00137-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Organization WH. Nutrition in adolescence: issues and challenges for the health sector: issues in adolescent health and development. 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Organization WH . WHO Regional Office for South-East Asia; 2006. Adolescent nutrition: a review of the situation in selected South-East Asian countries.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Benoist B, Cogswell M, Egli I, McLean E. WHO Global Database of anaemia; 2008. Worldwide prevalence of anaemia 1993-2005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18498676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prentice AM. Vol. 80. Karger Publishers; 2015. pp. 49&#x2013;59. (Nutrition challenges and issues of relevance to adolescents in low-and middle-income countries. Health and nutrition in adolescents and young women: Preparing for the next generation).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Awaluddin S, Ahmad N, Naidu B, Mohamad M, Yusof M. A population-based anaemia screening using point-of care in estimating prevalence of anaemia in Malaysian adults: findings from a Nationwide survey. J Community Med Health Educ. 2017;7:513. doi: 10.4172/2161-0711.1000513.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2161-0711.1000513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusoff H, Daud WNW, Ahmad Z. Nutrition education and knowledge, attitude and hemoglobin status of Malaysian adolescents. Southeast Asian J Trop Med Public Health. 2012;43(1):192&#x2013;200.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23082570</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fanzo J, Hawkes C, Udomkesmalee E, Afshin A, Allemandi L, Assery O, et&#xa0;al. 2018 Global Nutrition Report. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazreen MA, Su TT, Jalaludin MY, Dahlui M, Chinna K, Ismail M. An exploratory study on risk factors for chronic non-communicable diseases among adolescents in Malaysia: overview of the Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team study (The MyHeART study) BMC Public Health. 2014;14(3):S6. doi: 10.1186/1471-2458-14-S3-S6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2458-14-S3-S6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4251135</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25437068</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Majid HA Su TT, Jalaludin MY, Al Sadat N. University of Malaya Press; Kuala Lumpur: 2019. Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team (MyHeART) Study Handbook.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watkins D, Murray L, McCarron P, Boreham C, Cran G, Young I. Ten-year trends for fatness in Northern Irish adolescents: the Young Hearts Projects&#x2014;repeat cross-sectional study. Int J Obes. 2005;29(6):579&#x2013;585. doi: 10.1038/sj.ijo.0802945.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ijo.0802945</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15889116</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization . World Health Organization; 2011. Haemoglobin concentrations for the diagnosis of anaemia and assessment of severity.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>England J, Fraser P. Differentiation of iron deficiency from thalassaemia trait by routine blood-count. Lancet. 1973;1(7801):449&#x2013;452. doi: 10.1016/s0140-6736(73)91878-3.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(73)91878-3</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4120365</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mousa AO. Types of anemias with low MCV using Mentzer Index and RBC count among patients seen in Basrah Al-Sadir Teaching Hospital. Med J Babylon. 2014;11:292&#x2013;296.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Freedman LS, Midthune D, Arab L, Prentice RL, Subar AF, Willett W. Combining a food frequency questionnaire with 24-hour recalls to increase the precision of estimation of usual dietary intakes&#x2014;Evidence from the validation studies pooling project. Am J Epidemiol. 2018;187(10):2227&#x2013;2232. doi: 10.1093/aje/kwy126.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/aje/kwy126</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6166211</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29917051</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrows TL, Martin RJ, Collins CE. A systematic review of the validity of dietary assessment methods in children when compared with the method of doubly labeled water. J Am Diet Assoc. 2010;110(10):1501&#x2013;1510. doi: 10.1016/j.jada.2010.07.008.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jada.2010.07.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20869489</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee E, Ismail M, Nasir M, Khatijah I. Institute for Medical Research; Kuala Lumpur: 1997. Nutrient Composition of Malaysian Foods. Malaysian Food Composition Database Programme; p. 310.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Corp I. Version 22. IBM Corp; Armonk, NY: 2013. (IBM SPSS Statistics for Windows). 0 ed.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayashi F, Yoshiike N, Yoshita K, Kawahara K. Trends in the prevalence of anaemia in Japanese adult women, 1989&#x2013;2003. Public Health Nutr. 2008;11(3):252&#x2013;257. doi: 10.1017/S1368980007000274.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1368980007000274</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17601361</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute for Public Health (IPH) National Health and Morbidity Survey 2015 (NHMS 2015). Vol. II: Non-Communicable Diseases, Risk Factors &amp; Other Health Problems. National Institutes of Health, Ministry of Health; Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia: 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sekhar DL, Murray-Kolb LE, Kunselman AR, Weisman CS, Paul IM. Association between menarche and iron deficiency in non-anemic young women. PLoS ONE. 2017;12(5)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5423639</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28486542</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Institute for Public Health (IPH) National Health and Morbidity Survey (NHMS) National Institutes of Health, Ministry of Health Malaysia; Kuala Lumpur: 2017. Adolescent Nutrition Survey 2017, Malaysia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Coordinating Committee on Food and Nutrition (NCCFN) Ministry of Health; Putrajaya, Malaysia: 2017. Recommended Nutrient Intakes for Malaysia: A Report of the Technical Working Group on Nutritional Guidelines.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lanzkowsky P. Manual of Pediatric Hematology and Oncology. 2011;3:38&#x2013;57.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ntaios G, Chatzinikolaou A, Saouli Z, Girtovitis F, Tsapanidou M, Kaiafa G. Discrimination indices as screening tests for &#x3b2;-thalassemic trait. Ann Hematol. 2007;86(7):487&#x2013;491. doi: 10.1007/s00277-007-0302-x.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00277-007-0302-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17476506</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miri-Moghaddam E, Sargolzaie N. Cut off determination of discrimination indices in differential diagnosis between iron deficiency anemia and &#x3b2;-thalassemia minor. Int J Hematol Oncol Stem Cell Res. 2014;8(2):27&#x2013;32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4003440</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24800036</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesfaye M, Yemane T, Adisu W, Asres Y, Gedefaw L. Anemia and iron deficiency among school adolescents: burden, severity, and determinant factors in southwest Ethiopia. Adolesc Health Med Ther. 2015;6:189&#x2013;196. doi: 10.2147/AHMT.S94865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/AHMT.S94865</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4687608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26719736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Moraes ACF, Bel-Serrat S, Manios Y, Molnar D, Kafatos A, Cuenca-Garc&#xed;a M. Dietary protein and amino acids intake and its relationship with blood pressure in adolescents: the HELENA STUDY. Eur J Public Health. 2015;25(3):450&#x2013;456. doi: 10.1093/eurpub/cku233.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurpub/cku233</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25619683</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patil S, Patil N, Joglekar C, Yadav A, Nilawar A, Banavali U. Protocol: aDolescent and prEconception health peRspectiVe of Adult Non-communicable diseases (DERVAN): protocol for rural prospective adolescent girls cohort study in Ratnagiri district of Konkan region of India (DERVAN-1) BMJ Open. 2020;10(9):e035926. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2019-035926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2019-035926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7476477</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32895267</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saeedi P, Black K, Haszard J, Skeaff S, Stoner L, Davidson B. Dietary patterns, cardiorespiratory and muscular fitness in 9&#x2013;11-year-old children from Dunedin, New Zealand. Nutrients. 2018;10(7):887. doi: 10.3390/nu10070887.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu10070887</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6073327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29996543</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quick facts, Malaysia Educational Statistics. Educational Planning and Research Division. Ministry of Education Malaysia. 2019 ISSN: 1985-6407.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alam SLS, Purnamasari R, Bahar E, KYk Rahadian. Mentzer index as a screening tool for iron deficiency anemia in 6-12-year-old children. Paediatrica Indonesiana. 2014;54(5):294&#x2013;298. doi: 10.14238/pi54.5.2014.294-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14238/pi54.5.2014.294-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>