<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39907033</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>02</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-9254</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>97</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Jun</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of adolescence</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Adolesc</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Physical Activity and Its Relationship With National-Based Examination Results Among Adolescents.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1057</StartPage><EndPage>1073</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1057-1073</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jad.12479</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This study investigated the longitudinal relationship between self-reported physical activity and national examination results among adolescents in an upper-middle-income country.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study engaged in a secondary data analysis derived from a closed prospective cohort consisting of 579 students, who were recruited at the age of 13 in 2012 and followed up at ages 15 (2014) and 17 (2016) as part of the Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team (MyHeART) study, which was conducted across three states in Peninsula Malaysia. Physical activity levels were evaluated using the Physical Activity Questionnaire, and outcomes were assessed based on the National-Based Examinations at ages 15 (Form 3, Year 9) and 17 (Form 5, Year 11) in Malaysia. A multivariate ordinal regression employing complex sample analysis was applied to ascertain the relationship between physical activity and national examination results.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In Form 3 (Year 9), those physically active performed better in Malay Language, English Language, Mathematics and Science. Those physically active in Form 5 (Year 11), performed better in Modern Mathematics, Chemistry, and Principles of Accounting. Longitudinally, there was an increase in the overall percentage of those who were overweight and obese and an increase in those with suboptimal dietary and iron intake.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study has shown that those physically active students fared better in several subjects in the national-based examinations. Suitable physical activity intervention should be tailored accordingly to support adolescents' optimum achievement in academia.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025 Foundation for Professionals in Services to Adolescents.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venugopal</LastName><ForeName>V</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Population Health, Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ismail</LastName><ForeName>M</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Population Health, Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mohamed</LastName><ForeName>M N A</ForeName><Initials>MNA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Sports Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chinna</LastName><ForeName>K</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Faculty of Business and Information Science, UCSI University, Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jalaludin</LastName><ForeName>M Y</ForeName><Initials>MY</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Faculty of Medicine, University Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Su</LastName><ForeName>T T</ForeName><Initials>TT</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>South East Asia Community Observatory (SEACO), Jeffrey Cheah School of Medicine and Health Sciences, Monash University Malaysia, Subang Jaya, Selangor, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Majid</LastName><ForeName>H A</ForeName><Initials>HA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2718-8424</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Centre for Population Health, Department of Social and Preventive Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, University of Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Health and Rehabilitation Sciences, Health Sciences University, Bournemouth, United&#xa0;Kingdom.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>This study was supported by funding from the University of Malaya Research Programme (RP022-14HTM) and the Vice-Chancellor Research Grant (UMQUB3D-2011).</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>05</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>J Adolesc</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>7808986</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0140-1971</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015444" MajorTopicYN="Y">Exercise</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008296" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Malaysia</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011446" MajorTopicYN="N">Prospective Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008137" MajorTopicYN="N">Longitudinal Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">academic achievement</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adolescents</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">national&#x2010;based examinations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">physical activity</Keyword></KeywordList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>2</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>30</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>21</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>22</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39907033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jad.12479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>References</Title><Reference><Citation>Abdul Manaf, Z., S. Shahar, N. S. Safii, and H. Haron. 2015. Atlas of Food Exchanges &amp; Portion Sizes. MDC Publishers Sdn. Bhd.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abou Elmagd, M. 2016. &#x201c;Benefits, Need and Importance of Daily Exercise.&#x201d; International Journal of Physical Education, Sports and Health 3, no. 5: 22&#x2013;27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Acosta, W., T. H. Meek, H. Schutz, E. M. Dlugosz, K. T. Vu, and T. Garland, Jr. 2015. &#x201c;Effects of Early&#x2010;Onset Voluntary Exercise on Adult Physical Activity and Associated Phenotypes in Mice.&#x201d; Physiology &amp; Behavior 149: 279&#x2013;286. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physbeh.2015.06.020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmad, N., H. H. Asim, N. Juatan, et al. 2021. &#x201c;Contributing Factors to Decline in Physical Activity Among Adolescents: A Scoping Review.&#x201d; Malaysian Journal of Social Sciences and Humanities (MJSSH) 6: 447&#x2013;463. https://doi.org/10.47405/mjssh.v6i9.998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghadir, A., S. Gabr, and Z. Iqbal. 2020. &#x201c;Effect of Gender, Physical Activity and Stress&#x2010;Related Hormones on Adolescent's Academic Achievements.&#x201d; International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health 17, no. 11: 4143. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijerph17114143.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Almaqhawi, A., and M. Albarqi. 2022. &#x201c;The Effects of Technology Use on Children's Physical Activity: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study in the Eastern Province of Saudi Arabia.&#x201d; Journal of Medicine and Life 15, no. 10: 1240&#x2013;1245. https://doi.org/10.25122/jml-2022-0148.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alqahtani, Y., O. A. Assiri, N. S. Al&#x2010;Shahrani, N. S. Alyazidi, and M. H. Alshahrani. 2020. &#x201c;Relationship Between Nutritional Habits and School Performance Among Primary School Students in Asser Region.&#x201d; Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care 9, no. 4: 1986&#x2013;1990. https://doi.org/10.4103/jfmpc.jfmpc_885_19.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alshwaiyat, N., A. Ahmad, W. M. R. Wan Hassan, and H. Al&#x2011;jamal. 2021. &#x201c;Association Between Obesity and Iron Deficiency (Review).&#x201d; Experimental and Therapeutic Medicine 22, no. 5: 1268. https://doi.org/10.3892/etm.2021.10703.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>&#xc1;lvarez&#x2010;Bueno, C., C. Pesce, I. Cavero&#x2010;Redondo, M. S&#xe1;nchez&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez, M. Garrido&#x2010;Miguel, and V. Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;Vizca&#xed;no. 2017. &#x201c;Academic Achievement and Physical Activity: A Meta&#x2010;Analysis.&#x201d; Pediatrics 140, no. 6: e20171498. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2017-1498.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alves, J. G. B., and G. V. Alves. 2019. &#x201c;Effects of Physical Activity on Children's Growth.&#x201d; Jornal de Pediatria 95, no. Suppl 1: 72&#x2013;78. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jped.2018.11.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ashtary&#x2010;Larky, D., S. Daneghian, M. Alipour, et al. 2018. &#x201c;Waist Circumference to Height Ratio: Better Correlation With Fat Mass Than Other Anthropometric Indices During Dietary Weight Loss in Different Rates.&#x201d; International Journal of Endocrinology and Metabolism 16, no. 4: e55023. https://doi.org/10.5812/ijem.55023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Asigbee, F. M., S. D. Whitney, and C. E. Peterson. 2018. &#x201c;The Link Between Nutrition and Physical Activity in Increasing Academic Achievement.&#x201d; Journal of School Health 88, no. 6: 407&#x2013;415. https://doi.org/10.1111/josh.12625.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Axxya Systems. 2015. Nutritionist Pro&#x2122; database.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bacopoulou, F., V. Efthymiou, G. Landis, A. Rentoumis, and G. P. Chrousos. 2015. &#x201c;Waist Circumference, Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Hip Ratio and Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio Reference Percentiles for Abdominal Obesity Among Greek Adolescents.&#x201d; BMC Pediatrics 15: 50. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12887-015-0366-z.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barth Ved&#xf8;y, I., K. R. Skulberg, S. A. Anderssen, H. E. Tjomsland, and M. Thurston. 2021. &#x201c;Physical Activity and Academic Achievement Among Norwegian Adolescents: Findings From a Longitudinal Study.&#x201d; Preventive Medicine Reports 21: 101312. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmedr.2021.101312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>B&#xe9;langer, M., M. Casey, M. Cormier, et al. 2011. &#x201c;Maintenance and Decline of Physical Activity During Adolescence: Insights From a Qualitative Study.&#x201d; International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity 8, no. 1: 117. https://doi.org/10.1186/1479-5868-8-117.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Belcher, B. R., J. Zink, A. Azad, C. E. Campbell, S. P. Chakravartti, and M. M. Herting. 2021. &#x201c;The Roles of Physical Activity, Exercise, and Fitness in Promoting Resilience During Adolescence: Effects on Mental Well&#x2010;Being and Brain Development.&#x201d; Biological Psychiatry. Cognitive Neuroscience and Neuroimaging 6, no. 2: 225&#x2013;237. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpsc.2020.08.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brady, S. M., R. Salway, J. Mariapun, et al. 2024. &#x201c;Accelerometer&#x2010;Measured 24&#x2010;hour Movement Behaviours Over 7 Days in Malaysian Children and Adolescents: A Cross&#x2010;Sectional Study.&#x201d; PLoS One 19, no. 2: e0297102. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0297102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown, K. A., D. R. Patel, and D. Darmawan. 2017. &#x201c;Participation in Sports in Relation to Adolescent Growth and Development.&#x201d; Translational Pediatrics 6, no. 3: 150&#x2013;159. https://tp.amegroups.org/article/view/14626.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Burrows, T. L., R. J. Martin, and C. E. Collins. 2010. &#x201c;A Systematic Review of the Validity of Dietary Assessment Methods in Children When Compared With the Method of Doubly Labeled Water.&#x201d; Journal of the American Dietetic Association 110, no. 10: 1501&#x2013;1510. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jada.2010.07.008.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caldwell, A. E., D. K. Cummings, P. L. Hooper, et al. 2023. &#x201c;Adolescence Is Characterized by More Sedentary Behaviour and Less Physical Activity Even Among Highly Active Forager&#x2010;Farmers.&#x201d; Proceedings Biological Sciences 290, no. 2010: 20231764. https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2023.1764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Charlton, R., M. B. Gravenor, A. Rees, et al. 2014. &#x201c;Factors Associated With Low Fitness in Adolescents &#x2013; A Mixed Methods Study.&#x201d; BMC Public Health 14, no. 1: 764. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-14-764.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chung, Q. E., S. A. Abdulrahman, M. K. Jamal Khan, H. B. Jahubar Sathik, and A. Rashid. 2018. &#x201c;The Relationship Between Levels of Physical Activity and Academic Achievement Among Medical and Health Sciences Students at Cyberjaya University College of Medical Sciences.&#x201d; Malaysian Journal of Medical Sciences 25, no. 5: 88&#x2013;102. https://doi.org/10.21315/mjms2018.25.5.9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cole, T. J. 2000. &#x201c;Establishing a Standard Definition for Child Overweight and Obesity Worldwide: International Survey.&#x201d; BMJ 320, no. 7244: 1240. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.320.7244.1240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donnelly, J. E., C. H. Hillman, D. Castelli, et al. 2016. &#x201c;Physical Activity, Fitness, Cognitive Function, and Academic Achievement in Children: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 48, no. 6: 1223&#x2013;1224. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000000966.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dzoolkarnain, H. H., A. Ahmad Tajri, S. A. Lamat, and N. H. S. Bakri. 2021. &#x201c;Physical Activity Participation and Academic Performance Among Uitm Seremban Students.&#x201d; International Journal of Academic Research in Business and Social Sciences 11, no. 11: 372&#x2013;380. https://doi.org/10.6007/IJARBSS/v11-i11/11198.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elish, P. N., C. S. Bryan, P. J. Boedeker, et al. 2022. &#x201c;The Longitudinal Association Between Objectively&#x2010;Measured School&#x2010;Day Physical Activity and Academic Achievement in US Elementary School Students.&#x201d; International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity 19, no. 1: 90. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-022-01328-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eslami, M., F. Pourghazi, M. Khazdouz, et al. 2022. &#x201c;Optimal Cut&#x2010;Off Value of Waist Circumference&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio to Predict Central Obesity in Children and Adolescents: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Diagnostic Studies.&#x201d; Frontiers in Nutrition 9: 985319. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnut.2022.985319.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Faught, E. L., W. Qian, V. L. Carson, et al. 2019. &#x201c;The Longitudinal Impact of Diet, Physical Activity, Sleep, and Screen Time on Canadian Adolescents&#x2019; Academic Achievement: An Analysis From the Compass Study.&#x201d; Preventive Medicine 125: 24&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ypmed.2019.05.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fern&#xe1;ndez&#x2010;Bustos, J. G., &#xc1;. Infantes&#x2010;Paniagua, R. Cuevas, and O. R. Contreras. 2019. &#x201c;Effect of Physical Activity on Self&#x2010;Concept: Theoretical Model on the Mediation of Body Image and Physical Self&#x2010;Concept in Adolescents.&#x201d; Frontiers in Psychology 10: 1537. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2019.01537.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gallagher, A. M., J. M. Savage, L. J. Murray, et al. 2002. &#x201c;A Longitudinal Study Through Adolescence to Adulthood: The Young Hearts Project, Northern Ireland.&#x201d; Public Health 116, no. 6: 332&#x2013;340. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.ph.1900871.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Getu, T. 2020. &#x201c;The Effect of Physical Activity on Academic Performance and Mental Health: Systematic Review.&#x201d; American Journal of Science, Engineering and Technology 5, no. 3: 118&#x2013;123. https://doi.org/10.11648/j.ajset.20200503.12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gordon&#x2010;Larsen, P., N. S. The, and L. S. Adair. 2010. &#x201c;Longitudinal Trends in Obesity in the United States From Adolescence to the Third Decade of Life.&#x201d; Obesity 18, no. 9: 1801&#x2013;1804. https://doi.org/10.1038/oby.2009.451.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gunter, K. B., H. C. Almstedt, and K. F. Janz. 2012. &#x201c;Physical Activity in Childhood May Be the Key to Optimizing Lifespan Skeletal Health.&#x201d; Exercise and Sport Sciences Reviews 40, no. 1: 13&#x2013;21. https://doi.org/10.1097/JES.0b013e318236e5ee.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha, A. S., J. Y. Y. Ng, C. Lonsdale, D. R. Lubans, and F. F. Ng. 2019. &#x201c;Promoting Physical Activity in Children Through Family&#x2010;Based Intervention: Protocol of the &#x201c;Active 1&#x2009;+&#x2009;Fun&#x201d; Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; BMC Public Health 19, no. 1: 218. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-019-6537-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hashim, H., F. Golok, and R. Ali. 2011. &#x201c;Profiles of Exercise Motivation, Physical Activity, Exercise Habit, and Academic Performance in Malaysian Adolescents: A Cluster Analysis.&#x201d; International Journal of Collaborative Research on Internal Medicine &amp; Public Health 3, no. 3: 416&#x2013;428.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Have, M., J. H. Nielsen, M. T. Ernst, et al. 2018. &#x201c;Classroom&#x2010;Based Physical Activity Improves Children's Math Achievement &#x2010; a Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; PLoS One 13, no. 12: e0208787. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0208787.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazreen, M. A., T. T. Su, M. Y. Jalaludin, et al. 2014. &#x201c;An Exploratory Study on Risk Factors for Chronic Non&#x2010;Communicable Diseases Among Adolescents in Malaysia: Overview of the Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team Study (The Myheart Study).&#x201d; BMC Public Health 14 Suppl 3, no. 3: S6. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-14-S3-S6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazreen, M. A., T. T. Su, M. Y. Jalaludin, L. Ramli, N. A. S. Abdul Mohsein, and P. Y. Sim. 2016. &#x201c;Dietary Intake Among Adolescents in a Middle&#x2010;Income Country: An Outcome From the Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team Study (The Myhearts Study).&#x201d; PLoS One 11, no. 5: e0155447. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0155447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hazreen, M. A., T. T. Su, M. Y. Jalaludin, and N. A. Sadat. 2019. Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team (MyHeART) Study Handbook. University of Malaya Press.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hraste, M., A. De Giorgio, P. M. Jelaska, J. Padulo, and I. Grani&#x107;. 2018. &#x201c;When Mathematics Meets Physical Activity in the School&#x2010;Aged Child: The Effect of an Integrated Motor and Cognitive Approach to Learning Geometry.&#x201d; PLoS One 13, no. 8: e0196024. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0196024.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaac, V., S. Sim, H. Zheng, V. Zagorodnov, E. S. Tai, and M. Chee. 2011. &#x201c;Adverse Associations Between Visceral Adiposity, Brain Structure, and Cognitive Performance in Healthy Elderly.&#x201d; Frontiers in Aging Neuroscience 3: 12. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2011.00012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalantari, H. A., and S. Esmaeilzadeh. 2016. &#x201c;Association Between Academic Achievement and Physical Status Including Physical Activity, Aerobic and Muscular Fitness Tests in Adolescent Boys.&#x201d; Environmental Health and Preventive Medicine 21, no. 1: 27&#x2013;33. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12199-015-0495-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal, A. A., and N. Yusari. 2014. &#x201c;Malaysian Students' Involvement in Physical Activity and the Impact on Academic Achievement.&#x201d; Standard Journal of Educational Research and Essay 2, no. 1: 32&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kari, J. T., J. Pehkonen, N. Hutri&#x2010;K&#xe4;h&#xf6;nen, O. T. Raitakari, and T. H. Tammelin. 2017. &#x201c;Longitudinal Associations Between Physical Activity and Educational Outcomes.&#x201d; Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 49, no. 11: 2158&#x2013;2166. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000001351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keszty&#xfc;s, D., M. Traub, R. Lauer, T. Keszty&#xfc;s, and J. M. Steinacker. 2016. &#x201c;Correlates of Longitudinal Changes in the Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio of Primary School Children: Implications for Prevention.&#x201d; Preventive Medicine Reports 3: 1&#x2013;6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmedr.2015.11.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kompara Lukan&#x10d;i&#x10d;, M. 2021. &#x201c;Language Learning With Physical Activity: The Case of Learning Italian in Tourism.&#x201d; Training, Language and Culture 5: 10&#x2013;28. https://doi.org/10.22363/2521-442X-2021-5-3-10-28.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kowalski, K. C., P. R. Crocker, and R. M. Donen 2004. The physical activity questionnaire for older children (PAQ&#x2010;C) and adolescents (PAQ&#x2010;A) manual. College of Kinesiology, University of Saskatchewan.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kumar, B., R. Robinson, and S. Till. 2015. &#x201c;Physical Activity and Health in Adolescence.&#x201d; Clinical Medicine 15, no. 3: 267&#x2013;272. https://doi.org/10.7861/clinmedicine.15-3-267.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Landry, B. W., and S. W. Driscoll. 2012. &#x201c;Physical Activity in Children and Adolescents.&#x201d; PM &amp; R: The Journal of Injury, Function, and Rehabilitation 4, no. 11: 826&#x2013;832. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pmrj.2012.09.585.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee, O., D. Lee, S. Lee, and Y. S. Kim. 2016. &#x201c;Associations Between Physical Activity and Obesity Defined by Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio and Body Mass Index in the Korean Population.&#x201d; PLoS One 11, no. 7: e0158245. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0158245.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Livingstone, M., A. Prentice, W. Coward, et al. 1992. &#x201c;Validation of Estimates of Energy Intake by Weighed Dietary Record and Diet History in Children and Adolescents.&#x201d; The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 56, no. 1: 29&#x2013;35. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/56.1.29.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacLellan, D., J. Taylor, and K. Wood. 2008. &#x201c;Food Intake and Academic Performance Among Adolescents.&#x201d; Canadian Journal of Dietetic Practice and Research 69, no. 3: 141&#x2013;144. https://doi.org/10.3148/69.3.2008.141.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maghsoudi, E., M. Kandiah, L. W. Kong, B. Yusof, and M. Appukutty. 2014. &#x201c;Physical Fitness and Academic Performance Among Undergraduate Students of a Public University in Malaysia.&#x201d; European Journal of Sports and Exercise Science 3, no. 2: 6&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mandolesi, L., A. Polverino, S. Montuori, et al. 2018. &#x201c;Effects of Physical Exercise on Cognitive Functioning and Wellbeing: Biological and Psychological Benefits.&#x201d; Frontiers in Psychology 9: 509. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00509.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin&#x2010;Martinez, C., P. L. Valenzuela, M. Martinez&#x2010;Zamora, and &#xd3;. Martinez&#x2010;de&#x2010;Quel. 2023. &#x201c;School&#x2010;Based Physical Activity Interventions and Language Skills: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Randomized Controlled Trials.&#x201d; Journal of Science and Medicine in Sport 26, no. 2: 140&#x2013;148. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsams.2022.12.007.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mavilidi, M. F., D. R. Lubans, P. J. Morgan, et al. 2019. &#x201c;Integrating Physical Activity Into the Primary School Curriculum: Rationale and Study Protocol for the &#x201c;Thinking While Moving in English&#x201d; Cluster Randomized Controlled Trial.&#x201d; BMC Public Health 19, no. 1: 379. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-019-6635-2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCarthy, H. D., T. J. Cole, T. Fry, S. A. Jebb, and A. M. Prentice. 2006. &#x201c;Body Fat Reference Curves for Children.&#x201d; International Journal of Obesity 30, no. 4: 598&#x2013;602. https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.ijo.0803232.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McPherson, A., L. Mackay, J. Kunkel, and S. Duncan. 2018. &#x201c;Physical Activity, Cognition and Academic Performance: An Analysis of Mediating and Confounding Relationships in Primary School Children.&#x201d; BMC Public Health 18, no. 1: 936. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-018-5863-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McTiernan, A., C. M. Friedenreich, P. T. Katzmarzyk, et al. 2019. &#x201c;Physical Activity in Cancer Prevention and Survival: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 51, no. 6: 1252&#x2013;1261. https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000001937.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mehranfar, S., Y. Jalilpiran, A. Jafari, et al. 2024. &#x201c;Validity of Dietary Assessment Methods Compared With Doubly Labeled Water in Children: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis.&#x201d; Obesity Reviews 25, no. 9: e13768. https://doi.org/10.1111/obr.13768.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Education Malaysia. 2016. Sistem Analisis Peperiksaan Sekolah. https://sapsnkra.moe.gov.my.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ministry of Health Malaysia. 2011. Malaysian Food Composition Database. https://myfcd.moh.gov.my/index.html.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Sallehuddin, S., R. Abd. Talib, R. Salleh, et al. 2021. &#x201c;Calcium and Iron Intakes of Adolescents in Malaysia and Their Relationships With Body Mass Index (Bmi): Findings From the Adolescent Nutrition Survey 2017.&#x201d; Malaysian Journal of Nutrition 27, no. 2: 317&#x2013;326. https://doi.org/10.31246/mjn-2020-0054.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mohd Zaki, N. A., N. Sahril, M. A. Omar, M. H. Ahmad, A. Baharudin, and N. S. Mohd Nor. 2016. &#x201c;Reliability and Validity of the Physical Activity Questionnaire for Older Children (Paq&#x2010;C) In Malay Language.&#x201d; International Journal of Public Health Research 6, no. 1: 670&#x2013;676. https://spaj.ukm.my/ijphr/index.php/ijphr/article/view/16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Molina, X. P., D. P, J. Finkelstein, and R. Kuriyan. 2022. &#x201c;Longitudinal Changes in Waist Circumference and Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio in Children and Adolescents in Southern India.&#x201d; Current Developments in Nutrition 6, no. Suppl 1: 938. https://doi.org/10.1093/cdn/nzac067.058.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence. 2023. Obesity: Identification, assessment and management. NICE Guideline Number 189. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK588750/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng, A. K., N. N. Hairi, M. Y. Jalaludin, and H. A. Majid. 2019. &#x201c;Dietary Intake, Physical Activity and Muscle Strength Among Adolescents: The Malaysian Health and Adolescents Longitudinal Research Team (MyHeART) Study.&#x201d; BMJ Open 9, no. 6: e026275. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjopen-2018-026275.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oliveira, R. G., and D. P. Guedes. 2016. &#x201c;Physical Activity, Sedentary Behavior, Cardiorespiratory Fitness and Metabolic Syndrome in Adolescents: Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis of Observational Evidence.&#x201d; PLoS One 11, no. 12: e0168503. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0168503.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ong, S. H., S. T. Chen, J. J. Chong, J. Y. Chan, T. M. Tan, and J. J. Lee. 2018. &#x201c;Use of Children&#x2010;Physical Activity Questionnaire (C&#x2010;PAQ) and Subjective Global Nutrition Assessment (SGNA) in Assessing Physical Activity Level and Nutritional Status of Children With Special Needs.&#x201d; Clinical Nutrition 37: S244. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.clnu.2018.06.1863.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ozemek, C., D. R. Laddu, C. J. Lavie, et al. 2018. &#x201c;An Update on the Role of Cardiorespiratory Fitness, Structured Exercise and Lifestyle Physical Activity in Preventing Cardiovascular Disease and Health Risk.&#x201d; Progress in Cardiovascular Diseases 61, no. 5: 484&#x2013;490. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pcad.2018.11.005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Papasideris, M., S. T. Leatherdale, K. Battista, and P. A. Hall. 2021. &#x201c;An Examination of the Prospective Association Between Physical Activity and Academic Achievement in Youth at the Population Level.&#x201d; PLoS One 16, no. 6: e0253142. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0253142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pasdar, Y., S. Moradi, J. Moludi, et al. 2020. &#x201c;Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio Is a Better Discriminator of Cardiovascular Disease Than Other Anthropometric Indicators in Kurdish Adults.&#x201d; Scientific Reports 10, no. 1: 16228. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-73224-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pate, R. R., J. I. Flynn, and M. Dowda. 2016. &#x201c;Policies for Promotion of Physical Activity and Prevention of Obesity in Adolescence.&#x201d; Journal of Exercise Science &amp; Fitness 14, no. 2: 47&#x2013;53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesf.2016.07.003.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pathrudu, G. B. 2015. &#x201c;Waist Hip Ratio Is Negatively Associated With Academic Performance of Students.&#x201d; International Journal of Health Research in Modern Integrated Medical Sciences 2, no. 1: 13&#x2013;16.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pellicer&#x2010;Chenoll, M., X. Garcia&#x2010;Masso, J. Morales, et al. 2015. &#x201c;Physical Activity, Physical Fitness and Academic Achievement in Adolescents: A Self&#x2010;Organizing Maps Approach.&#x201d; Health Education Research 30, no. 3: 436&#x2013;448. https://doi.org/10.1093/her/cyv016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Posadzki, P., D. Pieper, R. Bajpai, et al. 2020. &#x201c;Exercise/Physical Activity and Health Outcomes: An Overview of Cochrane Systematic Reviews.&#x201d; BMC Public Health 20, no. 1: 1724. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12889-020-09855-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proia, P., A. Amato, P. Drid, D. Korovljev, S. Vasto, and S. Baldassano. 2021. &#x201c;The Impact of Diet and Physical Activity on Bone Health in Children and Adolescents.&#x201d; Frontiers in Endocrinology 12: 704647. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2021.704647.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rudzinska, I., and M. Jakov&#x13c;eva. 2015. &#x201c;Sport Student Foreign Language Learning and Use Habits.&#x201d; Proceedings of the International Scientific Conference: Society, Integration, Education 1: 233. https://doi.org/10.17770/sie2014vol1.766.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ruiz&#x2010;Ariza, A., A. Grao&#x2010;Cruces, N. E. M. de Loureiro, and E. J. Mart&#xed;nez&#x2010;L&#xf3;pez. 2017. &#x201c;Influence of Physical Fitness on Cognitive and Academic Performance in Adolescents: A Systematic Review From 2005&#x2013;2015.&#x201d; International Review of Sport and Exercise Psychology 10: 108&#x2013;133. https://doi.org/10.1080/1750984X.2016.1184699.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saad, R. A., and H. M. Qutob. 2022. &#x201c;The Relationship Between Anemia and Obesity.&#x201d; Expert Review of Hematology 15, no. 10: 911&#x2013;926. https://doi.org/10.1080/17474086.2022.2131521.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sani, S. H., Z. Fathirezaie, S. Brand, et al. 2016. &#x201c;Physical Activity and Self&#x2010;Esteem: Testing Direct and Indirect Relationships Associated With Psychological and Physical Mechanisms.&#x201d; Neuropsychiatric disease and treatment 12: 2617&#x2013;2625. https://doi.org/10.2147/ndt.S116811.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sanyaolu, A., C. Okorie, X. Qi, J. Locke, and S. Rehman. 2019. &#x201c;Childhood and Adolescent Obesity in the United States: A Public Health Concern.&#x201d; Global Pediatric Health 6: 2333794x19891305. https://doi.org/10.1177/2333794x19891305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schlichting, M. L., K. F. Guarino, H. E. Roome, and A. R. Preston. 2022. &#x201c;Developmental Differences in Memory Reactivation Relate to Encoding and Inference in the Human Brain.&#x201d; Nature Human Behaviour 6, no. 3: 415&#x2013;428. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-021-01206-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sember, V., G. Jurak, G. Starc, and S. A. Morrison. 2022. &#x201c;Can Primary School Mathematics Performance Be Predicted by Longitudinal Changes in Physical Fitness and Activity Indicators?&#x201d; Frontiers in Psychology 13: 796838. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2022.796838.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shahril, M. R., T. I. Unal, J. E. Wong, et al. 2023. &#x201c;Results From the Malaysia 2022 Report Card on Physical Activity for Children and Adolescents.&#x201d; Journal of Exercise Science and Fitness 21, no. 1: 88&#x2013;94. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jesf.2022.11.001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shamsudin, S., S. F. Ismail, A. Al&#x2010;Mamun, and S. K. B. S. Nordin. 2014. &#x201c;Examining the Effect of Extracurricular Activities on Academic Achievements Among the Public University Students in Malaysia.&#x201d; Asian Social Science 10: 171.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao, J., L. Yu, X. Shen, D. Li, and K. Wang. 2010. &#x201c;Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio, an Optimal Predictor for Obesity and Metabolic Syndrome in Chinese Adults.&#x201d; The Journal of Nutrition, Health and Aging 14, no. 9: 782&#x2013;785. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12603-010-0106-x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shao, T., and X. Zhou. 2023. &#x201c;Correlates of Physical Activity Habits in Adolescents: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; Frontiers in Physiology 14: 1131195. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2023.1131195.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silva, T. O., M. M. Norde, A. C. Vasques, et al. 2023. &#x201c;Association of Physical Activity and Sitting With Metabolic Syndrome and Hyperglycemic Clamp Parameters in Adolescents &#x2010; Brams Pediatric Study.&#x201d; Frontiers in Endocrinology 14: 1191935. https://doi.org/10.3389/fendo.2023.1191935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, A., L. Uijtdewilligen, J. W. Twisk, W. van Mechelen, and M. J. Chinapaw. 2012. &#x201c;Physical Activity and Performance at School: A Systematic Review of the Literature Including a Methodological Quality Assessment.&#x201d; Archives of Pediatrics &amp; Adolescent Medicine 166, no. 1: 49&#x2013;55. https://doi.org/10.1001/archpediatrics.2011.716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh, A. S., E. Saliasi, V. van den Berg, et al. 2019. &#x201c;Effects of Physical Activity Interventions on Cognitive and Academic Performance in Children and Adolescents: A Novel Combination of a Systematic Review and Recommendations From an Expert Panel.&#x201d; British Journal of Sports Medicine 53, no. 10: 640&#x2013;647. https://doi.org/10.1136/bjsports-2017-098136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Sluijs, E. M. F., U. Ekelund, I. Crochemore&#x2010;Silva, et al. 2021. &#x201c;Physical Activity Behaviours in Adolescence: Current Evidence and Opportunities for Intervention.&#x201d; The Lancet 398, no. 10298: 429&#x2013;442. https://doi.org/10.1016/s0140-6736(21)01259-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sneck, S., H. Viholainen, H. Syv&#xe4;oja, et al. 2019. &#x201c;Effects of School&#x2010;Based Physical Activity on Mathematics Performance in Children: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity 16, no. 1: 109. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-019-0866-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>So, W. Y. 2012. &#x201c;Association Between Physical Activity and Academic Performance in Korean Adolescent Students.&#x201d; BMC Public Health 12: 258. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2458-12-258.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Staveren, W., J. de Boer, and J. Burema. 1985. &#x201c;Validity and Reproducibility of a Dietary History Method Estimating the Usual Food Intake During One Month.&#x201d; The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 42, no. 3: 554&#x2013;559. https://doi.org/10.1093/ajcn/42.3.554.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan, R. A., A. H. Kuzel, M. E. Vaandering, and W. Chen. 2017. &#x201c;The Association of Physical Activity and Academic Behavior: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; Journal of School Health 87, no. 5: 388&#x2013;398. https://doi.org/10.1111/josh.12502.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweatt, K., W. T. Garvey, and C. Martins. 2024. &#x201c;Strengths and Limitations of BMI in the Diagnosis of Obesity: What Is the Path Forward?&#x201d; Current Obesity Reports 13, no. 3: 584&#x2013;595. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13679-024-00580-1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syv&#xe4;oja, H. J., A. Kankaanp&#xe4;&#xe4;, H. Hakonen, et al. 2021. &#x201c;How Physical Activity, Fitness, and Motor Skills Contribute to Math Performance: Working Memory as a Mediating Factor.&#x201d; Scandinavian Journal of Medicine &amp; Science in Sports 31, no. 12: 2310&#x2013;2321. https://doi.org/10.1111/sms.14049.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Syv&#xe4;oja, H. J., A. Kankaanp&#xe4;&#xe4;, L. Joensuu, et al. 2019. &#x201c;The Longitudinal Associations of Fitness and Motor Skills With Academic Achievement.&#x201d; Medicine &amp; Science in Sports &amp; Exercise 51, no. 10: 2050&#x2013;2057. https://doi.org/10.1249/MSS.0000000000002031.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taras, H. 2005. &#x201c;Physical Activity and Student Performance at School.&#x201d; Journal of School Health 75, no. 6: 214&#x2013;218. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1746-1561.2005.00026.x.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tee, E. S., K. Indris, M. N. Azudin, and M. I. Noor. 1997. Nutrient composition of Malaysian foods (4th ed.) Ministry of Health Malaysia.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tewari, A., G. Kumar, A. Maheshwari, V. Tewari, and J. Tewari. 2023. &#x201c;Comparative Evaluation of Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio and BMI in Predicting Adverse Cardiovascular Outcome in People With Diabetes: A Systematic Review.&#x201d; Cureus 15, no. 5: e38801. https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.38801.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Veloo, A., and R. Md&#x2010;Ali. 2016. &#x201c;Physical Education Teachers Challenges in Implementing School Based Assessment.&#x201d; International Review of Management and Marketing 6, no. 8S: 48&#x2013;53. https://econjournals.com/index.php/irmm/article/view/3909.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vikram, N. K., A. N. Latifi, A. Misra, et al. 2016. &#x201c;Waist&#x2010;To&#x2010;Height Ratio Compared to Standard Obesity Measures as Predictor of Cardiometabolic Risk Factors in Asian Indians in North India.&#x201d; Metabolic syndrome and related disorders 14, no. 10: 492&#x2013;499. https://doi.org/10.1089/met.2016.0041.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang, T., Q. Gao, Y. Yao, et al. 2023. &#x201c;Causal Relationship Between Obesity and Iron Deficiency Anemia: A Two&#x2010;Sample Mendelian Randomization Study.&#x201d; Frontiers in Public Health 11: 1188246. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpubh.2023.1188246.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watson, A., A. Timperio, H. Brown, K. Best, and K. D. Hesketh. 2017. &#x201c;Effect of Classroom&#x2010;Based Physical Activity Interventions on Academic and Physical Activity Outcomes: A Systematic Review and Meta&#x2010;Analysis.&#x201d; International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity 14, no. 1: 114. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12966-017-0569-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Whooten, R., L. Kerem, and T. Stanley. 2019. &#x201c;Physical Activity in Adolescents and Children and Relationship to Metabolic Health.&#x201d; Current Opinion in Endocrinology, Diabetes &amp; Obesity 26, no. 1: 25&#x2013;31. https://doi.org/10.1097/med.0000000000000455.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Woodhouse, A., P. D. Lamport, and A. Mark. 2012. &#x201c;The Relationship of Food and Academic Performance: A Preliminary Examination of the Factors of Nutritional Neuroscience, Malnutrition, and Diet Adequacy.&#x201d; Christian Perspectives in Education 5, no. 1: 1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2008. Waist Circumference and Waist&#x2013;Hip Ratio: Report of a WHO expert consultation. https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/44583.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2011. Haemoglobin Concentrations for the Diagnosis of Anaemia and Assessment of Severity. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/WHO-NMH-NHD-MNM-11.1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2018. Global action plan on physical activity 2018&#x2013;2030: More active people for a healthier world. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789241514187.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2020. WHO guidelines on physical activity and sedentary behaviour. https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240015128.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization. 2023. Global Accelerated Action for the Health of Adolescents (AA&#x2010;HA!): Guidance to support country implementation (2nded.). https://www.who.int/health-topics/adolescent-health.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyszy&#x144;ska, J., S. Ring&#x2010;Dimitriou, D. Thivel, et al. 2020. &#x201c;Physical Activity in the Prevention of Childhood Obesity: The Position of the European Childhood Obesity Group and the European Academy of Pediatrics.&#x201d; Frontiers in Pediatrics 8: 535705. https://doi.org/10.3389/fped.2020.535705.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yu, C. C. W., S. Chan, F. Cheng, R. Y. T. Sung, and K. T. Hau. 2006. &#x201c;Are Physical Activity and Academic Performance Compatible? Academic Achievement, Conduct, Physical Activity and Self&#x2010;Esteem of Hong Kong Chinese Primary School Children.&#x201d; Educational Studies 32, no. 4: 331&#x2013;341. https://doi.org/10.1080/03055690600850016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou, J., H. Liu, H. Wen, X. Wang, Y. Wang, and T. Yang. 2022. &#x201c;The Association Between Physical Activity and Mathematical Achievement Among Chinese Fourth Graders: A Moderated Moderated&#x2010;Mediation Model.&#x201d; Frontiers in Psychology 13: 862666. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2022.862666.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>