<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">20599999</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2010</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1090-2449</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>126</Volume><Issue>3</Issue><PubDate><Year>2010</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Experimental parasitology</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Exp Parasitol</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Giardia duodenalis: the double-edged sword of immune responses in giardiasis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>292</StartPage><EndPage>297</EndPage><MedlinePgn>292-7</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.exppara.2010.06.014</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Giardiasis is one of the most common intestinal protozoan infections worldwide. The etiological agent, Giardia duodenalis (syn. Giardia lamblia, Giardia intestinalis), is a flagellated, binucleated protozoan parasite which infects a wide array of mammalian hosts (Adam, 2001). The symptoms of giardiasis include abdominal cramps, nausea, and acute or chronic diarrhea, with malabsorption and failure of children to thrive occurring in both sub-clinical and symptomatic disease (Thompson et al., 1993). Infections are transmitted by cysts which are excreted in the feces of infected humans and animals. Human giardiasis is distributed worldwide, with rates of detection between 2-5% in the developed world and 20-30% in the developing nations (Farthing, 1994). There is significant variation in the outcome of Giardia infections. Most infections are self-limiting, although re-infection is common in endemic areas and chronic infections also occur. Moreover, some individuals suffer from severe cramps, nausea and diarrhea while others escape these overt symptoms. This review will describe recent advances in parasite genetics and host immunity that are helping to shed light on this variability.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>(c) 2010 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Solaymani-Mohammadi</LastName><ForeName>Shahram</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Center for Infectious Disease, Reiss Science Building, Georgetown University, Washington, DC 20057, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Singer</LastName><ForeName>Steven M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>R01 AI049565</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>R03 AI081033</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>AI-81033</GrantID><Acronym>AI</Acronym><Agency>NIAID NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2010</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>18</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Exp Parasitol</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0370713</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0014-4894</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D000913">Antibodies, Protozoan</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D016052">Protozoan Vaccines</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D056704" MajorTopicYN="N">Adaptive Immunity</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000913" MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies, Protozoan</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004195" MajorTopicYN="N">Disease Models, Animal</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016829" MajorTopicYN="N">Giardia lamblia</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005873" MajorTopicYN="N">Giardiasis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="Y">immunology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007113" MajorTopicYN="N">Immunity, Innate</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008407" MajorTopicYN="N">Mast Cells</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000276" MajorTopicYN="N">immunology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016052" MajorTopicYN="N">Protozoan Vaccines</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2009</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>31</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2010</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2010</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>11</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2010</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2010</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2010</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>21</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2011</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20599999</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS216512</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2933943</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.exppara.2010.06.014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S0014-4894(10)00209-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Abdul-Wahid A, Faubert G. Mucosal delivery of a transmission-blocking DNA vaccine encoding Giardia lamblia CWP2 by Salmonella typhimurium bactofection vehicle. Vaccine. 2007;25:8372&#x2013;8383.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17996337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adam RD. Biology of Giardia lamblia. Clinical Microbiology Reviews. 2001;14:447&#x2013;475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC88984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11432808</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aley SB, Zimmerman M, Hetsko M, Selsted ME, Gillin FD. Killing of Giardia lamblia by cryptdins and cationic neutrophil peptides. Infection and Immunity. 1994;62:5397&#x2013;5403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC303280</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7960119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Anderson KA, Brooks AS, Morrison AL, Reid-Smith RJ, Martin SW, Benn DM, Peregrine AS. Impact of Giardia vaccination on asymptomatic Giardia infections in dogs at a research facility. The Canadian Veterinary Journal. 2004;45:924&#x2013;930.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC545982</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15600158</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Andersen YS, Gillin FD, Eckmann L. Adaptive immunity-dependent intestinal hypermotility contributes to host defense against Giardia spp. Infection and Immunity. 2006;74:2473&#x2013;2476.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1418922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16552082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angarano G, Maggi P, Di Bari MA, Larocca AM, Congedo P, Di Bari C, Brandonisio O, Chiodo F. Giardiasis in HIV: a possible role in patients with severe immune deficiency. European Journal of Epidemiology. 1997;13:485&#x2013;487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9258558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ayabe T, Ashida T, Kohgo Y, Kono T. The role of Paneth cells and their antimicrobial peptides in innate host defense. Trends in Microbiology. 2004;12:394&#x2013;398.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15276616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bachur TP, Vale JM, Co&#xea;lho IC, Queiroz TR, Chaves Cde. S. Enteric parasitic infections in HIV/AIDS patients before and after the highly active antiretroviral therapy. The Brazilian Journal of Infectious Disease. 2008;12:115&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18641847</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayraktar MR, Mehmet N, Durmaz R. Serum cytokine changes in Turkish children infected with Giardia lamblia with and without allergy: Effect of metronidazole treatment. Acta Tropica. 2005;95:116&#x2013;122.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15979046</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bienz M, Dai WJ, Welle M, Gottstein B, M&#xfc;ller N. Interleukin-6-deficient mice are highly susceptible to Giardia lamblia infection but exhibit normal intestinal immunoglobulin A responses against the parasite. Infection and Immunity. 2003;71:1569&#x2013;1573.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC148820</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12595479</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buret A, Gall DG, Olson ME. Effects of murine giardiasis on growth, intestinal morphology, and disaccharidase activity. The Journal of Parasitology. 1990;76:403&#x2013;409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2191103</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buret A, Gall DG, Olson ME. Growth, activities of enzymes in the small intestine, and ultrastructure of microvillous border in gerbils infected with Giardia duodenalis. Parasitology Research. 1991;77:109&#x2013;114.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2027878</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buret AG, Mitchell K, Muench DG, Scott KG. Giardia lamblia disrupts tight junctional ZO-1 and increases permeability in non-transformed human small intestinal epithelial monolayers: effects of epidermal growth factor. Parasitology. 2002;125:11&#x2013;19.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12166516</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Buret AG. Mechanisms of epithelial dysfunction in giardiasis. Gut. 2007;56:316&#x2013;317.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1856818</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17339241</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cevallos A, Carnaby S, James M, Farthing JG. Small intestinal injury in a neonatal rat model of giardiasis is strain dependent. Gastroenterology. 1995;109:766&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7657104</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chin AC, Teoh DA, Scott KG, Meddings JB, Macnaughton WK, Buret AG. Strain-dependent induction of enterocyte apoptosis by Giardia lamblia disrupts epithelial barrier function in a caspase-3-dependent manner. Infection and Immunity. 2002;70:3673&#x2013;3680.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC128105</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12065509</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daniels CW, Belosevic M. Disaccharidase activity in male and female C57BL/6 mice infected with Giardia muris. Parasitology Research. 1995;81:143&#x2013;147.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7731922</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davids BJ, Palm JE, Housley MP, Smith JR, Andersen YS, Martin MG, Hendrickson BA, Johansen FE, Sv&#xe4;rd SG, Gillin FD, Eckmann L. Polymeric immunoglobulin receptor in intestinal immune defense against the lumen-dwelling protozoan parasite Giardia. The Journal of Immunology. 2006;177:6281&#x2013;6290.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17056558</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ebert EC. Giardia induces proliferation and interferon gamma production by intestinal lymphocytes. Gut. 1999;44:342&#x2013;346.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1727435</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10026318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckmann L, Laurent F, Langford TD, Hetsko ML, Smith JR, Kagnoff MF, Gillin FD. Nitric oxide production by human intestinal epithelial cells and competition for arginine as potential determinants of host defense against the lumen-dwelling pathogen Giardia lamblia. The Journal of Immunology. 2000;164:1478&#x2013;1487.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10640765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckmann L. Mucosal defences against Giardia. Parasite Immunology. 2003;25:259&#x2013;270.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12969444</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Erlich JH, Anders RF, Roberts-Thomson IC, Schrader JW, Mitchell GF. An examination of differences in serum antibody specificities and hypersensitivity reactions as contributing factors to chronic infection with the intestinal protozoan parasite, Giardia muris, in mice. The Australian Journal of Experimental Biology and Medical Science. 1983;61:599&#x2013;615.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6689264</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Farthing MJG. Giardiasis as a disease. In: Thompson RCA, Reynoldson JA, Lymbery AJ, editors. Giardia: from molecules to diseases. CAB International; Oxon: 1994. pp. 15&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feitosa G, Bandeira AC, Sampaio DP, Badar&#xf3; R, Brites C. High prevalence of giardiasis and stronglyloidiasis among HIV-infected patients in Bahia, Brazil. The Brazilian Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2001;5:339&#x2013;344.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12010598</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geurden T, Levecke B, Cacci&#xf3; SM, Visser A, De Groote G, Casaert S, Vercruysse J, Claerebout E. Multilocus genotyping of Cryptosporidium and Giardia in non-outbreak related cases of diarrhoea in human patients in Belgium. Parasitology. 2009;136:1161&#x2013;1168.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19631012</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gillon J, Al Thamery D, Ferguson A. Features of small intestinal pathology (epithelial cell kinetics, intraepithelial lymphocytes, disaccharidases) in a primary Giardia muris infection. Gut. 1982;23:498&#x2013;506.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1419712</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7076025</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guk SM, Yong TS, Chai JY. Role of murine intestinal intraepithelial lymphocytes and lamina propria lymphocytes against primary and challenge infections with Cryptosporidium parvum. The Journal of Parasitology. 2003;89:270&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12760640</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haque R, Roy S, Kabir M, Stroup SE, Mondal D, Houpt ER. Giardia assemblage A infection and diarrhea in Bangladesh. The Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2005;192:2171&#x2013;2173.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16288384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hardin JA, Buret AG, Olson ME, Kimm MH, Gall DG. Mast cell hyperplasia and increased macromolecular uptake in an animal model of giardiasis. The Journal of Parasitology. 1997;83:908&#x2013;912.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9379297</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heyworth MF, Carlson JR, Ermak TH. Clearance of Giardia muris infection requires helper/inducer T lymphocytes. The Journal of Experimental Medicine. 1987;165:1743&#x2013;1748.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2188375</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2953846</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Homan WL, Mank TG. Human giardiasis: genotype linked differences in clinical symptomatology. International Journal for Parasitology. 2001;31:822&#x2013;826.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11403774</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Istre GR, Dunlop TS, Gaspard GB, Hopkins RS. Waterborne giardiasis at a mountain resort: evidence for acquired immunity. American Journal of Public Health. 1984;74:602&#x2013;604.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1651646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6721017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Isaac-Renton JL, Lewis LF, Ong CS, Nulsen MF. A second community outbreak of waterborne giardiasis in Canada and serological investigation of patients. The Transactions of the Royal Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene. 1994;88:395&#x2013;399.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7570815</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jim&#xe9;nez JC, Fontaine J, Grzych JM, Dei-Cas E, Capron M. Systemic and mucosal responses to oral administration of excretory and secretory antigens from Giardia intestinalis. Clinical and diagnostic laboratory immunology. 2004;11:152&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC321332</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715563</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jung HC, Eckmann L, Yang SK, Panja A, Fierer J, Morzycka-Wroblewska E, Kagnoff MF. A distinct array of proinflammatory cytokines is expressed in human colon epithelial cells in response to bacterial invasion. The Journal of Clinical Investigation. 1995;95:55&#x2013;65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC295369</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7814646</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamda JD, Singer SM. Phosphoinositide 3-kinase-dependent inhibition of dendritic cell interleukin-12 production by Giardia lamblia. Infection and Immunity. 2009;77:685&#x2013;693.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2632045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19047410</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohli A, Bushen OY, Pinkerton RC, Houpt E, Newman RD, Sears CL, Lima AA, Guerrant RL. Giardia duodenalis assemblage, clinical presentation and markers of intestinal inflammation in Brazilian children. Transactions of the Royal Society of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene. 2008;102:718&#x2013;725.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2963065</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18485429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larocque R, Nakagaki K, Lee P, Abdul-Wahid A, Faubert GM. Oral immunization of BALB/c mice with Giardia duodenalis recombinant cyst wall protein inhibits shedding of cysts. Infection and Immunity. 2003;71:5662&#x2013;5669.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC201086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14500486</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee P, Faubert G. Expression of the Giardia lamblia cyst wall protein 2 in Lactococcus lactis. Microbiology. 2006a;152:1981&#x2013;1990.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16804173</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee P, Faubert GM. Oral immunization of BALB/c mice by intragastric delivery of Streptococcus gordonii-expressing Giardia cyst wall protein 2 decreases cyst shedding in challenged mice. FEMS Microbiology Letters. 2006b;265:225&#x2013;236.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17081198</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Levinson JD, Nastro LJ. Giardiasis with total villous atrophy. Gastroenterology. 1978;74:271&#x2013;275.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">620900</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li E, Zhou P, Petrin Z, Singer SM. Mast cell-dependent control of Giardia lamblia infections in mice. Infection and Immunity. 2004;72:6642&#x2013;6649.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC523017</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15501797</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li E, Zhou P, Singer SM. Neuronal nitric oxide synthase is necessary for elimination of Giardia lamblia infections in mice. The Journal of Immunology. 2006;176:516&#x2013;521.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2585514</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16365445</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li E, Zhao A, Shea-Donohue T, Singer SM. Mast cell-mediated changes in smooth muscle contractility during mouse giardiasis. Infection and Immunity. 2007;75:4514&#x2013;4518.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1951189</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17620354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Little MC, Bell LV, Cliffe LJ, Else KJ. The characterization of intraepithelial lymphocytes, lamina propria leukocytes, and isolated lymphoid follicles in the large intestine of mice infected with the intestinal nematode parasite Trichuris muris. The Journal of Immunology. 2005;175:6713&#x2013;6722.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16272327</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Matowicka-Karna J, Dymicka-Piekarska V, Kemona H. IFN-gamma, IL-5, IL-6 and IgE in patients infected with Giardia intestinalis. Folia Histochemica et Cytobiologica. 2009;47:93&#x2013;97.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19419945</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Merluzzi S, Frossi B, Gri G, Parusso S, Tripodo C, Pucillo C. Mast cells enhance proliferation of B lymphocytes and drive their differentiation toward IgA-secreting plasma cells. Blood. 2010;115:2810&#x2013;2817.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20101023</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moretto M, Weiss LM, Khan IA. Induction of a rapid and strong antigen-specific intraepithelial lymphocyte response during oral Encephalitozoon cuniculi infection. The Journal of Immunology. 2004;172:4402&#x2013;4409.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3086354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15034055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrison HG, McArthur AG, Gillin FD, et al. Genomic minimalism in the early diverging intestinal parasite Giardia lamblia. Science. 2007;317:1921&#x2013;1926.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17901334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nash TE. Antigenic variation in Giardia lamblia and the host's immune response. Philosophical Transactions of The Royal Society of London. Series B. Biological Science. 1997;352:1369&#x2013;1375.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1692022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9355129</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oberhuber G, Kastner N, Stolte M. Giardiasis: a histologic analysis of 567 cases. Scandinavian Journal of Gastroenterology. 1997;32:48&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9018766</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson ME, Morck DW, Ceri H. The efficacy of a Giardia lamblia vaccine in kittens. Canadian Journal of Veterinary Research. 1996;60:249&#x2013;256.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1263845</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8904660</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson ME, Morck DW, Ceri H. Preliminary data on the efficacy of a Giardia vaccine in puppies. The Canadian Veterinary Journal. 1997;38:777&#x2013;779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1576788</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9426944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson ME, Ceri H, Morck DW. Giardia Vaccination. Parasitology Today. 2000;16:213&#x2013;217.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10782082</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olson ME, Hannigan CJ, Gaviller PF, Fulton LA. The use of a Giardia vaccine as an immunotherapeutic agent in dogs. The Canadian Veterinary Journal. 2001;42:865&#x2013;868.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1476664</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11708205</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>P&#xe9;rez PF, Minnaard J, Rouvet M, Knabenhans C, Brassart D, De Antoni GL, Schiffrin EJ. Inhibition of Giardia intestinalis by extracellular factors from Lactobacilli: an in vitro study. Applied and Environmental Microbiology. 2001;67:5037&#x2013;5042.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC93268</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11679323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ringqvist E, Palm JE, Skarin H, Hehl AB, Weiland M, Davids BJ, Reiner DS, Griffiths WJ, Eckmann L, Gillin FD, Sv&#xe4;rd SG. Release of metabolic enzymes by Giardia in response to interaction with intestinal epithelial cells. Molecular and Biochemical Parasitology. 2008;159:85&#x2013;91.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3658456</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18359106</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roberts-Thomson IC, Mitchell GF. Giardiasis in mice. I. Prolonged infections in certain mouse strains and hypothymic (nude) mice. Gastroenterology. 1978;75:42&#x2013;46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">401094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roskens H, Erlandsen SL. Inhibition of in vitro attachment of Giardia trophozoites by mucin. The Journal of Parasitology. 2002;88:869&#x2013;873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12435122</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roxstr&#xf6;m-Lindquist K, Ringqvist E, Palm D, Sv&#xe4;rd S. Giardia lamblia-induced changes in gene expression in differentiated Caco-2 human intestinal epithelial cells. Infection and Immunity. 2005;73:8204&#x2013;8208.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1307045</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16299316</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roxstr&#xf6;m-Lindquist K, Palm D, Reiner D, Ringqvist E, Sv&#xe4;rd SG. Giardia immunity--an update. Trends in Parasitology. 2006;22:26&#x2013;31.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16303332</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salzman NH, Underwood MA, Bevins CL. Paneth cells, defensins, and the commensal microbiota: a hypothesis on intimate interplay at the intestinal mucosa. Seminars in Immunology. 2007;19:70&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17485224</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scott KG, Logan MR, Klammer GM, Teoh DA, Buret AG. Jejunal brush border microvillous alterations in Giardia muris-infected mice: role of T lymphocytes and interleukin-6. Infection and Immunity. 2000;68:3412&#x2013;3418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97613</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10816492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shant J, Ghosh S, Bhattacharyya S, Ganguly NK, Majumdar S. Mode of action of a potentially important excretory-secretory product from Giardia lamblia in mice enterocytes. Parasitology. 2005;131:57&#x2013;69.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16038397</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shant J, Ghosh S, Bhattacharyya S, Ganguly NK, Majumdar S. The alteration in signal transduction parameters induced by the excretory-secretory product from Giardia lamblia. Parasitology. 2004;129:421&#x2013;430.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15521630</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shant J, Bhattacharyya S, Ghosh S, Ganguly NK, Majumdar S. A potentially important excretory-secretory product of Giardia lamblia. Experimental Parasitology. 2002;102:178&#x2013;186.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12856314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer SM, Nash TE. T-cell-dependent control of acute Giardia lamblia infections in mice. Infection and Immunity. 2000a;68:170&#x2013;175.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10603384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singer SM, Nash TE. The role of normal flora in Giardia lamblia infections in mice. The Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2000b;181:1510&#x2013;1512.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10751141</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh A, Janaki L, Petri WA, Jr., Houpt ER. Giardia intestinalis assemblages A and B infections in Nepal. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene. 2009;81:538&#x2013;539.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3412867</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19706929</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith PD. Pathophysiology and immunology of giardiasis. Annual Review of Medicine. 1985;36:295&#x2013;307.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3888054</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snel SJ, Baker MG, Kamalesh V, French N, Learmonth J. A tale of two parasites: the comparative epidemiology of cryptosporidiosis and giardiasis. Epidemiology and infection. 2009;137:1641&#x2013;1650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19393124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Snider DP, Skea D, Underdown BJ. Chronic giardiasis in B-cell-deficient mice expressing the xid gene. Infection and Immunity. 1988;56:2838&#x2013;2842.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC259658</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3262587</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Solaymani-Mohammadi S, Genkinger JM, Loffredo CA, Singer SM. A meta-analysis of the effectiveness of albendazole compared with metronidazole as treatments for infections with Giardia duodenalis. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases. 2010;4:e682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20485492</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>St&#xe4;ger S, Gottstein B, M&#xfc;ller N. Systemic and local antibody response in mice induced by a recombinant peptide fragment from Giardia lamblia variant surface protein (VSP) H7 produced by a Salmonella typhimurium vaccine strain. International Journal for Parasitology. 1997;27:965&#x2013;971.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9292314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stark D, Barratt JL, van Hal S, Marriott D, Harkness J, Ellis JT. Clinical significance of enteric protozoa in the immunosuppressed human population. Clinical Microbiology Reviews. 2009;22:634&#x2013;650.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2772358</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19822892</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein JE, Radecki SV, Lappin MR. Efficacy of Giardia vaccination in the treatment of giardiasis in cats. Journal of American Veterinary Medicine Association. 2003;222:1548&#x2013;1551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12784960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stevens DP, Frank DM, Mahmoud AA. Thymus dependency of host resistance to Giardia muris infection: studies in nude mice. The Journal of Immunology. 1978;120:680&#x2013;682.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">621403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teoh DA, Kamieniecki D, Pang G, Buret AG. Giardia lamblia rearranges F-actin and alpha-actinin in human colonic and duodenal monolayers and reduces transepithelial electrical resistance. The Journal of Parasitology. 2000;86:800&#x2013;806.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10958459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson RC, Reynoldson JA, Mendis AH. Giardia and giardiasis. Advances in Parasitology. 1993;32:71&#x2013;160.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8237618</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thompson RC. Echinococcus, Giardia and Cryptosporidium: observational studies challenging accepted dogma. Parasitology. 2009;136:1529&#x2013;1535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19366481</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Troeger H, Epple HJ, Schneider T, Wahnschaffe U, Ullrich R, Burchard GD, Jelinek T, Zeitz M, Fromm M, Schulzke JD. Effect of chronic Giardia lamblia infection on epithelial transport and barrier function in human duodenum. Gut. 2007;56:328&#x2013;335.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1856804</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16935925</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Uehlinger FD, O'Handley RM, Greenwood SJ, Guselle NJ, Gabor LJ, Van Velsen CM, Steuart RF, Barkema HW. Efficacy of vaccination in preventing giardiasis in calves. Veterinary Parasitology. 2007;146:182&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7126623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17350765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>von Allmen N, Christen S, Forster U, Gottstein B, Welle M, M&#xfc;ller N. Acute trichinellosis increases susceptibility to Giardia lamblia infection in the mouse model. Parasitology. 2006;133:139&#x2013;149.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16677442</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Williamson AL, O'Donoghue PJ, Upcroft JA, Upcroft P. Immune and pathophysiological responses to different strains of Giardia duodenalis in neonatal mice. International Journal for Parasitology. 2000;30:129&#x2013;136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10704595</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P, Li E, Zhu N, Robertson J, Nash T, Singer SM. Role of interleukin-6 in the control of acute and chronic Giardia lamblia infections in mice. Infection and Immunity. 2003;71:1566&#x2013;1568.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC148826</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12595478</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou P, Li E, Shea-Donohue T, Singer SM. Tumour necrosis factor alpha contributes to protection against Giardia lamblia infection in mice. Parasite Immunology. 2007;29:367&#x2013;374.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2443547</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17576366</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>