<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">39328848</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>28</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Print">2307-8960</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print"><Volume>12</Volume><Issue>27</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>26</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>World journal of clinical cases</Title><ISOAbbreviation>World J Clin Cases</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Deciphering the iron enigma: Navigating the complexities of iron metabolism in critical illness.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>6027</StartPage><EndPage>6031</EndPage><MedlinePgn>6027-6031</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12998/wjcc.v12.i27.6027</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Iron is a double-edged sword! Despite being essential for numerous physiological processes of the body, a dysregulated iron metabolism can result in tissue damage, exaggerated inflammatory response, and increased susceptibility to infection with certain pathogens that thrive in iron-rich environment. During sepsis, there is an alteration of iron metabolism, leading to increased transport and uptake into cells. This increase in labile iron may cause oxidative damage and cellular injury (ferroptosis) which progresses as the disease worsens. Critically ill patients are often complicated with systemic inflammation which may contribute to multiple organ dysfunction syndrome or sepsis, a common cause of mortality in intensive care unit. Originally, ferritin was known to play an important role in the hematopoietic system for its iron storage capacity. Recently, its role has emerged as a predictor of poor prognosis in chronic inflammation and critical illnesses. Apart from predicting the disease outcome, serum ferritin can potentially reflect disease activity as well.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9;The Author(s) 2024. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mishra</LastName><ForeName>Anjali</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Holy Family Hospital, Delhi 110025, India.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Juneja</LastName><ForeName>Deven</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Critical Care Medicine, Max Super Speciality Hospital, New Delhi 110017, India. devenjuneja@gmail.com.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016421">Editorial</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>World J Clin Cases</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101618806</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2307-8960</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Critical illness</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ferritin</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iron</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mortality</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sepsis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: The authors declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>20</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>7</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>6</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>27</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>26</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39328848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11326100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v12.i27.6027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Galaris D, Barbouti A, Pantopoulos K. Iron homeostasis and oxidative stress: An intimate relationship. Biochim Biophys Acta Mol Cell Res. 2019;1866:118535.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31446062</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Swelm RPL, Wetzels JFM, Swinkels DW. The multifaceted role of iron in renal health and disease. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2020;16:77&#x2013;98.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31554933</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prakash D. Anemia in the ICU: anemia of chronic disease versus anemia of acute illness. Crit Care Clin. 2012;28:333&#x2013;343, v.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22713609</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litton E, Lim J. Iron Metabolism: An Emerging Therapeutic Target in Critical Illness. Crit Care. 2019;23:81.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6408790</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30850005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boshuizen M, Binnekade JM, Nota B, van de Groep K, Cremer OL, Tuinman PR, Horn J, Schultz MJ, van Bruggen R, Juffermans NP Molecular Diagnosis and Risk Stratification of Sepsis (MARS) Consortium. Iron metabolism in critically ill patients developing anemia of inflammation: a case control study. Ann Intensive Care. 2018;8:56.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5930297</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29717382</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kell DB, Pretorius E. Serum ferritin is an important inflammatory disease marker, as it is mainly a leakage product from damaged cells. Metallomics. 2014;6:748&#x2013;773.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24549403</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rusu D, Blaj M, Ristescu I, Patrascanu E, Gavril L, Lungu O, Siriopol I, Buzincu I, Grigora&#x219; I. Outcome Predictive Value of Serum Ferritin in ICU Patients with Long ICU Stay. Medicina (Kaunas) 2020;57</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7822040</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33375016</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Koperdanova M, Cullis JO. Interpreting raised serum ferritin levels. BMJ. 2015;351:h3692.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26239322</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia PC, Longhi F, Branco RG, Piva JP, Lacks D, Tasker RC. Ferritin levels in children with severe sepsis and septic shock. Acta Paediatr. 2007;96:1829&#x2013;1831.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18001337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kyriazopoulou E, Leventogiannis K, Norrby-Teglund A, Dimopoulos G, Pantazi A, Orfanos SE, Rovina N, Tsangaris I, Gkavogianni T, Botsa E, Chassiou E, Kotanidou A, Kontouli C, Chaloulis P, Velissaris D, Savva A, Cullberg JS, Akinosoglou K, Gogos C, Armaganidis A, Giamarellos-Bourboulis EJ Hellenic Sepsis Study Group. Macrophage activation-like syndrome: an immunological entity associated with rapid progression to death in sepsis. BMC Med. 2017;15:172.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5603161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28918754</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sang L, Teng W, Zhao M, Ding P, Xu X, Wang Y, Cao L. Association between serum ferritin and outcomes in critically ill patients: a retrospective analysis of a large intensive care unit database. Chin Med J (Engl) 2022;135:2634&#x2013;2636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9945381</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35170511</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fang YP, Zhang HJ, Guo Z, Ren CH, Zhang YF, Liu Q, Wang Z, Zhang X. Effect of Serum Ferritin on the Prognosis of Patients with Sepsis: Data from the MIMIC-IV Database. Emerg Med Int. 2022;2022:2104755.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9747303</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36523541</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He L, Guo C, Su Y, Ding N. The relationship between serum ferritin level and clinical outcomes in sepsis based on a large public database. Sci Rep. 2023;13:8677.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10225766</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37248291</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grange C, Lux F, Brichart T, David L, Couturier A, Leaf DE, Allaouchiche B, Tillement O. Iron as an emerging therapeutic target in critically ill patients. Crit Care. 2023;27:475.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10694984</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38049866</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbaspour N, Hurrell R, Kelishadi R. Review on iron and its importance for human health. J Res Med Sci. 2014;19:164&#x2013;174.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3999603</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24778671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bruner AB, Joffe A, Duggan AK, Casella JF, Brandt J. Randomised study of cognitive effects of iron supplementation in non-anaemic iron-deficient adolescent girls. Lancet. 1996;348:992&#x2013;996.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8855856</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brutsaert TD, Hernandez-Cordero S, Rivera J, Viola T, Hughes G, Haas JD. Iron supplementation improves progressive fatigue resistance during dynamic knee extensor exercise in iron-depleted, nonanemic women. Am J Clin Nutr. 2003;77:441&#x2013;448.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12540406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shu J, Hu Y, Yu X, Chen J, Xu W, Pan J. Elevated serum iron level is a predictor of prognosis in ICU patients with acute kidney injury. BMC Nephrol. 2020;21:303.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7382811</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711469</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao R, Liu JH, Qiu ZL. Value of serum iron and urine neutrophil gelatinase-associated lipocalin in predicting the mortality of critically ill patients with sepsis. Clin Invest Med. 2024;47:4&#x2013;12.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38546383</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Patel M, Ramavataram DV. Non transferrin bound iron: nature, manifestations and analytical approaches for estimation. Indian J Clin Biochem. 2012;27:322&#x2013;332.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3477448</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24082455</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tacke F, Nuraldeen R, Koch A, Strathmann K, Hutschenreuter G, Trautwein C, Strnad P. Iron Parameters Determine the Prognosis of Critically Ill Patients. Crit Care Med. 2016;44:1049&#x2013;1058.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26934143</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brissot P, Ropert M, Le Lan C, Lor&#xe9;al O. Non-transferrin bound iron: a key role in iron overload and iron toxicity. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2012;1820:403&#x2013;410.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21855608</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang DC, Zheng BJ, Li J, Yu Y. Iron and ferritin effects on intensive care unit mortality: A meta-analysis. World J Clin Cases. 2024;12:2803&#x2013;2812.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11185325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38899309</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Juneja D, Nasa P, Chanchalani G, Cherian A, Jagiasi B, Javeri Y, Kola V, Kothekar A, Kumar P, Maharaj M, Munjal M, Sivakumar MN, Nikalje A, Nongthombam R, Ray S, Sinha M, Sodhi K, Myatra S. ISCCM position statements on the management of sepsis in resource limited settings. Ind J Crit Care Med</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang G, Shao F, Yuan W, Wu J, Qi X, Gao J, Shao R, Tang Z, Wang T. Predicting sepsis in-hospital mortality with machine learning: a multi-center study using clinical and inflammatory biomarkers. Eur J Med Res. 2024;29:156.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10918942</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38448999</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang Y, Xu W, Yang P, Zhang A. Machine learning for the prediction of sepsis-related death: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak. 2023;23:283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10712076</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38082381</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>