<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39263752</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>30</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>18</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1524-4539</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>150</Volume><Issue>14</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Oct</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Circulation</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Circulation</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Standardized Data Elements for Patients With Acute Pulmonary Embolism: A Consensus Report From the Pulmonary Embolism Research Collaborative.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1140</StartPage><EndPage>1150</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1140-1150</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.067482</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Recent advances in therapy and the promulgation of multidisciplinary pulmonary embolism teams show great promise to improve management and outcomes of acute pulmonary embolism (PE). However, the absence of randomized evidence and lack of consensus leads to tremendous variations in treatment and compromises the wide implementation of new innovations. Moreover, the changing landscape of health care, where quality, cost, and accountability are increasingly relevant, dictates that a broad spectrum of outcomes of care must be routinely monitored to fully capture the impact of modern PE treatment. We set out to standardize data collection in patients with PE undergoing evaluation and treatment, and thus establish the foundation for an expanding evidence base that will address gaps in evidence and inform future care for acute PE. To do so, &gt;100 international PE thought leaders convened in Washington, DC, in April 2022 to form the Pulmonary Embolism Research Collaborative. Participants included physician experts, key members of the US Food and Drug Administration, patient representatives, and industry leaders. Recognizing the multidisciplinary nature of PE care, the Pulmonary Embolism Research Collaborative was created with representative experts from stakeholder medical subspecialties, including cardiology, pulmonology, vascular medicine, critical care, hematology, cardiac surgery, emergency medicine, hospital medicine, and pharmacology. A list of critical evidence gaps was composed with a matching comprehensive set of standardized data elements; these data points will provide a foundation for productive research, knowledge enhancement, and advancement of clinical care within the field of acute PE, and contribute to answering urgent unmet needs in PE management. Evidence produced through the Pulmonary Embolism Research Collaborative, as it is applied to data collection, promises to provide crucial knowledge that will ultimately produce a robust evidence base that will lead to standardization and harmonization of PE management and improved outcomes.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosenfield</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5633-6983</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston (K.R., J.Y.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bowers</LastName><ForeName>Terry R</ForeName><Initials>TR</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-7244-4345</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Medicine, Beaumont University Hospital, Corewell Health, Royal Oak, MI (T.R.B.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barnett</LastName><ForeName>Christopher F</ForeName><Initials>CF</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1095-5794</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, University of California, San Francisco (C.F.B.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>George A</ForeName><Initials>GA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Kentucky HealthCare, University of Kentucky College of Pharmacy, Lexington (G.A.D.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giri</LastName><ForeName>Jay</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8076-0098</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Cardiovascular Medicine Division, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia (J.G.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horowitz</LastName><ForeName>James M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8220-5434</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Langone Health, Department of Medicine, Division of Cardiology, New York University, New York (J.M.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Huisman</LastName><ForeName>Menno V</ForeName><Initials>MV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1423-5348</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Thrombosis and Hemostasis, Leiden University Medical Center, Netherlands (M.V.H., F.A.K.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dutch Thrombosis Network, Leiden, Netherlands (M.V.H., F.A.K.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hunt</LastName><ForeName>Beverley J</ForeName><Initials>BJ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4709-0774</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Hematology, Kings Healthcare Partners, London, United Kingdom (B.J.H.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Keeling</LastName><ForeName>Brent</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiovascular Surgery, Emory University, Atlanta, GA (B.K.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kline</LastName><ForeName>Jeffrey A</ForeName><Initials>JA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7190-3109</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Emergency Medicine, School of Medicine, Wayne State University, Detroit, MI (J.A.K.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Klok</LastName><ForeName>Frederikus A</ForeName><Initials>FA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9961-0754</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine-Thrombosis and Hemostasis, Leiden University Medical Center, Netherlands (M.V.H., F.A.K.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Dutch Thrombosis Network, Leiden, Netherlands (M.V.H., F.A.K.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Konstantinides</LastName><ForeName>Stavros V</ForeName><Initials>SV</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6359-7279</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Thrombosis and Hemostasis, University Medical Center Mainz, Germany (S.V.K.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, Democritus University of Thrace, Greece (S.V.K.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lanno</LastName><ForeName>Michelle T</ForeName><Initials>MT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-7202-1027</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Embolism Response Team Consortium, Nashua, NH (M.T.L., J.L.R.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lookstein</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, NY (R.L.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moriarty</LastName><ForeName>John M</ForeName><Initials>JM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8108-520X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, David Geffen School of Medicine, University of California, Los Angeles (J.M.M.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>N&#xed; &#xc1;inle</LastName><ForeName>Fionnuala</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University College Dublin School of Medicine, Mater Misericordiae University Hospital, Ireland (F.N.A.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Hematology, Royal College of Surgeons in Ireland, Dublin (F.N.A.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reed</LastName><ForeName>Jamie L</ForeName><Initials>JL</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0009-0004-4859-1417</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Pulmonary Embolism Response Team Consortium, Nashua, NH (M.T.L., J.L.R.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosovsky</LastName><ForeName>Rachel P</ForeName><Initials>RP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2392-7365</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Massachusetts General Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston (R.P.R.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Royce</LastName><ForeName>Sara M</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>US Food and Drug Administration, Silver Spring, MD (S.M.R., E.M.W.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Secemsky</LastName><ForeName>Eric A</ForeName><Initials>EA</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3861-3163</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Boston, MA (E.A.S.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sharp</LastName><ForeName>Andrew S P</ForeName><Initials>ASP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9085-8881</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, University Hospital of Wales and Cardiff University (A.S.P.S.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sista</LastName><ForeName>Akhilesh K</ForeName><Initials>AK</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Weill Cornell Medicine, New York, NY (A.K.S.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Roy E</ForeName><Initials>RE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, University of Pittsburgh Medical Center, PA (R.E.S.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wells</LastName><ForeName>Phil</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8657-8326</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Ottawa Hospital, University of Ottawa, Canada (P.W.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston (K.R., J.Y.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whatley</LastName><ForeName>Eleni M</ForeName><Initials>EM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>US Food and Drug Administration, Silver Spring, MD (S.M.R., E.M.W.).</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><CollectiveName>Pulmonary Embolism Research Collaborative (PERC) Attendees</CollectiveName></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>K23 HL150290</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant><Grant><GrantID>U01 HL107352</GrantID><Acronym>HL</Acronym><Agency>NHLBI NIH HHS</Agency><Country>United States</Country></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016446">Consensus Statement</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>12</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Circulation</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>0147763</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0009-7322</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011655" MajorTopicYN="Y">Pulmonary Embolism</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000208" MajorTopicYN="N">Acute Disease</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">data collection</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multidisciplinary care team</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">percutaneous aspiration</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary embolism</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">registry data</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">standardization</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thrombectomy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thrombolytic therapy</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Dr Rosenfield reports consulting fees from Abbott Vascular, Boston Scientific, Contego, Imperative Care, Johnson &amp; Johnson, Biosense Webster, Medtronic, Neptune Medical, and Philips; board membership for the PERT (Pulmonary Embolism Response Team) Consortium; and stock or stock options in Access Vascular, Althea Medical, Auxetics, Contego, Endospan, Imperative Care, Innova Vascular, InspireMD, JanaCare, Magneto, MedAlliance, Neptune Medical, Orchestra, Sealonix, Shockwave, Skydance, Summa Therapeutics, Thrombolex, Vantis Vascular, Vasorum, Viz.ai, and Vumedi. Dr Bowers reports consulting fees from Truvic, Inc, lecture fees from Janssen and Bristol Myers Squibb (BMS)-Pfizer, payment for expert testimony, and participation on Advisory Board of Truvic, Inc. Dr Barnett reports payment for expert testimony. Dr Davis reports travel support for attending the Pulmonary Embolism Research Collaborative meeting. Dr Giri reports research support from Boston Scientific, Inc, and Inari Medical; consulting fees from Boston Scientific, Inc, Cordis, and Abbott Vascular; support for attending meetings from Inari Medical; participation on an advisory board for Angiodynamics, Inc, and Boston Scientific, Inc; participation in leadership at Society for Cardiac Angiography and Intervention and the PERT Consortium; and stock or stock options in Endovascular Engineering. Dr Horowitz reports research support from Inari Medical; consultation and personal lecture fees from Inari Medical and Penumbra, Inc; and support for attending meetings from Inari Medical. Dr Keeling reports consulting fees from Angiodynamics, Inc, Penumbra, Inc, Viz.ai, and Dexcom. Dr Klok reports institutional research support from Bayer, Bristol Myers Squibb, Actelion, Boston Scientific, Inc, Leo Pharma, the Netherlands Organisation for Health Research and Development, the Dutch Thrombosis Association, the Dutch Heart Foundation, and the Horizon Europe program; service on the Board of the Rembrandt Institute of Cardiovascular Science; Chair of the Board of the Dutch Society of Vascular Medicine; nucleus member of the European Society of Cardiology work group on pulmonary circulation and RV function; nucleus member of ISTH SSC diagnostic and predictive variables; Chair of the Board of the Dutch Thrombosis Network; and medical lead, Anticoagulation Clinic Leiden. Dr Konstantinides reports personal and institutional consulting fees from Bayer AG, Daiichi-Sankyo, and Boston Scientific, Inc, and personal lecture fees from Bayer AG, Daiichi-Sankyo, Pfizer&#x2013;Bristol Myers Squibb, and Boston Scientific, Inc. Dr Lookstein reports consulting fees from Penumbra, Inc, Boston Scientific, Inc, Medtronic, Cordis, Becton Dickinson, Abbott Vascular, Neptune Medical, Imperative Care, and Aidoc; payment for expert testimony; participation on advisory boards for Magneto, Boston Scientific, Inc, Medtronic, and Trireme; leadership roles at the PERT Consortium, Critical Limb Ischemia Global Society, and Society of Interventional Radiology; and stock or stock options in Imperative Vascular, Thrombolex, Innova Vascular, and Summa Vascular. Dr Moriarty reports research support from Angiodynamics, Inc, and Penumbra, Inc; consulting fees from Angiodynamics, Inc, Penumbra Inc, Inquis Medical, Innova Vascular, Boston Scientific Inc, Auxetics, and Retriever Medical; and participation on the data safety monitoring board for Penumbra, Inc. Dr N&#xed; &#xc1;inle reports institutional research support from Sanofi, Daiichi-Sankyo, the Irish Health Research Board, Bayer, and Boston Scientific, Inc; patents pending for European Application No. 20166826.6; past member of World Thrombosis Day International Steering Committee; Director at Large and Member, International Network of Venous ThromboEmbolism Research Networks Council; Co-Director, InVite; Co-Founder and member of Executive Committee of Venous Thromboembolism Ireland; Advisory Committee for Human Medicines; member of &#x201c;Preventing Venous Thromboembolism in Hospitals&#x201d; Collaborative Advisory Group; Board Member, Thrombosis Ireland Patient Organization and Charity; and National Lead, Irish Venous Thromboembolism Patient Safety Programme. Dr Rosovsky reports research support from BMS and Janssen; consulting fees from Abbott, BMS, Dova, Inari Medical, Janssen, and Penumbra, Inc; participation on the data safety monitoring board for the Pepper Trial and Harvard Cancer Center; unpaid President-Elect of the PERT Consortium; and unpaid member of ASH Committee on Quality. Dr Secemsky reports research support from NIH/NHLBINIH/NHBLI K23HL150290, Food and Drug Administration, Becton-Dickinson, Boston Scientific, Inc, Cook Medical, Cardiovascular Systems Inc., Laminate Medical, Medtronic, and Philip; consulting fees and personal lecture fees from Abbott, Bayer, Becton-Dickinson, Boston Scientific, Inc, Cook, Cardiovascular Systems Inc., Inari Medical, Medtronic, Philips, Shockwave, and VentureMed; and participation on data safety monitoring boards for LIFE BTK, BIOMIMCS3D, HI-PEITHO, and Transcend. Dr Sharp reports consulting and lecture fees from Medtronic, Boston Scientific, Inc, Philips, Recor Medical, and Penumbra, Inc. Dr Sista reports research support from NIH/NHLBI as principal investigator of U34 and UG3 awards, unpaid participation on data safety monitoring boards for Angiodynamics, Inc, and Thrombolex, Inc; and participation on the Board of Directors for the Society of Interventional Radiology. Dr Wells reports participation on the data safety monitoring board for Anthos. The other authors report no conflicts.</CoiStatement><InvestigatorList><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Abudi</LastName><ForeName>Tami</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Adams</LastName><ForeName>George</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ahmad</LastName><ForeName>Hajira</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ajao</LastName><ForeName>Adebola</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Archard</LastName><ForeName>Erin</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Auger</LastName><ForeName>William</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Avila-Tang</LastName><ForeName>Erika</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barnes</LastName><ForeName>Geoff</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Barnett</LastName><ForeName>Christopher</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bashir</LastName><ForeName>Riyaz</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Benenati</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Berman</LastName><ForeName>Aaron</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bowers</LastName><ForeName>Terry</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Buck</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Burnett</LastName><ForeName>Allison</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cameron</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cavanaugh</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cerminaro</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daniel</LastName><ForeName>Daniel</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Daves</LastName><ForeName>Seanna</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Davis</LastName><ForeName>George</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dicks</LastName><ForeName>Andrew</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Elder</LastName><ForeName>Mahir</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Farrell</LastName><ForeName>Ann</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Garman</LastName><ForeName>Alissa</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gatzemeier</LastName><ForeName>Jamee</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Giannikopoulos</LastName><ForeName>Demetri</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gibson</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Goldberg</LastName><ForeName>Joshua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gonsalves</LastName><ForeName>Carin</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Grodzin</LastName><ForeName>Charles</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gundert</LastName><ForeName>Emily</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gurley</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Heresi</LastName><ForeName>Gustavo</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hlozek</LastName><ForeName>Kristen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hoerst</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Hooks</LastName><ForeName>Brandon</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Horowitz</LastName><ForeName>James</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaber</LastName><ForeName>Wissam</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jaff</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jimenez</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Johnston-Cox</LastName><ForeName>Hillary</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kaatz</LastName><ForeName>Scott</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kolluri</LastName><ForeName>Raghu</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Laird</LastName><ForeName>John</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lake</LastName><ForeName>Leslie</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Langston</LastName><ForeName>Matthew</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Lossef</LastName><ForeName>Steven</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Love</LastName><ForeName>Charles</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mackel</LastName><ForeName>Julie</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Massaro</LastName><ForeName>Lori</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McDaniel</LastName><ForeName>Michael</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>McNally</LastName><ForeName>Vicki</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Merli</LastName><ForeName>Geno</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mina</LastName><ForeName>Bushra</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Monreal</LastName><ForeName>Manuel</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Moores</LastName><ForeName>Lisa</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Morris</LastName><ForeName>Timothy</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nossair</LastName><ForeName>Fadi</ForeName><Initials>F</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Connell</LastName><ForeName>Gregory</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>O'Corragain</LastName><ForeName>Oisin</ForeName><Initials>O</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ouriel</LastName><ForeName>Kenneth</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Parikh</LastName><ForeName>Sahil</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piazza</LastName><ForeName>Gregory</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pohlson</LastName><ForeName>Katie</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Polverini</LastName><ForeName>Peter</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pomeroy</LastName><ForeName>Jordan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pugliese</LastName><ForeName>Steve</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pullin</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Quinto</LastName><ForeName>Brian</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rali</LastName><ForeName>Parth</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rivera-Lebron</LastName><ForeName>Belinda</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robertson</LastName><ForeName>Bill</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rosengard</LastName><ForeName>Bruce</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shaw</LastName><ForeName>Miranda</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Simonton</LastName><ForeName>Chuck</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sista</LastName><ForeName>Akhilesh</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Smith</LastName><ForeName>Roy</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Spyropoulos</LastName><ForeName>Alex</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Srivastava</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sterling</LastName><ForeName>Keith</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Strauss</LastName><ForeName>Jayme</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Taber</LastName><ForeName>Margaret</ForeName><Initials>M</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tapson</LastName><ForeName>Victor</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tawney</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Tu</LastName><ForeName>Thomas</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Valent</LastName><ForeName>Tom</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Venkat</LastName><ForeName>Venkat</ForeName><Initials>V</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walach</LastName><ForeName>Elad</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ward</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ward</LastName><ForeName>Adam</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weinberg</LastName><ForeName>Ido</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wells</LastName><ForeName>Phil</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>West</LastName><ForeName>Frances Mae</ForeName><Initials>FM</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>West</LastName><ForeName>Nick</ForeName><Initials>N</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Whatley</LastName><ForeName>Eleni</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yang</LastName><ForeName>Joanna</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials></Investigator><Investigator ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Yongpravat</LastName><ForeName>Charlie</ForeName><Initials>C</Initials></Investigator></InvestigatorList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>8</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>12</Day><Hour>5</Hour><Minute>3</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39263752</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS2017685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11698503</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.124.067482</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sedhom R, Megaly M, Elbadawi A, Elgendy IY, Witzke CF, Kalra S, George JC, Omer M, Banerjee S, Jaber WA, et al. Contemporary National Trends and Outcomes of Pulmonary Embolism in the United States. Am J Cardiol. 2022;176:132&#x2013;138.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35637010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benjamin EJ, Virani SS, Callaway CW, Chamberlain AM, Chang AR, Cheng S, Chiuve SE, Cushman M, Delling FN, Deo R, et al. Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics-2018 Update: A Report From the American Heart Association. Circulation. 2018;137:e67&#x2013;e492.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29386200</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Heit JA, Spencer FA and White RH. The epidemiology of venous thromboembolism. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2016;41:3&#x2013;14.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4715842</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780736</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith SB, Geske JB, Kathuria P, Cuttica M, Schimmel DR, Courtney DM, Waterer GW and Wunderink RG. Analysis of National Trends in Admissions for Pulmonary Embolism. Chest. 2016;150:35&#x2013;45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6026254</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26905364</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barco S, Mahmoudpour SH, Valerio L, Klok FA, Munzel T, Middeldorp S, Ageno W, Cohen AT, Hunt BJ and Konstantinides SV. Trends in mortality related to pulmonary embolism in the European Region, 2000&#x2013;15: analysis of vital registration data from the WHO Mortality Database. Lancet Respir Med. 2020;8:277&#x2013;287.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31615719</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barco S, Valerio L, Ageno W, Cohen AT, Goldhaber SZ, Hunt BJ, Iorio A, Jimenez D, Klok FA, Kucher N, et al. Age-sex specific pulmonary embolism-related mortality in the USA and Canada, 2000&#x2013;18: an analysis of the WHO Mortality Database and of the CDC Multiple Cause of Death database. Lancet Respir Med. 2021;9:33&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7550106</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33058771</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huisman MV, Barco S, Cannegieter SC, Le Gal G, Konstantinides SV, Reitsma PH, Rodger M, Vonk Noordegraaf A and Klok FA. Pulmonary embolism. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2018;4:18028.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29770793</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gwozdz AM, de Jong CMM, Fialho LS, Likitabhorn T, Sossi F, Jaber PB, H&#xf8;jen AA, Arcelus JI, Auger WR, Ay C, et al. Development of an international standard set of outcome measures for patients with venous thromboembolism: an International Consortium for Health Outcomes Measurement consensus recommendation. Lancet Haematol. 2022;9:e698&#x2013;e706.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36055334</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Jong CMM, Rosovsky RP and Klok FA. Outcomes of venous thromboembolism care: future directions. J Thromb Haemost. 2023;21:1082&#x2013;1089.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36863565</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Office of Minority Health. Homepage. 2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration Communication. Collection of Race and Ethnicity Data in Clinical Trials. 2016.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin KA, McCabe ME, Feinglass J and Khan SS. Racial Disparities Exist Across Age Groups in Illinois for Pulmonary Embolism Hospitalizations. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2020;40:2338&#x2013;2340.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7484333</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32762456</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Phillips AR, Reitz KM, Myers S, Thoma F, Andraska EA, Jano A, Sridharan N, Smith RE, Mulukutla SR and Chaer R. Association Between Black Race, Clinical Severity, and Management of Acute Pulmonary Embolism: A Retrospective Cohort Study. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10:e021818.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8649302</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34431356</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pribish AM, Beyer SE, Krawisz AK, Weinberg I, Carroll BJ and Secemsky EA. Sex differences in presentation, management, and outcomes among patients hospitalized with acute pulmonary embolism. Vasc Med. 2020;25:541&#x2013;548.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8076890</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33203347</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Agarwal S, Clark D 3rd, Sud K, Jaber WA, Cho L and Menon V. Gender Disparities in Outcomes and Resource Utilization for Acute Pulmonary Embolism Hospitalizations in the United States. Am J Cardiol. 2015;116:1270&#x2013;1276.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26341183</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wadhera RK, Secemsky EA, Wang Y, Yeh RW and Goldhaber SZ. Association of Socioeconomic Disadvantage With Mortality and Readmissions Among Older Adults Hospitalized for Pulmonary Embolism in the United States. J Am Heart Assoc. 2021;10:e021117.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8403328</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34210156</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Aujesky D, Obrosky DS, Stone RA, Auble TE, Perrier A, Cornuz J, Roy PM and Fine MJ. Derivation and validation of a prognostic model for pulmonary embolism. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2005;172:1041&#x2013;1046.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2718410</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16020800</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bova C, Sanchez O, Prandoni P, Lankeit M, Konstantinides S, Vanni S and Jimenez D. Identification of intermediate-risk patients with acute symptomatic pulmonary embolism. Eur Respir J. 2014;44:694&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24696111</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>RCoPo L. National early warning score (NEWS): standardising the assessment of acute-illness severity in the NHS &#x2014; report of a working party. Royal College of Physicians. 2012.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bavalia R, Stals MAM, Mulder FI, Bistervels IM, Coppens M, Faber LM, Hendriks SV, Hofstee HMA, Huisman MV, van der Hulle T, et al. Use of the National Early Warning Score for predicting deterioration of patients with acute pulmonary embolism: a post-hoc analysis of the YEARS Study. Emerg Med J. 2023;40:61&#x2013;66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36344240</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rawal A, Ardeshna D, Hesterberg K, Cave B, Ibebuogu UN and Khouzam RN. Is there an optimal &#x201c;door to cath time&#x201d; in the treatment of acute pulmonary embolism with catheter-directed thrombolysis? Ann Transl Med. 2019;7:419.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6787388</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31660318</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pruszczyk P, Klok FA, Kucher N, Roik M, Meneveau N, Sharp ASP, Nielsen-Kudsk JE, Obradovi&#x107; S, Barco S, Giannini F, et al. Percutaneous treatment options for acute pulmonary embolism: a clinical consensus statement by the ESC Working Group on Pulmonary Circulation and Right Ventricular Function and the European Association of Percutaneous Cardiovascular Interventions. EuroIntervention. 2022;18:e623&#x2013;e638.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10241264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36112184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boon G, Barco S, Bertoletti L, Ghanima W, Huisman MV, Kahn SR, Noble S, Prandoni P, Rosovsky RP, Sista AK, et al. Measuring functional limitations after venous thromboembolism: Optimization of the Post-VTE Functional Status (PVFS) Scale. Thrombosis research. 2020;190:45&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32298840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klok FA, Cohn DM, Middeldorp S, Scharloo M, Buller HR, van Kralingen KW, Kaptein AA and Huisman MV. Quality of life after pulmonary embolism: validation of the PEmb-QoL Questionnaire. J Thromb Haemost. 2010;8:523&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20025645</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Delcroix M, Torbicki A, Gopalan D, Sitbon O, Klok FA, Lang I, Jenkins D, Kim NH, Humbert M, Jais X, et al. ERS statement on chronic thromboembolic pulmonary hypertension. Eur Respir J. 2021;57.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33334946</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Humbert M, Kovacs G, Hoeper MM, Badagliacca R, Berger RMF, Brida M, Carlsen J, Coats AJS, Escribano-Subias P, Ferrari P, et al. 2022 ESC/ERS Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of pulmonary hypertension. Eur Heart J. 2022;43:3618&#x2013;3731.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36017548</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morris TA, Fernandes TM and Channick RN. Evaluation of Dyspnea and Exercise Intolerance After Acute Pulmonary Embolism. Chest. 2023;163:933&#x2013;941.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10107059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35792185</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. The Least Burdensome Provisions: Concept and Principles. 2019.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Use of Real-World Evidence to Support Regulatory Decision-Making for Medical Devices. 2017.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Real-World Data: Assessing Registries to Support Regulatory Decision-Making for Drug and Biological Products - Guidance for Industry. 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stein PD, Matta F and Goldman J. Obesity and pulmonary embolism: the mounting evidence of risk and the mortality paradox. Thrombosis research. 2011;128:518&#x2013;523.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22078437</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gauthier K, Kovacs MJ, Wells PS, Le Gal G, Rodger M and investigators R. Family history of venous thromboembolism (VTE) as a predictor for recurrent VTE in unprovoked VTE patients. J Thromb Haemost. 2013;11:200&#x2013;203.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23114022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinides SV, Meyer G, Becattini C, Bueno H, Geersing GJ, Harjola VP, Huisman MV, Humbert M, Jennings CS, Jimenez D, et al. 2019 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism developed in collaboration with the European Respiratory Society (ERS): The Task Force for the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Respir J. 2019;54.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31473594</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Budd AC, Rhodes M, Forster AJ, Noghani P, Carrier M and Wells PS. Prescribing patterns and outcomes of venous thromboembolism prophylaxis in hospitalized medical and cancer patients: Observations from the Ottawa Hospital. Thrombosis research. 2021;197:144&#x2013;152.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33217622</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia D, Akl EA, Carr R and Kearon C. Antiphospholipid antibodies and the risk of recurrence after a first episode of venous thromboembolism: a systematic review. Blood. 2013;122:817&#x2013;824.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23760616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodger MA, Kahn SR, Wells PS, Anderson DA, Chagnon I, Le Gal G, Solymoss S, Crowther M, Perrier A, White R, et al. Identifying unprovoked thromboembolism patients at low risk for recurrence who can discontinue anticoagulant therapy. CMAJ. 2008;179:417&#x2013;426.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2518177</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18725614</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Winter MA, van Es N, Buller HR, Visseren FLJ and Nijkeuter M. Prediction models for recurrence and bleeding in patients with venous thromboembolism: A systematic review and critical appraisal. Thrombosis research. 2021;199:85&#x2013;96.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33485094</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prins MH, Lensing AWA, Prandoni P, Wells PS, Verhamme P, Beyer-Westendorf J, Bauersachs R, Bounameaux H, Brighton TA, Cohen AT, et al. Risk of recurrent venous thromboembolism according to baseline risk factor profiles. Blood Adv. 2018;2:788&#x2013;796.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5894264</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29632234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bates SM and Ginsberg JS. Clinical practice. Treatment of deep-vein thrombosis. N Engl J Med. 2004;351:268&#x2013;277.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15254285</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rosano GMC, Rodriguez-Martinez MA, Spoletini I and Regidor PA. Obesity and contraceptive use: impact on cardiovascular risk. ESC Heart Fail. 2022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9773763</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36103980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schulman S, Kearon C, Subcommittee on Control of Anticoagulation of the S, Standardization Committee of the International Society on T and Haemostasis. Definition of major bleeding in clinical investigations of antihemostatic medicinal products in non-surgical patients. J Thromb Haemost. 2005;3:692&#x2013;694.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15842354</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Quigley N, Gagnon S and Fortin M. Aetiology, diagnosis and treatment of moderate-to-severe haemoptysis in a North American academic centre. ERJ Open Res. 2020;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7569161</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33123556</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meyer G, Vicaut E, Danays T, Agnelli G, Becattini C, Beyer-Westendorf J, Bluhmki E, Bouvaist H, Brenner B, Couturaud F, et al. Fibrinolysis for patients with intermediate-risk pulmonary embolism. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:1402&#x2013;1411.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24716681</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Joint Commission. National Patient Safety Goal for Anticoagulant Therapy. 2018:1&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Konstantinides SV, Meyer G, Becattini C, Bueno H, Geersing GJ, Harjola VP, Huisman MV, Humbert M, Jennings CS, Jimenez D, et al. 2019 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and management of acute pulmonary embolism developed in collaboration with the European Respiratory Society (ERS). Eur Heart J. 2020;41:543&#x2013;603.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504429</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gaddh M and Rosovsky RP. Venous Thromboembolism: Genetics and Thrombophilias. Semin Respir Crit Care Med. 2021;42:271&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33694139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khair RM, Nwaneri C, Damico RL, Kolb T, Hassoun PM and Mathai SC. The Minimal Important Difference in Borg Dyspnea Score in Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2016;13:842&#x2013;849.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5018926</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26974862</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>