<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41046287</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>07</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6831</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>25</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2025</Year><Month>Oct</Month><Day>04</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>BMC oral health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>BMC Oral Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Investigating the relationships among age, occlusal traits, and malocclusion severity in preschool children: a cross-sectional study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1529</StartPage><MedlinePgn>1529</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1529</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12903-025-06718-4</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The aim of this cross-sectional epidemiological study was to explore the associations of age and occlusal factors with the severity of malocclusion among preschool children attending public kindergarten in Tirana, the capital city of Albania.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Clinical data regarding malocclusion traits were collected from October 2023-May 2024 by examining 3- to 6-year-old children who were frequenting 18 randomly selected public kindergartens in Tirana, Albania. A child presenting one of the following altered occlusal traits was recorded as having malocclusion: class II or III canine relationship, distal step (Ds), increased overjet (OVJ), deep overbite (OVB)&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;50% or anterior open bite (AOB), cross bite (CB) either anterior (ACB) or posterior (PCB). The relationships between categorical variables were evaluated with the continuity correction test, Fisher's exact test for 2&#x2009;&#xd7;&#x2009;2 tables and the Pearson chi-square test forr&#xd7;c tables. Binary logistic regression analysis and multivariable logistic regression analysis were used to determine the risk factors affecting a child's malocclusion severity.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 719 children aged 3-6 years (362 females and 357 males) with a mean age of 4.03 years who met the inclusion criteria were included in the study. There were no differences in terms of age or sex. The OVJ frequency and incidence of deep OVB&#x2009;&gt;&#x2009;50% were 15.4%, and deep OVB was more common in the 4-year-old group. The incidence of AOB was 2.6%, which was greater among 5-year-old children. The multivariate regression analysis revealed that children in the 4-year-old group had a 1.62-fold greater risk of developing severe malocclusion (OR (95% CI):1.62 (1.05-2.50); p&#x2009;=&#x2009;0.030). Those with increased OVJ had a 15.15-fold greater risk of developing more severe malocclusion (OR (95% CI):15.15 (5.87-39.09) p&#x2009;&lt;&#x2009;0.001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results of this study demonstrate that an age of 4 years, increased OVJ, a class III canine relationship and primary second molars in Ds are factors associated with the severity of malocclusion among preschool children.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2025. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kongo</LastName><ForeName>Elona</ForeName><Initials>E</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dentistry, Faculty of Medical Science, Albanian University, Tirana, Albania. elona.kongo@albanianuniversity.edu.al.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Emir</LastName><ForeName>Busra</ForeName><Initials>B</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Faculty of Medicine, Izmir Katip Celebi University, Izmir, Turkey.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gribizi</LastName><ForeName>Ilda</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Dentistry, Faculty of Medical Science, Albanian University, Tirana, Albania.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gravina</LastName><ForeName>Beatrice Manes</ForeName><Initials>BM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Independent Researcher, Rome, Italy.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>04</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>BMC Oral Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101088684</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1472-6831</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002675" MajorTopicYN="N">Child, Preschool</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008310" MajorTopicYN="Y">Malocclusion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000367" MajorTopicYN="N">Age Factors</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012720" MajorTopicYN="N">Severity of Illness Index</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Malocclusion</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Occlusal traits</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Preschool children</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declarations. Ethics approval and consent to participate: The study was conducted in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki and approved by the Institutional Review Board (or Ethics Committee) of Albanian University (protocol code: 434;date of approval: 24/05/2023).&#xa0; Written informed consent was obtained from the parents. Consent for publication: Not applicable. Competing interests: The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2025</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>14</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2025</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>29</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>14</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2025</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>4</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41046287</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12497344</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-025-06718-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12903-025-06718-4</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Otsugu M, Sasaki Y, Mikasa Y, Kadono M, Sasaki H, Kato T, Nakano K. Incompetent lip seal and nail biting as risk factors for malocclusion in Japanese preschool children aged 3&#x2013;6 years. BMC Pediatr. 2023;26: 23:532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10601139</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37884943</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Dental Federation. From Strictly Aesthetics to an Integral Part of Oral Health: A Brief History of Orthodontics through the Ages. Available online: https://www.fdiworlddental.org/strictly-aesthetics-integral-part-oral-health-brief-history-orthodonticsthrough-ages</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moraes RB, Knorst JK, Pfeifer AB, Vargas-Ferreira F, Ardenghi TM. Pathways to anterior open bite after changing of pacifier sucking habit in preschool children: a cohort study. Int J Pediatr Dent. 2021;31:278&#x2013;84.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ipd.12725</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32949057</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akta&#x15f; N, Palaz ZH, Akal N. The evaluation of occlusion characteristic and deleterious oral habits in 3-to 5-year-old children. ADO KlinikBilimlerDergisi. 2024;13:303&#x2013;11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongo E, Ga&#xe7;e E, Gravina BM, Gribizi I, Gravina GM. A gender-based comparative study of the risk of malocclusion and occlusal traits among preschool-age children. Ann Stomatol. 2025;5(1):30&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grippaudo MM, Quinzi V, Manai A, Paolantonio EG, Valente F, La Torre G, Marzo G. Orthodontic treatment need and timing: assessment of evolutive malocclusion conditions and associated risk factors. Eur J Paediatr Dent. 2020;3:203&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32893653</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagner Y, Heinrich-Weltzien R. Occlusal characteristics in 3-year-old children&#x2013;results of a birth cohort study. BMC Oral Health. 2015;15:1&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-015-0080-0</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4528377</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26251128</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Au Yeung KS, Shan Z, Sum FH, Wong KW, Lee HM, Yang Y. Association between occlusal features and masticatory function in Hong Kong preschool children: a survey with one-year longitudinal follow-up. BMC Oral Health. 2024;5: 24187.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10845510</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38317203</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou C, Duan P, He H, Song J, Hu M, Liu Y, Liu Y, Guo J, Jin F, Cao Y, Jiang L. Expert consensus on pediatric orthodontic therapies of malocclusions in children. Int J Oral Sci. 2024;16(1):32.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41368-024-00299-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11021504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38627388</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ngan P, Fields H. Orthodontic diagnosis and treatment planning in the primary dentition. ASDC J Dent Child. 1995;1:6225.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7775680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baccetti T, Franchi L, McNamara JA Jr, Tollaro I. Early dentofacial features of class II malocclusion: a longitudinal study from the deciduous through the mixed dentition. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 1997;111:502&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0889-5406(97)70287-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9155809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dos Santos PR, Ambrosano GB, Ambrosano GB, de Castro Meneghim M, Vedovello SA. A longitudinal study of the probability of developing malocclusion in children using a bayesian analysis. Am J Orthod Dentofac Orthop. 2024;25:244.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajodo.2024.05.011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38935005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimberg L, Lennartsson B, S&#xf6;derfeldt B, Bondemark L. Malocclusions in children at 3 and 7 years of age: a longitudinal study. Eur J Orthod. 2013;35:131&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ejo/cjr110</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22045694</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdellatif HM, Sawan N, Alabdulmohsen AM, AlKheraif G, AlKhonin H, Ali A, Elkateb MA. Prevalence and risk indicators of primary dentition malocclusion in Riyadh-Saudi Arabia using a new case definition: a cross-sectional study. Saudi Dent J. 2024;36:60&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.sdentj.2023.09.003</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10874786</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38375380</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ravaghi V, Holmes R, Steele J, et al. The impact of oral conditions on children in England, Wales and Northern Ireland 2013. Br Dent J. 2016. 10.1038/sj.bdj.2016.600.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.bdj.2016.600</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27561577</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ramos-Jorge J, Motta T, Marques LS, Paiva SM, Ramos-Jorge ML. Association between anterior open bite and impact on quality of life of preschool children. Braz Oral Res. 2015;29:46.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1807-3107BOR-2015.vol29.0046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25741623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sakaryali D, Bani ME, Cinar C, Alacam AL. Evaluation of the impact of early childhood caries, traumatic dental injury, and malocclusion on oral health&#x2013;related quality of life for Turkish preschool children and families. Niger J Clin Pract. 2019;22:817&#x2013;23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/njcp.njcp_581_18</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31187768</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongo E, Ga&#x4ab;e E, Gravina GM, et al. Cross-bite and oral habits among Albanian autistic children according to the stages of occlusal development. Sci Rep. 2024b;24:70004&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11325034</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39143117</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pegoraro ND, Santos CM, Colvara BC, Rech RS, Faustino-Silva DD, Hugo FN, Hilgert JB. Prevalence of malocclusion in early childhood and its associated factors in a primary care service in Brazil. Sociedade Brasileira de Fonoaudiologia InCoDAS. 2021;34:e20210007.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9769416</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34816947</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Berneburg M, Zeyher C, Merkle T, M&#xf6;ller M, Schaupp E, G&#xf6;z G. Orthodontic findings in 4-to 6-year-old kindergarten children from Southwest Germany. J Orofac Orthopedics/Fortschritte Der Kieferorthop. 2010;1:71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20503000</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dimberg L, Lennartsson B, Arnrup K, Bondemark L. Prevalence and change of malocclusions from primary to early permanent dentition: a longitudinal study. Angle Orthod. 2015;85(5):728&#x2013;34.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2319/080414-542.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8610411</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25867255</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chang MC, Chen HL, Huang ST, Wang HP, Liu HY. Relationship between orofacial dysfunction and orofacial features, oral function, and eating performance among preschool children. J Dent Sci. 2024;19(2):1044&#x2013;51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jds.2023.06.022</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11010608</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38618088</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishara SE, Warren JJ, Broffitt B, Levy SM. Changes in the prevalence of nonnutritive sucking patterns in the first 8 years of life. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 2006;130:31&#x2013;6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajodo.2004.11.033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16849069</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldens CA, Martins RP, Maciel RR, Vargas-Ferreira F, Kramer PF. Factors associated with the occurrence of distoclusion in the primary dentition: a hierarchical analysis. J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2016;40(1):88&#x2013;93.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17796/1053-4628-40.1.88</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26696113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atasever&#x130;&#x15f;ler AA, Hezenci Y, Bulut M. Prevalence of orthodontic malocclusion in children aged 10&#x2013;12: an epidemiological study. BMC Oral Health. 2025;25(1): 249.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-025-05650-x</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11834610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39966826</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gomes MC, Neves &#xc9;T, Perazzo MF, Martins CC, Paiva SM, Granville-Garcia AF. Association between psychological factors, socio-demographic conditions, oral habits and anterior open bite in five-year-old children. Acta Odontol Scand. 2018;76(8):553&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00016357.2018.1472294</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29764280</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ferro R, Besostri A, Olivieri A, Quinzi V, Scibetta D. Prevalence of cross-bite in a sample of Italian preschoolers. Eur J Paediatr Dent. 2016;17(1):307&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28045319</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khda M, Kiliaridis S, Antonarakis GS. Spontaneous correction and new development of posterior crossbite from the deciduous to the mixed dentition. Eur J Orthod. 2023;3:266&#x2013;70.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ejo/cjac061</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36203363</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Germa A, Cl&#xe9;ment C, Weissenbach M, Heude B, Forhan A, Martin-Marchand L, Bonet M, Vital S, Kaminski M, Nabet C. Early risk factors for posterior crossbite and anterior open bite in the primary dentition. Angle Orthod. 2016;86(5):832&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2319/102715-723.1</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8600852</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26998889</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kirzioglu Z, Simsek S, Yilmaz Y. Longitudinal occlusal changes during the primary dentition and during the passage from primary dentition to mixed dentition among a group of Turkish children. Eur Archives Pediatr Dentistry: Official J Eur Acad Pediatr Dentistry. 2013;14:97&#x2013;103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40368-013-0014-y</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23553007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hegde S, Panwar S, Bolar DR, Sanghavi MB. Characteristics of occlusion in primary dentition of preschool children of Udaipur, India. Eur J Dent. 2012;6:051&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0039-1698930</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3252810</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22229007</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barros SE, Chiqueto K, Janson G, Ferreira E. Factors influencing molar relationship behavior in the mixed dentition. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 2015;148:782&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajodo.2015.05.020</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26522038</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bishara SE, Hoppens BJ, Jakobsen JR, Kohout FJ. Changes in the molar relationship between the deciduous and permanent dentitions: a longitudinal study. Am J Orthod Dentofacial Orthop. 1988;93(1):19&#x2013;28. 10.1016/0889-5406(88)90189-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0889-5406(88)90189-8</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3422119</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>da Silva LP, Gleiser R. Occlusal development between primary and mixed dentitions: a 5-year longitudinal study. J Dent Child. 2008;75:287&#x2013;94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19040816</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kongo E, Gribizi I, Spahiu E, Gravina GM. Prevalence of malocclusion and oral health-related factors among pre-school children in Northern Albania. J Clin Pediatr Dentistry. 2024;148:136.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38548643</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>