<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36449922</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>02</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>13</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1938-808X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>97</Volume><Issue>12</Issue><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Dec</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Academic medicine : journal of the Association of American Medical Colleges</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Acad Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Engaging Retired Physicians as Educators: Motivations and Experiences of Participants in a Novel Educational Program.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>1841</StartPage><EndPage>1846</EndPage><MedlinePgn>1841-1846</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ACM.0000000000004981</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE">Physician retirement has important impacts on medical learners as well as retiring physicians themselves. Retiring physicians take with them a wealth of knowledge, wisdom, and expertise and can feel a loss of identity, lack of fulfillment, and reduced social connectedness after leaving the institution. To address this, a novel educational program providing retired physicians with renewed educational roles was implemented in 2018 within a university-associated pediatric department. This study sought to explore the retired physicians' experiences in this new intergenerational program, including their motivations to reengage as educators after retirement.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">The authors designed this study using qualitative description. Semistructured interviews were conducted in the Department of Pediatrics of McGill University in 2019 with retired physicians who participated in the educational program's inaugural year. Role theory and psychosocial development theory were used to design the interview guide and inform the thematic analysis. Iterative analysis of the interview transcripts was deductive and inductive.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Of the 8 retired physicians who participated in the program's first cohort, 7 participated in this study. Analysis of the data yielded 4 main themes: a challenging shift to retirement, a desire for reengagement after retirement, role dissonance, and gaining by giving. The retired physicians were motivated to engage as educators. Although they experienced some discomfort in their new nonclinical roles, they described their experiences as fulfilling, with benefits such as intellectual stimulation, social connectedness, and a sense of purpose.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Retired physicians' motivations to reengage academically and their experiences contributing to educational activities in this program highlight the importance of supporting physicians during the transition to retirement and establishing formal programs to engage retired physicians as educators.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 by the Association of American Medical Colleges.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Plotnick</LastName><ForeName>Laurie H</ForeName><Initials>LH</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>L.H. Plotnick is associate professor, Department of Pediatrics, and associate member, Institute of Health Sciences Education, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sternszus</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>R. Sternszus is assistant professor, Department of Pediatrics and Institute of Health Sciences Education, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Macdonald</LastName><ForeName>Mary Ellen</ForeName><Initials>ME</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>M.E. Macdonald is associate professor, Faculty of Dentistry, and associate member, Institute of Health Sciences Education, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steinert</LastName><ForeName>Yvonne</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Y. Steinert is professor, Department of Family Medicine and Institute of Health Sciences Education, Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>20</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Acad Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8904605</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1040-2446</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D012179" MajorTopicYN="Y">Retirement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009042" MajorTopicYN="N">Motivation</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010820" MajorTopicYN="Y">Physicians</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004522" MajorTopicYN="N">Educational Status</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D004644" MajorTopicYN="N">Emotions</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>12</Month><Day>3</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day><Hour>14</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36449922</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ACM.0000000000004981</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00001888-202212000-00033</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pong RW, Lemire F, Tepper J. Physician retirement in Canada: What is known and what needs to be done. Paper presented at: 10th International Medical Workforce Conference; March 20&#x2013;24, 2007; Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>College of Family Physicians of Canada, Canadian Medical Association, Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada. National Physician Survey. Ottawa, ON, Canada: Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada; 2004.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dall T, West T, Chakrabarti R, Reynolds R, Iacobucci W. 2018 Update: The Complexities of Physician Supply and Demand: Projections from 2016 to 2030. Washington, DC: Association of American Medical Colleges; March 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>College of Family Physicians of Canada, Canadian Medical Association, Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada. National Physician Survey. Ottawa, ON, Canada: Royal College of Physicians and Surgeons of Canada; 2013.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver MP, Pang NC, Williams SA. &#x201c;Why give up something that works so well?&#x201d;: Retirement expectations among academic physicians. Educ Gerontol. 2015;41:333&#x2013;347.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hall JG. The challenge of developing career pathways for senior academic pediatricians. Pediatr Res. 2005;57:914&#x2013;919.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katlic MR, Coleman J. The aging surgeon. Adv Surg. 2016;50:93&#x2013;103.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dickie GL. Should older family physicians retire? Can Fam Physician. 2012;58:23&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Breytspraak LM, Arnold L, Hogan K. Dimensions of an intergenerational relationship between medical students and mentors-on-aging. J Intergen Relat. 2008;6:131&#x2013;153.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kalisch HR, Coughlin DR, Ballard SM, Lamson A. Old age is a part of living: Student reflections on intergenerational service-learning. Gerontol Geriatr Educ. 2013;34:99&#x2013;113.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dorfman LT, Murty S, Ingram JG, Evans RJ. Incorporating intergenerational service-learning into an introductory gerontology course. J Gerontol Soc Work. 2003;39:219&#x2013;240.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greene D. Reciprocity in two conditions of service-learning. Educ Gerontol. 1998;24:411&#x2013;424.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hernandez CR, Gonzalez MZ. Effects of intergenerational interaction on aging. Educ Gerontol. 2008;34:292&#x2013;305.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stearns J, Everard KM, Gjerde CL, Stearns M, Shore W. Understanding the needs and concerns of senior faculty in academic medicine: Building strategies to maintain this critical resource. Acad Med. 2013;88:1927&#x2013;1933.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>George LK. Sociological perspectives on life transitions. Annu Rev Sociol. 1993;19:353&#x2013;373.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver MP. Critical reflection on physician retirement. Can Fam Physician. 2016;62:783&#x2013;784.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenfield EA, Marks NF. Formal volunteering as a protective factor for older adults&#x2019; psychological well-being. J Gerontol. 2004;59:S258&#x2013;S264.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pushkar D, Reis M, Morros M. Motivation, personality and well-being in older volunteers. Int J Aging Hum Dev. 2002;55:141&#x2013;162.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Morrow-Howell N, Hinterlong J, Rozario P, Tang F. Effects of volunteering on the well-being of older adults. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 2003;58:S137&#x2013;S145.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kinnevy S, Morrow-Howell N. Perceived benefits of intergenerational tutoring. Gerontol Geriatr Educ. 2000;20:3&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Willigen M. Differential benefits of volunteering across the life course. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 2000;55:S308&#x2013;S318.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Knight T, Skouteris H, Townsend M, Hooley M. The act of giving: A systematic review of nonfamilial intergenerational interaction. J Intergen Relat. 2014;12:257&#x2013;278.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beth Johnson Foundation. A Guide to Intergenerational Practice. Stoke-on-Trent, UK: Beth Johnson Foundation; March 2011.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bank I, de Leeuw JP, Lijfering WM, de Bois MHW, Van Woerkom TCAM, Wijnen-Meijer M. Are retired physicians suitable for the coaching of clerks? Int J Med Educ. 2017;8:343&#x2013;350.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carter MAT, Cook K. Adaptation to retirement: Role changes and psychological resources. Career Devel Q. 1995;44:67&#x2013;82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haslam C, Lam BCP, Branscombe NK, et al. Adjusting to life in retirement: The protective role of new group memberships and identification as a retiree. Eur J Work Organ Psychol. 2018;27:822&#x2013;839.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fruge E, Margolin J, Horton T, et al. Defining and managing career challenges for mid-career and senior stage pediatric hematologist/oncologists. Pediatr Blood Cancer. 2010;55:1180&#x2013;1184.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sclafani JD. Psychosocial development. Salkind NJ, ed. In: Encyclopedia of Human Development. Newbury Park, CA: SAGE Publications; 2005.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sandelowski M. Whatever happened to qualitative description? Res Nurs Health. 2000;23:334&#x2013;340.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver MP, Easty LK. Planning for retirement from medicine: A mixed-methods study. CMAJ Open. 2017;5:E123&#x2013;E129.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nowell LS, Norris JM, White DE, Moules NJ. Thematic analysis: Striving to meet the trustworthiness criteria. Int J Qual Methods. 2017;16:1&#x2013;13.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moss AJ, Greenberg H, Dwyer EM, et al. Senior academic physicians and retirement considerations. Prog Cardiovasc Dis. 2013;55:611&#x2013;615.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sloane PD, Cohen LW, Konrad TR, Williams CS, Schumacher JG, Zimmerman S. Brief communication: Physician interest in volunteer service during retirement. Ann Intern Med. 2008;149:317&#x2013;322.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehlman K, Ligon M. The application of a generativity model for older adults. Int J Aging Hum Dev. 2012;74:331&#x2013;344.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cheng ST. Generativity in later life: Perceived respect from younger generations as a determinant of goal disengagement and psychological well-being. J Gerontol B Psychol Sci Soc Sci. 2009;64:45&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kotre J. Outliving the Self: Generativity and the Interpretation of Lives. Baltimore, MD: Johns Hopkins University Press; 1984.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Virshup B, Coombs RH. Physicians&#x2019; adjustment to retirement. West J Med. 1993;158:142&#x2013;144.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sataloff RT. Physicians and retirement. Ear Nose Throat J. 2019;98:394&#x2013;395.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Atchley RA. Continuity theory of normal aging. Gerontologist. 1989;29:183&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Silver MP, Hamilton AD, Biswas A, Warrick NI. A systematic review of physician retirement planning. Hum Res Health. 2016;14:67.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>