<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36335794</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-2828</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>90</Volume><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>Nov</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Ultrasonics sonochemistry</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Ultrason Sonochem</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Quantifying OH radical generation in hydrodynamic cavitation via coumarin dosimetry: Influence of operating parameters and cavitation devices.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>106207</StartPage><MedlinePgn>106207</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">106207</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ultsonch.2022.106207</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1350-4177(22)00303-0</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Hydrodynamic cavitation (HC) has been extensively investigated for effluent treatment applications. Performance of HC devices or processes is often reported in terms of degradation of organic pollutants rather than quantification of hydroxyl (OH) radicals. In this study, generation of OH radicals in vortex based cavitation device using coumarin dosimetry was quantified. Coumarin was used as the chemical probe with an initial concentration of 100&#xa0;&#xb5;M (15&#xa0;ppm). Generation of OH radicals was quantified by analysing generated single hydroxylated products. The influence of operating parameters such as pH and type of acid used to adjust pH, dissolved oxygen, and inlet and outlet pressures was investigated. Acidic pH was found to be more conducive for generating OH radicals and therefore subsequent experiments were performed at pH of 3. Sulphuric acid was found to be more than three times effective than hydrochloric acid in generating OH radicals. Effect of initial levels of dissolved oxygen was found to influence OH radical generation. Performance of vortex based cavitation device was then compared with other commonly used cavitation devices based on orifice and venturi. The vortex based cavitation device was found to outperform the orifice and venturi based devices in terms of initial per-pass factor. Influence of device scale (nominal flow rate through the device) on performance was then evaluated. The results presented for these devices unambiguously quantifies their cavitational performance. The presented results will be useful for evaluating computational models and stimulate further development of predictive computational models in this challenging area.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2022 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>De-Nasri</LastName><ForeName>Sebastien J</ForeName><Initials>SJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Sarvothaman</LastName><ForeName>Varaha P</ForeName><Initials>VP</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Nagarajan</LastName><ForeName>Sanjay</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, UK; Sustainable Environment Research Centre, University of South Wales, Pontypridd CF37 1DL, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Manesiotis</LastName><ForeName>Panagiotis</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Robertson</LastName><ForeName>Peter K J</ForeName><Initials>PKJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, UK.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ranade</LastName><ForeName>Vivek V</ForeName><Initials>VV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Queen's University Belfast, Belfast BT9 5AG, UK; Bernal Institute, University of Limerick, Limerick, Ireland. Electronic address: Vivek.Ranade@ul.ie.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Netherlands</Country><MedlineTA>Ultrason Sonochem</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9433356</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1350-4177</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>BBX060AN9V</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D006861">Hydrogen Peroxide</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>3352-57-6</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017665">Hydroxyl Radical</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D003374">Coumarins</NameOfSubstance></Chemical><Chemical><RegistryNumber>S88TT14065</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D010100">Oxygen</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D057446" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hydrodynamics</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006861" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hydrogen Peroxide</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017665" MajorTopicYN="N">Hydroxyl Radical</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003374" MajorTopicYN="N">Coumarins</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010100" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Advanced oxidation process</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dosimetry</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hydrodynamic cavitation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vortex diode</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: Vivek Ranade reports a relationship with VIVIRA Process Technologies that includes: board membership.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>1</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>18</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>25</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>19</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2022</Year><Month>10</Month><Day>19</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36335794</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9641053</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultsonch.2022.106207</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S1350-4177(22)00303-0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Sarvothaman V.P., Simpson A., Ranade V.V. Comparison of hydrodynamic cavitation devices based on linear and swirling flows: degradation of dichloroaniline in water. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2020;59(30):13841&#x2013;13847. doi: 10.1021/acs.iecr.0c02125.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.0c02125</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nagarajan S., Ranade V.V. Pre-treatment of distillery spent wash (vinasse) with vortex based cavitation and its influence on biogas generation. Bioresour. Technol. Reports. 2020;11</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mane M.B., Bhandari V.M., Balapure K., Ranade V.V. A novel hybrid cavitation process for enhancing and altering rate of disinfection by use of natural oils derived from plants. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2020;61</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31675658</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson A., Ranade V.V. 110th Anniversary: Comparison of cavitation devices based on linear and swirling flows: hydrodynamic characteristics. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2019;58(31):14488&#x2013;14509. doi: 10.1021/acs.iecr.9b02757.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.9b02757</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gogate P.R., Pandit A.B. Engineering design methods for cavitation reactors II: hydrodynamic cavitation. AIChE J. 2000;46(8):1641&#x2013;1649.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranade V.V., Kulkarni A.A., Bhandari V.M. Vortex diodes as effluent treatment devices. Google Patents. 2016</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sivakumar M., Pandit A.B. Wastewater treatment: a novel energy efficient hydrodynamic cavitational technique. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2002;9(3):123&#x2013;131.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12154685</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mishra K.P., Gogate P.R. Intensification of degradation of Rhodamine B using hydrodynamic cavitation in the presence of additives. Sep. Purif. Technol. 2010;75(3):385&#x2013;391.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>P.H.L. Alves, P.d.S.L. Silva, D.C. Ferreira, J.C.d.S.I. Gon&#xe7;alves, COD removal from sucrose solution using hydrodynamic cavitation and hydrogen peroxide: a comparison between Venturi device and orifice plate, RBRH 24 (2019).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter J., Badve M., Rajoriya S., George S., Saharan V.K., Pandit A.B. Hydrodynamic cavitation: an emerging technology for the intensification of various chemical and physical processes in a chemical process industry. Rev. Chem. Eng. 2017;33(5):433&#x2013;468.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mancuso G., Langone M., Andreottola G. A critical review of the current technologies in wastewater treatment plants by using hydrodynamic cavitation process: principles and applications. J. Environ. Health Sci. Eng. 2020;18(1):311&#x2013;333.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7203374</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32399243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ranade V.V., Prasad Sarvothaman V., Simpson A., Nagarajan S. Scale-up of vortex based hydrodynamic cavitation devices: a case of degradation of di-chloro aniline in water. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2021;70 doi: 10.1016/j.ultsonch.2020.105295.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultsonch.2020.105295</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786610</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32791465</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zupanc M., Petkov&#x161;ek M., Zevnik J., Kozmus G., &#x160;mid A., Dular M. Anomalies detected during hydrodynamic cavitation when using salicylic acid dosimetry to measure radical production. Chem. Eng. J. 2020;396</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Amin L.P., Gogate P.R., Burgess A.E., Bremner D.H. Optimization of a hydrodynamic cavitation reactor using salicylic acid dosimetry. Chem. Eng. J. 2010;156(1):165&#x2013;169.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Arrojo S., Nerin C., Benito Y. Application of salicylic acid dosimetry to evaluate hydrodynamic cavitation as an advanced oxidation process. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2007;14(3):343&#x2013;349.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17027314</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iida Y., Yasui K., Tuziuti T., Sivakumar M. Sonochemistry and its dosimetry. Microchem. J. 2005;80(2):159&#x2013;164.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sutkar V.S., Gogate P.R. Design aspects of sonochemical reactors: techniques for understanding cavitational activity distribution and effect of operating parameters. Chem. Eng. J. 2009;155(1&#x2013;2):26&#x2013;36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>De-Nasri S.J., Nagarajan S., Robertson P.K.J., Ranade V.V. Quantification of hydroxyl radicals in photocatalysis and acoustic cavitation: Utility of coumarin as a chemical probe. Chem. Eng. J. 2020;127560</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarvothaman V.P., Nagarajan S., Ranade V.V. Treatment of solvent-contaminated water using vortex-based cavitation: influence of operating pressure drop, temperature, aeration, and reactor scale. Ind Eng Chem Res. 2018;57(28):9292&#x2013;9304. doi: 10.1021/acs.iecr.8b01688.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.iecr.8b01688</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capocelli M., Musmarra D., Prisciandaro M., Lancia A. Chemical effect of hydrodynamic cavitation: simulation and experimental comparison. AIChE J. 2014;60(7):2566&#x2013;2572.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pawar S.K., Mahulkar A.V., Pandit A.B., Roy K., Moholkar V.S. Sonochemical effect induced by hydrodynamic cavitation: Comparison of venturi/orifice flow geometries. AIChE J. 2017;63(10):4705&#x2013;4716.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>V.V. Ranade, Bhandari, V.M., Nagarajan, S., Sarvothaman, V.P., and Simpson, A.T., Hydrodynamic Cavitation: Devices, Design and Applications, Wiley-VCH2022.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Capocelli M., Prisciandaro M., Lancia A., Musmarra D. Hydrodynamic cavitation of p-nitrophenol: a theoretical and experimental insight. Chem. Eng. J. 2014;254:1&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>G&#x105;gol M., Cako E., Fedorov K., Soltani R.D.C., Przyjazny A., Boczkaj G. Hydrodynamic cavitation based advanced oxidation processes: Studies on specific effects of inorganic acids on the degradation effectiveness of organic pollutants. J. Mol. Liq. 2020;307</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rooze J., Rebrov E.V., Schouten J.C., Keurentjes J.T.F. Dissolved gas and ultrasonic cavitation&#x2013;a review. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2013;20(1):1&#x2013;11.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22705074</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>S.J. De-Nasri, S. Nagarajan, P.K.J. Robertson, V.V. Ranade, , Quantification of hydroxyl radicals in photocatalysis and acoustic cavitation: Utility of coumarin as a chemical probe, Elsevier, 2021, p. 127560.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson A., Ranade V.V. Modelling of hydrodynamic cavitation with orifice: Influence of different orifice designs. Chem. Eng. Res. Des. 2018;136:698&#x2013;711.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson A., Ranade V.V. Modeling hydrodynamic cavitation in venturi: Influence of venturi configuration on inception and extent of cavitation. AIChE J. 2019;65(1):421&#x2013;433.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Simpson A., Ranade V.V. Flow characteristics of vortex based cavitation devices: Computational investigation on influence of operating parameters and scale. AIChE J. 2019;65(9):e16675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarvothaman V.P., Simpson A.T., Ranade V.V. Modelling of vortex based hydrodynamic cavitation reactors. Chem. Eng. J. 2019;377</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Didenko Y.T., McNamara W.B., Suslick K.S. Hot spot conditions during cavitation in water. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1999;121(24):5817&#x2013;5818.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bagal M.V., Gogate P.R. Degradation of diclofenac sodium using combined processes based on hydrodynamic cavitation and heterogeneous photocatalysis. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2014;21(3):1035&#x2013;1043.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24262760</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Musmarra D., Prisciandaro M., Capocelli M., Karatza D., Iovino P., Canzano S., Lancia A. Degradation of ibuprofen by hydrodynamic cavitation: Reaction pathways and effect of operational parameters. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2016;29:76&#x2013;83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26584987</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang X., Jia J., Wang Y. Combination of photocatalysis with hydrodynamic cavitation for degradation of tetracycline. Chem. Eng. J. 2017;315:274&#x2013;282.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Srinivas N.S., Ramanan K.K., Rayappan J.B.B., Kaleekkal N.J., Jegadeesan G.B. Coumarin as a chemical probe to evaluate efficiency of vortex&#x2013;based hydrodynamic cavitation process. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2022;10(1)</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lutze H.V., Kerlin N., Schmidt T.C. Sulfate radical-based water treatment in presence of chloride: formation of chlorate, inter-conversion of sulfate radicals into hydroxyl radicals and influence of bicarbonate. Water Res. 2015;72:349&#x2013;360.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25455043</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>M.T. Ashby, Hypothiocyanite, Advances in inorganic chemistry, Elsevier2012, pp. 263-303.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sukhatskiy Y.V., Znak Z.O., Zin O.I. Cavitation and its combinations with other advanced oxidation processes in phenol wastewater treatment: a review. Voprosy khimii i khimicheskoi tekhnologii. 2020;4:16&#x2013;30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sarvothaman V.P. Queen's University Belfast, Queen's University Belfast; 2020. Hydrodynamic Cavitation for Effluent Treatment: Using Vortex-based Cavitation Devices. PhD Thesis.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suslick K.S., Mdleleni M.M., Ries J.T. Chemistry induced by hydrodynamic cavitation. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 1997;119(39):9303&#x2013;9304. doi: 10.1021/ja972171i.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/ja972171i</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu C.D., Zhang Z.L., Wu Y., Wang L., Chen L.J. Effects of operating parameters and additives on degradation of phenol in water by the combination of H2O2 and hydrodynamic cavitation. Desalin. Water Treat. 2015;53(2):462&#x2013;468. doi: 10.1080/19443994.2013.846234.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19443994.2013.846234</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Suryawanshi P.G., Bhandari V.M., Sorokhaibam L.G., Ruparelia J.P., Ranade V.V. Solvent degradation studies using hydrodynamic cavitation. Environ. Prog. Sustainable Energy. 2018;37(1):295&#x2013;304.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Soyama H., Hoshino J. Enhancing the aggressive intensity of hydrodynamic cavitation through a Venturi tube by increasing the pressure in the region where the bubbles collapse. AIP Adv. 2016;6(4) doi: 10.1063/1.4947572.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.4947572</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Angaji M.T., Ghiaee R. Decontamination of unsymmetrical dimethylhydrazine waste water by hydrodynamic cavitation-induced advanced Fenton process. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2015;23:257&#x2013;265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25262345</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rajoriya S., Bargole S., Saharan V.K. Degradation of reactive blue 13 using hydrodynamic cavitation: Effect of geometrical parameters and different oxidizing additives. Ultrason. Sonochem. 2017;37:192&#x2013;202.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28427623</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Carpenter J., George S., Saharan V.K. Low pressure hydrodynamic cavitating device for producing highly stable oil in water emulsion: Effect of geometry and cavitation number. Chem. Eng. Process. Process Intensif. 2017;116:97&#x2013;104. doi: 10.1016/j.cep.2017.02.013.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cep.2017.02.013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Saharan V.K., Pandit A.B., Satish Kumar P.S., Anandan S. Hydrodynamic cavitation as an advanced oxidation technique for the degradation of acid red 88 dye. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2012;51(4):1981&#x2013;1989.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holkar C.R., Jadhav A.J., Pinjari D.V., Pandit A.B. Cavitationally driven transformations: a technique of process intensification. Ind. Eng. Chem. Res. 2019;58(15):5797&#x2013;5819.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>