<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Manual"><PMID Version="1">30969181</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2020</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>15</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2329-9185</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>4</Issue><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>JBJS reviews</Title><ISOAbbreviation>JBJS Rev</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Proximal Junctional Kyphosis: A Pediatric and Adult Spinal Deformity Surgery Dilemma.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e4</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e4</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2106/JBJS.RVW.18.00059</ELocationID><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mika</LastName><ForeName>Aleksander P</ForeName><Initials>AP</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5260-4506</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Rochester, Rochester, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mesfin</LastName><ForeName>Addisu</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0076-4185</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Rochester, Rochester, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Rubery</LastName><ForeName>Paul T</ForeName><Initials>PT</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2576-3242</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Rochester, Rochester, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Molinari</LastName><ForeName>Robert</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6947-7454</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Rochester, Rochester, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kebaish</LastName><ForeName>Khaled M</ForeName><Initials>KM</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2186-2166</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, The Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Menga</LastName><ForeName>Emmanuel N</ForeName><Initials>EN</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5512-1713</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, University of Rochester, Rochester, New York.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>JBJS Rev</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101674872</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2329-9185</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017408" MajorTopicYN="N">Guidelines as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D007738" MajorTopicYN="N">Kyphosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D011183" MajorTopicYN="N">Postoperative Complications</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiopathology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013123" MajorTopicYN="Y">Spinal Fusion</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2020</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>16</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>11</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30969181</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/JBJS.RVW.18.00059</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">01874474-201904000-00008</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Daniels AH, DePasse JM, Eberson CP, Lucas PR, Palumbo MA. Adult spinal deformity: contemporary treatment and patient outcomes. R I Med J (2013). 2015 Jul 1;98(7):32-41.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lowe TG, Kasten MD. An analysis of sagittal curves and balance after Cotrel-Dubousset instrumentation for kyphosis secondary to Scheuermann&#x2019;s disease. A review of 32 patients. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 1994 Aug 1;19(15):1680-5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glattes RC, Bridwell KH, Lenke LG, Kim YJ, Rinella A, Edwards C 2nd. Proximal junctional kyphosis in adult spinal deformity following long instrumented posterior spinal fusion: incidence, outcomes, and risk factor analysis. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2005 Jul 15;30(14):1643-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Helgeson MD, Shah SA, Newton PO, Clements DH 3rd, Betz RR, Marks MC, Bastrom T; Harms Study Group. Evaluation of proximal junctional kyphosis in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis following pedicle screw, hook, or hybrid instrumentation. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2010 Jan 15;35(2):177-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bridwell KH, Lenke LG, Cho SK, Pahys JM, Zebala LP, Dorward IG, Cho W, Baldus C, Hill BW, Kang MM. Proximal junctional kyphosis in primary adult deformity surgery: evaluation of 20 degrees as a critical angle. Neurosurgery. 2013 Jun;72(6):899-906.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart R, McCarthy I, O&#x2bc;Brien M, Bess S, Line B, Adjei OB, Burton D, Gupta M, Ames C, Deviren V, Kebaish K, Shaffrey C, Wood K, Hostin R; International Spine Study Group. Identification of decision criteria for revision surgery among patients with proximal junctional failure after surgical treatment of spinal deformity. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2013 Sep 1;38(19):E1223-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart RA, Rastegar F, Contag A, Kane M, Daniels A, Klineberg E, Eastlack R, Smith JS, Hostin R, Hamilton DK, Gum JL, Burton DC, Sheer JK, Ames C, Schwab F, Lafage V, Bess S, Shaffrey C, Kebaish K; International Spine Study Group. Inter- and intra-rater reliability of the Hart-ISSG proximal junctional failure severity scale. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2018 Apr 15;43(8):E461-7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hart RA, Prendergast MA, Roberts WG, Nesbit GM, Barnwell SL. Proximal junctional acute collapse cranial to multi-level lumbar fusion: a cost analysis of prophylactic vertebral augmentation. Spine J. 2008 Nov-Dec;8(6):875-81. Epub 2008 Apr 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab F, Lafage V, Boyce R, Skalli W, Farcy JP. Gravity line analysis in adult volunteers: age-related correlation with spinal parameters, pelvic parameters, and foot position. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2006 Dec 1;31(25):E959-67.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer S, Lenke LG, Nemani VM, Fu M, Shifflett GD, Albert TJ, Sides BA, Metz LN, Cunningham ME, Kim HJ. Variations in occipitocervical and cervicothoracic alignment parameters based on age: a prospective study of asymptomatic volunteers using full-body radiographs. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2016 Dec 1;41(23):1837-44.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee GA, Betz RR, Clements DH 3rd, Huss GK. Proximal kyphosis after posterior spinal fusion in patients with idiopathic scoliosis. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 1999 Apr 15;24(8):795-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YJ, Lenke LG, Bridwell KH, Kim J, Cho SK, Cheh G, Yoon J. Proximal junctional kyphosis in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis after 3 different types of posterior segmental spinal instrumentation and fusions: incidence and risk factor analysis of 410 cases. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2007 Nov 15;32(24):2731-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YJ, Bridwell KH, Lenke LG, Glattes CR, Rhim S, Cheh G. Proximal junctional kyphosis in adult spinal deformity after segmental posterior spinal instrumentation and fusion: minimum five-year follow-up. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2008 Sep 15;33(20):2179-84.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim YJ, Bridwell KH, Lenke LG, Kim J, Cho SK. Proximal junctional kyphosis in adolescent idiopathic scoliosis following segmental posterior spinal instrumentation and fusion: minimum 5-year follow-up. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2005 Sep 15;30(18):2045-50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollenbeck SM, Glattes RC, Asher MA, Lai SM, Burton DC. The prevalence of increased proximal junctional flexion following posterior instrumentation and arthrodesis for adolescent idiopathic scoliosis. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2008 Jul 1;33(15):1675-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lonner B, Yoo A, Terran JS, Sponseller P, Samdani A, Betz R, Shuffelbarger H, Shah SA, Newton P. Effect of spinal deformity on adolescent quality of life: comparison of operative Scheuermann kyphosis, adolescent idiopathic scoliosis, and normal controls. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2013 May 20;38(12):1049-55.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Yagi M, Nyugen J, Cunningham ME, Boachie-Adjei O. Combined anterior-posterior surgery is the most important risk factor for developing proximal junctional kyphosis in idiopathic scoliosis. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2012 Jun;470(6):1633-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hostin R, McCarthy I, O&#x2bc;Brien M, Bess S, Line B, Boachie-Adjei O, Burton D, Gupta M, Ames C, Deviren V, Kebaish K, Shaffrey C, Wood K, Hart R; International Spine Study Group. Incidence, mode, and location of acute proximal junctional failures after surgical treatment of adult spinal deformity. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2013 May 20;38(12):1008-15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagi M, Rahm M, Gaines R, Maziad A, Ross T, Kim HJ, Kebaish K, Boachie-Adjei O; Complex Spine Study Group. Characterization and surgical outcomes of proximal junctional failure in surgically treated patients with adult spinal deformity. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2014 May 1;39(10):E607-14.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Iyer S. Proximal junctional kyphosis. J Am Acad Orthop Surg. 2016 May;24(5):318-26.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagi M, Akilah KB, Boachie-Adjei O. Incidence, risk factors and classification of proximal junctional kyphosis: surgical outcomes review of adult idiopathic scoliosis. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2011 Jan 1;36(1):E60-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yagi M, King AB, Boachie-Adjei O. Incidence, risk factors, and natural course of proximal junctional kyphosis: surgical outcomes review of adult idiopathic scoliosis. Minimum 5 years of follow-up. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2012 Aug 1;37(17):1479-89.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wu CH, Yang KC, Chang HH, Yen JF, Tsai KS, Huang KC. Sarcopenia is related to increased risk for low bone mineral density. J Clin Densitom. 2013 Jan-Mar;16(1):98-103. Epub 2012 Sep 10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hassanzadeh H, Gupta S, Jain A, El Dafrawy MH, Skolasky RL, Kebaish KM. Type of anchor at the proximal fusion level has a significant effect on the incidence of proximal junctional kyphosis and outcome in adults after long posterior spinal fusion. Spine Deform. 2013 Jul;1(4):299-305. Epub 2013 Aug 2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ha Y, Maruo K, Racine L, Schairer WW, Hu SS, Deviren V, Burch S, Tay B, Chou D, Mummaneni PV, Ames CP, Berven SH. Proximal junctional kyphosis and clinical outcomes in adult spinal deformity surgery with fusion from the thoracic spine to the sacrum: a comparison of proximal and distal upper instrumented vertebrae. J Neurosurg Spine. 2013 Sep;19(3):360-9. Epub 2013 Jul 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab F, Ungar B, Blondel B, Buchowski J, Coe J, Deinlein D, DeWald C, Mehdian H, Shaffrey C, Tribus C, Lafage V. Scoliosis Research Society-Schwab adult spinal deformity classification: a validation study. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2012 May 20;37(12):1077-82.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mendoza-Lattes S, Ries Z, Gao Y, Weinstein SL. Proximal junctional kyphosis in adult reconstructive spine surgery results from incomplete restoration of the lumbar lordosis relative to the magnitude of the thoracic kyphosis. Iowa Orthop J. 2011;31:199-206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Iyer S, Lenke LG, Nemani VM, Albert TJ, Sides BA, Metz LN, Cunningham ME, Kim HJ. Variations in sagittal alignment parameters based on age: a prospective study of asymptomatic volunteers using full-body radiographs. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2016 Dec 1;41(23):1826-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang J, Zhao Y, Shen B, Wang C, Li M. Risk factor analysis of proximal junctional kyphosis after posterior fusion in patients with idiopathic scoliosis. Injury. 2010 Apr;41(4):415-20. Epub 2010 Jan 27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yilgor C, Sogunmez N, Boissiere L, Yavuz Y, Obeid I, Kleinst&#xfc;ck F, P&#xe9;rez-Grueso FJS, Acaroglu E, Haddad S, Mannion AF, Pellise F, Alanay A; European Spine Study Group (ESSG). Global alignment and proportion (GAP) score: development and validation of a new method of analyzing spinopelvic alignment to predict mechanical complications after adult spinal deformity surgery. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2017 Oct 4;99(19):1661-72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rhee JM, Bridwell KH, Won DS, Lenke LG, Chotigavanichaya C, Hanson DS. Sagittal plane analysis of adolescent idiopathic scoliosis: the effect of anterior versus posterior instrumentation. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2002 Nov 1;27(21):2350-6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Bridwell KH, Lenke LG, Park MS, Ahmad A, Song KS, Piyaskulkaew C, Hershman S, Fogelson J, Mesfin A. Proximal junctional kyphosis results in inferior SRS pain subscores in adult deformity patients. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2013 May 15;38(11):896-901.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schreiber JJ, Anderson PA, Rosas HG, Buchholz AL, Au AG. Hounsfield units for assessing bone mineral density and strength: a tool for osteoporosis management. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2011 Jun 1;93(11):1057-63.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meredith DS, Schreiber JJ, Taher F, Cammisa FP Jr, Girardi FP. Lower preoperative Hounsfield unit measurements are associated with adjacent segment fracture after spinal fusion. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2013 Mar 1;38(5):415-8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kohan EM, Nemani VM, Hershman S, Kang DG, Kelly MP. Lumbar computed tomography scans are not appropriate surrogates for bone mineral density scans in primary adult spinal deformity. Neurosurg Focus. 2017 Dec;43(6):E4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Martin CT, Skolasky RL, Mohamed AS, Kebaish KM. Preliminary results of the effect of prophylactic vertebroplasty on the incidence of proximal junctional complications after posterior spinal fusion to the low thoracic spine. Spine Deform. 2013 Mar;1(2):132-8. Epub 2013 Mar 15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kebaish KM, Martin CT, O&#x2019;Brien JR, LaMotta IE, Voros GD, Belkoff SM. Use of vertebroplasty to prevent proximal junctional fractures in adult deformity surgery: a biomechanical cadaveric study. Spine J. 2013 Dec;13(12):1897-903. Epub 2013 Oct 4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ghobrial GM, Eichberg DG, Kolcun JPG, Madhavan K, Lebwohl NH, Green BA, Gjolaj JP. Prophylactic vertebral cement augmentation at the uppermost instrumented vertebra and rostral adjacent vertebra for the prevention of proximal junctional kyphosis and failure following long-segment fusion for adult spinal deformity. Spine J. 2017 Oct;17(10):1499-505. Epub 2017 May 15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raman T, Miller E, Martin CT, Kebaish KM. The effect of prophylactic vertebroplasty on the incidence of proximal junctional kyphosis and proximal junctional failure following posterior spinal fusion in adult spinal deformity: a 5-year follow-up study. Spine J. 2017 Oct;17(10):1489-98. Epub 2017 May 12.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lau D, Clark AJ, Scheer JK, Daubs MD, Coe JD, Paonessa KJ, LaGrone MO, Kasten MD, Amaral RA, Trobisch PD, Lee JH, Fabris-Monterumici D, Anand N, Cree AK, Hart RA, Hey LA, Ames CP; SRS Adult Spinal Deformity Committee. Proximal junctional kyphosis and failure after spinal deformity surgery: a systematic review of the literature as a background to classification development. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2014 Dec 1;39(25):2093-102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HJ, Bridwell KH, Lenke LG, Park MS, Song KS, Piyaskulkaew C, Chuntarapas T. Patients with proximal junctional kyphosis requiring revision surgery have higher postoperative lumbar lordosis and larger sagittal balance corrections. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2014 Apr 20;39(9):E576-80.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>