<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">37676883</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2767-3170</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>2</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>PLOS digital health</Title><ISOAbbreviation>PLOS Digit Health</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Randomized controlled trial of a smartphone-based cognitive behavioral therapy for chronic tinnitus.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e0000337</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e0000337</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e0000337</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1371/journal.pdig.0000337</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>Tinnitus, the phantom perception of sounds, generates distress and anxiety in those affected. Cognitive behavioral treatment approaches reproducibly help patients in managing chronic tinnitus. This study systematically evaluated the usefulness of a tinnitus app (with areas of attention and relaxation, mindfulness, acceptance, self-efficacy), which is prescribed for a total of nine months. One hundred eighty-seven participants with chronic tinnitus were equally randomized to an intervention arm that used a smartphone-based intervention -marketed as Kalmeda Tinnitus app-. and a control arm with delayed onset of treatment by 3 months. The first 3 months of a 9-months prescribed intervention have been analyzed as primary outcome. The Tinnitus Questionnaire (TQ) was used as primary endpoint to determine the reduction of tinnitus distress. Following intervention, there was a statistically significant and clinically relevant reduction of the TQ sum score in the intervention group compared to the control group (p&lt;0.001, Cohen's d effect size = 1.1). The secondary parameters, Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ9) and Perceived-Stress-Questionnaire (PSQ20) scores improved significantly in the intervention group whereas the Self Efficacy-Optimism-Pessimism short form (SWOP-K9) scores remained unchanged in both groups. Patients reported no treatment-related side effects. Taken together, use of this Tinnitus app lead to a significant decrease in tinnitus distress and a clinically relevant effect in the patients&#xb4; self-reported everyday management.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright: &#xa9; 2023 Walter et al. This is an open access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are credited.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Walter</LastName><ForeName>Uso</ForeName><Initials>U</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENT Practice Walter &amp; Zander, Duisburg and mynoise GmbH, Duisburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Pennig</LastName><ForeName>Stefan</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>context, Essen-Kettwig, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Kottmann</LastName><ForeName>Tanja</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>CRO Dr. med. Kottmann GmbH &amp; Co KG, Hamm, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Bleckmann</LastName><ForeName>Lothar</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>ENT Practice Dr. med. Bleckmann, Kleve, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>R&#xf6;schmann-Doose</LastName><ForeName>Kristina</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1375-2418</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>G. Pohl-Boskamp GmbH &amp; Co. KG, Hohenlockstedt, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Schlee</LastName><ForeName>Winfried</ForeName><Initials>W</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Eastern Switzerland University of Applied Sciences, St. Gallen, Switzerland.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Clinic and Polyclinic for Psychiatry and Psychotherapy, University of Regensburg, Regensburg, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>07</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>PLOS Digit Health</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9918335064206676</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2767-3170</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>I have read the journal&#x2019;s policy and the authors of this manuscript have the following competing interests: WS is stakeholder of the Lenox UG, a company which aims to translate research findings into digital health applications; SP, Leadership Consultant, member of context; UW, resident otorhinolaryngologist, developer of the Kalmeda Tinnitus app and managing director of mynoise GmbH; K R-D is employed by G. Pohl-Boskamp GmbH &amp; Co. KG (distribution partner for Kalmeda), and WS, UW, LB receive personal fees from G. Pohl-Boskamp GmbH &amp; Co. KG. TK, CEO of CRO Dr Kottmann received a contractual fee from mynoise for the conduct of the study.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>18</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>13</Hour><Minute>33</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37676883</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10484427</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pdig.0000337</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">PDIG-D-22-00338</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Biswas R, Lugo A, Akeroyd MA, Schlee W, Gallus S, Hall DA. Tinnitus prevalence in Europe: a multi-country cross-sectional population study. Lancet Regional Health-Europe. 2022;12: 100250. doi: 10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100250</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lanepe.2021.100250</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8671623</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34950918</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Br&#xfc;ggemann P, Szczepek AJ, Rose M, McKenna L, Olze H, Mazurek B. Impact of multiple factors on the degree of tinnitus distress. Front Hum Neurosci. 2016;10: 341. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2016.00341</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2016.00341</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4925660</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27445776</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wagenaar OVG, Schubert NMA, van Rood YR, Rosmalen JGM. Factors associated with Self Rated Health in persons with tinnitus from the general population. J Psychosom Res. 2022;153:110693. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110693</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2021.110693</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34920266</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hu J, Cui J, Xu JJ, Yin X, Wu Y,Qi J. The neural mechanisms of tinnitus: a perspective from functional magnetic resonance imaging. Front Neurosci. 2021;15: 621145. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2021.621145</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2021.621145</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7905063</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33642982</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hollis C, Morriss R, MArtin J, Amani S, Cotton R, Denis M, Lewis S. Technological innovations in mental healthcare: harnessing the digital revolution. Br JPsychiatry, 2015;206(4): 263&#x2013;265. doi: 10.1192/bjp.bp.113.142612</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1192/bjp.bp.113.142612</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25833865</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cima R, Mazurek B, Haider H, Kikidis D, Lapira A, Norena A, et al. A multidisciplinary European guideline for tinnitus: diagnostics, assessment, and treatment. HNO, 2019; 67(1): 10&#x2013;42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30847513</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hayes SC,Hofmann SG. The third wave of cognitive behavioral therapy and the rise of process-based care. World psychiatry, 2017;16(3): 245. doi: 10.1002/wps.20442</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/wps.20442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5608815</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28941087</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grewal R, Spielmann PM, Jones SEM, Hussain SSM. Clinical efficacy of tinnitus retraining therapy and cognitive behavioural therapy in the treatment of subjective tinnitus: a systematic review. J Laryngol Otol. 2014;128(12): 1028&#x2013;1033. doi: 10.1017/S0022215114002849</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0022215114002849</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25417546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesser H, Weise C, Westin VZ, Andersson G. A systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials of cognitive&#x2013;behavioral therapy for tinnitus distress. Clin Psychol Rev. 2011;31(4): 545&#x2013;553. doi: 10.1016/j.cpr.2010.12.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cpr.2010.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21237544</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westin VZ, Schulin M, Hesser H, Karlsson M, Noe RZ, Olofsson U, et al. Acceptance and commitment therapy versus tinnitus retraining therapy in the treatment of tinnitus: a randomised controlled trial. Behav Res Ther. 2011;49(11): 737&#x2013;747. doi: 10.1016/j.brat.2011.08.001</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brat.2011.08.001</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21864830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kelson J, Rollin A, Ridout B, Campbell A. Internet-delivered acceptance and commitment therapy for anxiety treatment: systematic review. J Med Internet Res. 2019;21(1): e12530. doi: 10.2196/12530</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/12530</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6371070</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30694201</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu H, Zhang J, Yang S, Wang X, Zhang W, Li J, et al. Efficacy of sound therapy interventions for tinnitus management: A protocol for systematic review and network meta-analysis. Medicine. 2021;100(41): e27509. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000027509</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000027509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8519222</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34731137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zenner H., <i>S3-Leitlinie 017/064</i>: <i>Chronischer Tinnitus</i>., 2015.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Goebel G,Hiller W. Tinnitus-Fragebogen:(TF); ein Instrument zur Erfassung von Belastung und Schweregrad bei Tinnitus; Handanweisung. Hogrefe, Verlag f&#xfc;r Psychologie; 1998.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Searchfield GD, Sander PJ, Doborjeh Z, Doborjeh M, Boldu R, Sun K, et al. A state-of-art review of digital technologies for the next generation of tinnitus therapeutics. FrontDigit Health. 2021;3. doi: 10.3389/fdgth.2021.724370</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fdgth.2021.724370</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8522011</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34713191</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fuller T, Cima R, LAngguth B, Mazurek B, Vlaeyen JWS, Hoare DJ. Cognitive behavioural therapy for tinnitus. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2020(1). doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD012614.pub2</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD012614.pub2</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6956618</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31912887</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Adamchic I, Tass PA, Langguth B, Hauptmann C, Koller M, Schecklmann M, et al. Linking the Tinnitus Questionnaire and the subjective Clinical Global Impression: Which differences are clinically important? Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2012;10(1): 1&#x2013;10. doi: 10.1186/1477-7525-10-79</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1477-7525-10-79</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3487915</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22781703</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beukes EW, Manchaiah V, Baguley DM, Allen PM. Process evaluation of Internet-based cognitive behavioural therapy for adults with tinnitus in the context of a randomised control trial. IntJ Audiol. 2018;57(2): 98&#x2013;109. doi: 10.1080/14992027.2017.1384858</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14992027.2017.1384858</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28990807</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Langenbach M, Olderog M, Michel O, Albus C, K&#xf6;hle K. Psychosocial and personality predictors of tinnitus-related distress. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2005;27(1): 73&#x2013;77. doi: 10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2004.08.008</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.genhosppsych.2004.08.008</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15694221</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodrigo H, Beukes EW, Andersson G, Manchaiah V. Internet-based cognitive&#x2013;behavioural therapy for tinnitus: secondary analysis to examine predictors of outcomes. BMJ open. 2021;11(8): e049384. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2021-049384</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-049384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8381319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34417217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beukes EW, Manchaiah V, Davies ASA, Allen PM. Participants&#x2019; experiences of an Internet-based cognitive behavioural therapy intervention for tinnitus. Int J Audiol. 2018;57(12): 947&#x2013;954. doi: 10.1080/14992027.2018.1514538</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14992027.2018.1514538</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30295113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brueggemann P, Neff PKA, Meyer M, Riemer N, Rose M, Mazurek B. On the relationship between tinnitus distress, cognitive performance and aging. Prog Brain Res. 2021;262: 263&#x2013;285. doi: 10.1016/bs.pbr.2021.01.028</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.pbr.2021.01.028</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33931184</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hesser H, Weise C, Rief W, Andersson G. The effect of waiting: a meta-analysis of wait-list control groups in trials for tinnitus distress. J Psychosom Res. 2011; 70(4): 378&#x2013;384. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2010.12.006</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2010.12.006</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21414459</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beukes EW, Vlaescu G, Manchaiah V, Baguley DM, Allen PM, Kaldo V, et al.Development and technical functionality of an Internet-based intervention for tinnitus in the UK. Internet Interv. 2016;6: 6&#x2013;15. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2016.08.002</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2016.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096206</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135809</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Beukes EW, Andersson G, Allen PM Manchaiah V, Baguley DM. Effectiveness of guided internet-based cognitive behavioral therapy vs face-to-face clinical care for treatment of tinnitus: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2018; 144(12): 1126&#x2013;1133. doi: 10.1001/jamaoto.2018.2238</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoto.2018.2238</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6583080</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30286238</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kleinst&#xe4;uber M, Weise C, Psychosocial variables that predict chronic and disabling tinnitus: a systematic review. Curr Top Behav Neurosci. 2020; 361&#x2013;380.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33527333</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hiller W, Goebel G. Rapid assessment of tinnitus-related psychological distress using the Mini-TQ. Int J Audiol. 2004;43(10): 600&#x2013;604. doi: 10.1080/14992020400050077</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14992020400050077</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15724525</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Grafe K, Zipfel S, Herzog W, Lowe B. Screening for psychiatric disorders with the Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ). Results from the German validation study. Diagnostica. 2004; 50(4): 171&#x2013;181.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>FliegeH, Rose M, Arck P, Levenstein S, Klapp BF. PSQ: Perceived Stress Questionnaire [Verfahrensdokumentation aus PSYNDEX Tests-Nr. 9004426, PSQ20-Skalenberechnung, PSQ20-Fragebogen Englisch, Deutsch, Deutsch (letzte 2 Jahre), PSQ30-Skalenberechnung, PSQ30-Fragebogen Englisch, Franz&#xf6;sisch, Deutsch, Italienisch, und Spanisch]. Leibniz-Zentrum f&#xfc;r Psychologische Information und Dokumentation (ZPID). Elektronisches Testarchiv; 2009; 2889.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Scholler G, Fliege H, Klapp BF. Questionnaire of self-efficacy, optimism and pessimism: reconstruction, selection of items and validation of an instrument by means of examinations of clinical samples. Psychother Psychosom Med Psychol. 1999; 49(8): 275&#x2013;283.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10488648</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thaban L, Mbuagbaw L, Zhang S, Samaan Z, Marcucci M, Ye C, et al. A tutorial on sensitivity analyses in clinical trials: the what, why, when and how. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2013; 13: 92. doi: 10.1186/1471-2288-13-92</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2288-13-92</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3720188</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23855337</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>