<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">36747265</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>08</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>09</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6215</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>24</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Feb</Month><Day>06</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Trials</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Trials</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Internet-based self-help intervention for procrastination: randomized control group trial protocol.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>82</StartPage><MedlinePgn>82</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">82</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13063-023-07112-7</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Procrastination or "postponing until later" is a common phenomenon defined as the intentional delay in partaking in and finishing important activities despite negative outcomes potentially outweighing the positive. Procrastination adversely affects mental health, academic performance, and career achievement. Although studies on procrastination intervention methods and effectiveness exist, utility and cost-effectiveness are limited by various factors, including practitioner availability and skills, barriers to participant participation, and the time investment required by participants. Thus, internet-based interventions could increase the availability of evidence-based treatments for adult procrastination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This study explored the efficacy of an online-based self-help intervention in the context of voluntary procrastination among undergraduate psychology students. The study design is a randomized controlled trial. Participants who self-reported procrastination-related problems and behaviours were included in the trial consisting of two groups; specifically, one group undergoing a self-directed internet-based intervention for coping with procrastination (N=160) and (2) another group with delayed access to the intervention programmes (waitlist control group; N=160). Follow-up assessments were scheduled 6 and 12 weeks after baseline, and the control group received the intervention after 12 weeks. Procrastination, measured by the Irrational Procrastination Scale and the Simple Procrastination Scale, was examined as the primary outcome. Meanwhile, secondary outcomes included susceptibility, stress, depression, anxiety, well-being, self-efficacy, time management strategies, self-control, cognition, and emotion regulation. Other measures comprised acceptability (e.g., intervention satisfaction, potential side effects, and expectations) and learning behaviour analysis to reflect adherence.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This randomized controlled trial will provide data on the effectiveness of online interventions for adult procrastination. If deemed effective, this low-cost, high-coverage internet-based intervention could aid more people who seek to address their procrastination.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Chinese Clinical Trial Registry.&#xa0; https://www.chictr.org.cn/showproj.aspx?proj=171246 .</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zhou</LastName><ForeName>Ying</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7109-7856</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Education, Beijing Open University, Beijing, 100081, People's Republic of China. zhouy@bjou.edu.cn.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jianhua</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>School of Foreign Languages, Renmin University of China, Beijing, 100872, People's Republic of China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><GrantID>19JYB023</GrantID><Agency>Beijing Municipal Social Science Foundation</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D000078325">Clinical Trial Protocol</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>06</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Trials</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101263253</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1745-6215</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000079382" MajorTopicYN="Y">Internet-Based Intervention</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035061" MajorTopicYN="N">Control Groups</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000075682" MajorTopicYN="Y">Procrastination</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008603" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Health</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D020407" MajorTopicYN="N">Internet</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D016032" MajorTopicYN="N">Randomized Controlled Trials as Topic</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive behavioural therapy</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Control group randomized trial</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Internet-based intervention</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Procrastination</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-regulated learning theory</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>11</Month><Day>30</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>16</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>8</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>9</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>6</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36747265</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9900198</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13063-023-07112-7</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13063-023-07112-7</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Steel P. The nature of procrastination: a meta-analytic and theoretical review of quintessential self-regulatory failure. Psychol Bull. 2007;133(1):65. doi: 10.1037/0033-2909.133.1.65.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0033-2909.133.1.65</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17201571</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zimmerman BJ. Attaining self-regulation: a social cognitive perspective. Handbook of self-regulation. Elsevier; 2000. pp. 13&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dewitte S, Schouwenburg HC. Procrastination, temptations, and incentives: the struggle between the present and the future in procrastinators and the punctual. Eur J Pers. 2002;16(6):469&#x2013;489. doi: 10.1002/per.461.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/per.461</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>W&#xe4;schle K, Allgaier A, Lachner A, Fink S, N&#xfc;ckles M. Procrastination and self-efficacy: tracing vicious and virtuous circles in self-regulated learning. Learn Instr. 2014;29:103&#x2013;114. doi: 10.1016/j.learninstruc.2013.09.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.learninstruc.2013.09.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell AJ, Watson DC. Procrastination: associations with achievement goal orientation and learning strategies. Pers Individ Differ. 2007;43(1):167&#x2013;178. doi: 10.1016/j.paid.2006.11.017.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2006.11.017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haghbin M, McCaffrey A, Pychyl TA. The complexity of the relation between fear of failure and procrastination. J Ration Emot Cogn Behav Ther. 2012;30(4):249&#x2013;263. doi: 10.1007/s10942-012-0153-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10942-012-0153-9</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gustavson DE, Miyake A. Academic procrastination and goal accomplishment: a combined experimental and individual differences investigation. Learn Individ Differ. 2017;54:160&#x2013;172. doi: 10.1016/j.lindif.2017.01.010.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lindif.2017.01.010</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5608091</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28943742</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Myrick JG. Emotion regulation, procrastination, and watching cat videos online: who watches Internet cats, why, and to what effect? Comput Hum Behav. 2015;52:168&#x2013;176. doi: 10.1016/j.chb.2015.06.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2015.06.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Van Eerde W. Procrastination: self-regulation in initiating aversive goals. Appl Psychol. 2000;49(3):372&#x2013;389. doi: 10.1111/1464-0597.00021.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1464-0597.00021</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klingsieck KB. Procrastination in different life-domains: is procrastination domain specific? Curr Psychol. 2013;32(2):175&#x2013;185. doi: 10.1007/s12144-013-9171-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12144-013-9171-8</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akram A, Fu C, Li Y, Javed MY, Lin R, Jiang Y, et al. Predicting students&#x2019; academic procrastination in blended learning course using homework submission data. IEEE Access. 2019;7:102487&#x2013;102498. doi: 10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2930867.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2930867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prem R, Scheel TE, Weigelt O, Hoffmann K, Korunka C. Procrastination in daily working life: a diary study on within-person processes that link work characteristics to workplace procrastination. Front Psychol. 2018;9:1087. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01087.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6042014</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30026712</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hen M, Goroshit M, Viengarten S. How decisional and general procrastination relate to procrastination at work: an investigation of office and non-office workers. Pers Individ Differ. 2021;172:110581. doi: 10.1016/j.paid.2020.110581.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.paid.2020.110581</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sederlund A, Burns L, Rogers W. Multidimensional models of perfectionism and procrastination: seeking determinants of both. Int J Environ Res Publ Health. 2020;17(14):5099. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17145099.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph17145099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7400384</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32679730</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jones IS, Blankenship DC. Year two: effect of procrastination on academic performance of undergraduate online students. J Appl Res High Educ. 2021:39 https://eric.ed.gov/?id=EJ1293903.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu L, Hecht T, editors. Waiting to advance? A study of trait and situational predictors of career procrastination behaviors. Academy of Management Proceedings; 2019: Academy of Management Briarcliff Manor, 10510. 10.5465/AMBPP.2019.12843</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sirois FM. Introduction: Conceptualizing the relations of procrastination to health and well-being. In: Sirois FM,&#xa0; Pychyl TA, editors. Procrastination, health, and well-being. 2016. p. 3&#x2013;20. Elsevier Academic Press. 10.1016/B978-0-12-802862-9.00001-3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zacks S, Hen M. Academic interventions for academic procrastination: a review of the literature. J Prev Interv Commun. 2018;46(2):117&#x2013;130. doi: 10.1080/10852352.2016.1198154.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10852352.2016.1198154</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29485384</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Malouff JM, Schutte NS. The efficacy of interventions aimed at reducing procrastination: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Couns Dev. 2019;97(2):117&#x2013;127. doi: 10.1002/jcad.12243.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcad.12243</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>van Eerde W, Klingsieck KB. Overcoming procrastination? A meta-analysis of intervention studies. Educ Res Rev. 2018;25:73&#x2013;85. doi: 10.1016/j.edurev.2018.09.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.edurev.2018.09.002</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Boettcher J, Carlbring P, Renneberg B, Berger T. Internet-based interventions for social anxiety disorder-an overview. Verhaltenstherapie. 2013;23(3):160&#x2013;168. doi: 10.1159/000354747.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000354747</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Glick DM, Orsillo SM. An investigation of the efficacy of acceptance-based behavioral therapy for academic procrastination. J Exp Psychol Gen. 2015;144(2):400&#x2013;409. doi: 10.1037/xge0000050.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/xge0000050</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25688905</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davis DR, Abbitt JT. An investigation of the impact of an intervention to reduce academic procrastination using short message service (SMS) technology. J Interact Online Learn. 2013;12(3) https://www.learntechlib.org/p/153513/.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Klassen RM, Krawchuk LL, Rajani S. Academic procrastination of undergraduates: low self-efficacy to self-regulate predicts higher levels of procrastination. Contemp Educ Psychol. 2008;33(4):915&#x2013;931. doi: 10.1016/j.cedpsych.2007.07.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cedpsych.2007.07.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gieselmann A, Pietrowsky R. Treating procrastination chat-based versus face-to-face: an RCT evaluating the role of self-disclosure and perceived counselor's characteristics. Comput Hum Behav. 2016;54:444&#x2013;452. doi: 10.1016/j.chb.2015.08.027.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chb.2015.08.027</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Litz BT, Engel CC, Bryant RA, Papa A. A randomized, controlled proof-of-concept trial of an internet-based, therapist-assisted self-management treatment for posttraumatic stress disorder. Am J Psychiatry. 2007;164(11):1676&#x2013;1684. doi: 10.1176/appi.ajp.2007.06122057.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/appi.ajp.2007.06122057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17974932</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental A, Forsstr&#xf6;m D, Nilsson S, Rizzo A, Carlbring P. Group versus Internet-based cognitive-behavioral therapy for procrastination: study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Internet Interv. 2014;1(2):84&#x2013;89. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2014.05.005.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2014.05.005</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Azizian F, Ramak N, Vahid F, Rezaee S, Sangani A. The effectiveness of cognitive simulation techniques group training on academic engagement and academic procrastination in nursing students. J Nurs Educ. 2020;9(2):54&#x2013;62.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ib&#xe1;&#xf1;ez MB, Pel&#xe1;ez J, Kloos CD. Interactive Mobile Communication, Technologies and Learning. Springer; 2018. Using an augmented reality geolocalized quiz game as an incentive to overcome academic procrastination.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eckert M, Ebert DD, Lehr D, Sieland B, Berking M. Does sms-support make a difference? Effectiveness of a two-week online-training to overcome procrastination. a randomized controlled trial. Front Psychol. 2018;9:1103. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01103.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01103</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6042057</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30026713</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Foulonneau A, Calvary G, Villain E. Proceedings of the 28th Australian Conference on Computer-Human Interaction. 2016. Stop procrastinating: TILT, time is life time, a persuasive application.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Inie N, Lungu MF. Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. 2021. Aiki-turning online procrastination into microlearning.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lukas CA, Berking M. Reducing procrastination using a smartphone-based treatment program: a randomized controlled pilot study. Internet Interv. 2018;12:83&#x2013;90. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2017.07.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2017.07.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6096330</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30135772</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Birkla D. An evaluation on values and committed action based intervention on academic procrastination. Southern Illinois University at Carbondale; 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gagnon J, Dionne F, Raymond G, Gr&#xe9;goire S. Pilot study of a Web-based acceptance and commitment therapy intervention for university students to reduce academic procrastination. J Am Coll Health. 2019;67(4):374&#x2013;382. doi: 10.1080/07448481.2018.1484361.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2018.1484361</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29979942</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental A, Forsell E, Svensson A, Forsstr&#xf6;m D, Andersson G, Carlbring P. Differentiating procrastinators from each other: a cluster analysis. Cogn Behav Ther. 2015;44(6):480&#x2013;490. doi: 10.1080/16506073.2015.1059353.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2015.1059353</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26178164</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gruber J, Prinstein MJ, Clark LA, Rottenberg J, Abramowitz JS, Albano AM, et al. Mental health and clinical psychological science in the time of COVID-19: Challenges, opportunities, and a call to action. Am Psychol. 2021;76(3):409&#x2013;426. doi: 10.1037/amp0000707.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/amp0000707</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873160</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32772538</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peixoto EM, Pallini AC, Vallerand RJ, Rahimi S, Silva MV. The role of passion for studies on academic procrastination and mental health during the COVID-19 pandemic. Soc Psychol Educ. 2021;24(3):877&#x2013;893. doi: 10.1007/s11218-021-09636-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11218-021-09636-9</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8184402</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34121913</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental A, Forsstr&#xf6;m D, Lindner P, Nilsson S, M&#xe5;rtensson L, Rizzo A, et al. Treating procrastination using cognitive behavior therapy: a pragmatic randomized controlled trial comparing treatment delivered via the internet or in groups. Behav Ther. 2018;49(2):180&#x2013;197. doi: 10.1016/j.beth.2017.08.002.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beth.2017.08.002</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29530258</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bandura A. The explanatory and predictive scope of self-efficacy theory. J Soc Clin Psychol. 1986;4(3):359. doi: 10.1521/jscp.1986.4.3.359.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1521/jscp.1986.4.3.359</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ajzen I. From intentions to actions: a theory of planned behavior. Action control. Springer; 1985. pp. 11&#x2013;39.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Locke EA, Latham GP. Building a practically useful theory of goal setting and task motivation: a 35-year odyssey. Am Psychol. 2002;57(9):705. doi: 10.1037/0003-066X.57.9.705.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0003-066X.57.9.705</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12237980</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ryan RM, Deci EL. Self-determination theory and the facilitation of intrinsic motivation, social development, and well-being. Schouwenburg, H. C. (2004). Procrastination in Academic Settings: General Introduction. H. C. Schouwenburg, C. H. Lay, T. A. Pychyl, &amp; J. R. Ferrari (Eds.), Counseling the procrastinator in academic settings. 3&#x2013;17. American Psychological Association. 10.1037/0003-066X.55.1.68</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11392867</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schouwenburg HC. Procrastination in academic settings: general introduction. In: Schouwenburg HC, Lay CH, Pychyl TA, Ferrari JR, editors. Counseling the procrastinator in academic settings. American Psychological Association; 2004. pp. 3&#x2013;17.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental A, Boettcher J, Andersson G, Schmidt B, Carlbring P. Negative effects of internet interventions: a qualitative content analysis of patients&#x2019; experiences with treatments delivered online. Cogn Behav Ther. 2015;44(3):223&#x2013;236. doi: 10.1080/16506073.2015.1008033.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/16506073.2015.1008033</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25705924</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shaw A, Zhang JJ. Psychometric properties of the Chinese Irrational Procrastination Scale: factor structure and measurement invariance across gender. Front Psychol. 2021:4726. 10.3389/fpsyg.2021.768581s.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8558432</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34733223</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lian S-l, Sun X-j, Zhou Z-k, Fan C-y, Niu G-f, Liu Q-q. Social networking site addiction and undergraduate students&#x2019; irrational procrastination: the mediating role of social networking site fatigue and the moderating role of effortful control. PloS One. 2018;13(12):e0208162. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0208162.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0208162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6289504</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30533013</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shen H-y. Doctoral dissertation, Southwest University. 2012. The study of the influence of perfectionism, achievement motivation and unconditional self-acceptance on procrastination.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li LI, Mu LI. Effects of mindfulness training on psychological capital, depression, and procrastination of the youth demographic. Iran J Public Health. 2020;49(9):1692. doi: 10.18502/ijph.v49i9.4086.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18502/ijph.v49i9.4086</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7898108</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33643944</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen S, Chiu H, Xu B, Ma Y, Jin T, Wu M, et al. Reliability and validity of the PHQ-9 for screening late-life depression in Chinese primary care. Int J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2010;25(11):1127&#x2013;1133. doi: 10.1002/gps.2442.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/gps.2442</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20029795</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Teymoori A, Gorbunova A, Haghish FE, Real R, Zeldovich M, Wu Y, et al. Factorial Structure and Validity of Depression (PHQ-9) and Anxiety (GAD-7) Scales after Traumatic Brain Injury. J Clin Med. 2020;9(837):49&#x2013;67. doi: 10.3390/jcm9030873.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm9030873</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7141536</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32210017</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He X, Li C, Qian J, Cui H, Wu W. Reliability and validity of a generalized anxiety disorder scale in general hospital outpatients. Shanghai Arch Psychiatry. 2010;22(4):200&#x2013;203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Toussaint A, H&#xfc;sing P, Gumz A, Wingenfeld K, H&#xe4;rter M, Schramm E, et al. Sensitivity to change and minimal clinically important difference of the 7-item Generalized Anxiety Disorder Questionnaire (GAD-7) J Affect Disord. 2020;265:395&#x2013;401. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2020.01.032.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2020.01.032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32090765</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Huang F, Wang H, Wang Z, Zhang J, Du W, Su C, et al. Psychometric properties of the perceived stress scale in a community sample of Chinese. BMC Psychiatry. 2020;20(1):130. doi: 10.1186/s12888-020-02520-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-020-02520-4</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082906</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32197589</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zeng G, Fung S-f, Li J, Hussain N, Yu P. Evaluating the psychometric properties and factor structure of the general self-efficacy scale in China. Curr Psychol. 2020:1&#x2013;11. 10.1007/s12144-020-00924-9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tan S, Guo Y. Revision of Self-Control Scale for Chinese College Students. Chin J Clin Psychol. 2008;16(5):468&#x2013;470. doi: 10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2008.05.022.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2008.05.022</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu X, Luo F, Yao S. Reliability and validity of the Cognitive Emotion Regulation Questionnair e- Chinese Ver sion. Chin J Clin Psychol. 2007;15(2):121&#x2013;124. doi: 10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2007.02.006.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.16128/j.cnki.1005-3611.2007.02.006</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou Y, Wang J. Psychometric properties of the MSLQ-B for adult distance education in China. Front Psychol. 2021:12. 10.3389/fpsyg.2021.620564.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7940182</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33708161</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schr&#xf6;der J, Sautier L, Kriston L, Berger T, Meyer B, Sp&#xe4;th C, et al. Development of a questionnaire measuring Attitudes towards Psychological Online Interventions&#x2013;the APOI. J Affect Disord. 2015;187:136&#x2013;141. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2015.08.044.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jad.2015.08.044</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26331687</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental A, Kottorp A, Forsstr&#xf6;m D, M&#xe5;nsson K, Boettcher J, Andersson G, et al. The Negative Effects Questionnaire: psychometric properties of an instrument for assessing negative effects in psychological treatments. Behav Cogn Psychother. 2019;47(5):559&#x2013;572. doi: 10.1017/S1352465819000018.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1352465819000018</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ng YY. Treatment of Generalized Anxiety Disorder (GAD): a randomized controlled trial of an internet self-help program with minimal non-therapist support [Ph.D.] Ann Arbor: The Chinese University of Hong Kong (Hong Kong); 2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rozental A, Forsstr&#xf6;m D, Tangen JA, Carlbring P. Experiences of undergoing Internet-based cognitive behavior therapy for procrastination: a qualitative study. Internet Interv. 2015;2(3):314&#x2013;322. doi: 10.1016/j.invent.2015.05.001.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.invent.2015.05.001</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>