<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37632285</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>01</Month><Day>31</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1743-498X</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>21</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Feb</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The clinical teacher</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin Teach</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A brief intervention decreases student distress.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e13629</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e13629</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/tct.13629</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF THE ARTICLE">Health professions graduate students have experienced substantial increases in stress and anxiety in recent years. This can result in decreased academic performance, poor retention, and burnout. Interventions to help students cope are therefore a critical need for academic institutions. The current study sought to demonstrate the effectiveness of a brief multimodal intervention in reducing student distress.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHOD">The study was a randomised controlled design that evaluated a brief intervention of cognitive-behavioural therapy, mindfulness, and healthy lifestyle choices. The Depression Anxiety Stress Scale-21 was administered to participants at baseline and two post-intervention time points. Control participants did not participate in any intervention. Participants were recruited from graduate students in first-year classes within the School of Health Professions at UT Southwestern Medical Center.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Analysis revealed an overall mild to moderate decline in Depression Anxiety Stress Scale-21 total scores over three assessment periods for both treatment and control groups, with no statistical differences noted between groups; however, the treatment group's scores declined approximately 6&#x2009;weeks before the control participants' scores declined.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">The pattern of change in the two groups suggests that our intervention facilitated the reduction in student anxiety more quickly than would have occurred normally and with sustained results.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2023 The Authors. The Clinical Teacher published by Association for the Study of Medical Education and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Shearin</LastName><ForeName>Staci Macklin</ForeName><Initials>SM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Physical Therapy, UT Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Jijia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Clinical Research, UT Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Reisch</LastName><ForeName>Joan</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Population &amp; Data Sciences, UT Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brewer-Mixon</LastName><ForeName>Karen</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9806-5472</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Applied Clinical Research, UT Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas, Texas, USA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><GrantList CompleteYN="Y"><Grant><Agency>UT Southwestern Medical Center</Agency><Country/></Grant></GrantList><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016449">Randomized Controlled Trial</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2023</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>26</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Clin Teach</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101227511</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1743-4971</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013315" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stress, Psychological</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003419" MajorTopicYN="N">Crisis Intervention</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="N">Students</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064866" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mindfulness</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2022</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>1</Month><Day>31</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>10</Hour><Minute>46</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>26</Day><Hour>4</Hour><Minute>23</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37632285</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tct.13629</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Title>REFERENCES</Title><Reference><Citation>Pierceall E, Keim M. Stress and coping strategies among community college students. Community Coll J Res Pract. 2007;31(9):703-712. https://doi.org/10.1080/10668920600866579</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Auerbach RP, Alonso J, Axinn WG, Cuijpers P, Ebert DD, Green JG, et al. Mental disorders among college students in the World Health Organization world mental health surveys. Psychol Med. 2016;46(14):2955-2970. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291716001665</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdulghani HM, AlKanhal AA, Mahmoud ES, Ponnamperuma GG, Alfaris EA. Stress and its effects on medical students: a cross-sectional study at a college of medicine in Saudi Arabia. J Health Popul Nutr. 2011;29(5):516-522. https://doi.org/10.3329/jhpn.v29i5.8906</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Labrague LJ, McEnroe-Petitte DM, Gloe D, Thomas L, Papathanasiou IV, Tsaras KA. Literature review on stress and coping strategies in nursing students. J Ment Health. 2017;26(5):471-480. https://doi.org/10.1080/09638237.2016.1244721</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>DeBerard MS, Spielmans GI, Julka DL. Predictors of academic achievement and retention among college freshmen: a longitudinal study. Coll Stud J. 2004;38(1):66-81.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wills J, Kelly M. What works to encourage student nurses to adopt healthier lifestyles? Findings from an intervention study. Nurse Educ Today. 2016;48:180-184. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nedt.2016.10.011</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xiao H, Carney D, Youn SJ, Janis R, Castonguay L, Hayes JA, et al. Are we in crisis? National mental health and treatment trends in college counseling centers. Psychol Serv. 2017;14(4):407-415. https://doi.org/10.1037/ser0000130</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wyatt T, Oswalt SB. Comparing mental health issues among undergraduate and graduate students. Am J Health Educ. 2013;44(2):96-107. https://doi.org/10.1080/19325037.2013.764248</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Smith TB, Dean B, Floyd S, Silva C, Yamashita M, Durtschi J, et al. Pressing issues in college counseling: a survey of American College Counseling Association members. J Coll Couns. 2007;10(1):64-78. https://doi.org/10.1002/j.2161-1882.2007.tb00007.x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown C. Doctors' health matters-earning to care for yourself. J Holist Nurs. 2008;5(2):32-36.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gonzalez MJ, Miranda-Massari JR. Diet and stress. Psychiatr Clin North am. 2014;37(4):579-589. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psc.2014.08.004</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Raimo J, LaVine S, Spielmann K, Akerman M, Friedman KA, Katona K, et al. The correlation of stress in residency with future stress and burnout: a 10-year prospective cohort study. J Grad Med Educ. 2018;10(5):524-531. https://doi.org/10.4300/JGME-D-18-00273.1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yusufov M, Nicoloro-Santa Barbara J, Grey NE, Moyer A, Lobel M. Meta-analytic evaluation of stress reduction interventions for undergraduate and graduate students. Int J Stress Manag. 2019;26(2):132-145. https://doi.org/10.1037/str0000099</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Barbosa P, Raymond G, Zlotnick C, Wilk J, Toomey R III, Mitchell J III. Mindfulness-based stress reduction training is associated with greater empathy and reduced anxiety for graduate healthcare students. Educ Health. 2013;26(1):9-14. https://doi.org/10.4103/1357-6283.112794</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Galante J, Dufour G, Vainre M, Wagner AP, Stochl J, Benton A, et al. A mindfulness-based intervention to increase resilience to stress in university students (the Mindful Student Study): a pragmatic randomised controlled trial. Lancet Glob Health. 2018;3(2):e72-e81. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2468-2667(17)30231-1</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Daya Z, Hearn JH. Mindfulness interventions in medical education: a systematic review of their impact on medical student stress, depression, fatigue and burnout. Med Teach. 2018;40(2):146-153. https://doi.org/10.1080/0142159X.2017.1394999</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ezegbe BN, Eseadi C, Ede MO, Igbo JN, Anyanwu JI, Ede KR, et al. Impacts of cognitive-behavioral intervention on anxiety and depression among social science education students: a randomized controlled trial. Medicine. 2019;98(15):e14935. https://doi.org/10.1097/MD.0000000000014935</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Howell AN, Rheingold AA, Uhde TW, Guille C. Web-based CBT for the prevention of anxiety symptoms among medical and health science graduate students. Cogn Behav Ther. 2019;48(5):385-405. https://doi.org/10.1080/16506073.2018.1533575</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mazurek Melnyk B, Hoying J, Tan A. Effects of the MINDSTRONG&#xa9; CBT-based program on depression, anxiety and healthy lifestyle behaviors in graduate health sciences students. J Am Coll Health. 2020;70(4):1001-1009.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Deasy C, Coughlan B, Pironom J, Jourdan D, Mcnamara PM. Psychological distress and lifestyle of students: implications for health promotion. Health Promot Int. 2014;30(1):77-87. https://doi.org/10.1093/heapro/dau086</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Douris PC, D'Agostino NA, Mathew SK, Anderson RP, Bauman KM, Tiangtham SA, et al. The physiological and psychological effects of the first year of an entry-level physical therapist education program on students. J Phys Ther Educ. 2020;34(3):186-191. https://doi.org/10.1097/JTE.0000000000000143</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shearin SM, Brewer-Mixon K. Effectiveness of a short education series to reduce anxiety for health professions graduate students: a pilot study. J Phys Ther Educ. 2020;34(1):12-18. https://doi.org/10.1097/JTE.0000000000000124</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Black Dog Institute. Depression Anxiety Stress Scale. 2018. http://www.blackdoginstitute.org.au. Accessed August 6, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sinclair SJ, Siefert CJ, Slavin-Mulford JM, Stein MB, Renna M, Blis M. Psychometric evaluation and normative data for the Depression, Anxiety, and Stress Scales-21 (DASS-21) in a nonclinical sample of U.S. adults. Eval Health Prof. 2011;35(3):259-279. https://doi.org/10.1177/0163278711424282</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Norton PJ. Depression Anxiety and Stress Scales (DASS-21): psychometric analysis across four racial groups. Anxiety Stress Coping. 2007;20(3):253-265. https://doi.org/10.1080/10615800701309279</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>American Psychological Association. Stress by generation. 2012. http://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/stress/2012/generations.aspx. Accessed August 2, 2018.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bayram N, Bilgel N. The prevalence and socio-demographic correlations of depression, anxiety and stress among a group of university students. Soc Psychiatry Psychiatr Epidemiol. 2008;43(8):667-672. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00127-008-0345-x</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lovibond SH, Lovibond PF. Manual for the Depression, Anxiety, Stress Scales 2nd ed. Sydney: Psychology Foundation; 1995.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Misra R, McKean M, West S, Russo T. Academic stress of college students: comparison of student and faculty perceptions. Coll Stud J. 2000;34(2):236.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamdan-Mansour AM, Puskar K, Bandak AG. Effectiveness of cognitive-behavioral therapy on depressive symptomatology, stress and coping strategies among Jordanian university students. Issues Ment Health Nurs. 2009;30(3):188-196. https://doi.org/10.1080/01612840802694577</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>