<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">37653795</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2023</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>04</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>06</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>102</Volume><Issue>34</Issue><PubDate><Year>2023</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>25</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The effects of paroxetine therapy on depressive symptom and motor function in the treatment of depression with Parkinson's disease: A meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>e34687</StartPage><MedlinePgn>e34687</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e34687</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000034687</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Paroxetine therapy has been used for treatment of patients with depression and Parkinson's disease (dPD) in many clinical studies, but, the effects of paroxetine in dPD patients are not completely understood. The aim of this study was to systematically evaluate the effects of paroxetine therapy on depressive symptom and motor function in the treatment of dPD, in order to confer a reference for clinical practice.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Randomized controlled trials (RCTs) of paroxetine for dPD published up to October, 2022 were retrieved. Standardised mean difference (SMD), odds ratio (OR), and 95% confidence interval (CI) were calculated and heterogeneity was measured with the I2 test. The outcomes of interest were as follows: the efficacy, Hamilton depression rating scale score, unified Parkinson's disease rating scale score, Hamilton anxiety rating scale score or adverse events.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Thirty-four RCTs with 2819 participants were included. Compared with control group, the pooled effects of paroxetine therapy on depression were (22 trials; OR 3.62, 95% CI 2.63 to 4.98, P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001) for antidepressant response (25 trials; SMD -2.14, 95% CI -2.73 to -1.56, P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001) for Hamilton depression rating scale score, the pooled effects of paroxetine therapy on motor function were (10 trials; OR 4.63, 95% CI 3.15 to 6.79, P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001) for anti-PD efficacy (18 trials; SMD -2.02, 95% CI -2.48 to -1.55, P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001) for total unified Parkinson's disease rating scale score. The Hamilton anxiety rating scale score showed significant decrease in the paroxetine treatment group compared to control group (10 trials; SMD -1.93, 95% CI -2.65 to -1.22, P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001). In addition, paroxetine therapy reduced the number of any adverse events obviously in dPD patients (twenty trials; OR 0.42, 95% CI 0.31 to 0.57, P&#x2005;&lt;&#x2005;.00001).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Paroxetine therapy has clinical benefits for improvement of depressive symptom and motor function in dPD patients, moreover, it is of high drug safety. Further well-designed, multi-center RCTs needed to identify these findings.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2023 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>Li-Lin</ForeName><Initials>LL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Pharmacy, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Agricultural Resources Chemistry and Biotechnology, Yulin Normal University, Yulin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wu</LastName><ForeName>Yu-Lin</ForeName><Initials>YL</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Pharmacy, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Agricultural Resources Chemistry and Biotechnology, Yulin Normal University, Yulin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mo</LastName><ForeName>Ye</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Pharmacy, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Agricultural Resources Chemistry and Biotechnology, Yulin Normal University, Yulin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gou</LastName><ForeName>Ling</ForeName><Initials>L</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Pharmacy, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Agricultural Resources Chemistry and Biotechnology, Yulin Normal University, Yulin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Chen</LastName><ForeName>Mei-Ling</ForeName><Initials>ML</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Pharmacy, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Agricultural Resources Chemistry and Biotechnology, Yulin Normal University, Yulin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Wang</LastName><ForeName>Yan</ForeName><Initials>Y</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Guangdong Province Hospital of Integrated Traditional Chinese and Western Medicine, Foshan, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Zang</LastName><ForeName>Qing-Min</ForeName><Initials>QM</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Pharmacy, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Agricultural Resources Chemistry and Biotechnology, Yulin Normal University, Yulin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jiang</LastName><ForeName>De-Qi</ForeName><Initials>DQ</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6684-3789</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Biology and Pharmacy, Guangxi Key Laboratory of Agricultural Resources Chemistry and Biotechnology, Yulin Normal University, Yulin, China.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><ChemicalList><Chemical><RegistryNumber>41VRH5220H</RegistryNumber><NameOfSubstance UI="D017374">Paroxetine</NameOfSubstance></Chemical></ChemicalList><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D017374" MajorTopicYN="Y">Paroxetine</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010300" MajorTopicYN="Y">Parkinson Disease</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D003863" MajorTopicYN="N">Depression</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D035061" MajorTopicYN="N">Control Groups</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073216" MajorTopicYN="N">Mental Status and Dementia Tests</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>4</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2023</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>1</Day><Hour>1</Hour><Minute>44</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2023</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>25</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37653795</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10470685</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000034687</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202308250-00067</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Pontone GM, Mills KA. Optimal treatment of depression and anxiety in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry. 2021;29:530&#x2013;40.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33648830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Starkstein SE, Brockman S. Management of depression in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review. Mov Disord Clin Pract. 2017;4:470&#x2013;7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6174394</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30363415</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Prange S, Klinger H, Laurencin C, et al. Depression in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: current understanding of its neurobiology and implications for treatment. Drugs Aging. 2022;39:417&#x2013;39.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9200562</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35705848</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ceravolo R, Nuti A, Piccinni A, et al. Paroxetine in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: effects on motor and depressive symptoms. Neurology. 2000;55:1216&#x2013;8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11071504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Skapinakis P, Bakola E, Salanti G, et al. Efficacy and acceptability of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors for the treatment of depression in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. BMC Neurol. 2010;10:49.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2903535</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20565960</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Assogna F, Pellicano C, Savini C, et al. Drug choices and advancements for managing depression in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Curr Neuropharmacol. 2020;18:277&#x2013;87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7327944</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31622207</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broen MP, Leentjens AF, K&#xf6;hler S, et al. Trajectories of recovery in depressed Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients treated with paroxetine or venlafaxine. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2016;23:80&#x2013;5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26739248</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen LJ, Hu XJ, Yi ZH, et al. Analysis of the efficacy of paroxetine in adjuvant treatment of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and depression. Mod Prac Med. 2018;30:927&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richard IH, McDermott MP, Kurlan R, et al.; SAD-PD Study Group. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of antidepressants in Parkinson disease. Neurology. 2012;78:1229&#x2013;36.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3324323</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22496199</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feng Y, Yuan LP, Li Y. Observation of the curative effect of paroxetine in the treatment of depression in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Chin J Gerontol. 2011;31:2322&#x2013;3.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, et al.; PRISMA Group. Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA Statement. Open Med. 2009;3:e123&#x2013;30.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3090117</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21603045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Altman DG, G&#xf8;tzsche PC, et al.; Cochrane Bias Methods Group. The Cochrane collaboration&#x2019;s tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2011;343:d5928.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3196245</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22008217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jiang DQ, Jiang LL, Wang Y, et al. The role of pramipexole in the treatment of patients with depression and Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Asian J Psychiatr. 2021;61:102691.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33992852</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Higgins JP, Thompson SG. Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Stat Med. 2002;21:1539&#x2013;58.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12111919</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chen XC. Clinical effect of Paroxetine in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression. Chin Mod Med. 2020;27:66&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gong L, Zhang J, Tian WJ, et al. Analysis of the efficacy and adverse reactions of paroxetine in the treatment of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and depression. Healthful Friend. 2018;18:130&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hou WJ. Clinical effect of paroxetine on Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients with depression and anxiety. Chin J Clin Rational Drug Use. 2022;15:47&#x2013;50.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li HZ. Study on the efficacy and adverse reactions of paroxetine in the treatment of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and depression. Strait Pharm J. 2019;31:178&#x2013;80.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XH, Xue J. Clinical analysis of paroxetine combined with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression and anxiety symptoms. China Continuing Med Edu. 2015;7:147&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liang XS. Efficacy and side effects of paroxetine in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients with depression. J Clin Med. 2017;4:556&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu L, Li SY, Xu Y. Effect of paroxetine combined with levodopa on HAMD score and QOL score in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Med Innovat China. 2020;17:57&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Liu R. Analysis of clinical efficacy of paroxetine in the treatment of depression in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. World Clin Med. 2016;10:89&#x2013;90.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li XJ, Chen H. Clinical study of paroxetine hydrochloride in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression and anxiety symptoms. Chin J Prac Nerv Dis. 2015;18:69&#x2013;70.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lv D. Efficacy and adverse reactions of paroxetine in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression. Guide China Med. 2020;18:47&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma HR. Evaluation of the efficacy of paroxetine in the treatment of depressed patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Chin J Mod Appl Pharm. 2006;23:344&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ma N, Liu T, Meng XL. Clinical effect of paroxetine hydrochloride on depression and anxiety in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Diet Health 2016;3:56&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mai H. Effect of paroxetine on depression in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Mod Diagn Treat. 2014;25:5343&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Meng XL, Fang JS, Liu YX, et al. Clinical treatment of paroxetine on Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients complicated with depression and anxiety symptoms. Chin J Clin Pharmacol. 2013;29:403&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Menza M, Dobkin RD, Marin H, et al. A controlled trial of antidepressants in patients with Parkinson disease and depression. Neurology. 2009;72:886&#x2013;92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2677475</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19092112</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Song YH, Niu JP, Peng RQ, et al. Clinical study on the efficacy and adverse reactions of paroxetine tablets in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression. China Health Standard Management. 2020;11:82&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wang XY. Evaluation of the efficacy and adverse reactions of paroxetine in the treatment of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and depression. Chin J Mod Drug Appl. 2020;14:146&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu HY. Analysis of the efficacy of paroxetine in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression and its adverse reactions. Smart Health. 2020;6:106&#x2013;7.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Xu XX, Quan QY, Luo T, et al. Clinical analysis of paroxetine in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients with depression. J Front Med. 2021;11:101&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yan TE. Study on the efficacy of paroxetine in the treatment of depression in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. Health Protect Promot. 2016;16:105&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang CC, Tang QE. Efficacy of paroxetine in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients with depression. Guide China Med. 2014;12:159&#x2013;60.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang Y, Chen JJ, Luo Y. Observation on the therapeutic effect of paroxetine hydrochloride on Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients with anxiety and depression. Chin J Clinicians. 2021;49:1073&#x2013;6.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zang XW. Discussion on the effectiveness of paroxetine in the treatment of patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and depression and the incidence of adverse reactions. Syst Med. 2021;6:16&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang DQ, Ye WY, Zeng WJ, et al. The effects of paroxetine on medication compliance and efficacy in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and depression. Hebei Med J. 2014;36:3722&#x2013;4.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang HJ. Effects of paroxetine in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression and anxiety. Mod J Integrat Trad Chin West Med. 2015;24:649&#x2013;51.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang JM. Evaluation of the clinical effect of paroxetine hydrochloride on Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression and anxiety symptoms. Psychol Doct. 2017;23:38&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao HF, Luo HL, Feng ZZ, et al. Efficacy and safety of Paroxetine Hydrochloride in the treatment of in Parkinson&#x2019; s disease patients combined with depression and anxiety. J Int Psychiatry. 2017;44:480&#x2013;2.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zheng LF, Lin P, Zhang X, et al. Clinical trial of paroxetine tablets combined with pramipexole tablets in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease with depression. Chin J Clin Pharmacol. 2018;34:1819&#x2013;21.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhou HY, Long JF, Yue H, et al. Effects of paroxetine combination therapy on clinical outcomes, index scores and adverse reactions in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients combined with depression and anxiety. J Front Med. 2018;8:114&#x2013;5.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu J. The clinical effects of paroxetine hydrochloride in the treatment of Parkinson&#x2019;s disease patients with depression and anxiety symptoms. Word Latest Med Inform. 2018;18:140&#x2013;1.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhu Y. Clinical efficacy of paroxetine in patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease and depression. China J Pharm Econ. 2014;9:27&#x2013;8.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jellinger KA. The pathobiological basis of depression in Parkinson disease: challenges and outlooks. J Neural Transm (Vienna). 2022;129:1397&#x2013;418.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9628588</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36322206</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Salehi MA, Mohammadi S, Gouravani M, et al. Brain microstructural alterations of depression in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a systematic review of diffusion tensor imaging studies. Hum Brain Mapp. 2022;43:5658&#x2013;80.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9704780</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35855597</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dobkin RD, Menza M, Bienfait KL, et al. The impact of antidepressant treatment on cognitive functioning in depressed patients with Parkinson&#x2019;s disease. J Neuropsychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2010;22:188&#x2013;95.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2872099</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20463113</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tesei S, Antonini A, Canesi M, et al. Tolerability of paroxetine in Parkinson&#x2019;s disease: a prospective study. Mov Disord. 2000;15:986&#x2013;9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11009210</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>