<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">38778162</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>25</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2398-6352</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>7</Volume><Issue>1</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>May</Month><Day>22</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>NPJ digital medicine</Title><ISOAbbreviation>NPJ Digit Med</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>The EU passes the AI Act and its implications for digital medicine are unclear.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>135</StartPage><MedlinePgn>135</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">135</ELocationID><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1038/s41746-024-01116-6</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>On 13 March 2024, the much-anticipated AI Act was passed by the EU parliament and will soon be adopted as EU law. It will apply new requirements for developers and deployers of AI-enabled digital health tools (DHTs), including for a defined class of high-risk AI systems and for general-purpose AI. Although the text of the law is available, complete in all but the final checks of legal wording much is still not known about how the AI Act will affect the digital health landscape in the EU and beyond. The wording of many aspects of the Act is ambiguous, and often high-level objectives are stated, with the detail to come later in associated guidance, standards, and member state law and policy. It is also uncertain how the Act will intersect with pre-existing sector-specific legislation for medical AI. There are future steps in the legislative process that can clarify ambiguity, including standards, guidelines, and implementing laws, and the author remains optimistic the EU will get the implementation right.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilbert</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1997-1689</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Else Kr&#xf6;ner Fresenius Center for Digital Health, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany. stephen.gilbert@tu-dresden.de.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>05</Month><Day>22</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>NPJ Digit Med</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101731738</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2398-6352</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CoiStatement>S.G. declares a nonfinancial interest as an Advisory Group member of the EY-coordinated &#x201c;Study on Regulatory Governance and Innovation in the Field of Medical Devices&#x201d; conducted on behalf of the DG SANTE of the European Commission. S.G. declares the following competing financial interests: he has or has had consulting relationships with Una Health GmbH, Lindus Health Ltd., Flo Ltd, Thymia Ltd., FORUM Institut f&#xfc;r Management GmbH, High-Tech Gr&#xfc;nderfonds Management GmbH, and Ada Health GmbH and holds share options in Ada Health GmbH. S.G. is a News and Views Editor for npj Digital Medicine. S.G. played no role in the internal review or decision to publish this News and Views article.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>23</Day><Hour>0</Hour><Minute>42</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>23</Hour><Minute>34</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2024</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38778162</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11111757</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-024-01116-6</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1038/s41746-024-01116-6</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>European Parliament legislative resolution of 13 March 2024 on the proposal for a regulation of the European Parliament and of the Council on laying down harmonized rules on Artificial Intelligence (Artificial Intelligence Act) and amending certain Union Legislative Acts (COM(2021)0206&#x2014;C9-0146/2021&#x2014;2021/0106(COD)). https://www.europarl.europa.eu/doceo/document/TA-9-2024-0138_EN.pdf (2024).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Artificial Intelligence Act: MEPs adopt landmark law. https://www.europarl.europa.eu/news/en/press-room/20240308IPR19015/artificial-intelligence-act-meps-adopt-landmark-law</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>European Commission. Proposal for a regulation of the European Parliament and of the Council laying down harmonized rules on artificial intelligence (artificial intelligence act) and amending certain union legislative acts. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/resource.html?uri=cellar:e0649735-a372-11eb-9585-01aa75ed71a1.0001.02/DOC_1&amp;format=PDF (2021).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation><i>Regulation (EU) 2017/745 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 5 April 2017 on Medical Devices, Amending Directive 2001/83/EC, Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 and Regulation (EC) No 1223/2009 and Repealing Council Directives 90/385/EEC and 93/42/EEC (Text with EEA Relevance.)</i>. <i>OJ L</i> vol. 117 http://data.europa.eu/eli/reg/2017/745/oj/eng (2017).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>REGULATION (EU) 2017/746 OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND OF THE COUNCIL of 5 April 2017 on in vitro diagnostic medical devices and repealing Directive 98/79/EC and Commission Decision 2010/227/EU. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32017R0746&amp;from=EN (2022).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, S. et al. Learning from experience and finding the right balance in the governance of artificial intelligence and digital health technologies. <i>J. Med. Internet Res.</i><b>25</b>, e43682 (2023).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10148205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37058329</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bertuzzi, L. EU&#x2019;s AI Act negotiations hit the brakes over foundation models. https://www.euractiv.com/section/artificial-intelligence/news/eus-ai-act-negotiations-hit-the-brakes-over-foundation-models/ (2023).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Derraz, B. et al. New regulatory thinking is needed for AI-based personalised drug and cell therapies in precision oncology. <i>npj Precis. Oncol.</i><b>8</b>, 1&#x2013;11 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10828509</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38291217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert, S., Baca-Motes, K., Quer, G., Wiedermann, M. &amp; Brockmann, D. Citizen data sovereignty is key to wearables and wellness data reuse for the common good. <i>npj Digit. Med.</i><b>7</b>, 1&#x2013;3 (2024).</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10861551</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38347159</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>REGULATION (EU) 2016/679 OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND OF THE COUNCIL of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation). https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679 (2016).</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>