<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">41821400</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>22</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2026</Year><Month>04</Month><Day>24</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1477-0970</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><Issue>5</Issue><PubDate><Year>2026</Year><Month>Apr</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Multiple sclerosis (Houndmills, Basingstoke, England)</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Mult Scler</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>AI-enabled Living Labs: Accelerating innovation in multiple sclerosis care and research.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>451</StartPage><EndPage>458</EndPage><MedlinePgn>451-458</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/13524585261424136</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>The rapid rise of artificial intelligence (AI) and digital health technologies presents new opportunities for personalized care in multiple sclerosis (MS). However, implementation in routine practice is limited by regulatory hurdles, fragmented infrastructure and a lack of agile real-world evaluation methods. Living Labs (LLs) emerge as dynamic environments for advancing MS care and research, supporting early testing and iterative development of digital tools, while fostering structured collaboration among patients, clinicians, researchers and regulators. In this review, we conceptually frame LLs in MS and provide a concrete, clinic-ready implementation framework for AI-enabled application in real-world practice. Using a digital-based voice task as an exemplar with automated feature extraction, we detail integration patterns and define key performance indicators for feasibility, data quality, usability and clinical utility. We show how this co-designed model can generate decision-relevant evidence, may help shorten time-to-action and embed innovation seamlessly into clinical workflows. Finally, we align LL operations with ethical and regulatory standards and outline strategies to responsibly scale across centres.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Inojosa</LastName><ForeName>Hernan</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1377-836X</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Clinical Neuroscience, Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Carl Gustav Carus Dresden, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mathias</LastName><ForeName>Rebecca</ForeName><Initials>R</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3906-2415</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Else Kr&#xf6;ner Fresenius Center for Digital Health, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Dillenseger</LastName><ForeName>Anja</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Clinical Neuroscience, Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Carl Gustav Carus Dresden, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Voigt</LastName><ForeName>Isabel</ForeName><Initials>I</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0097-8589</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Clinical Neuroscience, Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Carl Gustav Carus Dresden, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Trentzsch</LastName><ForeName>Katrin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Clinical Neuroscience, Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Carl Gustav Carus Dresden, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Steinigen-Fuchs</LastName><ForeName>Julia</ForeName><Initials>J</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Member of the Ethics Committee, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Piehler</LastName><ForeName>Katrin</ForeName><Initials>K</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Quality and Medical Risk Management, Data Security, University Hospital Carl Gustav Carus Dresden, Technical University of Dresden, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Gilbert</LastName><ForeName>Stephen</ForeName><Initials>S</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Else Kr&#xf6;ner Fresenius Center for Digital Health, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ziemssen</LastName><ForeName>Tjalf</ForeName><Initials>T</Initials><Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8799-8202</Identifier><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center of Clinical Neuroscience, Department of Neurology, Faculty of Medicine and University Hospital Carl Gustav Carus Dresden, TUD Dresden University of Technology, Dresden, Germany.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType><PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2026</Year><Month>03</Month><Day>13</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>England</Country><MedlineTA>Mult Scler</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9509185</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1352-4585</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001185" MajorTopicYN="Y">Artificial Intelligence</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Learning Health System</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Living Lab</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">artificial intelligence</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">digital health</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multiple sclerosis</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting InterestsThe authors declared the following potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article: H.I. received speaker honoraria from Roche and financial support for research activities from Novartis, Teva, Biogen, Roche, and Alexion. S.G. declares a nonfinancial interest as an Advisory Group member of the EY-coordinated &#x2018;Study on Regulatory Governance and Innovation in the field of Medical Devices&#x2019; conducted on behalf of the Directorate-General for Health and Food Safety (SANTE) of the European Commission. S.G. declares the following competing financial interests: S.G. has or has had consulting relationships with Una Health GmbH, Lindus Health Ltd., Flo Ltd., ICURA ApS, Rock Health Inc., Thymia Ltd., FORUM Institut f&#xfc;r Management GmbH, High-Tech Gr&#xfc;nderfonds Management GmbH, Directorate-General for Research and Innovation of the European Commission and Ada Health GmbH and holds share options in Ada Health GmbH. T.Z. reports scientific advisory board and/or consulting for Biogen, Roche, Novartis, BMS, Sanofi and Merck; compensation for serving on speaker&#x2019;s bureaus for Roche, Neuraxpharm, Novartis, Merck, NovoNordisk, Sanofi, BMS, TEVA and Biogen; and research support from Biogen, Novartis, Merck, TEVA and Sanofi. A.D., K.T., J.S-F. and K.P. declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>52</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2026</Year><Month>3</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>3</Hour><Minute>32</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2026</Year><Month>4</Month><Day>22</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">41821400</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC13100325</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/13524585261424136</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Thompson AJ, Baranzini SE, Geurts J, et al. Multiple sclerosis. Lancet 2018; 391: 1622&#x2013;1636.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29576504</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Oh J, Airas L, Harrison D, et al. Neuroimaging to monitor worsening of multiple sclerosis: Advances supported by the grant for multiple sclerosis innovation. Front Neurol 2023; 14: 1319869.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10722910</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">38107636</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chitnis T, Prat A. A roadmap to precision medicine for multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler 2020; 26(5): 522&#x2013;532.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31965904</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dillenseger A, Weidemann ML, Trentzsch K, et al. Digital biomarkers in multiple sclerosis. Brain Sci 2021; 11: 1519.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8615428</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34827518</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schwab P, Karlen W. A deep learning approach to diagnosing multiple sclerosis from Smartphone data. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform 2021; 25(4): 1284&#x2013;1291.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32877343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gurevich M, Zilkha-Falb R, Sherman J, et al. Machine learning-based prediction of disease progression in primary progressive multiple sclerosis. Brain Commun 2025; 7(1): fcae427.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11707605</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39781330</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kynoch K, Ramis MA, Khalil H. PREMS and PROMS data within the acute health care context: A scoping review protocol. JBI Evid Synth 2021; 19(1): 229&#x2013;235.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32813406</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gilbert S, Mathias R, Sch&#xf6;nfelder A, et al. A roadmap for safe, regulation-compliant Living Labs for AI and digital health development. Sci Adv 2025; 11: eadv7719.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC12077496</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40367163</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zipfel N, Horreh B, Hulshof CTJ, et al. The relationship between the living lab approach and successful implementation of healthcare innovations: An integrative review. BMJ Open 2022; 12: e058630.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9240880</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35768105</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swinkels ICS, Huygens MWJ, Schoenmakers TM, et al. Lessons learned from a living lab on the broad adoption of ehealth in primary health care. J Med Internet Res 2018; 20: e83.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5897624</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29599108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Richardson S, Sinha A, Vahia I, et al. Brain health living labs. Am J Geriatr Psychiatry 2021; 29(7): 698&#x2013;703.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9011364</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33342676</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Schleimer E, Pearce J, Barnecut A, et al. A precision medicine tool for patients with multiple sclerosis (the open MS BioScreen): Human-centered design and development. J Med Internet Res 2020; 22: e15605.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7381029</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628124</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pomare C, Mahmoud Z, Vedovi A, et al. Learning health systems: A review of key topic areas and bibliometric trends. Learn Health Syst 2022; 6(1): e10265.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8753300</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35036549</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Horwitz LI, Kuznetsova M, Jones SA. Creating a learning health system through rapid-cycle, randomized testing. N Engl J Med 2019; 381: 1175&#x2013;1179.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31532967</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Clinical decision support software, guidance for industry, and Food and Drug Administration Staff, https://www.fda.gov/regulatory-information/search-fda-guidance-documents/clinical-decision-support-software (2022, accessed 15 August 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Health and Human Services Department. Health data, technology, and interoperability: Certification program updates, algorithm transparency, and information sharing (HTI-1) final Rule, HTTPS://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2024/01/09/2023-28857/health-data-technology-and-interoperability-certification-program-updates-algorithm-transparency-and (2024, accessed 15 August 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedict RHB, Amato MP, DeLuca J, et al. Cognitive impairment in multiple sclerosis: Clinical management, MRI, and therapeutic avenues. Lancet Neurol 2020; 19(10): 860&#x2013;871.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC10011205</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32949546</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Weinstock-Guttman B, Sormani MP, Repovic P. Predicting long-term disability in multiple sclerosis: A narrative review of current evidence and future directions. Int J MS Care 2022; 24(4): 184&#x2013;188.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9296054</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35875463</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Montalban X, Graves J, Midaglia L, et al. A smartphone sensor-based digital outcome assessment of multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler 2022; 28(4): 654&#x2013;664.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8961252</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34259588</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benedict RH, DeLuca J, Phillips G, et al. Validity of the Symbol Digit Modalities Test as a cognition performance outcome measure for multiple sclerosis. Mult Scler 2017; 23(5): 721&#x2013;733.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5405816</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28206827</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Block VJ, Bove R, Zhao C, et al. Association of continuous assessment of step count by remote monitoring with disability progression among adults with multiple sclerosis. JAMA Netw Open 2019; 2: e190570.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6484622</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30874777</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ianculescu M, B&#x103;jenaru L, Vasilevschi A-M, et al. Advancing neurodegenerative disease management: Technical, ethical, and regulatory insights from the NeuroPredict platform. Future Internet 2025; 17: 320.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Voigt I, Inojosa H, Wenk J. et al. Building a monitoring matrix for the management of multiple sclerosis. Autoimmun Rev 2023; 22: 103358.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">37178996</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Conradsson D, Ytterberg C, Engelkes C, et al. Activity limitations and participation restrictions in people with multiple sclerosis: A detailed 10-year perspective. Disabil Rehabil 2021; 43(3): 406&#x2013;413.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31190568</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crosby LE, Ware RE, Goldstein A, et al. Development and evaluation of iManage: a self-management app co-designed by adolescents with sickle cell disease. Pediatr Blood Cancer 2017; 64(1): 139&#x2013;145.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7354646</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27574031</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tabari P, Costagliola G, De Rosa M, et al. State-of-the-Art Fast Healthcare Interoperability Resources (FHIR)-Based Data Model and Structure Implementations: Systematic Scoping Review. JMIR Med Inform 2024; 12: e58445.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC11472501</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39316433</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The European Parliament and the council of The European Union. Regulation (EU) 2017/745 of the European Parliament of the Council of 5 April 2017 on medical devices. Official Journal of the European Union, 2017. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg/2017/745/oj/eng (2017, accessed 20 August 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
Union TEPatCoTE. Regulation 2016/6798 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 april 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data. Official Journal of the European Union, 2016. https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg/2016/679/oj/eng (2016, accessed 20 August 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
The European Parliament and the council of The European Union. Regulation (EU) 2024/1689 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 13 June 2024 laying down harmonised rules on artificial intelligence. Official Journal of the European Union, https://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg/2024/1689/oj/eng (2024, accessed 20 August 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Medical Association . Declaration of Helsinki: Ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA 2013; 310: 2191&#x2013;2194.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24141714</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>ISO. ISO 14155: 2020&#x2013;Clinical investigation of medical devices for human subjects&#x2013;Good clinical practice. Geneva, Switzerland: International Organization for Standardization, 2020</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>
International Council for Harmonisation of Technical Requirements for Pharmaceuticals for Human Use (ICH). Integrated Addendum to ICH E6(R1): Guideline for good clinical practice E6(R2). ICH, https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/ich-e6-good-clinical-practice-scientific-guideline (2016, accessed 20 August 2025).</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lavin A, Gilligan-Lee CM, Visnjic A, et al. Technology readiness levels for machine learning systems. Nat Commun 2022; 13: 6039.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9585100</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">36266298</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garthof S, Sch&#xe4;fer S, Elmers J, et al. Speech as a digital biomarker in multiple sclerosis: Automatic analysis of speech metrics using a multi-speech-task protocol in a cross-sectional MS cohort study. Mult Scler 2025; 31(7): 856&#x2013;865.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">40515641</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Narmadha K, Varalakshmi P. Federated learning in healthcare: A privacy preserving approach. Stud Health Technol Inform 2022; 294: 194&#x2013;198.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35612055</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Forrest CB, McTigue KM, Hernandez AF, et al. PCORnet&#xae; 2020: Current state, accomplishments, and future directions. J Clin Epidemiol 2021; 129: 60&#x2013;67.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7521354</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33002635</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>