<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated"><PMID Version="1">39016312</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2024</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>14</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2025</Year><Month>06</Month><Day>19</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5409</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>40</Volume><Issue>9</Issue><PubDate><Year>2024</Year><Month>Sep</Month><Day>01</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>The Clinical journal of pain</Title><ISOAbbreviation>Clin J Pain</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Virtual Reality for Subacute Pain After Orthopedic Traumatic Musculoskeletal Injuries: A Mixed Methods Pilot Study.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>526</StartPage><EndPage>541</EndPage><MedlinePgn>526-541</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/AJP.0000000000001231</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Acute orthopedic traumatic musculoskeletal injuries are prevalent, costly, and often lead to persistent pain and functional limitations. Psychological risk factors (eg, pain catastrophizing and anxiety) exacerbate these outcomes but are often overlooked in acute orthopedic care. Addressing gaps in current treatment approaches, this mixed-methods pilot study explored the use of a therapeutic virtual reality (VR; RelieVRx ), integrating principles of mindfulness and cognitive-behavioral therapy, for pain self-management at home following orthopedic injury.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We enrolled 10 adults with acute orthopedic injuries and elevated pain catastrophizing or pain anxiety from Level 1 Trauma Clinics within the Mass General Brigham health care system. Participants completed daily RelieVRx sessions at home for 8 weeks, which included pain education, relaxation, mindfulness, games, and dynamic breathing biofeedback. Primary outcomes were a priori feasibility, appropriateness, acceptability, satisfaction, and safety. Secondary outcomes were pre-post measures of pain, physical function, sleep, depression, and hypothesized mechanisms (pain self-efficacy, mindfulness, and coping).</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The VR and study procedures met or exceeded all benchmarks. We observed preliminary improvements in pain, physical functioning, sleep, depression, and mechanisms. Qualitative exit interviews confirmed high satisfaction with RelieVRx and yielded recommendations for promoting VR-based trials with orthopedic patients.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The results support a larger randomized clinical trial of RelieVRx versus a sham placebo control to replicate the findings and explore mechanisms. There is potential for self-guided VR to promote evidence-based pain management strategies and address the critical mental health care gap for patients following acute orthopedic injuries.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright &#xa9; 2024 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Mace</LastName><ForeName>Ryan A</ForeName><Initials>RA</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health Outcomes and Interdisciplinary Research, Massachusetts General Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Brewer</LastName><ForeName>Julie R</ForeName><Initials>JR</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health Outcomes and Interdisciplinary Research, Massachusetts General Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Cohen</LastName><ForeName>Joshua E</ForeName><Initials>JE</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Center for Health Outcomes and Interdisciplinary Research, Massachusetts General Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Ly</LastName><ForeName>Thuan V</ForeName><Initials>TV</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Massachusetts General Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Weaver</LastName><ForeName>Michael J</ForeName><Initials>MJ</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, Brigham and Women's Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Borsook</LastName><ForeName>David</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Harvard Medical School.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Massachusetts General Hospital.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2024</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>01</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>Clin J Pain</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>8507389</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>0749-8047</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><MeshHeadingList><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000076142" MajorTopicYN="Y">Virtual Reality</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D064866" MajorTopicYN="Y">Mindfulness</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D058443" MajorTopicYN="N">Catastrophization</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D015928" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognitive Behavioral Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059408" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Management</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D063367" MajorTopicYN="N">Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D059352" MajorTopicYN="N">Musculoskeletal Pain</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName><QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName><QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D000073278" MajorTopicYN="N">Self-Management</DescriptorName></MeshHeading><MeshHeading><DescriptorName UI="D010147" MajorTopicYN="N">Pain Measurement</DescriptorName></MeshHeading></MeshHeadingList><CoiStatement>This study was funded by the Cathedral Fund and support was provided by Applied VR. The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2024</Year><Month>2</Month><Day>5</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2024</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>17</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2024</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>12</Hour><Minute>43</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2024</Year><Month>7</Month><Day>17</Day><Hour>7</Hour><Minute>35</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">39016312</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AJP.0000000000001231</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">00002508-202409000-00004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Morris S, Lenihan B, Duddy L, et al. Outcome after musculoskeletal trauma treated in a regional hospital. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2000;49:461&#x2013;469.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busse JW, Heels-Ansdell D, Makosso-Kallyth S, et al. Patient coping and expectations predict recovery after major orthopaedic trauma. Br J Anaesth. 2019;122:51&#x2013;59.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Clay FJ, Newstead SV, Watson WL, et al. Bio-psychosocial determinants of persistent pain 6 months after non-life-threatening acute orthopaedic trauma. J Pain. 2010;11:420&#x2013;430.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Proctor TJ, Mayer TG, Gatchel RJ, et al. Unremitting health-care-utilization outcomes of tertiary rehabilitation of patients with chronic musculoskeletal disorders. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2004;86:62&#x2013;69.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mojtabai R. National trends in long-term use of prescription opioids. Pharmacoepidemiol Drug Saf. 2018;27:526&#x2013;534.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vranceanu AM, Bachoura A, Weening A, et al. Psychological factors predict disability and pain intensity after skeletal trauma. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2014;96:e20.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Turner JA, Anderson ML, Balderson BH, et al. Mindfulness-based stress reduction and cognitive behavioral therapy for chronic low back pain: similar effects on mindfulness, catastrophizing, self-efficacy, and acceptance in a randomized controlled trial. Pain. 2016;157:2434&#x2013;2444.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cherkin DC, Sherman KJ, Balderson BH, et al. Effect of mindfulness-based stress reduction vs cognitive behavioral therapy or usual care on back pain and functional limitations in adults with chronic low back pain: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2016;315:1240&#x2013;1249.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Westenberg RF, Zale EL, Heinhuis TJ, et al. Does a brief mindfulness exercise improve outcomes in upper extremity patients? A randomized controlled trial. Clin Orthop. 2018;476:790&#x2013;798.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chad-Friedman E, Talaei-Khoei M, Ring D, et al. First use of a brief 60-second mindfulness exercise in an orthopedic surgical practice: results from a pilot study. Arch Bone Jt Surg. 2017;5:400&#x2013;405.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnall BD, Scheman J, Davin S, et al. Pain psychology: a global needs assessment and national call to action. Pain Med Malden Mass. 2016;17:250&#x2013;263.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vranceanu AM, Beks RB, Guitton TG, et al. How do orthopaedic surgeons address psychological aspects of illness? Arch Bone Jt Surg. 2017;5:2&#x2013;9.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mallari B, Spaeth EK, Goh H, et al. Virtual reality as an analgesic for acute and chronic pain in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Pain Res. 2019;12:2053&#x2013;2085.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Keefe FJ, Huling DA, Coggins MJ, et al. Virtual reality for persistent pain: a new direction for behavioral pain management. Pain. 2012;153:2163&#x2013;2166.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Melzack R, Wall PD. Pain mechanisms: a new theory. Science. 1965;150:971&#x2013;979.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colloca L, Raghuraman N, Wang Y, et al. Virtual reality: physiological and behavioral mechanisms to increase individual pain tolerance limits. Pain. 2020;161:2010&#x2013;2021.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Crombez G, Eccleston C, Van Damme S, et al. Fear-avoidance model of chronic pain: the next generation. Clin J Pain. 2012;28:475&#x2013;483.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vlaeyen JWS, Linton SJ. Fear-avoidance and its consequences in chronic musculoskeletal pain: a state of the art. Pain. 2000;85:317&#x2013;332.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eccleston C, Fisher E, Liikkanen S, et al. A prospective, double-blind, pilot, randomized, controlled trial of an &#x201c;embodied&#x201d; virtual reality intervention for adults with low back pain. Pain. 2022;163:1700&#x2013;1715.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>MacIntyre E, Sigerseth M, Larsen TF, et al. Get your head in the game: a replicated single-case experimental design evaluating the effect of a novel virtual reality intervention in people with chronic low back pain. J Pain. 2023;24:1449&#x2013;1464.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Groenveld TD, Smits MLM, Knoop J, et al. Effect of a behavioral therapy-based virtual reality application on quality of life in chronic low back pain. Clin J Pain. 2023;39:278&#x2013;285.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia LM, Birckhead BJ, Krishnamurthy P, et al. An 8-week self-administered at-home behavioral skills-based virtual reality program for chronic low back pain: double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial conducted during COVID-19. J Med Internet Res. 2021;23:e26292.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Darnall BD, Krishnamurthy P, Tsuei J, et al. Self-administered skills-based virtual reality intervention for chronic pain: randomized controlled pilot study. JMIR Form Res. 2020;4:e17293.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddox T, Sparks C, Oldstone L, et al. Durable chronic low back pain reductions up to 24 months after treatment for an accessible, 8-week, in-home behavioral skills-based virtual reality program: a randomized controlled trial. Pain Med. 2023;24:1200&#x2013;1203.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hasenbring M, Hallner D, Klasen B. Psychological mechanisms in the transition from acute to chronic pain: over- or underrated?. Schmerz Berl Ger. 2001;15:442&#x2013;447.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chou R, McCarberg B. Managing acute back pain patients to avoid the transition to chronic pain. Pain Manag. 2011;1:69&#x2013;79.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pool JJM, Ostelo RWJG, Knol D, et al. Are psychological factors prognostic indicators of outcome in patients with sub-acute neck pain? Man Ther. 2010;15:111&#x2013;116.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mariano TY, Urman RD, Hutchison CA, et al. Cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) for subacute low back pain: a systematic review. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2018;22:15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Orenius T, Sil&#xe9;n E, Nuortimo A, et al. Psychological interventions in preventing chronicity of sub-acute back pain: a systematic review. Scand J Pain. 2022;22:211&#x2013;217.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Monticone M, Cedraschi C, Ambrosini E, et al. Cognitive-behavioural treatment for subacute and chronic neck pain. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2015;2024:CD010664.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lester EG, Hopkins SW, Popok PJ, et al. Adaptation of a live video mind-body program to a web-based platform for English-speaking adults with neurofibromatosis: protocol for the NF-Web Study. JMIR Res Protoc. 2021;10:e27526.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Greenberg J, Lin A, Zale EL, et al. Development and early feasibility testing of a mind-body physical activity program for patients with heterogeneous chronic pain; the getactive study. J Pain Res. 2019;12:3279&#x2013;3297.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jacobs CA, Mace RA, Greenberg J, et al. Development of a mind body program for obese knee osteoarthritis patients with comorbid depression. Contemp Clin Trials Commun. 2021;21:100720.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lester E, DiStefano S, Mace R, et al. Virtual mind-body treatment for geographically diverse youth with neurofibromatosis: a pilot randomized controlled trial. Gen Hosp Psychiatry. 2020;62:72&#x2013;78.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mace RA, Greenberg J, Stauder M, et al. My healthy brain: a multimodal lifestyle program to promote brain health. Aging Ment Health. 2022;26:980&#x2013;991.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Mace RA, Doorley JD, Popok PJ, et al. Live video adaptations to a mind-body activity program for chronic pain and cognitive decline: protocol for the virtual active brains study. JMIR Res Protoc. 2021;10:e25351.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gold JI, Belmont KA, Thomas DA. The neurobiology of virtual reality pain attenuation. Cyberpsychology Behav Impact Internet Multimed Virtual Real Behav Soc. 2007;10:536&#x2013;544.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li A, Monta&#xf1;o Z, Chen VJ, et al. Virtual reality and pain management: current trends and future directions. Pain Manag. 2011;1:147&#x2013;157.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhao N, Fan L, Zeng J, et al. Virtual reality in managing dental pain and anxiety: a comprehensive review. Front Med. 2023;10:1285142.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Creswell J, Plano Clark V. Choosing a mixed methods design. Designing and Conducting Mixed Methods Research. SAGE Publications Inc.; 2017. https://us.sagepub.com/sites/default/files/upm-binaries/35066_Chapter3.pdf</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vranceanu AM, Jacobs C, Lin A, et al. Results of a feasibility randomized controlled trial (RCT) of the Toolkit for Optimal Recovery (TOR): a live video program to prevent chronic pain in at-risk adults with orthopedic injuries. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2019;5:30.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Garcia LM, Darnall BD, Krishnamurthy P, et al. Self-administered behavioral skills-based at-home virtual reality therapy for chronic low back pain: protocol for a randomized controlled trial. JMIR Res Protoc. 2021;10:e25291.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health (NCCIH. Framework for Developing and Testing Mind and Body Interventions. Grants and Funding. 2020. Accessed September 1, 2020. https://www.nccih.nih.gov/grants/framework-for-developing-and-testing-mind-and-body-interventions</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lancaster GA, Dodd S, Williamson PR. Design and analysis of pilot studies: recommendations for good practice. J Eval Clin Pract. 2004;10:307&#x2013;312.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Leon AC, Davis LL, Kraemer HC. The role and interpretation of pilot studies in clinical research. J Psychiatr Res. 2011;45:626&#x2013;629.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kraemer HC. &#x201c;Rules&#x201d; of evidence in assessing the efficacy and effectiveness of treatments. Dev Neuropsychol. 2011;24:705&#x2013;718.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Marin TJ, Van Eerd D, Irvin E, et al. Multidisciplinary biopsychosocial rehabilitation for subacute low back pain. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;6:CD002193.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bussi&#xe8;res AE, Stewart G, Al-Zoubi F, et al. The treatment of neck pain-associated disorders and Whiplash-associated disorders: a clinical practice guideline. J Manipulative Physiol Ther. 2016;39:523&#x2013;564.e27.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vranceanu AM, Bakhshaie J, Reichman M, et al. A live video program to prevent chronic pain and disability in at-risk adults with acute orthopedic injuries (toolkit for optimal recovery): protocol for a Multisite Feasibility Study. JMIR Res Protoc. 2021;10:e28155.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bakhshaie J, Doorley J, Reichman M, et al. Optimizing the implementation of a multisite feasibility trial of a mind-body program in acute orthopedic trauma. Transl Behav Med. 2022;12:642&#x2013;653.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vranceanu AM, Bakhshaie J, Reichman M, et al. Understanding barriers and facilitators to implementation of psychosocial care within orthopedic trauma centers: a qualitative study with multidisciplinary stakeholders from geographically diverse settings. Implement Sci Commun. 2021;2:102.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor AM, Phillips K, Patel K, et al. Assessment of physical function and participation in chronic pain clinical trials: IMMPACT/OMERACT recommendations. Pain. 2016;157:1836&#x2013;1850.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>World Health Organization, ed. International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health: ICF . World Health Organization; 2001.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Devilly GJ, Borkovec TD. Psychometric properties of the credibility/expectancy questionnaire. J Behav Ther Exp Psychiatry. 2000;31:73&#x2013;86.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Larsen DL, Attkisson CC, Hargreaves WA, et al. Assessment of client/patient satisfaction: development of a general scale. Eval Program Plann. 1979;2:197&#x2013;207.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bangor A, Kortum PT, Miller JT. An empirical evaluation of the system usability scale. Int J Hum-Comput Interact. 2008;24:574&#x2013;594.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose M, Bjorner JB, Becker J, et al. Evaluation of a preliminary physical function item bank supported the expected advantages of the Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS). J Clin Epidemiol. 2008;61:17&#x2013;33.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Stone AA, Broderick JE, Junghaenel DU, et al. PROMIS fatigue, pain intensity, pain interference, pain behavior, physical function, depression, anxiety, and anger scales demonstrate ecological validity. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016;74:194&#x2013;206.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Broderick JE, Schneider S, Junghaenel DU, et al. Validity and reliability of patient-reported outcomes measurement information system (PROMIS) instruments in osteoarthritis. Arthritis Care Res. 2013;24:1625&#x2013;1633.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rothrock NE, Kaat AJ, Vrahas MS, et al. Validation of PROMIS Physical Function Instruments in patients with an orthopaedic trauma to a lower extremity. J Orthop Trauma. 2019;33:377&#x2013;383</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rose AJ, Bayliss E, Huang W, et al. Evaluating the PROMIS-29 v2.0 for use among older adults with multiple chronic conditions. Qual Life Res. 2018;27:2935&#x2013;2944.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Purvis TE, Andreou E, Neuman BJ, et al. Concurrent validity and responsiveness of PROMIS health domains among patients presenting for anterior cervical spine surgery. Spine. 2017;42:E1357&#x2013;E1365.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Swiontkowski MF, Engelberg R, Martin DP, et al. Short Musculoskeletal Function Assessment Questionnaire: validity, reliability, and responsiveness. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 1999;81:1245&#x2013;1260.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf MW, El Moumni M, Heineman E, et al. Short Musculoskeletal Function Assessment: normative data of the Dutch population. Qual Life Res. 2015;24:2015&#x2013;2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>de Graaf MW, Reininga IH, Wendt KW, et al. The Short Musculoskeletal Function Assessment: a study of the reliability, construct validity and responsiveness in patients sustaining trauma. Clin Rehabil. 2019;33:923&#x2013;935.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>McCreary DL, Cunningham BP. Minimum clinically important difference in Short Musculoskeletal Function Assessment: what change matters in ankle fractures. Foot Ankle Spec. 2021;14:496&#x2013;500.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Alghadir AH, Anwer S, Iqbal A, et al. Test-retest reliability, validity, and minimum detectable change of visual analog, numerical rating, and verbal rating scales for measurement of osteoarthritic knee pain. J Pain Res. 2018;11:851&#x2013;856.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bahreini M, Safaie A, Mirfazaelian H, et al. How much change in pain score does really matter to patients? Am J Emerg Med. 2020;38:1641&#x2013;1646.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Polomano RC, Galloway KT, Kent ML, et al. Psychometric Testing of the Defense and Veterans Pain Rating Scale (DVPRS): a new pain scale for military population. Pain Med. 2016;17:1505&#x2013;1519.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sullivan MJL, Bishop SR, Pivik J. The Pain Catastrophizing Scale: development and validation. Psychol Assess. 1995;7:524&#x2013;532.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bascour-Sandoval C, Albayay J, Mart&#xed;nez-Molina A, et al. Psychometric properties of the PCS and the PCS-4 in individuals with musculoskeletal pain. Psicothema. 2022;34:323&#x2013;331.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Roelofs J, McCracken L, Peters ML, et al. Psychometric Evaluation of the Pain Anxiety Symptoms Scale (PASS) in chronic pain patients. J Behav Med. 2004;27:167&#x2013;183.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cuijpers P, Smit F, Willemse G. Predicting the onset of major depression in subjects with subthreshold depression in primary care: a prospective study. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 2005;111:133&#x2013;138.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nota SPFT, Bot AGJ, Ring D, et al. Disability and depression after orthopaedic trauma. Injury. 2015;46:207&#x2013;212.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rodriguez-Leal FA, Haase R, Akg&#xfc;n K, et al. Nonwalking response to fampridine in patients with multiple sclerosis in a real-world setting. Ther Adv Chronic Dis. 2019;10:2040622319835136.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nicholas MK. The Pain Self-Efficacy Questionnaire: taking pain into account. Eur J Pain. 2007;11:153&#x2013;163.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dub&#xe9; MO, Langevin P, Roy JS. Measurement properties of the Pain Self-Efficacy Questionnaire in populations with musculoskeletal disorders: a systematic review. PAIN Rep. 2021;6:e972.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Feldman G, Hayes A, Kumar S, et al. Mindfulness and emotion regulation: the development and initial validation of the Cognitive and Affective Mindfulness Scale-Revised (CAMS-R). J Psychopathol Behav Assess. 2007;29:177&#x2013;190.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Doorley JD, Mace RA, Popok PJ, et al. Feasibility randomized controlled trial of a mind-body activity program for older adults with chronic pain and cognitive decline: the virtual &#x201c;Active Brains&#x201d; study. Gerontologist. 2021;62:1082&#x2013;1094.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chimenti RL, Rakel BA, Dailey DL, et al. Test-retest reliability and responsiveness of PROMIS sleep short forms within an RCT in women with fibromyalgia. Front Pain Res. 2021;2:682072.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ibaseta A, Rahman R, Andrade NS, et al. Determining validity, discriminant ability, responsiveness, and minimal clinically important differences for PROMIS in adult spinal deformity. J Neurosurg Spine. 2021;34:725&#x2013;733.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nie JW, Hartman TJ, Oyetayo OO, et al. Impact of sleep disturbance on clinical outcomes in lumbar decompression. World Neurosurg. 2023;172:e304&#x2013;e311</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Busner J, Targum SD. The Clinical Global Impressions Scale. Psychiatry Edgmont. 2007;4:28&#x2013;37.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Maddox T, Oldstone L, Sackman J, et al. Sociodemographic predictors of clinical effectiveness, therapeutic program engagement, and device usability for an in-home virtual reality program for chronic low back pain: secondary analysis of a randomized controlled trial. J Med Ext Real. 2024;1:65&#x2013;72.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Onken LS, Carroll KM, Shoham V, et al. Reenvisioning clinical science: unifying the discipline to improve the public health. Clin Psychol Sci J Assoc Psychol Sci. 2014;2:22&#x2013;34.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>RStudio Team. RStudio: Integrated Development Environment for R. 2022. Accessed September 23, 2022. http://www.rstudio.com/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>R Core Team. R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. 2020. Accessed June 1, 2021. https://www.R-project.org/</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HY. Statistical notes for clinical researchers: assessing normal distribution (2) using skewness and kurtosis. Restor Dent Endod. 2013;38:52&#x2013;54.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hair J, Black WC, Babin BJ, et al. Multivariate Data Analysis, 7th ed. Pearson Educational International; 2010.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eldridge SM, Chan CL, Campbell MJ, et al. CONSORT 2010 statement: extension to randomised pilot and feasibility trials. BMJ. 2016;355:i5239.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cohen J. Statistical Power Analysis for the Behavioral Sciences, 2nd ed. L. Erlbaum Associates; 1988.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vindrola-Padros C, Johnson GA. Rapid techniques in qualitative research: a critical review of the literature. Qual Health Res. 2020;30:1596&#x2013;1604.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Gale RC, Wu J, Erhardt T, et al. Comparison of rapid vs in-depth qualitative analytic methods from a process evaluation of academic detailing in the Veterans Health Administration. Implement Sci. 2019;14:11.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Renfro CP, Rome Z, Gatwood J, et al. Use of rapid assessment procedures when analyzing qualitative data in pharmacy research. Res Soc Adm Pharm RSAP. 2022;18:2249&#x2013;2253.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hamilton AB, Finley EP. Qualitative methods in implementation research: an introduction. Psychiatry Res. 2019;280:112516.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Taylor B, Henshall C, Kenyon S, et al. Can rapid approaches to qualitative analysis deliver timely, valid findings to clinical leaders? A mixed methods study comparing rapid and thematic analysis. BMJ Open. 2018;8:e019993.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Averill JB. Matrix analysis as a complementary analytic strategy in qualitative inquiry. Qual Health Res. 2002;12:855&#x2013;866.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Fetters MD, Curry LA, Creswell JW. Achieving integration in mixed methods designs&#x2014;principles and practices. Health Serv Res. 2013;48(pt 2):2134&#x2013;2156.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Guetterman TC, Fetters MD, Creswell JW. Integrating quantitative and qualitative results in health science mixed methods research through joint displays. Ann Fam Med. 2015;13:554&#x2013;561.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>O&#x2019;Cathain A, Murphy E, Nicholl J. Three techniques for integrating data in mixed methods studies. BMJ. 2010;341:c4587.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Reilly CA, Greeley AB, Jevsevar DS, et al. Virtual reality-based physical therapy for patients with lower extremity injuries: feasibility and acceptability. OTA Int. 2021;4:e132.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin HT, Li YI, Hu WP, et al. A scoping review of the efficacy of virtual reality and exergaming on patients of musculoskeletal system disorder. J Clin Med. 2019;8:791.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahern MM, Dean LV, Stoddard CC, et al. The effectiveness of virtual reality in patients with spinal pain: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Pain Pract. 2020;20:656&#x2013;675.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ehioghae M, Montoya A, Keshav R, et al. Effectiveness of virtual reality-based rehabilitation interventions in improving postoperative outcomes for orthopedic surgery patients. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2023;28:37&#x2013;45.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>The Major Extremity Trauma Rehabilitation Consortium (METRC). Early effects of the Trauma Collaborative Care Intervention: results from a prospective multicenter cluster clinical trial. J Orthop Trauma. 2019;33:538&#x2013;546.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Major Extremity Trauma Research Consortium (METRC). The 12-month effects of the trauma collaborative care intervention: a nonrandomized controlled trial. J Bone Jt Surg. 2022;104:1796&#x2013;1804.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Triberti S, Repetto C, Riva G. Psychological factors influencing the effectiveness of virtual reality-based analgesia: a systematic review. Cyberpsychology Behav Soc Netw. 2014;17:335&#x2013;345.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Borsook D, Youssef AM, Simons L, et al. When pain gets stuck: the evolution of pain chronification and treatment resistance. Pain. 2018;159:2421&#x2013;2436.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Holmes SA, Barakat N, Bhasin M, et al. Biological and behavioral markers of pain following nerve injury in humans. Neurobiol Pain Camb Mass. 2020;7:100038.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Previtali D, Boffa A, Di Martino A, et al. Recall bias affects pain assessment in knee osteoarthritis: a pilot study. Cartilage. 2022;13:50&#x2013;58.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jayakumar P, Overbeek CL, Lamb S, et al. What factors are associated with disability after upper extremity injuries? A systematic review. Clin Orthop. 2018;476:2190&#x2013;2215.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Obey MR, Miller AN. Resources for Patient mental health and well-being after orthopaedic trauma. J Orthop Trauma. 2022;36:S10&#x2013;S15.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Archer KR, Castillo RC, MacKenzie EJ, et al. Perceived need and unmet need for vocational, mental health, and other support services after severe lower-extremity trauma. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2010;91:774&#x2013;780.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>