<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">31403414</PMID><DateRevised><Year>2024</Year><Month>02</Month><Day>27</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Print-Electronic"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1941-0042</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><PubDate><Year>2019</Year><Month>Aug</Month><Day>08</Day></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>IEEE transactions on image processing : a publication of the IEEE Signal Processing Society</Title><ISOAbbreviation>IEEE Trans Image Process</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>Graph Transform Optimization with Application to Image Compression.</ArticleTitle><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1109/TIP.2019.2932853</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText>In this paper, we propose a new graph-based transform and illustrate its potential application to signal compression. Our approach relies on the careful design of a graph that optimizes the overall rate-distortion performance through an effective graph-based transform. We introduce a novel graph estimation algorithm, which uncovers the connectivities between the graph signal values by taking into consideration the coding of both the signal and the graph topology in rate-distortion terms. In particular, we introduce a novel coding solution for the graph by treating the edge weights as another graph signal that lies on the dual graph. Then, the cost of the graph description is introduced in the optimization problem by minimizing the sparsity of the coefficients of its graph Fourier transform (GFT) on the dual graph. In this way, we obtain a convex optimization problem whose solution defines an efficient transform coding strategy. The proposed technique is a general framework that can be applied to different types of signals, and we show two possible application fields, namely natural image coding and piecewise smooth image coding. The experimental results show that the proposed graph-based transform outperforms classical fixed transforms such as DCT for both natural and piecewise smooth images. In the case of depth map coding, the obtained results are even comparable to the state-of-the-art graph-based coding method, that are specifically designed for depth map images.</AbstractText></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Fracastoro</LastName><ForeName>Giulia</ForeName><Initials>G</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Thanou</LastName><ForeName>Dorina</ForeName><Initials>D</Initials></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Frossard</LastName><ForeName>Pascal</ForeName><Initials>P</Initials></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2019</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>08</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>United States</Country><MedlineTA>IEEE Trans Image Process</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>9886191</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>1057-7149</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>14</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2019</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>13</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31403414</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TIP.2019.2932853</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>