<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2025//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_250101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle><MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM"><PMID Version="1">34484832</PMID><DateCompleted><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateCompleted><DateRevised><Year>2021</Year><Month>09</Month><Day>21</Day></DateRevised><Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection"><Journal><ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2090-1224</ISSN><JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet"><Volume>32</Volume><PubDate><Year>2021</Year><Month>Sep</Month></PubDate></JournalIssue><Title>Journal of advanced research</Title><ISOAbbreviation>J Adv Res</ISOAbbreviation></Journal><ArticleTitle>A new general integral transform for solving integral equations.</ArticleTitle><Pagination><StartPage>133</StartPage><EndPage>138</EndPage><MedlinePgn>133-138</MedlinePgn></Pagination><ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jare.2020.08.016</ELocationID><Abstract><AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION">Integral transforms are important to solve real problems. Appropriate choice of integral transforms helps to convert differential equations as well as integral equations into terms of an algebraic equation that can be solved easily.During last two decades many integral transforms in the class of Laplace transform are introduced such as Sumudu, Elzaki, Natural, Aboodh, Pourreza, Mohand, G_transform, Sawi and Kamal transforms.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">In this paper, we introduce a general integral transform in the class of Laplace transform. We study the properties of this transform. Then we compare it with few exiting integral transforms in the Laplace family such as Laplace, Sumudu, Elzaki and G\_transforms, Pourreza, Aboodh and etc.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="METHODS">A new integral transform is introduced. Then some properties of this integral transform are discussed. This integral transform is used to solve this new transform is used for solving higher order initial value problems, integral equations and fractional order integral equation.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="RESULTS">It is proved that those new transforms in the class of Laplace transform which are introduced during last few decades are a special case of this general transform. It is shown that there is no advantage between theses transforms unless for special problems.</AbstractText><AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">It has shown that this new integral transform covers those exiting transforms such as Laplace, Elzaki and Sumudu transforms for different value of <i>p</i>(<i>s</i>) and <i>q</i>(<i>s</i>). We used this new transform for solving ODE, integral equations and fractional integral equations. Also, we can introduce new integral transforms by using this new general integral transform.</AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>&#xa9; 2021 The Authors. Published by Elsevier B.V. on behalf of Cairo University.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><AuthorList CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Jafari</LastName><ForeName>Hossein</ForeName><Initials>H</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics, University of Mazandaran, Babolsar, Iran.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematical Sciences, University of South Africa, UNISA0003, South Africa.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, China Medical University Hospital, China Medical University, Taichung 110122, Taiwan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Informatics, Azerbaijan University, Jeyhun Hajibeyli, 71, AZ1007, Baku, Azerbaijan.</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><Language>eng</Language><PublicationTypeList><PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType></PublicationTypeList><ArticleDate DateType="Electronic"><Year>2020</Year><Month>08</Month><Day>28</Day></ArticleDate></Article><MedlineJournalInfo><Country>Egypt</Country><MedlineTA>J Adv Res</MedlineTA><NlmUniqueID>101546952</NlmUniqueID><ISSNLinking>2090-1224</ISSNLinking></MedlineJournalInfo><CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset><KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM"><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">26A33</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">31B10</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">44A10</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fractional order integral equations</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Integral equation</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Laplace transform</Keyword><Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ordinary differential equations</Keyword></KeywordList><CoiStatement>The author declare that they have no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement></MedlineCitation><PubmedData><History><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received"><Year>2020</Year><Month>6</Month><Day>7</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>2</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>23</Day></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>6</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>2</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>0</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline"><Year>2021</Year><Month>9</Month><Day>7</Day><Hour>6</Hour><Minute>1</Minute></PubMedPubDate><PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release"><Year>2020</Year><Month>8</Month><Day>28</Day></PubMedPubDate></History><PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34484832</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8408327</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jare.2020.08.016</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pii">S2090-1232(20)30202-2</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Aboodh K.S. The new integral transform aboodh transform. Global J Pure Appl Mathe. 2013;9(1):35&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abbas N., Malik M.Y., Alqarni M.S., Nadeem S. Study of three dimensional stagnation point flow of hybrid nanofluid over an isotropic slip surface. Physica A. 2020;554:124020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi S.A.P., Hosseinzadeh H., Cherati A.Y. A new integral transform for solving higher order linear ordinary differential equations. Nonlinear Dyn Syst Theory. 2019;19(2):243&#x2013;252.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ali U., Malik M.Y., Rehman K.U., Alqarni M.S. Exploration of cubic autocatalysis and thermal relaxation in a non-Newtonian flow field with MHD effects. Physica A. 2020;549:124349.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ahmadi S.A.P., Hosseinzadeh H., Cherati A.Y. A new integral transform for solving higher order linear ordinary Laguerre and Hermite differential equations. Int J Appl Comput Math. 2019;5:142. doi: 10.1007/s40819-019-0712-1.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40819-019-0712-1</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelrahim Mahgoub M.M. The new integral transform mohand transform. Adv Theoret Appl Mathe. 2017;12(2):113&#x2013;120.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Abdelrahim Mahgoub M.M. The new integral transform sawi transform. Adv Theoret Appl Mathe. 2019;14(1):81&#x2013;87.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baleanu D., Wu G. Some further results of the laplace transform for variable-order fractional difference equations. Fract Calcul Appl Anal. 2019;22(6):1641&#x2013;1654. doi: 10.1515/fca-2019-0084.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1515/fca-2019-0084</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Baleanu D., Diethelm K., Scalas E., Trujillo J.J. World Scientific Publishing Company; 2012. Fractional calculus: models and numerical methods.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Bokhari A., Baleanu D., Belgacem R. Application of Shehu transform to Atangana-Baleanu derivatives. J Mathe Comput Sci. 2020;20(2):101&#x2013;107.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chand M, Hammouch Z. Unified fractional integral formulae involving generalized multiindex Bessel function. In: 4th International Conference on Computational Mathematics and Engineering Sciences (CMES-2019). CMES 2019. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, vol 1111. Springer, Cham, 2020.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cho I., Hwajoon K. The solution of Bessel&#x2019;s equation by using Integral Transform. Appl Mathe Sci. 2014;7(122):6069&#x2013;6075.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Davies B. Springer; New York, NY: 2002. Integral transforms and their applications.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Eltayeb H., Kiliman A., Fisher B. A new integral transform and associated distributions. Integral Transforms Special Funct. 2010;21(5):367&#x2013;379.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elzaki T.M. The new integral transform Elzaki Transform. Global J Pure Appl Mathe. 2011;7(1):57&#x2013;64.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Elzaki T.M., Elzaki S.M., Hilal E.M.A. Elzaki and sumudu transforms for solving some differential equations. Global J Pure Appl Mathe. 2012;8(2):167&#x2013;173.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Jafari H., Sadeghi Roushan S., Haghbin A. The Laplace decomposition method for solving n-th order fuzzy differential equations. Ann Fuzzy Mathe Informat. 2014;7(4):653&#x2013;660.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kamal H., Sedeeg A. The new integral transform Kamal transform. Adv Theoret Appl Mathe. 2016;11(4):451&#x2013;458.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H. On the form and properties of an integral transform with strength in integral transforms. Far East J Mathe Sci. 2017;102(11):2831&#x2013;2844.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim H. The intrinsic structure and properties of laplace-typed integral transforms. Mathe Probl Eng, 2017, Article ID 1762729, 8 p.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan Z.H., Khan W.A. N-transform properties and applications. NUST J Eng Sci. 2008;1(1):127&#x2013;133.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Khan M., Salahuddin T., Malik M.Y., Alqarni M.S., Alqahtani A.M. Numerical modeling and analysis of bioconvection on MHD flow due to an upper paraboloid surface of revolution. Physica A. 2020;553:124231.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kexue L., Jigen P. Laplace transform and fractional differential equations. Appl Mathe Lett. 2011;24(12):2019&#x2013;2023.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Panasare P.D., Chalke S.P., Choure A.G. Application of Laplace transformation in cryptography. Int J Mathe Archive. 2012;3(7):2470&#x2013;2473.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lin S., Lu C. Laplace transform for solving some families of fractional differential equations and its applications. Adv Differ Equ. 2013;2013:137. doi: 10.1186/1687-1847-2013-137. 9pages.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1687-1847-2013-137</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Li C, Qian D, Chen YQ. On riemann-liouville and caputo derivatives, discrete dynamics in nature and society, volume 2011, Article ID 562494, 15 pages, doi: 10.1155/2011/562494.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Medina G.D., Ojeda N.R., Pereira J.H., Romero L.G. Fractional laplace transform and fractional calculus. Int Mathe Forum. 2017;12(20):991&#x2013;1000.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nadeem S., Malik M.Y., Abbas N. Heat transfer of three-dimensional micropolar fluid on a Riga plate. Can J Phys. 2020;98(1):32&#x2013;38.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Podlubny I. Academic Press; San Diego: 1999. Fractional differential equations.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rashid S., Hammouch Z., Kalsoom H., Ashraf R., Chu Y.M. New investigations on the generalized K-fractional integral operators. Front Phys. 2020;8:25.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh J., Kumar D., Baleanu D., Rathore S. An efficient numerical algorithm for the fractional Drinfeld&#x2013;Sokolov&#x2013;Wilson equation. Appl Math Comput. 2018;335:12&#x2013;24.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweilam NH, AL-Mekhlafi SM, Baleanu D. Nonstandard finite difference method for solving complex-order fractional Burgers&#x2019; equations. J Adv Res. 2020 https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jare.2020.04.007 [In Press].</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7474191</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32922970</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sweilam N.H., Al-Ajami T.M. Legendre spectral-collocation method for solving some types of fractional optimal control problems. J Adv Res. 2015;6(3):393&#x2013;403.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4523169</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26257937</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Shah K., Junaid M., Ali N. Extraction of laplace, sumudu, fourier and mellin transform from the natural transform. J Appl Envron Biol Sci. 2015;5(9):1&#x2013;10.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tanveer A., Salahuddin T., Khan M., Malik M.Y., Alqarni M.S. Theoretical analysis of non-Newtonian blood flow in a microchannel. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2020;191:105280.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32066045</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Watugala G.K. Sumudu transform: a new integral transform to solve differential equations and control engineering problems. Int J Math Educat Sci Technol. 1993;24(1):35&#x2013;43.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Yang X.J. A new integral transform operator for solving the heat-diffusion problem. Appl Mathe Lett. 2017;64:193&#x2013;197.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>West B.J., Bologna M., Grigolini P. Physics of Fractal Operators. Institute for Nonlinear Science. Springer; New York, NY: 2003. Fractional Laplace Transforms.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ziane D., Baleanu D., Belghaba K., Hamdi Cherif M. Local fractional Sumudu decomposition method for linear partial differential equations with local fractional derivative. J King Saud Univ-Sci. 2019;31(1):1018&#x2013;1364.</Citation></Reference><Reference><Citation>Zhang J. A Sumudu based algorithm for solving differential equations. Comput Sci J Moldova. 2007;15(3):45.</Citation></Reference></ReferenceList></PubmedData></PubmedArticle></PubmedArticleSet>